<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-02T03:01:24.317913+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-01 15:00:59.545000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T03:01:24.317951+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing challenges with Bitcoin regarding address reuse and information leakage cannot be entirely eliminated. However, the community has the power to influence user behavior through the implementation of certain system rules. Proposals aimed at altering these behaviors can either incentivize or disincentivize specific actions. For instance, changes that make CoinJoins marginally less expensive than individual transactions could encourage users towards more privacy-centric practices. 

The concept of CISA (Coin Input Selection Algorithm) is introduced as a mechanism to promote transactions that incorporate multiple inputs. This approach not only benefits transactions that are inherently coordinated but also extends its advantages to those where all inputs are controlled by a single user. Essentially, by making consolidated transactions financially more appealing, CISA aims to motivate a shift in how transactions are structured, thereby indirectly addressing some of the privacy concerns associated with Bitcoin usage.

For further details on this topic, including technical discussions and community feedback, one can refer to the archived content available at [this link](https://web.archive.org/web/20260101145930/https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/12). This resource provides deeper insights into the proposed changes and their potential impact on Bitcoin transaction practices.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-01T15:00:59.545000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
