<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v30.1 Released</title>
  <updated>2026-01-03T02:53:06.378283+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-02 16:08:56.413000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v30.1 Released</title>
    <updated>2026-01-03T02:53:06.378328+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-1-released/2183" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest version of Bitcoin Core, v30.1, is now available for download. This new release brings with it several new features, a range of bug fixes, and performance enhancements alongside updated translations. Users encountering any issues are encouraged to use the GitHub issue tracker for reporting.

For those looking to upgrade from an older version, the process involves shutting down the existing software before initiating the upgrade. This might require a few minutes for complete shutdown, especially in cases where a direct upgrade from an end-of-life (EOL) version is attempted. Data directory migration during such upgrades might extend the duration. It's important to note that Bitcoin Core continues to support old wallet versions across upgrades.

Compatibility of Bitcoin Core extends to operating systems running Linux Kernel 3.17 and above, macOS 13 and above, and Windows 10 and higher. While it may function on other Unix-like systems as well, these environments undergo less frequent testing, and using Bitcoin Core on unsupported systems is generally discouraged.

Significant updates in this release touch on various components of Bitcoin Core:

- The Wallet segment sees an improvement where unconfirmed TRUC coins with ancestors are not considered.
- Build dependencies have been updated for better fallback downloading and a patch added for Windows11Style plugin, alongside a change to turn off macOS SDK compression to ensure determinism.
- In IPC, adjustments have been made to facilitate multiprocess operations without requiring specific arguments and to reduce message logging overhead. Additionally, there are fixes to miner operations regarding empty mempool scenarios and enhancements in interfaces to enable canceling of ongoing waitNext calls.
- P2P network changes include the removal of a dnsseed entry.
- The GUI has been modernized with custom filtering options and the inclusion of new wallet creation and migration commands in the history filter.
- Testing frameworks and documentation have received updates for better clarity and efficiency.
- Several miscellaneous improvements have been made to continuous integration processes and manpage generation, among others.

This release was made possible thanks to contributions from numerous individuals, highlighting the collaborative effort of the Bitcoin Core development community. Contributors to this version include Ava Chow, Cory Fields, Eugene Siegel, and others, along with those contributing to translations and other non-direct contributions.

For detailed information or to download the new version, please refer to the official Bitcoin Core website.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-02T16:08:56.413000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
