<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
  <updated>2026-01-04T03:12:04.045761+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jgmcalpine</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-03 22:17:28.856000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
    <updated>2026-01-04T03:12:04.045797+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ark-as-a-channel-factory-compressed-liquidity-management-for-improved-payment-feasibility/2179/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the economic efficiencies and drawbacks of utilizing Ark for improving payment feasibility through compressed liquidity management in comparison with On-chain funded topologies. Ark-funded models, referred to as "the Factory," allow a Liquidity Service Provider (LSP) to minimize liquidity mismatches efficiently. However, this model introduces a perpetual "Liveness Tax" due to the necessity of refreshing or rolling over backing virtual Transaction Outputs (vTXOs) at each expiry period, typically every 2 to 4 weeks. This requirement not only incurs recurring Application Specific Port (ASP) fees but also operational demands.

On the other hand, the On-chain funded model, known as "Legacy channels," presents a different set of economic implications. In this scenario, an LSP faces a high opportunity cost due to the inefficient allocation of locked capital. Despite this inefficiency, the model benefits from near-zero maintenance costs, contrasting sharply with the continuous overhead associated with the Ark-funded approach.

A pivotal question arises regarding the strategic deployment of these funding models within a network graph to enhance payment feasibility. The inquiry delves into whether an entire network should adopt the Ark-funded model to leverage its liquidity management benefits fully or if there exists a demand threshold. Beyond this threshold, predictable demand enables balanced flows or high velocity, thereby diminishing the value of dynamic resizing offered by the Factory. This situation could render a static channel approach more economically advantageous, prompting a reassessment of the Factory's role: whether it serves as a permanent solution or merely a transitional phase towards Liquidity Discovery.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-03T22:17:28.856000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
