<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
  <updated>2026-01-06T03:03:17.184170+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-05 12:53:27.321000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T03:03:17.184201+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ark-as-a-channel-factory-compressed-liquidity-management-for-improved-payment-feasibility/2179/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses the intricacies of liquidity management within a specific technological framework, focusing on the optimization of liquidity requirements and the challenges associated with it. The sender highlights two main components that need to be addressed: worst-case overlap exposure and inbound liquidity. The former refers to a scenario where refreshed vtxos (presumably virtual transaction outputs) are in a state where they cannot easily be consolidated due to timing constraints, potentially leading to inefficiencies in liquidity management. This situation can be mitigated by utilizing the Lightning Network (LN) to decrease the velocity of Ark refreshes, which in turn reduces the worst-case overlap exposure.

In terms of inbound liquidity, the discussion points out how liquidity service providers (LSPs) often have funds tied up in channels that are rarely used. This is particularly problematic when considering mobile users who may not frequently come online to manage their channels. The introduction of LN atop the Ark protocol is suggested as a solution to more accurately align liquidity allocation with actual usage patterns. Through this method, unused liquidity can be reclaimed over time as the need for it decreases, or additional channels can be opened if necessary, albeit at an increased liquidity cost due to the need to refresh.

A significant challenge mentioned is the optimization of ASP/LSP liquidity in the face of negligible marginal vbytes costs, implying that while the cost of adding additional data to a blockchain transaction has decreased, managing liquidity effectively remains complex. Moreover, there's an inherent risk in the relationship between ASPs and LSPs concerning trust and the management of channels, especially if a mobile client goes offline unexpectedly. In such cases, unless there is a trust or identity continuity between the ASP and LSP, the latter might risk losing funds at tree timeout due to their inability to unroll channels promptly.

This summary encapsulates the key points raised in the email regarding the management of liquidity in a blockchain context, emphasizing the potential of using layered network solutions like LN to address these challenges while also cautioning about the risks involved in ASP/LSP relationships.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-05T12:53:27.321000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
