<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
  <updated>2026-01-07T03:01:29.514012+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-06 14:16:50.579000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ark as a Channel Factory: Compressed Liquidity Management for Improved Payment Feasibility</title>
    <updated>2026-01-07T03:01:29.514046+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ark-as-a-channel-factory-compressed-liquidity-management-for-improved-payment-feasibility/2179/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies involved in transitioning state between trees, highlighting that while this process is manageable, particularly with rebindable signatures, it presents fewer complications. A significant concern arises when addressing the operational dynamics of the Language Server Protocol (LSP) as an independent entity, especially in scenarios where a client becomes unresponsive. In such situations, the necessity for the LSP to independently initiate the closure of the channel is underscored, marking a deviation from instances where channel participants are expected to return online eventually. In the latter case, there exists an opportunity for these participants to collaboratively engage in what is referred to as the "forfeit dance," thereby enabling migration. This analysis points to the nuanced challenges and considerations that come into play when managing state transitions in programming environments, especially in the context of maintaining smooth operational flows amidst potential disruptions in participant responsiveness.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-06T14:16:50.579000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
