<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:30.973029+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Nuh</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-07 17:00:27.916000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:30.973067+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bithoven-a-formally-verified-imperative-smart-contract-language-for-bitcoin/2189/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the exploration of using a specific compiler as an alternative to Simplicity for implementing STARK proofs and transaction introspection with OP_CAT combined with Schnorr tricks. The focus is on evaluating how this compiler could potentially offer a less disruptive method in comparison to traditional approaches, especially in the context of executing what are considered very hacky things necessary for these processes. This exploration suggests a curiosity about the practicality and efficiency of leveraging this compiler's capabilities to achieve the desired outcomes in cryptographic operations and smart contract functionalities.

In examining the potential use of this compiler, there's an implicit consideration of the technical nuances and challenges associated with employing STARK proofs and transaction introspection techniques. These are advanced cryptographic methods used to enhance privacy, security, and scalability in blockchain transactions and smart contracts. The conversation hints at a broader dialogue within the programming and cryptocurrency communities regarding the continuous search for more efficient, secure, and less disruptive ways to implement these complex cryptographic techniques.

This inquiry into the compiler's applicability and effectiveness reflects a deeper interest in optimizing blockchain technology's performance and security features. By considering alternatives like the mentioned compiler, the discourse underscores the ongoing efforts to refine and advance the technological underpinnings of cryptocurrencies and decentralized systems. Such discussions are crucial for the evolution of blockchain technology, as they drive innovation and encourage the development of solutions that can address existing limitations and challenges in the field.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-07T17:00:27.916000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
