<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2026-01-10T02:57:58.588731+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>GaloisField2718</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-09 15:21:44.761000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2026-01-10T02:57:58.588769+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bithoven-a-formally-verified-imperative-smart-contract-language-for-bitcoin/2189/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email highlights a collaborative potential between the recipient's work on Bithoven and the sender's project focused on formalizing state-bound assets on Bitcoin, specifically through the 'W' protocol as outlined in their [OPI-003](https://github.com/The-Universal-BRC-20-Extension/OPI/blob/19f9ab66ebbda1a4b210d7b110ba2af506c1/OPI/OPI-003-W.md) document. The sender's project employs categorical models, inspired by Nester's Ledger Structures, to establish a natural correlation between semantic states and physical Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) in the blockchain context. They pinpoint Bithoven’s contributions as crucial for the practical aspect of their theoretical framework, especially in addressing complex challenges related to Schnorr Introspection and Merklized Abstract Syntax Trees (MAST)-binding covenants.

The sender proposes a technical collaboration, suggesting that Bithoven’s static analyzer could be instrumental in tackling introspective patterns and integrating them into its grammar. This integration is deemed essential for advancing the sender's work on Bitcoin's state-bound assets, indicating that Bithoven's capabilities in static analysis might hold the key to resolving specific implementation challenges faced in the development of the 'W' protocol.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-09T15:21:44.761000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
