<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-16T03:02:23.864621+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:29:44.543000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-16T03:02:23.864654+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent development in the integration of notifications into the Silent Payments protocol through Nostr presents a significant advancement in digital transactions and communication. This innovative approach aims to enhance the user experience by providing seamless, efficient, and secure notification mechanisms alongside transactions.

The proposal introduces a starting point for a specification that leverages Nostr, a decentralized network, to facilitate notifications within the Silent Payments framework. This integration is designed to address the need for a more interactive and responsive transaction environment, catering to the evolving demands of users in the digital currency space. The concept not only aims to streamline the process but also to add an extra layer of engagement between parties involved in a transaction.

For those interested in exploring this concept further and contributing to its development, more information can be found on the dedicated discussion page at [DelvingBitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-notifications-via-nostr/2203). This platform provides a space for developers, enthusiasts, and stakeholders to collaborate, share ideas, and refine the specifications of this promising integration.

This initiative reflects a broader trend towards the fusion of financial technology and communication platforms, indicating a shift towards more interconnected and multifunctional digital services. By combining Silent Payments with Nostr notifications, the project aims to set a new standard for user-centered design in the realm of digital finance.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-15T23:29:44.543000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
