<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-18T03:09:17.708844+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-17 05:54:00.310000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-18T03:09:17.708885+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency transactions, innovative methods for enhancing user experience and security are constantly being explored. A notable development in this field is the integration of nostr—a decentralized communication protocol—into silent payment notifications. This advancement aims to streamline and secure notifications for transactions without compromising the user's privacy or the efficiency of the process.

A practical application of this concept has been realized through the creation of an Electrum plugin. This plugin serves as a prototype to test the feasibility and effectiveness of utilizing nostr for transaction notifications. The details of this implementation can be viewed on GitLab, where the project repository is hosted ([GitLab project](https://gitlab.com/1440000bytes/color-address)). Further, a demonstration of the plugin in action is accessible via a video link, showcasing the plugin's functionality and user interface ([Demo video](https://video.nostr.build/9ac082eab8512b43c14c75f219584c9ec5cd4b5f260bdff711577ee5f5261ad9.mp4)).

The notification structure within this system employs several key pieces of information to ensure security and anonymity. It includes the sender's public key, a counter to denote the message sequence, a stealth address for the recipient, a timestamp for the notification, and a unique notification ID. These elements are crucial for maintaining the integrity and confidentiality of the notification process, ensuring that only the intended recipient can access and understand the notification content.

Moreover, the validity and transparency of transactions facilitated through this plugin are underscored by the use of public blockchain explorers. A specific transaction example provided ([Transaction details](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/031843bc27bdbf2ea0649f52ad19ff59d0964b3e65fae9ecee5d79050fa41081)) allows for the verification and analysis of the transaction, promoting trust and confidence in the system. Additionally, the use of web archiving services ([Archive link](https://archive.is/yXlQe)) for preserving the state of web resources adds another layer of reliability and permanence to the digital artifacts related to this project.

This initiative exemplifies the potential for integrating emerging technologies like nostr into the cryptocurrency ecosystem to enhance the security, privacy, and efficiency of digital transactions. Through practical implementations such as the Electrum plugin, the feasibility and benefits of such integrations are demonstrated, paving the way for future innovations in this space.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T05:54:00.310000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
