<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-18T03:10:27.958386+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-17 18:04:48.840000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-18T03:10:27.958422+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around exploring the Hornet node, with particular emphasis on understanding its functionalities and related aspects. An attempt was made to locate the source code for further analysis, but it remains unfound as indicated on the [Hornet node overview page](https://hornetnode.org/overview.html). In addition to this, there's an interest in how Hornet might incorporate or relate to the concept of a mempool, a term not explicitly mentioned in the context of Hornet but widely recognized in blockchain technology discussions, particularly in relation to Bitcoin.

Satoshi Nakamoto's seminal work, often referred to simply as the Bitcoin whitepaper, is highlighted for its introduction of key network operations, including the process by which new transactions are broadcast to all nodes in the network. This process effectively describes the operational essence of what is known today as the mempool, underscoring its significance in ensuring transaction broadcast and validation across the blockchain network.

Moreover, practical advice is shared regarding the management and loading of Bitcoin Core nodes in the absence of a locally persisted `mempool.dat` file. A specific resource ([anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt)) is recommended for those interested in accessing current mempool data. This data, updated every 15 seconds, proves invaluable for initializing Bitcoin Core nodes with an up-to-date mempool, facilitating a smoother start-up and integration into the Bitcoin network. This advice underscores the ongoing efforts within the cryptocurrency community to share knowledge and resources that enhance the functionality and reliability of blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T18:04:48.840000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
