<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-19T03:10:25.938006+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-18 16:11:54.801000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-19T03:10:25.938046+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry delves into the specifics of Hornet Node, expressing a keen interest in understanding its architecture and performance metrics, particularly in comparison to other node implementations such as Bitcoin Core and libbitcoin. The person is intrigued by Hornet Node's distinctiveness as a separate node implementation and is eager to explore its source code, which they have yet to locate. They pose specific questions regarding how Hornet Node's performance was benchmarked against Bitcoin Core, pondering whether the comparison involved direct performance metrics between Bitcoin Core version XX.X and Hornet Node, or if it entailed integrating Hornet's UTXO database engine into Bitcoin Core to achieve the noted 15-minute performance figure.

Further, the individual expresses curiosity about whether Hornet Node has been compared to libbitcoin, another implementation known for its remarkable validation speed, which suggests a broader interest in understanding how Hornet Node stacks up against various high-performance node implementations. This inquiry extends to the versatility of Hornet Node's database engine, questioning whether it can serve broader purposes beyond its primary function, such as indexing or similar applications.

The sender's intent to delve deeper into the technical workings and potential applications of Hornet Node's database engine highlights a broader quest for knowledge and the possibility of contributing more informed feedback and questions upon reviewing the source code.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-18T16:11:54.801000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
