<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-19T03:10:59.267005+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-18 17:01:15.217000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-19T03:10:59.267039+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-notifications-via-nostr/2203/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of enhancing transaction verification processes, particularly within the context of Silent Payments and Nostr layers, the dialogue opens with a consideration of the minimal necessary data for transaction confirmation. The proposal suggests that at its most basic, a transaction identifier (txid) could suffice if immediate confirmation isn't required. However, for added protection against denial-of-service (DoS) attacks, it's recommended to include a block hash and merkle proof alongside the txid. This approach underscores the importance of robustness in transaction verification methods to mitigate potential security threats effectively.

The discussion further delves into the nuances of wallet design, acknowledging the diversity in data backend and scanning logic configurations across different wallets. It posits that when Bob receives a notification from an unverified source, he should inherently distrust the information until proven otherwise. The emphasis here is on the necessity for Bob to identify fraudulent attempts swiftly, minimizing computational waste. This introduces an interesting perspective on trust dynamics within digital transactions, highlighting the tweak field's relevance. If Bob receives a tweak from a trusted contact like Alice or someone within his Web of Trust, where DoS risks are minimal, the transaction verification process simplifies significantly. Bob would only require the transaction hexadecimal (txhex) to complete the verification, bypassing the need for exhaustive script analysis.

The conversation then shifts towards the flexibility and utility of the tweak field in facilitating easier client design and operation. By allowing light clients to work with just the transaction data and tweaks, the process becomes more streamlined and adaptable to various client architectures. This flexibility is crucial in accommodating diverse wallet designs, some of which may not directly serve data but rely on external scanning mechanisms, akin to the Frigate style. The proposed optional inclusion of the tweak field caters to these diverse requirements, ensuring that clients can disregard it if deemed untrustworthy or unnecessary for their specific configuration.

Lastly, the discourse poses a critical query regarding the expected behavior of Alice in relation to transaction confirmations. It questions whether Alice should wait for transaction confirmation before sending a notification message, highlighting the impact of this decision on the information's precision and utility. Light clients, especially those dependent on filters and block pulling, may struggle to accurately verify transactions based solely on a txid without compromising privacy. In contrast, wallets modeled after systems like Electrum might find the inclusion of a tweak field alongside the txid more beneficial, simplifying the verification process. This inquiry into Alice's expected actions opens a broader discussion on optimizing transaction verification practices to enhance security, efficiency, and user experience across different wallet technologies.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-18T17:01:15.217000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
