<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-20T03:05:10.355761+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>conduition</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-19 16:06:51.601000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-20T03:05:10.355795+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion introduces an innovative approach that could complement Tadge's OP_CIV as a budget-friendly method for signature aggregation tailored for post-quantum signatures. This approach, however, contrasts with OP_CIV and the alternative suggested by the author in a significant manner. Specifically, it requires users to commit publicly to a singular address for its utilization during spending. This characteristic implies a potential privacy concern, as the method does not provide users with privacy until the moment of spending. At this juncture, users are expected to choose which Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) to link via the common-owner-input heuristic. This method, despite its drawbacks, presents a novel angle on managing signatures in a post-quantum cryptographic environment, advocating for a balance between functionality and user privacy. The proposal is further detailed in the author's alternative suggestion available through a [posted link](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/oFbEQb_DB3I/m/jnrgEsixAgAJ), offering a deeper insight into their perspective on enhancing Bitcoin's protocol in anticipation of quantum computing advancements.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-19T16:06:51.601000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
