<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Argo: a garbled-circuits scheme for 1000x more efficient off-chain computation</title>
  <updated>2026-01-23T03:06:48.789342+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-22 02:12:31.262000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Argo: a garbled-circuits scheme for 1000x more efficient off-chain computation</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:06:48.789375+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/argo-a-garbled-circuits-scheme-for-1000x-more-efficient-off-chain-computation/2210" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of off-chain cryptography has led to more advanced and expressive smart contracts within the Bitcoin ecosystem. Innovations such as BitVM have introduced the use of SNARKs (Succinct Non-Interactive Arguments of Knowledge) to facilitate the proof of arbitrary computation, alongside garbled circuits which allow for the verification of these proofs to be efficiently moved off-chain. This development marks a significant step forward in the realm of blockchain technology, offering a pathway to more complex and secure transactions beyond the current capabilities.

A groundbreaking advancement in this field is the introduction of Argo MAC, a novel garbling primitive specifically designed to enhance the efficiency of garbled SNARK verifiers dramatically. The essence of Argo MAC lies in its ability to convert the encoding of a bit decomposition of an elliptic curve point into a homomorphic MAC (Message Authentication Code) of that same point. This conversion process is not only innovative but also paves the way for significantly more efficient garbling techniques compared to existing methods.

The potential of Argo MAC extends further with the promise of future research aimed at utilizing this new garbling primitive to construct garbled SNARK verifiers specifically for pairing-based SNARKs. Such advancements could revolutionize the verification process for these cryptographic proofs, making them over a thousand times more efficient than current standards. This leap in efficiency could greatly enhance the scalability and practicality of using blockchain technologies for a wide range of applications.

For readers interested in delving deeper into the technical aspects and implications of this research, the full details can be found in the published paper available at [IACR's ePrint archive](https://eprint.iacr.org/2026/049). This document provides a comprehensive overview of the Argo MAC system, including its theoretical foundations and potential applications in the field of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-22T02:12:31.262000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
