<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-23T03:06:09.278717+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>tobysharp</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-22 04:46:31.191000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:06:09.278750+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the development and testing of new blockchain technology components, specifically focusing on the Hornet UTXO(1) database. This work is part of a broader effort to achieve spec-based consensus, validation, and Initial Block Download (IBD), with an indication that mempool behavior analysis might be included in future developments. The most comprehensive documentation available for this project can be found at the provided link, which serves as a pivotal resource for understanding the current status and capabilities of the Hornet UTXO(1) database.

The conversation further delves into comparative performance analyses between Bitcoin Core v30.0 and the Hornet Node. A notable experimentation detail includes running Bitcoin Core with the `-assume-valid` option, effectively bypassing signature and script validation processes. This approach primarily assesses the costs associated with UTXO database construction and querying, suggesting a focus on optimizing these particular aspects of blockchain operation.

An interesting proposition mentioned involves a potential comparison with libbitcoin, hypothesizing that while libbitcoin may outperform Bitcoin Core, the Hornet's implementation of parallelism could ultimately lead to superior performance. This speculation underscores the ongoing exploration of ways to enhance blockchain efficiency, particularly during the initial block download phase, which is highlighted as an initial priority for the project.

Moreover, there's an openness to expanding the functionalities of the Hornet Node to include indexing transactions and addresses, among other features. This flexibility suggests a long-term vision for the project that goes beyond immediate performance improvements, hinting at a scalable framework capable of supporting a wide range of blockchain applications. The dialogue concludes with an invitation for further collaboration and the possibility of sharing the code more broadly upon completion of the current IBD phase, indicating a collaborative and open approach to development within the blockchain community.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-22T04:46:31.191000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
