<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2026-01-23T03:03:29.372128+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-22 19:09:37.255000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:03:29.372166+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent progress in utilizing Claude and updating the branch has led to significant improvements and fixes, culminating in a more stable and functional version. This new iteration is rebased on the latest master and ensures compatibility with bitcoin-inquisition 29.x on signet, incorporating TRUC/eph dust/P2A/1p1c package relay. Notably, it introduces automated anchor bumping that genuinely operates as intended, transitioning from an annex usage to an op_return commitment approach. Moreover, enhancements have been made to support node restarts without crashes and to facilitate cooperative closures of transactions, although the protocol for the latter remains somewhat rudimentary compared to legacy closures. The updated branch also boasts increased test coverage, albeit still at a proof-of-concept (PoC) level, indicating a substantial step forward in usability and reliability.

Several examples of transaction updates and closures have been provided, demonstrating the branch's capabilities in real-world scenarios. These include links to sample unilateral close update transactions, unilateral close settle transactions, and cooperative close transactions on mempool.space/signet, showcasing the practical application of the updates.

Furthermore, the migration of Claude from APO to a combination of OP_TEMPLATEHASH, OP_CSFS, and IK reflects a strategic enhancement aimed at improving functionality. This transition is evidenced by the BOLT draft revisions and the implementation of a one-shot approach documented on GitHub. Although OP_TEMPLATEHASH is not yet operational on inquisition and can only be tested in regtest environments, it represents a forward-looking development effort. Interested individuals are encouraged to experiment with these updates on signet via bitcoin-inquisition, as the maintenance cost of this PoC stage is minimal. This invitation underscores the project's openness to community involvement and feedback in refining and advancing the system.

For further information and to explore the specific updates and transactions mentioned, interested parties can visit the provided GitHub repositories and mempool.space/signet links: [bolts tree eltoo_trucd](https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/tree/eltoo_trucd), [lightning tree 2026-01-eltoo_rebased](https://github.com/instagibbs/lightning/tree/2026-01-eltoo_rebased), [sample unilateral close update tx](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/97b8925c1261f47fed5b2bd0d419a05b626db9364eb0d7d347bb3cfbf7dca73e), [sample unilateral close settle tx](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/b35b3549835931360106f2fc21c8f1782ac285c6136be7204636dde8594378c7vin=0), and [sample cooperative close tx](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/cb1990dd1de3a219ff1f30ab7cca2374dbb4616837a1eac7abbfb64b3a8570be).</summary>
    <published>2026-01-22T19:09:37.255000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
