<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:02.347291+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>optout</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-23 15:32:50.927000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:02.347333+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The primary concern addressed is the importance of privacy in cryptocurrency transactions, particularly emphasizing the various levels of onchain information sources that can potentially compromise this privacy. These sources range from easily accessible data available through chain explorers to more complex and detailed information that can be obtained through a full node or multiple probing nodes scattered across the network. Each level presents its own set of challenges and requires increasing amounts of resources to access. However, they also offer progressively more detailed insights, such as the timing of transactions or the estimated origin of funds, which can significantly impact the ability to maintain transactional privacy.

A specific scenario highlighted is the transfer of multiple Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) between wallets in separate transactions. The goal behind segregating these transactions is to prevent them from being linked together, thereby preserving the anonymity of the individuals involved. However, if these transactions are executed in close temporal proximity, various heuristics—like similar transaction structures, propagation patterns, or any prior linkages—can still be used to connect them with a high degree of certainty. This risk underscores the need for strategies that can obfuscate the relationship between these transactions.

One proposed solution to enhance privacy in this context is the introduction of random delays between transactions. Such a strategy could significantly reduce the likelihood of linking multiple UTXOs to the same individual based on the timing of their transactions. Nevertheless, implementing these delays manually is not only impractical but also labor-intensive. Therefore, there's a clear call for automated features within cryptocurrency systems that can streamline this process, thereby offering users a more robust privacy protection mechanism without requiring extensive manual intervention.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-23T15:32:50.927000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
