<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-27T03:11:19.003283+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>optout</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-26 08:27:33.713000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T03:11:19.003324+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the functionality and utility of a feature within a Bitcoin wallet application, which interacts with BitcoinCore. This feature pertains to transaction scheduling based on a set time, rather than the transaction's creation time. The significance of this lies in its ability to set `nLocktime` to coincide with the scheduled time, providing an alternative to having a process running for an extended period or requiring direct access to RPC for transaction submission. This is particularly highlighted as a solution for users who may not wish to keep their system running solely for the purpose of executing a transaction at a later time.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the feasibility of specifying a target time for transactions in terms of block height, as opposed to physical time. While this option is deemed possible, it is also noted that for the timeframe considered—ranging from a few hours to a few days—choosing between block height and physical time does not present a significant difference. This suggests a flexibility in how scheduled transactions can be implemented, without a strong preference for one method over the other in the context of short to medium-term scheduling.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-26T08:27:33.713000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
