<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disposing of "dust attack" UTXOs</title>
  <updated>2026-01-27T03:13:23.979503+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bubb1es</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-27 00:51:18.928000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disposing of "dust attack" UTXOs</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T03:13:23.979540+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disposing-of-dust-attack-utxos/2215/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent innovations in blockchain technology have led to the development of a new CLI application named "ddust," designed to facilitate de-dusting transactions in an efficient and user-friendly manner. This application allows users to combine higher fee-rate de-dusting transactions with those of lower rates, thereby optimizing the process of clearing minimal amounts of cryptocurrency from their wallets. The initiative not only enhances the user experience by simplifying the de-dusting process but also contributes positively to the digital currency ecosystem by aiding in the optimization of transaction fees and network usage.

The creator of "ddust" has diligently improved the accuracy of transaction size and fee rate estimates across different scenarios, ensuring the application's reliability and effectiveness. For instance, in one scenario focusing on Pay-To-Witness-Public-Key-Hash (P2WPKH) transactions, the base size is calculated at 65 bytes, incorporating various components such as overhead, input, and OP_RETURN output data, with a virtual size of 92.5 vB. The fee rates for this scenario are estimated to be approximately 3.16, 3.23, and 3.49 sats/vB, depending on the input value. An example transaction demonstrating this scenario can be viewed on the Signet test network, providing insights into the application's practical utility.

Another scenario explored involves Pay-To-Script-Hash (P2SH) 2-of-3 multisig transactions, demonstrating a significantly larger base size of 315 bytes due to the inclusion of more complex scripting mechanisms. The virtual size remains the same as the base size in this case, with fee rates slightly lower than the first scenario, illustrating the variability in transaction costs associated with different types of blockchain operations.

The third scenario examines Pay-To-Witness-Script-Hash (P2WSH) 2-of-3 multisig transactions, where the base size is similar to the first scenario, but the inclusion of witness data increases the virtual size to 129.25 vB. This scenario presents a middle ground in terms of fee rates compared to the other two scenarios, highlighting the nuanced cost implications of various transaction types within the blockchain framework.

Overall, the "ddust" application represents a significant step forward in addressing the challenges associated with wallet de-dusting, offering a practical solution that benefits both individual users and the broader digital currency community. By streamlining transaction processes and optimizing fee structures, the application exemplifies the ongoing innovation within the blockchain domain. Interested individuals can explore the application further through its GitHub repository, available at [“ddust” CLI app](https://github.com/bubb1es71/ddust), which provides a comprehensive overview of its functionalities and potential applications.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-27T00:51:18.928000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
