<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2026-01-28T03:06:31.459973+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>conduition</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-27 06:38:55.382000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T03:06:31.460016+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue touches upon the intricacies of enhancing security measures within technology systems, specifically discussing the potential use of a Trusted Platform Module (TPM) for managing cryptographic keys and signatures to protect against unauthorized access or alterations. The conversation begins with a critique of a proposed solution that involves rotating the TPM's authentication value or decryption key after every new signature to invalidate old disk backups. This approach, however, is quickly identified as problematic due to synchronization issues that arise from concurrent requests, leading to race conditions when writing to the TPM. 

The discussion then shifts towards an alternate strategy involving state commitments, suggesting its viability over the initially proposed method. This segment highlights the fundamental requirement for an independent and authenticated interface that can securely commit to a certain state, underlining that the specific choice of technology (e.g., TPM, webserver, database, nostr relay, thumb drive, or even Bitcoin's OP_RETURN function) for this interface is secondary to its capability to offer isolation and security away from the primary storage medium.

Furthermore, the conversation underscores the significance of exploring various technological options to achieve the desired level of security and integrity within systems, emphasizing the openness to innovation in selecting the appropriate tools and methods for safeguarding digital assets and operations against quantum computing threats and other advanced vulnerabilities. The exchange encapsulates a broader perspective on securing cryptographic operations, advocating for flexibility, creativity, and thorough consideration in the development and implementation of security measures.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-27T06:38:55.382000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
