<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BLISK: Boolean circuit Logic Integrated into the Single Key</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T03:32:58.002297+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>evd0kim</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-28 10:30:50.897000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BLISK: Boolean circuit Logic Integrated into the Single Key</title>
    <updated>2026-01-29T03:32:58.002334+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blisk-boolean-circuit-logic-integrated-into-the-single-key/2217/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The post inquires about a specific policy syntax related to Musig2, highlighting a scenario where `A` and `C` are designated as co-signers within a transaction mechanism that allows for on-chain spending. The policy string in question is defined as `let policy_str = "(policy my_policy (and (or A B) (or C D)))";`, indicating a logical structure where both `A` and `C` are essential participants in the authorization process. This setup implies that neither `B` nor `D` can independently authorize any form of spending without the involvement of their respective pairs.

The query seeks clarification on whether the policy signer within this context adequately resolves the Musig2 configuration, subsequently generating a valid partial signature that aligns with the specified requirements. The underlying concern revolves around the operational dynamics of Musig2 in handling scenarios where multiple signatories are involved, specifically in cases where certain signers are deemed necessary for transaction authorization, while others are not. This raises questions about the efficiency and reliability of the Musig2 setup in accommodating complex policy structures and ensuring secure transaction validation processes.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T10:30:50.897000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
