<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T03:32:26.734351+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stickies-v</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-28 17:01:22.676000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-29T03:32:26.734388+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Toby's project appears to be advancing well, with promising outcomes anticipated upon the release of the code for deeper analysis. The project incorporates a transaction output (TXO) database that is stored on disk, characterized by its append-only nature which implies it houses both spent and unspent transaction outputs. Additionally, there exists an in-memory unspent transaction output (UTXO) index, which Toby has mentioned could potentially be transitioned to disk storage as well. The query also seeks to understand the current sizes of both the database and the index at the latest blockchain height, indicating an interest in the scalability and storage requirements of Toby's system.

Furthermore, the question raised about the possibility of pruning spent transaction outputs from the disk database suggests an exploration into the efficiency and maintenance of the database. However, it is inferred that such pruning might not align with the project's architectural decisions, which are tailored towards server-class hardware. This approach indicates a design preference that possibly prioritizes performance and reliability over minimizing storage requirements.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T17:01:22.676000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
