<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T03:30:47.113802+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>simul</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-28 18:20:01.195000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
    <updated>2026-01-29T03:30:47.113836+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures/2168/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain security, particularly regarding transaction protocols, the implementation of secret-reveal sequences provides a robust defense mechanism against unauthorized transactions. This approach is fundamental in ensuring that even if an attacker manages to compromise the signature process, they cannot redirect funds without the correct secret. Protocols such as P2TR (Pay to Taproot) and P2TSH (Pay to Taproot Script Hash) emphasize the necessity of this secret for executing any spend transaction. The design inherently protects the system by invalidating spends to unintended destinations unless the pre-determined secret is disclosed.

The utilization of signatures, despite their potential vulnerability, serves as an additional barrier against frivolous or malicious activities, specifically MEV (Miner Extractable Value) attacks. By necessitating a signature, attackers are compelled to expend resources, thus introducing a cost to what would otherwise be free and possibly rampant griefing attacks. This strategic choice underlines a preference for layered security measures within transaction protocols, balancing between ease of use for legitimate transactions and deterrence against unauthorized ones.

Transaction protocols can be conceptualized through two primary scenarios or "shapes." The first scenario, referred to as the "happy path," involves the successful addition of an anchor transaction to a block. This transaction's movement is contingent upon a secret reveal, which subsequently locks in the transaction's destination. Only upon the revelation of the secret does the transaction proceed as intended, showcasing the protocol's reliance on this security measure. The second scenario addresses a breach in security, specifically when an attacker successfully compromises the numeric values (nums) integral to the transaction. Despite this breach, the absence of the secret reveal prevents the redirection of funds. The only permissible transaction redirects the funds "back to original," essentially returning them to the sender. While this results in lost transaction fees and potential profit for miners, it ensures that the attacker gains no financial benefit from their actions.

This dual-scenario framework underscores the intricate balance transaction protocols maintain between flexibility in transaction execution and stringent security measures. By prioritizing the safeguarding of funds through secrets and conditional transaction paths, these protocols mitigate the risks and potential damages from both direct attacks and systemic vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T18:20:01.195000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
