<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disposing of "dust attack" UTXOs</title>
  <updated>2026-01-31T03:27:22.553693+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2026-01-30 18:20:30.158000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disposing of "dust attack" UTXOs</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T03:27:22.553726+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disposing-of-dust-attack-utxos/2215/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the unspent transaction output (UTXO) set in Bitcoin provides valuable insights into the current state and distribution of transaction outputs that have not yet been spent. To facilitate this analysis, one can utilize the `dumptxoutset` RPC command along with a specific script available on GitHub. This script, found [here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/01651324f4e540f6b96cff31e89752c3f9417293/contrib/utxo-tools/utxo_to_sqlite.py), enables the export of the UTXO set to a SQLite database, making it easier to perform detailed examinations of the data. Through a series of SQL queries, it is possible to determine the quantity of UTXOs that are close to being considered dust (small value UTXOs that may not be worth spending due to high transaction fees) and analyze their creation dates.

In addition, there is an ongoing effort to enhance the tools available for UTXO analysis as evidenced by a pull request for a new utility that converts UTXO data into CSV format. This tool is accessible for review and feedback at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/34324). Contributions to the project, especially in the form of feedback on this pull request, are highly encouraged. This initiative underscores the community's commitment to improving Bitcoin's analytical capabilities and offers an opportunity for interested individuals to contribute to its development.</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T18:20:30.158000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
