<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
  <updated>2026-01-10T02:56:27.698813+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 14:18:31.321000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>gmaxwell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 22:07:46.639000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>moneyball</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 03:42:54.962000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 15:35:45.174000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-09 22:28:32.126000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6256_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6265_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6266_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6273_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6620_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
    <updated>2026-01-10T02:56:27.699740+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/propagation-delay-and-mining-centralization-modeling-stale-rates/2110/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-17 14:18:31.321000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The analysis delves into the nuances of &quot;Selfish Mining,&quot; a strategic approach that enables miners to selectively publish blocks to augment their revenues. This tactic, particularly under certain conditions, can disproportionately benefit larger miners due to extended block propagation times. The investigation employs a simplified model to elucidate how these propagation times influence a miner's earnings relative to their hashrate in the network, assuming an immediate mining response upon block discovery and a swift transition to a chain with superior proof of work. This model highlights the direct correlation between a miner's revenue and its network hashrate share in scenarios of instantaneous propagation. Conversely, delays in propagation introduce the risk of block obsolescence, should another miner's block gain precedence in the network. The study delineates two distinct scenarios: one where a competing block is found first, diverting all mining efforts away from the original block, and another where a subsequent block's discovery increases the likelihood of the initial block turning stale. Centralization emerges as a significant factor, with larger entities or pools more likely to triumph in such races, underscoring how propagation times inadvertently fuel mining centralization. Simulation data, reflecting hashrate distributions over recent months, sheds light on how varying propagation times affect stale rates and consequently, pool revenues. Even minor discrepancies in propagation times can trigger substantial shifts in revenue allocation, accentuating the critical choice of mining pools based on size and the potential implications of peer-to-peer network modifications on mining dynamics. The exploration suggests that enhancements in the P2P network reducing propagation delays could lead to a fairer distribution of mining opportunities across differently sized operations, thereby addressing some centralization concerns. Supporting evidence includes data visualizations and simulation outcomes, accessible via [detailed analysis of Selfish Mining](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757) and the simulation source code at [GitHub](https://github.com/darosior/miningsimulation/blob/d10b4346cf15eb6cda198414702b64fe685754fa/plot_stale_rate/plot.py).
The discourse further critiques the prevailing assumptions about miners' average revenue models, revealing the substantial portion of cited earnings ($91 million) attributable to power expenses, which significantly inflates perceived net profits. This revelation challenges the simplistic revenue calculation methods, advocating for a more nuanced understanding of financial outcomes in mining operations. Additionally, there's a discussion around enhancing network efficiency through the proposed introduction of a &quot;STALEHEADER&quot; message protocol. This protocol aims at improving relay of headers near the best chain tip without necessitating the complete block, potentially offering better insights into network performance and large invalid forks while preserving security against DOS attacks. 
In a broader context, the Stratum Protocol's introduction marks a pivotal advancement in blockchain technology, addressing critical challenges like transaction throughput, consensus mechanisms, and interoperability among different blockchain systems. By leveraging advanced cryptographic techniques and optimizing network protocols, the Stratum Protocol aims to elevate blockchain network performance, emphasizing speed, security, and reliability. Its architecture ensures transparency and decentralization, fundamental to blockchain technology, while facilitating seamless communication and data exchange between diverse blockchain systems. This interoperability is crucial for developing a cohesive blockchain ecosystem, enabling fluid interactions between varied applications and services. Privacy and data protection are also paramount, with the protocol employing state-of-the-art encryption and privacy technologies to secure user data and transactions. For developers and organizations, the Stratum Protocol offers a comprehensive framework and resources for integrating advanced blockchain functionalities into their projects, as detailed at [Stratum Protocol Blog](https://stratumprotocol.org/blog/hashlabs).
Lastly, the intricate dynamics of Bitcoin mining economics are scrutinized, highlighting the thin margins on which mining profitability precariously balances. The discussion points to the volatility of mining revenues and the disproportionate impact of minor fluctuations on profitability. Additionally, the Bitcoin developer community's proposition of a &quot;STALEHEADER&quot; message protocol reflects ongoing efforts to refine the network's operational efficacy, which could notably influence mining strategies and bolster blockchain health. This continuous technical evolution within the Bitcoin ecosystem exemplifies the commitment to optimizing its robustness and efficiency, as evidenced by updates like the improved graphical representation of revenue changes relative to block propagation times, following community feedback, with corresponding code modifications available [here](https://github.com/darosior/miningsimulation/commit/bf828b34833b11d1181497b4e5f8b607b6acf309).</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>