<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Disposing of &quot;dust attack&quot; UTXOs</title>
  <updated>2026-01-31T03:28:08.739992+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bubbes</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-25 17:20:49.445000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 04:46:10.061000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>remyers</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 15:49:40.339000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>AdamISZ</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 19:13:32.455000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>bubbes</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-27 00:24:53.183000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>bubbes</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-27 00:51:18.928000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>bubb1es</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-30 16:03:43.144000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>0xB10C</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-30 18:20:30.158000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>bubb1es</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-30 19:17:09.795000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6681_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6684_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6689_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6690_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6693_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6692_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6708_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6709_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6710_Disposing-of-dust-attack-UTXOs.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Disposing of &quot;dust attack&quot; UTXOs</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T03:28:08.741334+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disposing-of-dust-attack-utxos/2215/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-25 17:20:49.445000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The challenge of managing &quot;dust attack&quot; UTXOs in on-chain wallets is a significant issue within the cryptocurrency community. Adversaries deploy dust attacks by sending small amounts of cryptocurrency to numerous addresses, aiming to uncover connections between them. This strategy relies on the hope that these dust UTXOs will be inadvertently spent with larger, unrelated UTXOs, linking them together. Modern wallet designs have introduced measures to mitigate these risks by automatically locking dust UTXOs, preventing their usage. However, this solution increases the mempool size and introduces future risks, such as potential software bugs or misunderstandings by future wallet owners about the significance of these locked UTXOs. A proposed solution for disposing of dust UTXOs involves creating transactions that would spend these UTXOs entirely on transaction fees, using an OP_RETURN output. The feasibility of this approach has been made more practical with the lowering of the default minimum relay fee rate. 
The discussion further explores the implications of broadcasting transactions from personal IP addresses, particularly concerning privacy. It highlights the importance of maintaining caution and utilizing secure methods for transaction broadcasting to safeguard against network-based attacks that aim to de-anonymize users. Despite the defenses offered by full nodes, challenges remain in ensuring complete privacy protection against sophisticated espionage techniques. 
Recent updates in blockchain technology have led to the development of a CLI application named &quot;ddust,&quot; which optimizes the process of clearing minimal cryptocurrency amounts from wallets. This tool exemplifies innovation within the blockchain domain by simplifying de-dusting transactions and contributing to the optimization of transaction fees and network usage. The ddust tool allows for combining higher fee-rate de-dusting transactions with those of lower rates, showcasing its practical utility and reliability across various scenarios. 
Lastly, the conversation touches upon the investigation into the nature and quantity of dust attack UTXOs. Tools and scripts are available for analyzing the current UTXO set, offering insights into the prevalence of near-dust UTXOs and their creation times. This ongoing research contributes to a deeper understanding of dust attacks and the development of strategies to counteract them.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>