<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-25T03:15:26.296791+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>arminsdev</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 17:00:01.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-23 15:32:50.927000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ArmchairCryptologist</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-24 09:09:58.466000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6670_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6678_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6679_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-25T03:15:26.298020+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The concept of Scheduled Transaction Broadcast in Bitcoin Core introduces a novel approach towards enhancing transaction flexibility and privacy on the blockchain. This feature, still in its conceptual phase, would enable users to schedule transactions for future broadcast based on specific conditions or timings. Such a capability aims to address the need for obscuring the actual creation time of transactions, which is particularly relevant in scenarios where timing could reveal strategic or sensitive information. The proposed mechanism involves a new RPC called `schedulerawtransaction`, drawing parallels with the existing `sendrawtransaction` but designed to accommodate scheduling functionalities. This addition would necessitate a dedicated memory structure and a new file to persist scheduled transactions across restarts, highlighting the underlying technical complexities and considerations for implementation.
Further discussion delves into the broader implications of transaction timing and privacy within the blockchain domain, emphasizing the concept of anti-sniping. Anti-sniping concerns itself with the vulnerabilities associated with transaction timestamps, which could potentially be exploited to glean information about transaction origins. The discourse suggests that understanding and mitigating these vulnerabilities are crucial for protecting user privacy and enhancing the security of blockchain transactions. By examining the methods of transaction timestamping, stakeholders can identify potential weaknesses and develop strategies to conceal timing information, thereby fortifying the blockchain against targeted attacks.
The dialogue extends into the practicalities and technical challenges of implementing scheduled transactions at the node level, as opposed to client-side solutions. This approach posits several advantages, such as increased security and anonymity, by making it more difficult for external entities to trace transactions back to their origins based on timing data. However, realizing this feature requires the introduction of additional RPCs to manage, list, and cancel scheduled transactions, underlining the complexity and potential utility of such an integration. It raises essential questions about the feasibility and impact of incorporating scheduled transactions into existing blockchain infrastructures, considering network performance and security implications.
The conversation also explores use cases and technical considerations surrounding the execution of transactions at predetermined times without direct user intervention. This functionality caters especially to users who demand transactions to be automatically triggered by specific events, such as incoming payments. The discussion acknowledges the gap in current wallet solutions regarding scheduled transactions, suggesting the need for a specialized node setup for advanced users seeking autonomy in transaction broadcasting. Moreover, the importance of extending the RPC interface to support these advanced features is highlighted, indicating a move towards more sophisticated and flexible transaction management options within the blockchain ecosystem.
Addressing privacy concerns in peer-to-peer (P2P) networks, the discussion proposes delaying transaction broadcasts as a method to enhance user privacy by complicating the analysis of transaction patterns by adversaries. While this strategy introduces uncertainties for potential observers, it's recognized as part of a larger privacy strategy rather than a standalone solution. The narrative further underscores the multifaceted nature of privacy in cryptocurrency transactions, pointing out the various on-chain information sources that could compromise privacy. Highlighting scenarios like the transfer of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), the need for mechanisms like random delays between transactions is advocated to prevent linking transactions to individuals, calling for automated system features to bolster privacy protections efficiently.
Lastly, the communication touches upon the limitations of the nLockTime parameter as a privacy tool, noting its potential to inadvertently disclose transaction creation times. Despite some mitigation efforts, such as setting nLockTime to a random value within a certain range, there remains a significant chance that transactions will reveal their intended broadcast time, undermining privacy efforts. The discussion concludes with suggestions for improving ease of use and functionality around nLockTime settings, advocating for enhanced transaction creation features within Bitcoin Core to better support privacy-oriented practices.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>