<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-16T03:04:07.391007+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>RubenSomsen</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-16 00:25:04.617000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6626_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6628_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-16T03:04:07.391515+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-notifications-via-nostr/2203/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the innovative approach of integrating notifications for Silent Payments transactions through Nostr, building on the concept of stealth addresses within the same network. Silent Payments (SP) are designed to enable recipients to receive payments without requiring direct interaction during the transaction process. However, this design introduces a challenge for the recipient, who must sift through numerous transactions to identify those relevant to them, akin to finding &quot;needles in a haystack.&quot; This issue is somewhat mitigated by the proposal of out-of-band communication, where the sender informs the recipient of a payment, reducing the need for exhaustive searching.
The proposed notification schema is straightforward yet effective, primarily focusing on the transaction ID (txid) but also recommending the inclusion of additional data such as the tweak used in the transaction and an optional blockhash to aid in locating the transaction more efficiently. This approach not only streamlines the process for the recipient but also maintains the integrity and privacy of the transaction, given that the necessary computations to validate the payment can be performed with the information provided.
Nostr's role in this system is critical, acting as the communication layer for these notifications. The choice of keys used for sending and receiving notifications via Nostr is a vital consideration, with options ranging from using a scan key specifically for Silent Payments, creating a new dedicated key, or utilizing an existing public key used for other Nostr activities. Each option has implications for privacy and operational complexity. To ensure notifications reach their intended recipient, both parties must share at least one common relay, highlighting the decentralized nature of Nostr and the need for strategic relay selection to prevent notifications from being lost.
The final design recommendations include utilizing a JSON schema for notification content, which can easily be integrated into wallet implementations for seamless import and processing. This allows for flexibility in communication methods beyond Nostr, potentially leveraging any messaging platform for notification delivery. The outlined approach emphasizes user experience, aiming to reduce the burden of transaction scanning while maintaining privacy and security.
This system's design is significantly informed by previous discussions and proposals around stealth addresses and aims to apply similar user experience improvements to Silent Payments. While there are inherent challenges, such as potential spam attacks and the risk of incorrect implementation leading to issues with tweak data, the proposed solutions emphasize optimism in improving transaction efficiency without compromising security. The acknowledgment of possible complications and the provision of fallback mechanisms, like reverting to full-chain scanning in case of spam attacks, demonstrates a balanced view towards practicality and resilience in the face of adversities.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>