<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-19T03:11:11.758384+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>RubenSomsen</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-16 00:25:04.617000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-18 17:01:15.217000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6626_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6628_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6642_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-19T03:11:11.758935+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-notifications-via-nostr/2203/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent discussions shed light on innovative methods for managing blockchain transactions, specifically focusing on Silent Payments and the challenges associated with notifying recipients about incoming payments through Nostr. Silent Payments represent a novel approach where the receiver must identify their specific transactions from among many, necessitating an efficient notification system. A proposed solution for these notifications includes sending essential details like the transaction ID (txid), and possibly additional information such as the tweak used and an optional confirming blockhash or height. This would significantly aid in the recipient's verification process.
One of the principal topics discussed is the design of the notification schema, emphasizing a format that contains the txid, tweak, and an optional blockhash to streamline the verification process for the receiver, identified as Bob in the scenario. The use of Nostr as a communication layer for these notifications is explored, considering the privacy implications and the need for both the sender and receiver to share at least one common Nostr relay to ensure the delivery of notifications.
A pivotal aspect of the dialogue revolves around the operational challenges Bob faces when verifying the accuracy of the tweak data sent by Alice, the sender. The discussion points out the necessity for a balance between minimizing the data sent to avoid inefficiencies and enhancing the system's resistance to potential Denial of Service (DoS) attacks. Two distinct approaches are highlighted: one advocating for an &quot;absolutely minimal&quot; message format focusing on essential data, and another aiming to maximize DoS resistance through more comprehensive data checks.
Further elaboration on these strategies is provided, discussing the implications of including or omitting certain pieces of data in notifications. The conversation acknowledges the diversity in wallet designs and their data backend and scanning logic, suggesting that the inclusion of tweak data might be beneficial under specific circumstances, such as when the sender and receiver have a trusted relationship. This approach could offer more flexibility to client design and improve the efficiency of the verification process by enabling the receiver to focus only on essential computations.
The narrative also contemplates whether Alice should wait for the transaction to confirm before sending a notification, highlighting the trade-offs between immediate notification and the provision of more targeted information post-confirmation. Different wallet types, such as those based on Electrum, might benefit differently from the inclusion of tweak data in the notifications. This reflection underscores the importance of designing the notification mechanism in a way that accommodates various wallet designs and user preferences, ensuring the effectiveness and privacy of Silent Payments notifications within the Nostr framework.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>