<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-18T03:10:42.310707+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>tobysharp</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-11 21:25:57.349000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jsarenik</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-17 18:04:48.840000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6622_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6637_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-18T03:10:42.311211+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-11 21:25:57.349000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The development of Hornet UTXO(1) represents a significant leap forward in Bitcoin client technology. As part of the experimental Hornet Node project, which focuses on declarative consensus specification and high performance, this new UTXO database is designed for Bitcoin consensus validation. Created using modern C++ for maximum parallelism, it achieves high concurrency and lock-free operations, markedly improving throughput during consensus validation processes. A benchmark test on a 32 core development workstation showed that Hornet UTXO(1) could revalidate the entire mainnet chain, excluding script or signature validation, in just 15 minutes—a task that takes Bitcoin Core 167 minutes under similar conditions.
Hornet UTXO(1) supports all structural and contextual validation, builds the UTXO database, and validates that all transaction inputs correspond to unspent outputs with an architecture that allows critical operations like Append, Query, and Fetch to be executed concurrently without locks. It introduces the capability to submit blocks for validation out of order, enabling concurrent processing and automatic resolution of data dependencies. The system's index entries are height-tagged, facilitating state rewinding to fork points for reorganizations without requiring additional undo states and allowing queries against specific past chain states.
This innovative approach reduces serial dependency on previous block transactions by enabling independent work to progress concurrently and implements preemptive Append operations. Optimizations have been made for disk access through asynchronous, high queue-depth requests, and memory usage with compact, cache-friendly data structures along with fixed-size allocations. The implementation of Hornet UTXO(1) is notably concise, consisting of only 3,000 lines of C++23 code and avoiding external dependencies by eschewing hash maps in favor of sorted arrays and LSM trees.
The broader implications of this technology are discussed in T. Sharp's paper &quot;Hornet Node: A Declarative, Executable Specification of Bitcoin Consensus,&quot; available in HTML and PDF formats ([HTML](https://hornetnode.org/paper.html), [PDF](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.15754)). Developed as an unfunded personal project in the creator's spare time, this work represents a pivotal advancement in efficient Bitcoin consensus validation mechanisms. The developer encourages feedback, questions, and information on related work, inviting support from those interested in contributing to the ongoing development of this groundbreaking project.
Despite the detailed overview provided, the source code for the project is not yet available, and further details on how the system integrates with or impacts the mempool, a critical component of Bitcoin's network functionality as described by Satoshi in his original paper, remain unmentioned. For practical applications and testing involving Bitcoin Core nodes, the use of [mempool logs](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt) has been suggested for loading current mempool data on a fresh start without a locally persisted `mempool.dat`.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>