<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-27T03:11:33.385404+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>arminsdev</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 17:00:01.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-23 15:32:50.927000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ArmchairCryptologist</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-24 09:09:58.466000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 08:27:33.713000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6670_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6678_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6679_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6688_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T03:11:33.386814+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The introduction of a Scheduled Transaction Broadcast feature in Bitcoin Core has sparked significant interest and discussion within the development community. This feature, aimed at allowing users to schedule transactions for future broadcast to the bitcoin network, seeks to address several needs, including the desire to obscure the actual time of transaction creation and accommodate future conditions not easily managed through bitcoin scripts. The proposed implementation involves a new RPC, `schedulerawtransaction`, designed to store transactions until their designated broadcast time, either based on absolute time or block height. However, this feature raises several concerns, including potential conflicts with existing functionalities and the reliability of delivery, given that the success or failure of these scheduled transactions won't be immediately known.
Privacy in peer-to-peer (P2P) networks and the broader blockchain ecosystem is a paramount concern, with specific emphasis on anti-sniping and the protection of transaction timing details. Anti-sniping efforts focus on preventing information leakage related to the timing of transactions, a vulnerability that can be exploited by malicious actors. By obscuring transaction creation times, either through client-side solutions or directly at the node level, the blockchain community aims to enhance user privacy and security. The proposed `schedulerawtransaction` RPC represents a strategic effort to bolster anonymity features by complicating the traceability of transactions back to their origins based on timing.
The concept also extends to improving user convenience and technological capability through automation. Currently, wallet solutions lack inherent support for scheduling transactions, prompting users with advanced needs to operate dedicated nodes. These nodes would manage transaction scheduling, providing a &quot;fire-and-forget&quot; functionality that necessitates minimal post-transaction confirmation but includes the ability to cancel transactions before execution. This setup is particularly beneficial for power users seeking to automate transaction broadcasts without manual oversight.
Further discussions delve into using delayed transaction broadcasting as a method to enhance privacy within P2P networks. By introducing delays, the predictability and visibility of user activities to external observers are reduced, though not entirely eliminated. This strategy, while contributing to a broader privacy strategy, underscores the ongoing challenge of safeguarding user activities against sophisticated analysis by adversaries. 
Additionally, the conversation touches upon the importance of maintaining transactional privacy through methods such as random delays between transactions. This approach aims to prevent linking multiple Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) to the same individual based on the timing of their transactions, highlighting the need for automated features within cryptocurrency systems to enhance privacy protections.
Finally, the use of nLockTime in Bitcoin transactions presents both opportunities and challenges for privacy and scheduling. While it allows specifying the earliest time a transaction can be added to the blockchain, the current implementation in Bitcoin Core offers limited utility for those seeking to leverage it for precise scheduling purposes. This limitation points to a gap in functionality for users interested in more granular control over transaction timing, emphasizing the need for improvements that simplify the process of setting nLockTime and integrating it into transaction creation workflows.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>