<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2026-01-27T03:12:32.825554+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>ChrisChoH</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-06 18:23:50.652000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>Nuh</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-07 17:00:27.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ChrisChoH</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-09 03:04:28.055000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ftw</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-09 13:28:04.363000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>GaloisField</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-09 15:21:44.761000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>ChrisCho-H</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 05:53:45.293000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ChrisCho-H</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 05:56:14.919000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6576_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6579_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6590_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6592_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6615_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6686_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6687_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T03:12:32.826838+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bithoven-a-formally-verified-imperative-smart-contract-language-for-bitcoin/2189/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-06 18:23:50.652000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The introduction of Bithoven marks a significant milestone in the development of smart contract languages specifically designed for Bitcoin. Bithoven aims to strike a balance between the structured correctness provided by Miniscript and the familiar imperative control flow found in languages like C, including `if/else` statements and explicit variable usage. This initiative seeks to combine developer ease of use with the stringent safety requirements necessary for Bitcoin Script operations, enabling the creation of code that is both secure and efficient without sacrificing intuitive control structures. By utilizing an `LR(1)` parser and incorporating static analysis techniques, Bithoven ensures type safety and addresses common security vulnerabilities, such as unauthorized spending without a signature. The compiler has been meticulously designed to manage stack operations effectively, optimize opcodes, and support various Bitcoin address formats, including legacy, segwit, and taproot.
A noteworthy aspect of Bithoven is its emphasis on preventing undefined behavior through the formal definition of the language's semantics and the validation of its safety via proofs, detailed in a paper available on arXiv. An example provided demonstrates Bithoven's capability to handle conditional paths efficiently, showcasing its utility in facilitating transactions governed by specific rules like timelocks and signature verifications. The language's design philosophy promotes a clean stack after each operation, reflecting the operational principles of Bitcoin Script while striving for greater accessibility and expressiveness. Resources such as a GitHub repository, a Web IDE, official documentation, and the formal verification paper have been made available to support Bithoven’s development and encourage community engagement.
The conversation also delves into the potential use of a specific compiler as an alternative to Simplicity for implementing STARK proofs and transaction introspection using OP_CAT combined with Schnorr tricks. This exploration highlights the continuous search within the programming and cryptocurrency communities for methods that are secure, efficient, and less disruptive for cryptographic operations and smart contract functionalities. It underscores the importance of discussions around optimizing blockchain technology's performance and security features, which are crucial for the technological evolution of cryptocurrencies and decentralized systems.
Bithoven v0.0.1 focuses on ensuring mainnet safety by adhering strictly to SegWit/Taproot protocols and currently excludes experimental opcodes like `OP_CAT`. However, plans are underway to make the syntax more intuitive for users, particularly in handling Merkle paths by redefining the `+` operator. This approach aims to simplify the verification process of Merkle paths and reflects an innovative strategy to enhance user experience. Furthermore, there is an openness to exploring advanced features such as Schnorr Introspection, suggesting a collaborative effort to refine these aspects based on real-world use cases.
In addition, the email touches upon the challenge of simplifying the formalization process of covenants without compromising the system's ability to offer comprehensive introspection capabilities, which are essential for verification, analysis, and optimization. The sender of the email proposes a technical collaboration, highlighting the potential of Bithoven’s static analyzer in addressing introspective patterns and integrating them into its grammar. This collaboration could significantly advance the development of state-bound assets on Bitcoin, demonstrating Bithoven's critical role in overcoming implementation challenges within the 'W' protocol.
Lastly, Bithoven's approach to witness data is mentioned, indicating a less restrictive user experience compared to Simplicity but noting that manual management of stack opcodes and certain complexities in introspection might be present. A speculative implementation of introspection is discussed, suggesting the addition of new syntax to Bithoven, emphasizing the ongoing learning process and the potential for future enhancements to accommodate advanced functionalities like transaction introspection.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>