<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:46.017282+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>ChrisChoH</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-06 18:23:50.652000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>Nuh</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-07 17:00:27.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6576_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6579_Bithoven-A-Formally-Verified-Imperative-Smart-Contract-Language-for-Bitcoin.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bithoven: A Formally Verified, Imperative Smart Contract Language for Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:46.017688+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bithoven-a-formally-verified-imperative-smart-contract-language-for-bitcoin/2189/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-06 18:23:50.652000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The introduction of Bithoven marks a significant advancement in the domain of smart contract languages, particularly for developers working within the Bitcoin Script environment. Bithoven is designed to meld the structured correctness intrinsic to Miniscript with an imperative control flow syntax akin to that of C, which includes the utilization of `if/else` statements and explicit variables. This innovative approach aims to facilitate ease of use for developers while adhering to the stringent safety requirements essential for Bitcoin Script operations. By enabling developers to write code that is both safe and optimized without compromising on intuitive control structures, Bithoven addresses a critical need in the field.
Bithoven distinguishes itself through its use of an `LR(1)` parser and static analysis techniques to ensure type safety and address common security vulnerabilities, such as unauthorized transactions without a signature. The compiler is adept at managing stack operations efficiently and optimizing opcodes to enhance performance and reliability. Additionally, Bithoven offers support for various Bitcoin address formats, including legacy, segwit, and taproot, broadening its applicability across different Bitcoin transactions. A pivotal aspect of Bithoven's design is its focus on preventing undefined behavior by formally defining the language's semantics and validating its safety through comprehensive proofs, as detailed in a paper published on arXiv.
An example provided demonstrates Bithoven’s capabilities in handling conditional paths through clear, directive syntax, such as in a Hashed TimeLock Contract (HTLC) scenario. This illustrates how the language facilitates guidance for the compiler in processing explicit stack input definitions and conditional logic to enforce transaction rules effectively. Furthermore, Bithoven’s philosophy emphasizes maintaining a clean stack after each operation, aligning closely with the operational principles of Bitcoin Script but with enhanced accessibility and expressiveness.
Supporting resources for Bithoven include a GitHub repository, a Web IDE, official documentation, and the formal verification paper. These resources not only make Bithoven readily accessible to developers but also encourage community feedback and collaboration, highlighting the project's commitment to ongoing refinement and adaptability. This open invitation for community engagement is crucial for addressing potential edge cases and enhancing the robustness of the language in future updates.
Comparatively, Bithoven presents an intriguing alternative to Simplicity, offering a less disruptive option for developers. There is curiosity regarding how Bithoven would handle complex operations necessary for STARK proofs and transaction introspection using OP_CAT combined with Schnorr tricks, suggesting areas for further exploration and development within this promising smart contract language framework.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>