<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-16T03:02:41.592020+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>AdamISZ</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>AdamISZ</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-26 14:34:32.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-29 19:49:26.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-29 20:21:58.109000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-01 10:30:46.778000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:29:44.543000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5976_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5985_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5986_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/5991_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6627_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-16T03:02:41.593212+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion encompasses a novel cryptographic method facilitated through Nostr, employing Bitcoin's cryptographic techniques to generate new keys for receiving payments more securely and privately. This method addresses limitations in the existing BIP 47 protocol by enabling Alice to generate a new key for Bob and notify him via an encrypted message using NIP-17, enhancing user experience by avoiding issues like silent payment scanning and OP_RETURN notifications. It proposes a structured approach potentially outlined in a new BIP or NIP, illustrating through Python code examples how stealth public and private keys are generated. This showcases Nostr's potential in creating secure, anonymous transactions by leveraging shared secrets between parties, thus providing developers with tools to integrate stealth payment capabilities into their applications.
The inquiry delves into the mathematical and cryptographic framework of the proposed solution, focusing on the structural intricacies of generating a new key and notifying Bob without requiring direct scanning of transactions. The process involves complex interactions between various cryptographic elements, highlighting a layered security approach that combines hash functions with elliptic curve cryptography. The operational specifics include strategies for streamlining the monitoring process for Bob, hinting at a system where he maintains a batch of addresses for Alice to facilitate easier transaction monitoring.
Nostr's decentralized communication protocol is leveraged to address challenges in ensuring reliable transaction notifications. The proposal suggests mechanisms to mitigate the risks of missed transactions due to the stateless nature of Nostr, including using multiple relays and confirmation messages. Concerns about privacy and efficiency in transaction notifications are addressed by integrating nostr notifications with Silent Payments, aiming to reduce scanning efforts and potential metadata leakage. The proposal also discusses the development within the cryptocurrency landscape, emphasizing collaboration and innovation to refine secure transaction methods.
Furthermore, there is skepticism regarding wallets heavily reliant on Nostr for storing critical data without fallback mechanisms, highlighting instances of data integrity threats due to potential relay database deletions. The limited adoption of NIP-17 and concerns about metadata leakage underscore the need for cautious advancement in adopting new protocols. Practical applications of these concepts are explored, including the development of an Electrum plugin to test &quot;color addresses&quot; as a novel approach to address representation, indicating ongoing exploration and implementation efforts in enhancing cryptocurrency privacy and functionality.
Lastly, a reference is made to an evolving specification that integrates Nostr notifications with the Silent Payments protocol, offering a link to further details. This signifies a continuous interest and effort in refining cryptocurrency transaction methods to achieve a balance between privacy, security, and user experience.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>