<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CAT and Bitcoin’s Path to Quantum Resistance</title>
  <updated>2026-01-31T03:25:39.744926+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>sCryptts</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-20 09:14:24.297000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jsarenik</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-21 20:29:51.070000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jsarenik</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-30 11:21:32.686000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6653_OP-CAT-and-Bitcoin-s-Path-to-Quantum-Resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6658_OP-CAT-and-Bitcoin-s-Path-to-Quantum-Resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6707_OP-CAT-and-Bitcoin-s-Path-to-Quantum-Resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CAT and Bitcoin’s Path to Quantum Resistance</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T03:25:39.745546+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cat-and-bitcoin-s-path-to-quantum-resistance/2207/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-20 09:14:24.297000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The security foundation of Bitcoin is significantly anchored in its use of elliptic curve cryptography. This cryptographic technique ensures the generation of Bitcoin signatures with private keys while safeguarding against the reverse engineering of these private keys from public keys, a task deemed nearly impossible with conventional computing power. However, the emergence of quantum computing, particularly through the application of Shor’s algorithm, presents a formidable challenge to this security paradigm. Shor's algorithm is adept at solving the discrete logarithm problem, which is central to the cryptographic defenses of Bitcoin, thereby posing a risk of adversaries potentially deriving private keys from public ones. This situation underscores a critical vulnerability within Bitcoin's current cryptographic framework, predicated on the difficulty of reversing elliptic-curve point multiplication, a notion put into jeopardy by quantum computing advancements.
There is a growing consensus on the imperative for Bitcoin to evolve beyond its reliance on elliptic-curve cryptography to embrace alternative cryptographic methods. Such an evolution aims to preserve Bitcoin’s foundational attributes of simplicity, decentralization, and long-term stability, without necessitating frequent consensus redefinitions. Satoshi Nakamoto, the pseudonymous creator of Bitcoin, foresaw the need for such cryptographic adaptability in light of technological progress, including quantum computing. The reintroduction of OP_CAT is viewed as a strategic initiative towards maintaining Bitcoin’s cryptographic agility, enabling the experimentation with various post-quantum cryptographic constructions at the script level. This approach not only resonates with Satoshi's original vision but also provides a pragmatic pathway for Bitcoin to navigate the impending quantum era. Through OP_CAT, Bitcoin exhibits a readiness strategy that is both incremental and reversible, aimed at ensuring its resilience and longevity amidst quantum threats.
The practical feasibility of employing quantum computing to extract private keys from public keys, particularly concerning the secp256k1 elliptic curve utilized in Bitcoin transactions, has raised several considerations. These include the operational readiness of quantum computers, the time and cost implications of computing private keys, and the practicality of executing such an operation within the timeframe of a transaction pending in the mempool. The theoretical potential of quantum computing to compromise cryptographic algorithms underpins concerns over the derivation of private keys from public ones. Nonetheless, the actual utility of quantum computing in this context appears constrained, especially for minor transactions. Highlighted is a scenario involving a $25 Bitcoin transaction, illustrating the potential futility of deploying quantum computing against small-scale transactions that do not reuse addresses, thereby presenting a constantly moving target. This discussion also acknowledges the anticipatory measures within the Bitcoin scripting capabilities, notably the experimental phase involving OP_CAT on the signet testing network. This exploration signifies ongoing efforts within the Bitcoin community to fortify its scripting functionalities against emerging threats, aligning with proactive steps towards cryptographic modernization and security enhancement.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>