<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2026-01-19T03:09:55.634904+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 17:25:49.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 15:19:02.087000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 21:07:53.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:23:18.752000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:40:38.988000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 01:03:07.859000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6418_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6421_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6437_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6446_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6447_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6443_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6644_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2026-01-19T03:09:55.635923+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</published>
    <summary>SHRINCS represents a novel hybrid signature scheme that creatively blends the efficiency of stateful hash-based signatures with the robustness of stateless ones to cater to scenarios where a limited number of signatures are required from a given key. The integration of an unbalanced XMSS tree for stateful operations and a variant of SPHINCS+ for stateless operations allows SHRINCS to provide high-efficiency operations under normal circumstances while offering a reliable fallback in case of state loss or corruption. This dual-mode functionality is facilitated through the derivation of the public key by hashing both the stateful and stateless public keys, supporting seamless operation between modes based on the state's integrity. Key generation, restoration, signing, and verification processes are all designed to bolster this dual functionality. The innovative use of an &quot;unbalanced&quot; XMSS tree aims to optimize authentication path length for early signatures, significantly reducing signature size when few signatures are expected, which is crucial for applications like Bitcoin wallets. Furthermore, the employment of WOTS+C enhances the efficiency and security of the stateful path.
The conversation around post-quantum cryptography (PQC) delves into the adequacy of a 128-bit security level against quantum attacks, particularly those facilitated by Grover's algorithm. It challenges the conventional assessment of cryptographic strength by highlighting the substantial computational demands imposed by hash function circuit evaluations necessary for each iteration of Grover's algorithm. This evaluation underscores the importance of considering quantum-resistant metrics in assessing cryptographic strength. The detailed examination of SHRINCS at NIST security level 3, corresponding to 192-bit classical or 96-bit quantum resistance, provides insights into the complexities of signature sizes and computational demands in the face of quantum computing advancements.
Furthermore, the discussion touches upon the significance of checksums in the Winternitz One-Time Signature Scheme (WOTS) and its variant WOTS+ in preventing specific types of attacks, showcasing the cryptographic ingenuity embedded in their design. The exploration of checksum management techniques, contrasting traditional methods with more efficient strategies utilizing modulo operations, illustrates ongoing efforts to optimize data verification processes.
Concerns about the security of the WOTS scheme against specialized hardware capable of generating alternative signatures highlight the ongoing challenge of ensuring cryptographic security in an evolving technological landscape. Suggestions to enhance the immutability of WOTS signatures, such as increasing the size of both the envelope and the signature, reflect the continuous search for more secure and efficient cryptographic solutions.
The usage of SHRINCS within Bitcoin transactions introduces a unique approach to discouraging address reuse and mitigating risks associated with stateful schemes, such as fault injection attacks. These considerations point towards the inherent trade-offs and novel challenges faced in adopting such cryptographic solutions in decentralized systems like Bitcoin. The idea of standardizing two schemes within tapscript—SPHINCS (or a variant) and WOTS—and allowing wallets to choose their structure inside script trees presents a modular, albeit less unified, approach towards enhancing cryptographic practices within Bitcoin’s infrastructure. This proposition emphasizes the need for adaptability and cautious implementation in standardizing cryptographic solutions as BIPs, underscoring the complex interplay between security, efficiency, and usability in digital currency systems.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>