<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Provable Cryptography for Bitcoin: An Introduction (Workbook)</title>
  <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:10.423438+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-09 13:09:02.743000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>marathon-gary</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-07 15:08:08.088000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5855_Provable-Cryptography-for-Bitcoin-An-Introduction-Workbook-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6578_Provable-Cryptography-for-Bitcoin-An-Introduction-Workbook-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Provable Cryptography for Bitcoin: An Introduction (Workbook)</title>
    <updated>2026-01-08T03:06:10.423955+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/provable-cryptography-for-bitcoin-an-introduction-workbook/1974/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-09-09 13:09:02.743000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The comprehensive cryptography workbook is a meticulously developed resource designed to support an interactive workshop on Bitcoin cryptography. It is available for download at [this GitHub link](https://github.com/cryptography-camp/workbook/releases), offering a rich array of content developed through extensive refinement and testing, particularly with participant feedback. This process has ensured that the workbook is both polished and practical, suitable for real-world application and understanding.
Covering a broad spectrum of topics essential for mastering Bitcoin cryptography, the workbook introduces readers to foundational concepts such as algorithms, hash functions, and asymptotic security. It also dives into more specialized subjects including reductions, commitments, accumulators, and one-time signatures. A significant portion is devoted to exploring discrete logarithm problems, the random oracle model, programmable ROM, forking lemma, and signatures, with a special focus on key tweaking in signatures. The structured approach of the workbook is aimed at providing readers with the necessary background to understand advanced cryptographic signatures based on discrete logarithms and enhancing their skills in formalizing security notions for cryptographic primitives. This is crucial for the development and review of cryptographic protocols.
The workbook positions itself as a foundational tool that enables users to grasp state-of-the-art papers on cryptographic signatures and their security proofs. It offers detailed insights into discrete logarithm-based signatures, highlighted by the DahLIAS interactive aggregate signature scheme. Emphasis is placed on the importance of accurately defining protocol objectives and systematically introducing key proof techniques and security formalization. Through hands-on exercises, the workbook facilitates a gradual building of intuition and experience with theoretical concepts, illustrating how minor adjustments to security definitions or cryptographic schemes can have significant impacts on security proofs. A remarkable achievement of the workbook is the development of a preliminary proof for the Schnorr sign-to-contract scheme, marking a pioneering effort in cryptographic research.
For individuals interested in delving deeper into cryptography, but not necessarily limited to Bitcoin, another valuable resource is provided at [Joy of Cryptography](https://joyofcryptography.com/). This addition expands the horizon for learners beyond Bitcoin-specific cryptography. 
To engage with this workbook effectively, a background in modular arithmetic and basic probability theory is required, with an introductory knowledge of cryptography being beneficial. For those looking to prepare, Nadav Kohen's prework material serves as an excellent primer, accessible via [this link](https://github.com/cryptography-camp/prework). The creators welcome feedback, corrections, and suggestions for further refinement of the workbook, inviting contributions through issues or pull requests on the GitHub repository. This openness to collaboration underscores their commitment to continuous improvement and the workbook’s role as a robust educational tool for anyone keen on advancing their understanding of cryptographic principles underlying Bitcoin and related technologies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>