<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2026-01-20T03:04:40.266321+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 17:25:49.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 15:19:02.087000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 21:07:53.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:23:18.752000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:40:38.988000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 01:03:07.859000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 17:14:29.961000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6418_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6421_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6437_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6446_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6447_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6443_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6644_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6649_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2026-01-20T03:04:40.267411+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</published>
    <summary>SHRINCS represents a novel hybrid signature scheme that ingeniously combines the efficiency of stateful hash-based signatures with the robustness of stateless ones, offering a solution particularly suited for scenarios with limited signature requirements from a given key. The architectural foundation of SHRINCS leverages an unbalanced XMSS tree for stateful operations alongside a variant of SPHINCS+ for stateless operations, facilitating exceptionally efficient operations under normal conditions while also providing a reliable fallback in case the state is compromised. This dual-mode functionality is supported through a design where the public key is derived from both the stateful and stateless public keys, allowing seamless operation transition based on the integrity of the state. Key generation, restoration, signing, and verification processes are all tailored to accommodate this versatility.
The discussion on post-quantum cryptography (PQC) challenges the adequacy of a 128-bit security level, especially against quantum computing threats such as those posed by Grover's algorithm, which effectively reduces the security level by half. This analysis underscores the necessity of reevaluating cryptographic strength through a quantum-resistant lens, emphasizing the importance of detailed scrutiny at a granular level—specifically, the &quot;per envelope bytes&quot; concept—for ensuring comprehensive defense mechanisms against both current and future computational threats. Furthermore, the dialogue on the National Institute of Standards and Technology's (NIST) evaluation criteria for PQC highlights the significant computational demands imposed by hash function circuit evaluations, illustrating the impracticality of achieving sufficient acceleration through quantum computing under current technological constraints.
The Winternitz One-Time Signature Scheme (WOTS) and its enhanced variant, WOTS+, are spotlighted for their incorporation of checksums as a countermeasure against specific attack vectors, demonstrating their cryptographic resilience. This mechanism ensures that any attempt to alter the message content in a way that would still validate the signature becomes detectably invalid, thereby maintaining the integrity of the communication. Additionally, an alternative approach to managing checksums through summing up modulo negated values is introduced, presenting a method that promises size efficiency and resource optimization in data verification processes.
Concerns regarding the security of WOTS against the development of specialized hardware capable of generating valid alternative signatures highlight the ongoing challenges in cryptographic security. A proposed augmentation to increase the immutability of WOTS signatures, despite its subsequent retraction, reflects the dynamic nature of discussions around enhancing cryptographic schemes against sophisticated threats. 
The innovative balance SHRINCS introduces between stateful and stateless hashing is discussed, particularly its strategy to discourage address reuse by incrementally increasing transaction costs, alongside the vulnerabilities it faces, such as fault injection attacks. The proposal to integrate both SPHINCS and WOTS within Bitcoin's tapscript offers a modular and gradual integration strategy, albeit with potential privacy and efficiency drawbacks. The need for a more inclusive approach, allowing offline seed generation and acknowledging the practical challenges in maintaining secure state information, is acknowledged, suggesting a broader conversation with hardware wallet developers to explore feasible solutions.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>