<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-23T03:04:46.773284+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>arminsdev</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 17:00:01.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6670_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:04:46.774224+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The exploration into a scheduled transaction broadcast feature for Bitcoin Core has sparked considerable discussion. This feature would enable users to schedule their transactions for future broadcast to the bitcoin network, aiming to either conceal the actual time of transaction creation or accommodate conditions unaddressable through bitcoin scripts. The proposed implementation involves a new RPC called `schedulerawtransaction`, designed similarly to `sendrawtransaction` but tailored for scheduling. Transactions under this mechanism would be stored in a unique memory structure and saved in a separate file to ensure consistency across restarts. This development is in response to concerns over anti-snipping and the broader issue of information leakage through transaction timestamps. Anti-snipping focuses on protecting the details regarding the timing of transactions, a crucial aspect of enhancing privacy and security within blockchain networks. Addressing these vulnerabilities requires a deep understanding of how transactions are timestamped and developing strategies to mitigate potential risks.
Furthermore, there's an emphasis on the distinction between client-side and node-level implementations for obscuring transaction creation times. Implementing such features directly within nodes could offer better security or anonymity, making it harder to trace transactions back to their origins based on timing. This includes the necessity for additional RPCs for listing and canceling scheduled transactions, highlighting the complexity and utility of integrating such functionalities. Such advancements could significantly change transaction flows, offering users more strategic control over their transactions.
The concept also extends to the practicality of scheduled transactions for users needing automated execution at specific times or conditions, independent of manual intervention. This capability caters especially to &quot;power users&quot; who operate their own nodes and seek to automate transaction broadcasts without direct oversight. The discussion acknowledges the need for extending the RPC interface to effectively manage these scheduled transactions, including listing, canceling, and potentially verifying the outcomes of these transactions. Despite the primary use case being described as &quot;fire-and-forget,&quot; the value of being able to cancel a transaction before its execution was recognized.
Regarding privacy concerns, even with the delayed broadcasting of transactions, adversaries might still observe the same peer-to-peer communication patterns. This observation suggests that while the feature could provide some level of privacy benefit by obfuscating the actual transaction creation time, it may not fully shield users from all forms of analysis that could compromise privacy.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>