<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-22T03:09:03.285775+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>RubenSomsen</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-16 00:25:04.617000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-18 17:01:15.217000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>RubenSomsen</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-21 10:41:07.718000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6626_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6628_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6642_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6657_Silent-Payments-notifications-via-Nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Silent Payments notifications via Nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-22T03:09:03.286480+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-notifications-via-nostr/2203/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-15 23:09:56.492000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent discussions delve into the complexities of managing blockchain transactions, specifically focusing on Silent Payments and their integration with Nostr for notification purposes. The concept of Silent Payments introduces a non-interactive way to receive payments, where the transaction details are known only to the sender, necessitating an efficient method for notifying the receiver about incoming transactions. The proposed solution involves sending notifications through Nostr, including essential information like the transaction ID (txid), tweaks, and an optional blockhash or height. This approach aims to streamline the verification process for the recipient, significantly reducing the effort required to locate and confirm relevant transactions.
A critical aspect of this discussion is the balance between minimizing the data included in notifications to simplify the process and enhancing the system's resistance to Denial of Service (DoS) attacks by incorporating additional verification data. The dialogue suggests two distinct approaches: one that focuses on reducing the notification content to the most crucial elements, thereby lowering the risk of processing unnecessary or excessive information, and another that emphasizes bolstering DoS resistance through more comprehensive data checks. This dichotomy highlights the inherent trade-offs between operational simplicity and security, urging stakeholders to consider these factors carefully when managing blockchain transactions.
Moreover, the conversation explores the implications of different wallet designs on the transaction verification process. It acknowledges the diversity in data backend configurations and scanning logic among wallets, emphasizing the importance of distrust in unverified information sources. The discussion points out that if Bob receives tweak information from a trusted contact, the verification process becomes markedly simpler, allowing him to bypass exhaustive script analysis. This trust dynamic introduces a nuanced perspective on digital transactions, underscoring the potential for simplifying client design and operation by leveraging the tweak field effectively.
Furthermore, the discourse considers the practicality of Alice waiting for transaction confirmation before sending a notification. This consideration is pivotal as it affects the accuracy and utility of the information provided. Different wallet technologies, especially those relying on filters and block pulling, may face challenges in verifying transactions based solely on a txid without compromising privacy. The inclusion of a tweak field, in addition to the txid, could offer a more straightforward verification process for such wallets. This aspect of the discussion opens up broader considerations on optimizing transaction verification practices to enhance the overall user experience across various wallet platforms.
In summary, the dialogue underscores the multifaceted challenges and considerations involved in managing Silent Payments and notifications within the blockchain ecosystem. It highlights the need for a delicate balance between simplification and security, the impact of trust dynamics on transaction verification, and the importance of adapting to diverse wallet designs to streamline the verification process while maintaining privacy and efficiency.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>