<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
  <updated>2026-02-01T03:52:03.723552+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-20 17:45:05.552000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-21 04:37:01.593000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-22 14:07:54.236000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-05 04:37:39.131000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-05 14:54:10.257000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-06 07:57:55.513000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-28 22:26:36+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-29 00:56:22.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-31 03:56:18.682000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6466_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6469_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6472_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6481_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6561_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6566_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6573_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6704_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6705_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6713_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
    <updated>2026-02-01T03:52:03.724912+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/major-bip-360-update/2170/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Ethan Heilman, Isabel Foxen Duke, and Hunter Beast have initiated a significant revision of BIP 360 in response to community feedback, aiming for enhanced clarity and coherence in the documentation. This overhaul addresses the need for a fresh approach following substantial technical changes in previous updates, with a focus on articulating strategies to mitigate quantum-related risks effectively. The revised proposal continues to oppose the integration of post-quantum signature schemes, introducing instead a novel output type named &quot;Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH).&quot; This new type aims to protect against vulnerabilities to Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) that may arise from advancements in quantum computing or other cryptographic technologies. By omitting the key path spend, P2TSH strengthens Bitcoin's defenses against emerging threats, marking a crucial step towards quantum resistance. The update also enriches the technical framework by including test vectors in Python and Rust, facilitating broader understanding and easier implementation of the changes. Community members are encouraged to review these modifications via the provided links to the [BIP Repo](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1670) and [BIP360.org](http://bip360.org), highlighting the team's dedication to enhancing Bitcoin's security through collaborative efforts.
The conversation around the term Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH) raises concerns about future compatibility and clarity, especially with potential introductions of new tapleaf versions incorporating Simplicity—a high-level programming language aimed at smart contracts and blockchain applications. This situation underscores the importance of selecting nomenclature in blockchain technology that is both forward-looking and reflective of evolving landscapes. As blockchain technology becomes more complex and diverse, the necessity for names that clearly communicate functionality and compatibility becomes paramount. The naming conventions within the blockchain domain should ideally anticipate future developments, providing a clear framework that facilitates growth without compromising clarity.
A shift towards script-only transactions to combat quantum computing threats highlights an innovative approach emphasizing the use of TXHASH for a multi-step secret reveal mechanism. This method allows secure vaulting and spending of coins in a post-quantum environment without new signature schemes, proposing a significant move towards quantum-resistant cryptocurrency transactions. The terminology discussion extends to the precision in naming, where &quot;pay to script tree merkle root&quot; is suggested as a more fitting description than initially interpreted terms, ensuring clearer understanding of the operational specifics.
Further deliberation on naming conventions brings to light the balance between aesthetic cohesion and technical accuracy in the blockchain field. The choice of P2TSH, influenced by phonetic similarity to existing Bitcoin protocol elements, aims for consistency within transaction types. However, this preference has sparked debate over the impact of such decisions on the ecosystem's integrity, suggesting a need for more accurate naming like &quot;pay to script tree hash&quot; to avoid misleading stakeholders.
The introduction of Pay to Script Tree (P2ST) represents a notable advancement in cryptocurrency, enhancing transaction security and flexibility. By allowing funds to be locked under multiple conditions, P2ST broadens possibilities for transaction verification and execution, facilitating the creation of complex smart contracts and conditional transactions. This development not only improves upon limitations associated with earlier transaction types but also enhances privacy and efficiency through script trees, contributing significantly to the blockchain infrastructure's versatility and functional richness.
Finally, the discourse emphasizes the critical role of precise terminology in cryptographic systems, particularly concerning quantum resistance. The specific use of the term &quot;Hash&quot; and its implications for security highlight the necessity for clear communication in the design and discussion of quantum-resistant cryptographic systems. The critique of BIP-360's naming and its potential misrepresentation stresses the importance of accurately conveying purpose and mechanism in technical proposals to maintain trust and understanding within the cryptocurrency community.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>