<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BLISK: Boolean circuit Logic Integrated into the Single Key</title>
  <updated>2026-01-31T03:28:34.256584+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>olkurbatov</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 23:23:43.928000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>evdkim</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-28 10:30:50.897000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>olkurbatov</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-28 15:25:28.684000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>nkohen</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-30 20:39:16.816000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6691_BLISK-Boolean-circuit-Logic-Integrated-into-the-Single-Key.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6696_BLISK-Boolean-circuit-Logic-Integrated-into-the-Single-Key.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6698_BLISK-Boolean-circuit-Logic-Integrated-into-the-Single-Key.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6711_BLISK-Boolean-circuit-Logic-Integrated-into-the-Single-Key.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BLISK: Boolean circuit Logic Integrated into the Single Key</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T03:28:34.257412+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blisk-boolean-circuit-logic-integrated-into-the-single-key/2217/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-26 23:23:43.928000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent initiative aimed at enhancing Bitcoin's authorization policies has introduced a groundbreaking approach to incorporate complex boolean logic into the transaction validation process. This novel development seeks to address the limitations inherent in existing mechanisms by providing more nuanced control over bitcoin spending permissions, without compromising on privacy or efficiency. Traditional methods like threshold signatures and scripts have their drawbacks, such as limited expressiveness and visibility issues, respectively. In contrast, the new framework enables the encoding of intricate conditions using monotone boolean policies that combine AND/OR logic, all while keeping the policy complexity off-chain. This is achieved through a singular Schnorr signature verification against one Elliptic Curve (EC) point, simplifying the on-chain component.
This innovative system utilizes cryptographic primitives like MuSig2 for AND gates, Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) for OR gates, and Non-Interactive Zero-Knowledge proofs for ensuring verifiability and honesty in gate execution. These technologies facilitate a setup that supports non-interactive key rotation and allows users to continue using their existing long-term keys. The framework's ability to articulate complex policies, which were previously unattainable with threshold signatures, marks a significant advancement in digital currency transactions by maintaining privacy and security without revealing the underlying policy to external parties. For those interested in a deeper dive into this framework, comprehensive resources are available including an academic paper ([https://eprint.iacr.org/2026/088.pdf](https://eprint.iacr.org/2026/088.pdf)) and an explainer blog post ([https://hackmd.io/@olkurbatov/HJm5h0JH-l](https://hackmd.io/@olkurbatov/HJm5h0JH-l)), alongside the codebase for further exploration and feedback ([https://github.com/zero-art-rs/blisk](https://github.com/zero-art-rs/blisk)).
A particular inquiry within this context focuses on the operational dynamics of Musig2 in handling scenarios where certain signatories are deemed essential for transaction authorization. The described policy structure allows for a valid signature from four distinct coalitions, formed by combinations of specified participants, thereby enabling a flexible and secure authentication process. This system leverages a PK tree visualization to represent possible signer combinations, diverging from simple Musig2 aggregation and employing ECDH operations for key generation, enhancing both security and practical applicability.
Furthermore, questions have been raised regarding the necessity of the ECDH and attached ZKPs within the setup, proposing alternative approaches like Replicated Secret Sharing (RSS) for simpler and potentially more efficient key agreement processes. Despite these considerations, the established framework emphasizes security through mathematical rigor and practical flexibility, suggesting that even with the possibility of alternative methods, the chosen cryptographic strategies offer distinct advantages in terms of security and implementation feasibility. This discussion reflects ongoing exploration and optimization within cryptographic practices, highlighting the dynamic nature of digital currency security and authorization methodologies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>