<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
  <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:57.026500+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>tobysharp</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-11 21:25:57.349000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jsarenik</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-17 18:04:48.840000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-18 16:11:54.801000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>tobysharp</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 04:46:31.191000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>tobysharp</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 04:52:34.333000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 06:33:21.777000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>tobysharp</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-23 05:44:53.111000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6622_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6637_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6641_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6665_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6666_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6667_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6675_Hornet-UTXO-1-A-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-UTXO-database.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Hornet UTXO(1): A custom, constant-time, highly parallel UTXO database</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:57.027630+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hornet-utxo-1-a-custom-constant-time-highly-parallel-utxo-database/2201/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2026-01-11 21:25:57.349000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The development of Hornet UTXO(1) introduces a significant leap in Bitcoin client technology, embodying an experimental Bitcoin client that prioritizes high performance and declarative consensus specification. Constructed using modern C++ for optimal parallelism, it achieves a highly concurrent and lock-free operation. This advanced approach enables the revalidation of the entire mainnet chain to be completed in just 15 minutes on a 32-core workstation, a task that takes Bitcoin Core 167 minutes under similar conditions. Such efficiency is achieved through the database's ability to support all structural and contextual validations, build the UTXO database, and ensure transactions correspond to unspent outputs without the need for locks. The architecture also supports out-of-order block validation, concurrent processing, and automatic data dependency resolution, with features allowing state rewinding and queries against past chain states.
T. Sharp's paper, &quot;Hornet Node: A Declarative, Executable Specification of Bitcoin Consensus,&quot; available in [HTML](https://hornetnode.org/paper.html) and [PDF](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.15754) formats, details this innovation developed as an unfunded personal project. The system's design eliminates hash maps in favor of sorted arrays and LSM trees, optimizing disk access and memory usage through compact, cache-friendly data structures and fixed-size allocations. Despite its sophistication, Hornet UTXO(1) consists of only 3,000 lines of code, highlighting its efficiency and stand-alone nature without external dependencies.
The broader discussion touches on the potential integration of Hornet with traditional Bitcoin operations like the mempool, emphasizing the importance of efficient transaction broadcast and validation mechanisms. Practical advice is shared for initializing Bitcoin Core nodes with up-to-date mempool data, sourced from [anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt), to enhance network integration. The conversation further explores the architectural and performance nuances of Hornet Node compared to other implementations, raising questions about the feasibility of extending its database engine for broader applications beyond UTXO management.
The inquiry into Hornet Node's distinctiveness includes an interest in its source code and detailed performance benchmarks, particularly in relation to Bitcoin Core and libbitcoin. Speculations on Hornet's superior performance leverage, due to its implementation of parallelism, suggest a promising avenue for enhancing blockchain efficiency, especially during the initial block download phase. There's an openness to expanding Hornet Node's functionalities, indicating a scalable framework for supporting diverse blockchain applications.
A specific performance comparison highlights Hornet UTXO(1)'s superiority over Bitcoin Core, with inquiries into the hardware specifications used during testing to understand better the architectural choices behind its high performance. The system's storage solution, involving a combination of in-memory indexing and disk-based asynchronous reads, showcases a thoughtful design aimed at maximizing efficiency and scalability within server-class hardware environments. This detailed approach underscores the innovative engineering principles guiding the Hornet project, aiming to redefine consensus mechanisms and blockchain technology performance standards.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>