<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T03:31:03.694416+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-18 23:27:11.773000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>reardencode</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-30 19:14:33.031000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-08 12:16:09.922000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>reardencode</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-09 04:06:31.647000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-28 18:20:01.195000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6461_A-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6492_A-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6585_A-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6591_A-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6701_A-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
    <updated>2026-01-29T03:31:03.695404+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures/2168/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-18 23:27:11.773000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The email delves into an advanced method designed to enhance the security of Bitcoin transactions against potential quantum computing threats and signature forgeries. This method incorporates a multi-phase approach leveraging OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (OP_CTV) and OP_TXHASH/OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY protocols, as detailed in BIP119 and a draft proposal. The process starts with creating a protective &quot;Anchor envelope&quot; where, despite future possibilities of signature forgery, funds are constrained to move only along predetermined paths. By disabling Taproot key-path spending and employing Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve (NUMS) internal keys, the method forces all Taproot outputs through a script path, significantly bolstering quantum resistance.
The initial phase, Phase 0, is focused on channeling all value into a predestined Anchor envelope without locking in final recipients or templates. It utilizes OP_TXHASH to set conditions preventing the leakage of value outside of the Anchor output, thereby limiting transaction fee extractions. Subsequently, Phase 1 involves the creation of the Anchor UTXO on-chain, which then offers two spending paths: a reveal path requiring a one-time secret and matching a specific template via OP_CTV, and an escape hatch that does not disclose the secret but must match a different template, also enforced by OP_CTV. Phase 2 allows for choosing between these paths under stringent security measures ensuring funds remain secure even if signatures are compromised.
Moreover, this structured strategy restricts attackers to either delaying transactions or forcing their execution, thanks to its quantum-resistant design and reorganization resistance provided by the relative timelock mechanism. The protocol also supports graceful degradation in response to quantum advancements without requiring nodes to retain historical transaction indices, thus being prunable-friendly. For more technical insights and demonstration code, reference is made to a [Gist](https://gist.github.com/earonesty/ea086aa995be1a860af093f93bd45bf2).
The discussion also raises concerns regarding the construction's reliance on secp256k1 and NUMS points, highlighting a significant quantum vulnerability. Given that NUMS points can be compromised by a quantum adversary, the current construction would not be considered quantum safe. This vulnerability underscores the necessity for adaptability towards emerging security needs, including the capability for users to redirect funds to new, quantum-safe addresses upon withdrawal. A proposed solution suggests adopting Conditioned Commitment Verification (CCV) instead of relying solely on TXHASH for transactions, which could offer enhanced security and flexibility by allowing value flow enforcement and integration and extraction of the CTV reveal spend at the time of spending.
Additionally, the proposal emphasizes decoupling the operational dependency from NUMS points, focusing instead on the original construction of the system as a primary fallback or safety mechanism. This approach aims to limit the damage an attacker can inflict to merely causing disruption rather than enabling them to extract resources from the system. Such strategic decisions highlight the importance of establishing a robust baseline defense to mitigate the extent of harm an adversary can achieve.
In addressing the distinctions between P2TR and P2TSH script operations, it is noted that the choice between these has significant implications for the script's security and functionality, especially concerning vulnerabilities to quantum computing capabilities. The differentiation is crucial in deciding the appropriate script operation type to mitigate specific risks. Lastly, despite potential attacks, the structured secret-reveal sequence ensures that without the revealed secret, covenants restrict spending to only the required shape, emphasizing that the actual signature might become redundant in safeguarding transactions against unauthorized alterations.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>