<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
  <updated>2026-01-06T03:01:44.753615+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-20 17:45:05.552000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-21 04:37:01.593000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-22 14:07:54.236000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-05 04:37:39.131000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-05 14:54:10.257000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6466_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6469_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6472_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6481_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6561_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6566_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T03:01:44.754526+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/major-bip-360-update/2170/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</published>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain technology and its continuous evolution, the comprehensive rewrite of BIP 360 highlights a significant stride towards enhancing Bitcoin's defenses against quantum computing threats. This revision was prompted by the necessity for clearer documentation following previous updates that introduced substantial technical changes. The revamped BIP 360 retains its original stance on not incorporating post-quantum signature schemes but introduces a new output type known as &quot;Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH).&quot; This innovative approach omits the key path spend to shield against vulnerabilities in Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) that could be exploited by quantum computing advancements. This modification is crucial for fortifying Bitcoin against emerging threats to ECC, marking an essential development in ensuring the cryptocurrency's quantum resistance. Additionally, the updated proposal enhances its technical framework by including test vectors in Python and Rust, aimed at broadening understanding and facilitating easier implementation of these changes. The community is encouraged to review these modifications through resources available at [BIP Repo](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1670) and [BIP360.org](http://bip360.org), reflecting a commitment to collaborative refinement of Bitcoin's security.
The terminology used within the blockchain domain, particularly the term Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH), raises concerns regarding future compatibility and clarity. These apprehensions stem from the potential confusion that could arise with the introduction of new tapleaf versions, especially those incorporating Simplicity—a high-level programming language designed for smart contracts and blockchain applications. The evolution of blockchain technology brings about increased complexity and diversity in its components, necessitating a revisitation of naming conventions to ensure they remain intuitive and accurately descriptive. The challenge lies in developing a lexicon that is forward-looking and reflective of the blockchain's evolving landscape, accommodating new features and technologies without sacrificing clarity. This concern underscores the broader challenge of crafting terminologies that serve their intended purpose effectively as new capabilities like Simplicity are integrated.
Another innovative approach discussed is leveraging TXHASH for a multi-step secret reveal mechanism to safeguard cryptocurrency transactions against quantum threats. This method proposes a shift towards script-only transactions using operations like OP_CTV and OP_TXHASH, aiming for quantum resistance without the need for new signature schemes. For those interested in delving deeper into this concept, further information is accessible at [Delving into Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures/2168). This proactive stance ensures cryptocurrencies' security amidst the advent of quantum technologies.
Additionally, there's an ongoing debate regarding the most appropriate and clear terminology to describe certain blockchain concepts. While &quot;Pay to Tapscript Hash&quot; was chosen for its rhyming similarity to existing terms and aesthetic appeal in lists alongside other acronyms, it's argued that a term such as &quot;pay to script tree merkle root&quot; might offer a more accurate description. Despite the subjectivity of naming conventions and their imperfections, the dialogue reflects the community's efforts to balance simplicity, accuracy, and forward-compatibility in nomenclature, highlighting the nuanced challenges of evolving blockchain terminologies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>