<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-10-02T02:24:53.209957+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes.778000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-01T10:30:46.778000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T02:24:53.209990+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the skepticism regarding a wallet that primarily utilizes the nostr platform for storing critical data without ensuring a reliable fallback mechanism. It's highlighted that reliance on nostr doesn't necessitate a nostr-based wallet specifically but necessitates incorporating some relays in the settings coupled with a library versatile enough for various applications. The Electrum wallet, for instance, leverages this setup for facilitating submarine swaps, a practice detailed through a provided [link](https://x.com/ElectrumWallet/status/1933909910011453631).

There is an expression of unfamiliarity and curiosity regarding the adoption of NIP-17, especially given its potential application for Stealth Addresses which could inadvertently lead to a form of metadata leakage. Despite these uncertainties, the author mentions their use of NIP-17 in the amethyst project, where it has effectively addressed metadata leak issues. Additionally, Whitenoise's implementation of NIP-EE or MLS is brought into discussion, suggesting it as a potentially interesting avenue for exploration with further information accessible via a [link](https://github.com/nostr-protocol/nips/blob/b516adbf423a120045e07adf5358ae69f190f3c8/EE.md).

Finally, the conversation shifts towards practical application, revealing intentions to develop an Electrum plugin designed to test this concept in conjunction with a bitcoin wallet. This endeavor aims to introduce "color addresses," which propose using colors as Human Readable Parts (HRP) instead of the conventional 'npub', offering a novel approach to address representation. A link is supplied to provide more insight into this innovative idea ([link](https://x.com/1440000bytes/status/1971888952249606437)). This summary encapsulates a discourse exploring the integration of new standards and technologies in cryptocurrency wallets, highlighting both theoretical considerations and practical implementations aimed at enhancing privacy and functionality.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-01T10:30:46.778000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
