<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-10-02T02:23:55.351474+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-10-01 18:58:43.687000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T02:23:55.351506+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811/31" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the practicality and strategic implementation of cryptographic protocols, emphasizing the importance of preparing for quantum computing threats without prematurely disrupting existing systems. The dialogue opens with skepticism towards the relevance of enabling P2QRH independently of Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) locks, underlining a belief that such a feature should not be utilized absent PQC safeguards due to the potential vulnerabilities exposed by quantum computing advancements. The argument extends to advocate for cost-effective script paths as viable until the arrival of the quantum era, colloquially referred to as "Q-day," highlighting a preference for options that allow for gradual transition without severe repercussions.

Further exposition reveals an appreciation for the revised approach over the initial 360 proposal, signaling a positive reception towards the new direction being taken in cryptographic strategy. This perspective suggests a forward-thinking stance, advocating for the development of scripting capabilities robust enough to efficiently implement post-quantum schemes directly within scripts. Although recognizing this ambition might stir controversy, it underscores a broader vision aiming at enhancing script flexibility and resilience in anticipation of quantum computational challenges.

This discourse reflects a nuanced understanding of the balance required between immediate cryptographic functionality and long-term security foresight. It encapsulates a consensus towards evolutionary, rather than revolutionary, steps in cryptography, ensuring readiness for quantum advancements while maintaining current operational integrity.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-01T18:58:43.687000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
