<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-10-08T02:22:58.768003+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-07T22:18:45.760000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T02:22:58.768038+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/eclipsing-bitcoin-nodes-with-bgp-interception-attacks/1965/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the exploration of network vulnerabilities, particularly focusing on fingerprinting attacks and the mapping of network topologies to identify potential security weaknesses. It mentions a recent post on delving into fingerprinting nodes through addr requests and cites several research papers that have contributed to the understanding of these issues, including studies from bitdevs and notable publications on arXiv and in scientific repositories like HAL and TU Wien's digital library.

Further discussion points to the significance of understanding these vulnerabilities for enhancing security measures against attackers who might exploit such information before moving on to more sophisticated AS-level attacks. The sender suggests that leveraging this knowledge could simplify attackers' efforts, highlighting the need for immediate actions to counter such tactics.

The conversation transitions into the potential for raising awareness among Bitcoin node operators and Lightning Network participants about these network-level threats. It references educational initiatives by Optech, such as the Schnorr/Taproot Workshops and various field reports, including the "Waiting for Confirmation" series, as examples of efforts to educate the community. The email underscores the idea of expanding these educational endeavors to include workshops or blog posts specifically tailored to teaching network operators about recognizing and mitigating vulnerabilities, with an emphasis on features like ASMap and the importance of ISP/hoster protective measures, such as the adoption of RPKI.

A particular focus is placed on the Lightning Network, motivated by a presentation at the Bitcoin++ Lightning conference discussing privacy and network-level attacks as outlined in the Revelio paper. This segment advocates for incorporating a module on Lightning Network operations into educational content, given the interconnectedness of Lightning operators and Bitcoin node runners.

To complement the educational materials, the proposal includes developing a tool or script for node administrators to assess their ISP’s performance regarding privacy and security enhancements. Additionally, the creation of a public website containing a dataset for node runners to check their or their ISP/hoster’s status is suggested as a valuable resource. The sender expresses intent to engage Optech for feedback and support on this project, indicating a collective interest in advancing the understanding and mitigation of network-level security threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T22:18:45.760000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
