<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-10-10T02:26:23.391229+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-10-09 06:43:07.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T02:26:23.391261+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricate mechanisms of transaction privacy within blockchain networks, specifically addressing concerns about the potential exposure of transactions deemed private by miners. The conversation suggests a modification to the traditional interaction between nodes and miners, aiming to enhance privacy without compromising the network's efficiency or integrity.

A proposed communication sequence between plebs (regular nodes) and miners outlines a secure method for requesting and receiving transaction templates without necessitating the transmission of sensitive transaction data. This sequence emphasizes the avoidance of the `GETDATA` command to prevent unauthorized access to valuable or private transactions. Instead, it introduces a streamlined process where a node requests a template (`GETTEMPLATE`) from a miner, receives a list of transaction identifiers (`TEMPLATE`), and subsequently requests missing transactions (`SENDBLOCKTXNS`), to which the miner responds with the required transactions (`BLOCKTXNS`). This methodology aims to safeguard secret transactions from premature or unwanted disclosure.

Furthermore, the concept of a bastion node is introduced as a robust solution for enhancing data privacy. This specialized node acts as an intermediary, managing the relay of transactions, templates, and blocks between nodes (referred to as "plebs" in the context) and miners. The unique feature of this setup is its capacity to filter out transactions from miners, thereby preventing the dissemination of sensitive information while still facilitating the necessary exchange of transaction templates and block data. The diagram depicting the interaction between plebs, bastion nodes, helpers, and miners illustrates a sophisticated relay mechanism designed to protect transaction privacy while ensuring the network remains functional and secure.

This dialogue underscores the importance of privacy in transaction relays and proposes innovative solutions to mitigate risks associated with early transaction relay and exposure. By redefining the communication protocols between network participants and introducing specialized nodes, the strategy aims to preserve the confidentiality of transactions deemed private by miners, without undermining the principles of transparency and security that underpin blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-09T06:43:07.676000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
