<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-12T02:28:04.793021+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-11T18:15:40.020000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-12T02:28:04.793061+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses an innovative system termed B-SSL, aimed at enhancing Bitcoin security and management. This system addresses a critical issue prevalent in non-custodial wallets: the potential loss of keys, which can lead to inaccessible funds. By proposing a solution that maintains user control while preventing key loss, the B-SSL system represents a significant advancement in the realm of cryptocurrency storage and transactions.

The B-SSL framework is composed of two main components, each serving distinct groups and purposes. The first component, mint-005, introduces a mechanism for joint custody coordination. This feature is particularly beneficial for institutions that manage shared funds, enabling multiple parties to securely and efficiently oversee their collective assets. The second component focuses on individual users and companies, offering a sovereign vault complemented by human fail-safes. This structure ensures that users retain complete control over their assets without the risk of losing access due to misplaced keys.

Overall, the B-SSL system embodies a breakthrough in securing digital currencies like Bitcoin, promising enhanced safety and usability for both institutional and individual stakeholders. Its dual approach caters to the diverse needs of the cryptocurrency community, potentially setting a new standard for wallet design and management.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-11T18:15:40.020000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
