<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v30.0 Released</title>
  <updated>2025-10-15T02:31:51.010663+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-14T07:59:08.825000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v30.0 Released</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T02:31:51.010693+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-0-released/2050/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email content provides a detailed breakdown of the disk usage by various components within a Bitcoin node's data directory, showing how storage is allocated across different functionalities. The command `du -h -d1 .bitcoin/` was executed to display the sizes of directories at one level deep within the `.bitcoin` directory, revealing the distribution of disk space among various subdirectories like `testnet4`, `indexes`, `signet`, `wallets`, `blocks`, `regtest`, and `chainstate`.

A significant portion of the disk space, amounting to 97.6GB, is consumed by the `blocks` directory, indicating that this folder, which stores the blockchain blocks, is the largest data consumer. Following closely, the `indexes` directory uses 11.6GB, suggesting it holds substantial data, possibly indexing information for the blockchain that aids in faster queries and transaction validation processes.

Other directories like `testnet4` and `signet` occupy 1.5GB and 3.4GB, respectively, highlighting their roles in providing environments for testing and development purposes outside the main network. The `wallets` directory, using only 43.1MB, shows minimal space usage, reflecting its role in storing user wallet data. The `chainstate` directory also takes up a notable 10.6GB, suggesting it contains important data pertaining to the current state of the blockchain, which is crucial for validating new transactions.

Additionally, a small amount of space is used by the `regtest` directory, at 18.6MB, indicating its use for local testing and blockchain experimentation where developers can control block creation.

In summary, the email illustrates the significant variation in disk space allocation among the different components of a Bitcoin node, with the bulk of storage dedicated to the `blocks` and `indexes` directories. This allocation underscores the importance of these components in the operation of a Bitcoin node, handling the storage of blockchain data and indexing for efficient access and operations within the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-14T07:59:08.825000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
