<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-10-15T02:28:25.603620+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-10-14 17:49:26.068000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T02:28:25.603659+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/42" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Compact Block Relay (CBR) is a technology designed to enhance the efficiency of block propagation within blockchain networks. The testing performed using Knots revealed several critical insights into how CBR can significantly improve network performance. This test focused on evaluating the effectiveness of CBR in reducing latency and bandwidth usage during the block propagation process.

The experiment's findings underscored CBR's potential to streamline the way blocks are relayed across the network, primarily by minimizing the amount of data that needs to be transmitted between nodes. By only sending information that a receiving node does not already possess, CBR effectively reduces the bandwidth required for block propagation. This approach not only accelerates the dissemination of new blocks but also alleviates congestion on the network, leading to a more scalable and efficient blockchain infrastructure.

For further details on the methodology and results of this compact block relay testing with Knots, interested readers can access the full report [here](https://uncensoredtech.substack.com/p/compact-block-relay-with-extra-pool). This document provides an in-depth analysis of the test setup, execution, and outcomes, offering valuable insights into how CBR could be implemented to optimize blockchain networks.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-14T17:49:26.068000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
