<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v29.2 Released</title>
  <updated>2025-10-15T02:33:01.918079+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow.532000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-14T18:53:00.532000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v29.2 Released</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T02:33:01.918113+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v29-2-released/2061" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release of Bitcoin Core, version 29.2, is now available for download. This update brings with it a variety of bug fixes and performance improvements alongside updated translations. Users are encouraged to report any bugs encountered using the GitHub issue tracker.

For those upgrading from an older version, it's recommended to first shut down the existing application. The shutdown process may take a few minutes in certain cases. Installation steps vary by operating system: Windows users should run the installer provided, macOS users can copy over `/Applications/Bitcoin-Qt`, and Linux users should replace `bitcoind`/`bitcoin-qt` files accordingly. Upgrades from a version of Bitcoin Core that has reached its end-of-life (EOL) status are supported, though users may experience delays if the data directory requires migration. Compatibility of wallet versions from previous releases of Bitcoin Core is maintained.

Bitcoin Core version 29.2 supports operating systems that include Linux Kernel 3.17 and above, macOS 13 and higher, as well as Windows 10 and newer. While Bitcoin Core may operate on other Unix-like systems, these environments undergo less frequent testing and therefore are not officially recommended.

This release introduces several notable changes across various components of Bitcoin Core. In the peer-to-peer network layer, enhancements include the addition of a witness mutation check in the FillBlock function, along with updates ensuring proper header checks before calling FillBlock and adjustments to whitelist permissions for onion inbounds. Within the mempool component, enforcement of TRUC checks on reorganizations has been removed. The Remote Procedure Call (RPC) system sees a fix in the getblock(header) function, which now correctly returns the target for the tip. Continuous Integration (CI) processes have been migrated to hosted Cirrus Runners, with updates enabling more flexible use of libc++ instrumentation and the adoption of LLVM 21. Documentation improvements fix a case typo in the help section for `finalizepsbt`. Miscellaneous updates address a GCC compiling issue related to old systemtap versions, fix benchmark CSV output inconsistencies, and improve macOS deployment without translations.

Contributors to this release include both individuals and those assisting with translations, highlighting the community-driven effort behind Bitcoin Core's development. Notable contributors to version 29.2 include Amisha Chhajed, Eugene Siegel, fanquake, Greg Sanders, Hennadii Stepanov, Luke Dashjr, MarcoFalke, Martin Zumsande, Sebastian Falbesoner, Sjors Provoost, Vasil Dimov, and Will Clark, among others who have played vital roles in enhancing the software.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-14T18:53:00.532000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
