<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: Pluggable Filter Framework</title>
  <updated>2025-10-16T02:29:30.485934+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-15T04:48:45.393000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: Pluggable Filter Framework</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T02:29:30.485965+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-pluggable-filter-framework/2064/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin development, significant strides have been made as evident in two key resources. The first is a discussion hosted on a Google Groups forum dedicated to Bitcoin development, where a wide array of topics pertinent to the evolution and challenges of Bitcoin's technology are explored. This forum serves as a vital platform for developers, enthusiasts, and experts to exchange ideas, propose solutions, and deliberate on the future directions of Bitcoin. The link to this discussion can be accessed [here](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/o3JZhiOa2PQ/m/Pvg6ZQvSAQAJ).

The second resource is a detailed proposal found on GitHub, related to the Bitcoin Knots project. It outlines proposed changes to the software, aiming to address specific issues while also introducing enhancements that could significantly impact Bitcoin's functionality and reliability. The proposal includes comprehensive technical details, rationales for each change, and discussions on potential implications. For those interested in the technicalities of these proposed changes, the pull request can be viewed [here](https://github.com/bitcoinknots/bitcoin/pull/119).

These two resources collectively embody the ongoing efforts within the Bitcoin development community to refine and evolve the cryptocurrency's underlying technology. They highlight the collaborative nature of open-source projects where contributions from various individuals help shape the future of digital currencies. Through such discussions and proposals, the community aims to ensure that Bitcoin remains secure, efficient, and adaptable to meet the growing demands of its users.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-15T04:48:45.393000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
