<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: Pluggable Filter Framework</title>
  <updated>2025-10-16T02:29:56.713290+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-15T14:38:22.954000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: Pluggable Filter Framework</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T02:29:56.713321+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-pluggable-filter-framework/2064/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the mempool's purpose in modeling what will be mined in the context of Bitcoin, challenging the notion with specific policies implemented in Bitcoin Core. One such policy is the `dustrelayfee`, which defines the minimum fee rate for a transaction to not be considered dust. This concept is crucial as changing the dust limit affects which transactions are standard and impacts the network's operation. The policy implies that adjustments to the dust limit should be made cautiously and ideally be infrequent, suggesting an approach where increases in the dust limit follow periods where outputs below the new threshold were not being created.

The dialogue includes references to various transactions within the Bitcoin network, providing concrete examples of how these policies manifest in real-world scenarios. These transactions, identifiable by their unique hashes, illustrate diverse outcomes and behaviors in the mempool and can serve as case studies for understanding the implications of network policies on transaction processing and prioritization.

Including links to the source code and specific transactions on [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/40e7d4cd0d7f1d922b92b0c640d3d89eef059411/src/policy/policy.hL64) and [mempool.space](https://mempool.space), respectively, enriches the discussion by offering direct access to the technical definitions and real-time data. These resources support a deeper dive into the mechanics of Bitcoin’s transaction handling and provide a foundation for further analysis or critique of the current policies influencing what constitutes a viable or 'non-dust' transaction on the network.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-15T14:38:22.954000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
