<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:25.917160+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ftw2100</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-17T14:38:17.246000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:25.917197+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of integrating native Zero-Knowledge (ZK) verification into Bitcoin presents a novel approach, yet an alternative method suggests implementing this functionality via a metaprotocol layered over Bitcoin. This strategy avoids direct modifications to the Bitcoin base protocol, circumventing the need for a new opcode by utilizing existing witness space for embedding STARK proofs. Open-source indexers would play a crucial role in parsing this blockchain data, verifying the proofs, and managing the system's state off-chain.

This metaprotocol approach brings several advantages to the forefront. Firstly, it significantly reduces risk by preventing complex cryptographic primitives from being added directly to the consensus-critical base layer, hence avoiding potential implementation bugs or unanticipated economic incentives. Secondly, it fosters market-driven adoption by allowing the concept to be tested in a real-world environment. This enables the measurement of actual market demand and allows a social consensus to organically form around a specific STARK implementation without necessitating a contentious soft fork. Thirdly, the flexibility of this model permits various proof systems to compete and evolve. Should a superior technology surface, the ecosystem can adapt seamlessly without being constrained to a single protocol.

If the metaprotocol for STARK verification gains considerable traction and demonstrates its utility and safety, it would provide a robust, data-driven foundation for potentially integrating it natively into Bitcoin Script in the future. For those interested in further exploring the potential of building on Bitcoin without altering the script, the document available at [wtf.rich/w.pdf](wtf.rich/w.pdf) offers valuable insights into what can be achieved under the current protocol rules.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T14:38:17.246000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
