<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Peer-observer: A tool and infrastructure for monitoring the Bitcoin P2P network for attacks and anomalies</title>
  <updated>2025-10-18T02:21:58.504145+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-10-17 16:22:08.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Peer-observer: A tool and infrastructure for monitoring the Bitcoin P2P network for attacks and anomalies</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T02:21:58.504177+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/peer-observer-a-tool-and-infrastructure-for-monitoring-the-bitcoin-p2p-network-for-attacks-and-anomalies/1988/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A demo instance of the peer-observer has been successfully set up and is now available for public access at [demo.peer.observer](https://demo.peer.observer). This instance features two nodes, named `hal` and `len`, offering users the opportunity to explore its functionalities. The deployment of this instance was made possible through the sponsorship of server resources by [https://lclhost.org/](https://lclhost.org/), highlighting a collaborative effort in supporting the development and dissemination of such projects.

For those interested in the technical specifics or considering setting up their infrastructure, the NixOS infrastructure definition for this demo can be found on GitHub. The repository located at [https://github.com/0xB10C/peer-observer-infra-demo](https://github.com/0xB10C/peer-observer-infra-demo) provides all necessary details. Additionally, this project utilizes the peer-observer-infra-library, further details of which can also be explored on GitHub at [https://github.com/0xB10C/peer-observer-infra-library](https://github.com/0xB10C/peer-observer-infra-library). This information is crucial for developers or IT professionals interested in understanding the underlying technology or potentially replicating the setup for their purposes.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T16:22:08.698000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
