<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-18T02:22:49.321204+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan.408000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-17T18:40:47.408000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T02:22:49.321243+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse introduces a significant advancement in the realm of digital asset custody, emphasizing a novel solution to a longstanding problem: the fear of losing access keys. The innovation presented is a trustless key recovery system, aiming to bridge the gap between non-custodial and custodial services. This system, referred to as B-SSL, eradicates the primary concern associated with self-custody of digital assets—the potential loss of keys—by ensuring that while users maintain full control over their assets, there exists a secure method for key recovery that does not compromise the security or privacy of the user's assets.

B-SSL is positioned as a transformative development that could democratize the use of self-custody solutions by eliminating the risk of fund loss due to misplaced keys. The creator of this system believes it to be a pivotal breakthrough, potentially making self-custody accessible and appealing to a broader audience. According to them, a significant portion of the population (suggested to be around 80%) avoids self-custody solutions due to the fear of key loss. By addressing this issue head-on, B-SSL paves the way for widespread adoption of non-custodial solutions, shifting the role of custodians to merely holding the keys without any ability to access the funds themselves.

This innovation is celebrated as a result of one year of dedicated work, marking a notable achievement in enhancing user freedom and security in the digital domain. The developer expresses a deep sense of fulfillment and optimism regarding the impact of their work, suggesting that B-SSL could fundamentally alter how individuals interact with digital assets, providing a safer and more user-friendly approach to self-custody.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T18:40:47.408000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
