<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:00.085360+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>scoresby</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-17T19:01:58.254000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:00.085392+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the inquiry about the primary spending path for a digital wallet, the questioner seeks to understand how the process functions when a user wishes to spend coins. The mechanism described requires two signatures for a transaction to proceed: one from the user (key A) and another from a secondary party (C). This dual-signature requirement is pivotal for authorizing transactions.

The query further explores the role of the CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) timelock in this transaction process. Specifically, the person is trying to grasp how a timelock set to expire after one day influences transaction authorization. According to the described scenario, once the timelock expires—assuming the coins have been in the wallet for more than a day—both key A and C can sign off on the transaction without any delay. This detail prompts a deeper question regarding the purpose and effectiveness of the timelock, especially in terms of security and transaction management.

There appears to be some confusion or perhaps a mismatch between the expected functionality of the wallet and the described implementation. Typically, one might anticipate that storing coins in a wallet allows them to be kept for an unspecified duration with enforced delays on spending, possibly through transactions to intermediary addresses for added security. However, the enquirer suggests the current setup may not achieve this intended effect of securing stored coins against immediate withdrawal, seeking clarification on whether there's a misunderstanding of the system's design or if the design itself does not align with standard vault-like protections for cryptocurrency wallets.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T19:01:58.254000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
