<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-19T02:48:39.113161+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-18T06:45:22.323000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T02:48:39.113198+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of enforcing a time delay in transactions introduces a significant layer of security and operational integrity within certain systems. This process is facilitated through the use of a Convenience Service, which incorporates signer C as a critical component. The primary function of this service is to initiate a countdown for a specified time delay once it receives a spending transaction. This mechanism ensures that the transaction remains pending until the predefined time period elapses. 

Significantly, this approach diverges from more traditional methods such as CheckSequenceVerify (CSV), which commences its countdown immediately upon the transaction's acceptance into the network. In contrast, the Convenience Service operates off-chain, establishing a secure environment dedicated solely to cosigning activities. Within this environment, signer C plays a pivotal role by withholding its cosignature until the stipulated time delay concludes.

This innovative method offers an enhanced level of security by ensuring that transactions are not prematurely executed, thus allowing for additional verification or cancellation if necessary. By integrating such a system, entities can safeguard against unauthorized or hasty transactions, contributing to the overall reliability and trustworthiness of the operational framework.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T06:45:22.323000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
