<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-19T02:49:00.116958+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan 2025-10-18 18:20:02.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T02:49:00.116990+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The primary concern addressed involves preventing collusion between two custodians within a system that, if not viewed holistically, may prove challenging to fully comprehend. This highlights the importance of evaluating the system in its entirety rather than in isolated segments to ensure a thorough understanding and assessment of potential vulnerabilities, including those that might arise from custodian collusion.

Furthermore, there is an invitation to participate in the Bitcoin Optech audio recap discussion scheduled for next Tuesday. This opportunity could serve as a platform for deeper engagement with the subject matter and facilitate a more comprehensive analysis by allowing participants to share insights, ask questions, and collaborate on solutions to the identified problem of custodian collusion. The discussion aims to enrich participants' understanding and potentially contribute valuable perspectives on safeguarding the system against such collusion.

For those interested in joining the conversation or seeking further information on the topic, the Bitcoin Optech community provides resources and forums for discussion, which can be accessed through their official [website](https://bitcoinops.org). Engaging with these materials and the community might offer additional context and strategies for addressing the challenges posed by custodian collusion, thereby enhancing the security and integrity of the system in question.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T18:20:02.145000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
