<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
  <updated>2025-10-21T02:41:00.682900+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jal.800000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-20T03:19:18.800000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T02:41:00.682932+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-spam-problem-of-bitcoin-and-unpermissioned-broadcast-networks-in-general/1692/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse delves into the subjective nature of spam, highlighting that opinions on what constitutes spam vary significantly among individuals. This variance in perception is crucial, especially when considering the foundational principles of Bitcoin, which operates fundamentally as a consensus mechanism. The assertion that there's a universal agreement on the definition of spam is contested, underscoring the diversity of viewpoints and the potential for disagreement within communities engaged in discussions about spam. Moreover, the mention of Roger Ver's sybil attack on the protocol serves to illustrate the complexities and challenges inherent in managing consensus in decentralized systems.

Furthermore, the text makes a clear distinction regarding the categorization of topics within forums or discussion platforms, specifically pointing out that certain discussions do not align with the economics section. This suggests an underlying issue with how content is classified and the importance of appropriate categorization to foster relevant and constructive discourse. The emphasis on consensus and the diverse perceptions of spam underscore the broader challenges faced by decentralized systems in achieving unified agreement while accommodating differing views and opinions.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T03:19:18.800000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
