<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Nashian Orientation of Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2025-10-21T02:43:04.410612+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jal</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-20T03:34:32.965000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Nashian Orientation of Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T02:43:04.410646+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-nashian-orientation-of-bitcoin/2070" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration into the Nashian Orientation of Bitcoin presents a comprehensive examination divided into two distinct pathways: an initial set of six essays that provide a foundational understanding and a more elaborate series of fifteen essays that delve deeper into complex concepts using what is termed as "Szabonian Deconstruction." 

The first sextet introduces the concept of Ideal Money, highlighting its potential to elevate a global standard for monetary comparison free from political influence. By leveraging Nick Szabo’s interpretation of Adam Smith, these essays underscore the efficiency gains achievable through such a global standard. They address misconceptions surrounding the International Currency Price Index (ICPI) and argue against critics like Adam Back and Saifedean Ammous. The ICPI is presented not just as a theoretical construct but as a practical pathway towards achieving Ideal Money. This section also credits Hal Finney's contributions to the development of Bitcoin and digital banking, challenging the assumption that the lightning network negates the potential for bitcoin-backed banks. Through an analysis of bitcoin’s inherent limitations and potential roles in central banking and global economy, it sets the stage for understanding how digital currencies can complement existing financial systems. Nick Szabo’s theory of ‘collectibles’ and their 'unforgeable costliness' is extended to illustrate how Bitcoin could serve as a quality comparator for major currencies, culminating in an argument that Satoshi’s implementation of Bitgold aligns with Nash’s vision of Ideal Money.

The subsequent collection of fifteen essays employs "Szabonian Deconstruction" to navigate the nuanced interplay between social constructs and subjective truths in the realm of cryptocurrency and economic theory. These writings tackle various subjects including the contradictions of the Mises Regression Theorem with Bitcoin, critiques of Saifedean Ammous' Bitcoin Standard, and the application of game theory to pre-market commodity valuations. The deconstruction continues with discussions on money, Gresham's Law, the Cantillon Effect, and the implications of a Sybil attack on Bitcoin. The Satoshi Complex is explored as a phenomenon influencing the Bitcoin community’s dynamics. Further analysis extends to Hayek’s denationalization of money, offering new tools and metaphors for understanding his proposals in the context of Bitcoin. The essays also propose a framework for the Szabonian deconstruction of religions and thought systems, aiming to provide a structured approach to interpret complex historical and economic narratives. It concludes with a synthesis of ideas from Hayek, Nash, and Szabo to optimize global legacy currency systems and re-envision central banking within a Hayekian landscape.

Each piece contributes to a larger discourse on the evolution of digital currency, emphasizing the philosophical and technical underpinnings necessary for advancing towards an optimized global monetary system. The works collectively argue for a reconsideration of conventional economic theories and banking practices in light of the potential offered by Bitcoin and blockchain technology. Available online, these essays are accessible for both reading and listening, with audio versions shared via platforms like X and YouTube, providing a multimedia approach to engaging with these complex topics.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T03:34:32.965000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
