<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Nashian Orientation of Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2025-10-21T02:43:14.981202+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jal 2025-10-20 03:39:44.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Nashian Orientation of Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2025-10-21T02:43:14.981234+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-nashian-orientation-of-bitcoin/2070/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of Bitcoin's history and its impact on the global financial system is a subject of significant interest and debate. The origins of Bitcoin, as discussed in the series reviewed by Kyle Torpey, reveal a complex interplay between various foundational concepts and proposals. Notably, the mathematical equivalence drawn between Nick Szabo’s reconfiguration of his earlier bitgold concept, John Nash’s proposition for an International Commodity Price Index (ICPI) based global economy, and Satoshi Nakamoto’s implementation of Szabo’s bitgold into what we now know as Bitcoin, offers profound insights into the digital currency's design and its intended role within the global economy.

This connection underscores the intellectual lineage and evolution of ideas that underpin Bitcoin and highlights its potential to influence central banking systems. The notion that Bitcoin could serve as a foundation for bitcoin-backed central banks emerges as a particularly relevant discussion, especially in the context of current debates around spam transactions and the transactional throughput limitation imposed by Satoshi in Bitcoin's source code. This limitation, while technical, opens up broader conversations about the scalability, governance, and future development paths of Bitcoin.

Such discussions are crucial for understanding how Bitcoin fits into the larger narrative of monetary evolution and the challenges it faces in scaling to meet global financial needs. The series titled "The Theory of Bitcoin Backed Central Banks" not only delves into these technical and philosophical questions but also positions Bitcoin at the forefront of a potential paradigm shift in how national and international financial systems operate. By examining the interconnectedness of these ideas, the series contributes valuable perspectives on Bitcoin's ability to shape and be shaped by the evolving landscape of global finance.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T03:39:44.832000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
