<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-26T02:43:52.939652+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bicaru20</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-25T22:40:46.810000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-26T02:43:52.939691+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The core issue addressed revolves around the safeguarding of digital assets in the event of key loss, specifically focusing on the mechanisms for fund recovery without permanent loss. The concern raised pertains to the effectiveness and trustworthiness of the proposed recovery paths when a user loses their primary key, referred to as Key A. The recovery process, particularly through Path 3, necessitates a significant delay, possibly extending up to three years. This duration raises questions about the reliance on custodians, who are entrusted with shares like B1 and C, to facilitate the recovery.

Furthermore, there is a sense of ambiguity regarding the utility of Paths 1 and 2 for users who have not lost Key A. If the primary key remains in the user's possession, granting them full control over their private key, the rationale behind opting for these alternative recovery paths becomes unclear. This point highlights a potential gap in the recovery strategy, suggesting that the current framework might not fully cater to the diverse scenarios of key loss or mismanagement by providing a clear, efficient, and trustworthy method of fund recovery.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T22:40:46.810000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
