<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-27T02:51:32.652010+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan.361000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-26T11:32:35.361000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T02:51:32.652046+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The B-SSL protocol introduces an innovative approach to Bitcoin security, aiming to mitigate the catastrophic impact of total key loss while ensuring the user's sovereignty and on-chain verifiability. This is achieved through a series of timed Taproot spending paths that allow for various contingencies without relying on trusted intermediaries, all underpinned by Bitcoin's consensus rules.

The architecture of B-SSL employs three distinct paths to safeguard users' assets. The first path allows for everyday spending with a configurable delay ranging from 2 hours to 15 days, providing a buffer against unauthorized access due to hacks, coercion, or impulsive decisions. The second path is designed for annual self-rotation of keys, wherein a transaction is pre-signed for one year and must be renewed yearly, effectively resetting the vault's long-term delays and ensuring its ongoing viability. The third path serves as a disaster recovery or inheritance mechanism, activating only if the user has been inactive for three years, with strict conditions preventing custodians from prematurely accessing the funds.

To further enhance security, B-SSL facilitates the creation of chained vaults, where each successive vault inherits the assets of the previous one upon expiry. This setup ensures continuous protection and significantly lowers the risk of irreversible loss. If the user disappears and cannot initiate the transition to the next vault, only two outcomes are possible: legal intervention or a cryptographic deadman-switch recovery path. In either scenario, malicious custodians are prevented from misappropriating the funds due to the inherent design of the system, which either freezes the funds or directs them into a new B-SSL vault under predetermined conditions.

The security model of B-SSL ensures that users maintain full control over their assets as long as they possess certain key combinations. The loss of all keys does not equate to the loss of funds, thanks to the disaster recovery path. Custodians are disincentivized from acting against the user's interest, as their ability to access the funds is severely limited to actions that would only freeze the assets, thereby harming their reputation and business prospects without any financial gain.

In summary, B-SSL revolutionizes the way Bitcoin security is approached by making key loss a non-fatal event, introducing delay-based protections for transactions, and minimizing trust in recovery scenarios. This system ensures that users can regain control of their assets legally or via an automated process after two years, rendering the notion of handing over fund control to custodians obsolete and unnecessary. This framework not only enhances security but also preserves user autonomy and the integrity of the assets on the blockchain.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-26T11:32:35.361000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
