<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-27T02:51:40.071666+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ilghan</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-26T11:57:22.392000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T02:51:40.071696+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of B-SSL (Blockchain-Secured Sovereignty Ledger) introduces a revolutionary approach to digital asset management, ensuring users maintain absolute sovereignty over their assets throughout their lifetime. This innovative system also incorporates mechanisms for controlled recoverability in situations such as death or loss, safeguarding the user's assets and facilitating their transfer under predefined conditions. In the event of adverse scenarios, the worst outcome is the freezing of assets. This state is considered neutral and primarily affects the custodian's reputation rather than leading to direct loss of the user's assets. Importantly, this frozen state does not impose a time limit on the user, granting them unlimited time to pursue legal actions to reclaim access or control over their assets. This structure not only emphasizes the importance of individual control and security in digital asset management but also introduces a fail-safe mechanism that protects against unauthorized access while ensuring recoverability under specific circumstances.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-26T11:57:22.392000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
