<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:23.546655+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>REDBaron 2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:23.546687+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing debate within the Bitcoin community, often referred to as the Core vs. Knots discussion around censorship, highlights a deeper issue threatening the fundamental principles of Bitcoin: censorship-resistance, decentralization, and fungibility. This challenge is not merely a philosophical one but a critical juncture that could lead to Bitcoin rendering itself obsolete if left unaddressed. The shift in focus from Bitcoin’s original intent as "Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash" towards becoming a "Settlement Layer for Banks" underlines a deviation from its foundational Shelling Point, pushing the narrative towards regulatory compliance and centralization, which contradicts the essence of what Bitcoin was intended to be.

Hal Finney, one of the early contributors to Bitcoin, emphasized the intrinsic link between privacy and fungibility, noting that the lack of robust, cryptographic privacy measures within Bitcoin's protocol compromises its function as a neutral, global currency. The current state of Bitcoin, where transactions are public and traceable, has led to the classification of coins as "clean" or "dirty," undermining the principle of fungibility. This situation is exacerbated by the development priorities of the Bitcoin Core leadership, which have sidelined privacy and scalability, favoring solutions like CoinJoin and Lightning Network that do not address these foundational issues at the base layer.

The argument further advances by introducing game theory’s concept of Tit-for-Tat as a strategy for survival, suggesting that a robust mechanism against censorship could be the integration of Mimblewimble through atomic swaps and sidechains. Such an approach would not only safeguard against transaction censorship but also reinforce Bitcoin’s core values by enabling seamless and trustless value transfer, thus making any attempt at censorship economically futile.

The criticism extends to the Bitcoin Core development philosophy, which is seen as myopic due to its neglect of privacy and scalability. This stance has resulted in the endorsement of intermediate solutions like CoinJoin and the Lightning Network, which despite their intentions, fall short of addressing the underlying problems of fungibility and decentralization. Interestingly, the blog notes the support from entities like the World Economic Forum for Lightning Labs, raising questions about the influence of external factors on the development trajectory of Bitcoin.

In conclusion, the post posits a stark choice for the future of Bitcoin: continue on the current path towards centralization and regulatory capture, or adopt privacy-enhancing technologies such as Mimblewimble. It argues that without a shift towards incorporating robust privacy features, Bitcoin risks devolving into a system dominated by "tainted" and "untainted" coins, centralized control, and a departure from its vision as peer-to-peer electronic cash. The call to action is clear — for Bitcoin to thrive, it must return to its roots, heed the warnings of its early visionaries, and embrace the technological solutions available to secure its foundational principles. The inclusion of links to resources on Mimblewimble provides readers with a pathway to explore this proposed solution further. [Explore Grin and Mimblewimble](https://docs.grin.mw/wiki/introduction/grin-for-bitcoiners/) and engage with the ongoing discussion on [Bitcoin's GitHub page](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/33713).</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T12:04:16.225000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
