<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:40.539189+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-27T16:05:57.221000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:40.539220+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse surrounding CoinJoin reveals a complex landscape of privacy, trust, and coordination within the Bitcoin community. CoinJoin, a method designed to enhance transaction privacy by combining multiple payments from several users into a single transaction, thus obfuscating the source of funds, faces significant challenges. These include vulnerability to de-anonymization through advanced chain analysis techniques, especially as government AI and computing resources become increasingly sophisticated. However, solutions such as JoinMarket and JoinStr are noted for their ability to mitigate some of these challenges by eliminating the need for trust among participants and reducing the necessity for coordination.

The conversation also touches upon the development and potential application of covenants in Bitcoin transactions. Covenants represent a technical proposal aimed at adding more flexibility and control over the conditions under which bitcoins can be spent, which could further reduce the need for coordination among users of privacy-enhancing technologies like CoinJoin.

Moreover, the discussion highlights a broader debate within the Bitcoin ecosystem, often characterized as Core vs. Knots, focusing on issues of censorship and governance. This debate is not merely about technical choices but signals deeper ideological divides within the community. It's emphasized that this controversy is not unique to Bitcoin but has been observed in other blockchain projects as well. The mention of OP_RETURN, a type of Bitcoin transaction that allows for a small amount of data to be attached, underscores the multifaceted nature of the privacy discussion, indicating that concerns over privacy extend beyond simple transactional anonymity.

The discourse is further enriched by references to ongoing developments in the Monero project, as indicated by links to pull requests and issues on GitHub ([Monero Pull Request #8733](https://github.com/monero-project/monero/pull/8733), [Monero Issue #6668](https://github.com/monero-project/monero/issues/6668)). These references serve to illustrate the continuous efforts within cryptocurrency communities to address privacy, security, and governance issues, highlighting both the challenges and progress in the field.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T16:05:57.221000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
