<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:40:50.243012+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>nymius.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-27T20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:40:50.243047+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the intricacies of encoding for silent payment descriptors, as detailed in a transcript from the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024 conference. The transcript, available at [Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024: Silent Payment Descriptors](https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/silent-payment-descriptors), provides insights into the current methodologies and proposes enhancements to the existing framework. One key area of enhancement is the need for a format that encompasses “self-contained” spending material for individual outputs. This proposal suggests combining `tweak` with `b_spend`, where `tweak` itself is derived from a combination of `label`, `b_scan`, and a shared secret. Alternatively, a composition of `b_scan`, `b_m`, and a shared secret could serve a similar purpose. 

Additionally, there's consideration for encoding a range or limit directly onto the string for applicable labels, which could improve the flexibility and functionality of the system. This notion addresses potential limitations within the current setup, where `b_scan` and `b_spend` keys, by themselves, do not suffice for spending outputs without the tweak material from the originating transaction. The proposed enhancements aim to streamline the process and make it more efficient by allowing for a self-contained methodology that could potentially simplify transactions while enhancing security and privacy aspects inherent to cryptocurrency dealings.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T20:20:28.705000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
