<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:51.490613+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>REDBaron.609000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-27T19:00:40.609000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:51.490645+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing debate around data-storage mechanisms, specifically the `OP_RETURN` opcode in Bitcoin, is closely intertwined with concerns regarding the currency's fungibility—an essential property for any form of money. Fungibility implies that each unit of currency is indistinguishable from another, maintaining its equal value. The primary issue arises when spam transactions, or any form of unnecessary data, are permanently recorded on the blockchain. Such instances lead to the tagging of particular Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) by chain analysis tools, effectively marking them and potentially diminishing their value due to their association with spam or undesirable content. This permanent tagging is detrimental as it directly impacts Bitcoin's fungibility by distinguishing certain coins from others based on their transaction history.

In contrast, the Grin blockchain, which utilizes the Mimblewimble protocol, presents a solution to this problem through its inherent design. By eliminating addresses and transaction amounts from the ledger, Grin inherently prevents the attachment of metadata, including unwanted content or spam, to its units of currency. This approach not only addresses the bloat issue associated with storing non-transactional data on the blockchain but also safeguards the peer-to-peer utility of the currency by ensuring that all units remain equivalent and untraceable to their transaction history. Consequently, the Grin blockchain maintains the pristine condition of its currency units, upholding fungibility without the need for external intervention or complex solutions to remove or disassociate metadata from specific coins.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T19:00:40.609000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
