<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-29T02:48:26.552066+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>REDBaron 2025-10-28 18:07:55.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T02:48:26.552098+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the evolving landscape of blockchain technology, a significant distinction exists between traditional blockchains like those of Bitcoin and Monero and newer designs like Mimblewimble. The latter has introduced an innovative approach to handling data, particularly with its ability to erase metadata and history, ensuring a compact and efficient blockchain structure. This design philosophy starkly contrasts with conventional blockchains where data, once entered, is stored indefinitely. This permanent record-keeping has led to concerns over blockchain "bloat" where non-financial data occupies a substantial portion of the network, with estimates suggesting nearly 40% of Bitcoin's blockchain is comprised of such data.

One of the noteworthy features of the Grin blockchain, which utilizes Mimblewimble, is its resistance to data spam. Unlike Bitcoin, there are no mechanisms within Grin's protocol, such as `OP_RETURN`, that allow for the embedding of arbitrary data like JPEGs. This inherently prevents the misuse of the network for storing unrelated and potentially bloating information. Furthermore, the Grin blockchain's architecture allows it to remain exceptionally small and manageable, thanks to its continuous process of discarding unnecessary intermediate data. This efficiency not only makes running nodes less resource-intensive but also addresses scalability in a more sustainable manner.

The debate over the purpose and functionality of blockchain networks extends into the realms of regulation and governance. There's a growing tension between the desire for open, unregulated value networks advocated by many in the crypto community, and the push by banks, governments, and regulatory bodies for networks that are easily auditable, controllable, and compliant with regulations like know-your-customer (KYC). This clash of ideologies hints at an impending shift towards on-chain KYC practices, especially for networks like Bitcoin, which traditionally have been viewed primarily as vehicles for value transfer. The prospect of integrating KYC directly onto the blockchain signals a potential departure from the decentralized ethos many cryptocurrencies were built upon, as highlighted in discussions surrounding Bitcoin's `OP_RETURN` functionality and the controversies it has spurred, including proposals for network forks aimed at addressing these challenges as detailed in a report found [here](https://protos.com/bitcoins-op_return-war-just-went-nuclear-a-chain-fork-proposal/).</summary>
    <published>2025-10-28T18:07:55.377000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
