<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-31T02:44:13.017608+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>REDBaron.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-30T10:02:53.379000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T02:44:13.017637+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the inherent characteristics and future developments of Bitcoin, focusing on its base layer's transparency and traceability. Despite the ability to embed data like JPEGs, CSAM, or Know Your Customer (KYC) information on the blockchain, Bitcoin maintains its transparent nature due to the storage of addresses and transaction amounts on the blockchain. This aspect is crucial for optional privacy but also highlights a development direction that could be profit-oriented, specifically pointing towards Blockstream's strategies.

The involvement of major entities from France, the USA, Germany, as well as financial institutions like BlackRock and notable figures such as Michael Saylor, who have integrated Bitcoin into their strategic reserves, brings to light the necessity for these central banks and institutions to engage with Bitcoin in a legal manner. This includes legal transactions, accounting principles, and potentially introduces the concept of on-chain KYC within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The speculation about on-chain KYC gaining traction in Bitcoin is underscored by the mention of developments in both Bitcoin knots and coreV30, indicating no distinction in this approach across different versions or implementations of Bitcoin. This suggests a shift towards ensuring regulatory compliance and legal operability for institutional participants within the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T10:02:53.379000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
