<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-31T02:44:43.494629+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>REDBaron.787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-30T15:54:59.787000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T02:44:43.494655+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses concerns and skepticism toward the implementation of complex cryptographic solutions on Bitcoin, comparing these efforts to those of Ethereum's approach. It highlights a general apprehension regarding the addition of intricate layers to Bitcoin, questioning their security and potential for introducing numerous vulnerabilities and attack vectors. Specifically, it references an unnamed company's proposal, which appears to rely heavily on advanced cryptographic methods, suggesting that these ideas are still largely theoretical and primarily supported by venture capital funding, drawing a parallel to the ongoing development of the Lightning Network.

Furthermore, the email contrasts these cryptographic endeavors with MimbleWimble, praising its simplicity, elegance, and mathematical foundation. It implies that MimbleWimble offers a more secure and straightforward approach to enhancing privacy on blockchains compared to the criticized complex solutions. The author argues that true privacy on Bitcoin cannot be achieved through the addition of additional layers, hinting at a fundamental conflict between embedding data on the blockchain and maintaining user privacy, which could potentially lead to legal issues.

The sender expresses a cynical view towards the motivations behind venture capital-funded cryptographic projects, suggesting that despite claims of aiming to improve Bitcoin, there might be underlying motives aligned with government interests or the preservation of status quo within the crypto-community. This perspective presents a critical stance on the direction of Bitcoin’s development, especially regarding privacy and the implementation of new technologies funded by external capital.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T15:54:59.787000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
