<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Miniscript Studio - a fulll IDE based on Rust Miniscript</title>
  <updated>2025-10-31T02:45:17.854493+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>adys</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-31T00:31:15.736000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Miniscript Studio - a fulll IDE based on Rust Miniscript</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T02:45:17.854520+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/miniscript-studio-a-fulll-ide-based-on-rust-miniscript/2086" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Miniscript Studio is an innovative online Integrated Development Environment (IDE) designed to enhance the learning and development experience with Miniscript, a scripting language for Bitcoin. Originating from a project aimed at improving error handling in Miniscript expressions during the BTC++ hackathon, it evolved into a comprehensive platform incorporating a range of features that cater to both novice and experienced developers. Among these features are specialized editors for policies and Miniscripts that support indenting, clearing, syntax highlighting, and more, facilitating a smoother coding experience.

One of the remarkable aspects of Miniscript Studio is its versatility in handling different contexts and preferences. It includes a script area that displays resulting scripts and addresses for various Bitcoin contexts such as Legacy, SegWit, and Taproot, along with support for both testnet and mainnet environments. This feature is complemented by the ability to auto-generate key variables from hexadecimal values or map them to custom names, enhancing the flexibility and user-friendliness of the tool.

Furthermore, Miniscript Studio offers advanced features like HD Wallet Descriptors, supporting xpubs/tpubs and range descriptors, and Lift Functionality, which allows users to convert raw Scripts to Miniscript and vice versa. The inclusion of Taproot support adds another layer of modernity, accommodating x-only keys, multi-branch policies, and script/key paths. A unique addition is the spending cost analysis feature, which helps users evaluate the worst-case spending costs associated with their scripts.

To aid in debugging and optimization, Miniscript Studio provides a compile debug info display. It is also packed with examples and detailed descriptions to guide users through complex processes, making it a valuable resource for learning and experimentation. The IDE is customizable through a settings section, and users can save, load, and share their expressions, further promoting collaboration and sharing within the community. For more information on the capabilities and offerings of Miniscript Studio, interested individuals can refer to the detailed blog post available at [https://adys.dev/blog/miniscript-studio-intro](https://adys.dev/blog/miniscript-studio-intro).</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:31:15.736000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
