<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Public archive for Delving Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2025-11-01T02:44:38.823153+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-10-31 11:52:01.711000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Public archive for Delving Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T02:44:38.823191+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/public-archive-for-delving-bitcoin/87/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of updates and changes to the Bitcoin archive, a significant review was conducted to assess the differences between the current state of the [delving-bitcoin-archive](https://github.com/jamesob/delving-bitcoin-archive) and a new archival snapshot. This examination, detailed through a pull request opened on GitHub, aimed to identify not only the predictable variations such as the fluctuation in the number of likes or the addition of JSON fields exclusive to newer versions of the discourse but also to uncover content that had not been previously archived.

The investigation into the archive's comprehensiveness revealed an unexpected finding: several posts and topics were identified as missing from the initial archival process. This discovery underscores the dynamic nature of digital archives and highlights the challenges in maintaining an up-to-date and complete record of online discussions and contributions, particularly within fast-evolving communities such as those surrounding Bitcoin. The initiative to compare the existing archive with a fresh archival version serves as a critical step in ensuring that historical records are as thorough and accurate as possible, providing a valuable resource for anyone looking to understand the evolution and development of Bitcoin discussions over time.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T11:52:01.711000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
