<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-11-01T02:45:21.526991+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C.579000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-31T13:52:53.579000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T02:45:21.527027+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/44" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent statistics presented highlight the impact of adjustments made to Bitcoin nodes during the testing phase of version 30.0rc1, specifically in relation to the minrelayfee setting. The adjustments entailed a reduction in the default minrelayfee as part of an experimental approach aimed at enhancing the efficiency of block reconstruction processes. This strategy was implemented across all tested nodes from September 17, 2025, with preliminary results indicating a positive outcome. Notably, there was an improvement in the block reconstruction rate alongside a reduction in the volume of data requested from peers. This indicates a potential optimization in network efficiency and resource utilization.

The decision to lower the minrelayfee on all nodes was seen as a strategic move, although it is acknowledged that retaining some nodes on the previous version 29 might have offered additional insights into comparative performance metrics. Despite this, the primary focus remained on evaluating the release candidates' performance, underscoring the prioritization of comprehensive testing over comparative analysis. Moreover, the inclusion of a Bitcoin Knots node, named `nico`, operating under version 29.1 with default settings provided a broader base for assessing the system's behavior without the modifications introduced in subsequent versions. However, this node lacked the enhanced logging capabilities integrated into later updates, as detailed in a specific [GitHub pull request](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32582), which limited the available data on transaction size requests.

An anomaly was observed on October 18, 2025, where certain nodes including `bob`, `dave`, `luke`, and `nico` experienced low reconstruction rates. The underlying factors contributing to this occurrence have not been thoroughly investigated, leaving room for further analysis to understand the deviations noted. Overall, these activities form part of ongoing efforts to refine Bitcoin’s infrastructure by leveraging empirical data to guide adjustments aimed at optimizing network performance and reliability.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T13:52:53.579000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
