<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-11-01T02:48:28.933639+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>el_mcmurphy.206000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-31T14:57:42.206000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T02:48:28.933666+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the perceived shortcomings of Bitcoin and introduces Epic Cash as a solution that aligns more closely with what the original vision for Bitcoin might have evolved into. Epic Cash incorporates the Mimblewimble protocol at its core, which eliminates the need for addresses, thereby enhancing privacy and reducing the risk of tainted coins without requiring permission. This approach aims to preserve the fundamental qualities that initially made Bitcoin appealing, such as its emission schedule and the decentralization aspect. Furthermore, Epic Cash is designed to be accessible for mining to a vast audience, supporting over 7 billion CPUs and GPUs, emphasizing its commitment to inclusivity and widespread participation in the network. The intent behind Epic Cash is not to create just another alternative cryptocurrency but to offer a digital currency that embodies the original game theory principles that contributed to Bitcoin's value proposition as a peer-to-peer electronic cash system. For those interested in exploring this project further, more information can be found on their website, available at [Epic Cash](https://epiccash.com). This initiative reflects a broader effort within the cryptocurrency community to address some of the challenges and limitations associated with established digital currencies by returning to the foundational goals that sparked the creation of the crypto movement.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T14:57:42.206000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
