<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-01T02:48:03.864908+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.036000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-10-31T15:44:02.036000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T02:48:03.864937+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the technical aspect of proof settlement using the OP_CAT verifier, emphasizing its efficiency and practicality in blockchain transactions. It is noted that the proof settlement process involves approximately 175 transactions, cumulatively amounting to around 7.3MB. This detail underscores the method's potential for handling data and transactions efficiently within a blockchain network. 

Moreover, the conversation delves into the computational strategy of dividing the verification process into discrete steps distributed across multiple transactions. This approach is viewed positively from several perspectives, including bin packing, relay, and anti-Denial of Service (DoS) measures. By segmenting the computation, the system can potentially enhance its resilience against DoS attacks, improve transaction relay times, and optimize the packing of data in blocks.

This discussion reflects on the broader implications of employing such techniques in blockchain technology. It suggests that by breaking down complex computations into smaller, manageable pieces, the network can achieve greater efficiency and security. This methodological shift could have significant benefits for the scalability and reliability of blockchain systems, offering a viable solution to some of the pressing challenges facing this technology today.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T15:44:02.036000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
