<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-31T02:45:02.103149+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 16:05:57.221000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 19:00:40.609000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>garlonicon  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-28 07:51:38.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-28 18:07:55.377000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>vazertuche  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-29 20:02:51.004000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>REDBaron</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-30 10:02:53.379000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>vazertuche</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-30 13:18:28.258000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>vazertuche</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-30 13:23:56.622000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>REDBaron</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-30 15:54:59.787000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6146_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6148_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6151_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6152_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6154_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6159_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6166_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6168_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6169_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6171_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T02:45:02.104575+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The ongoing conversation around Bitcoin's evolution from its original vision as peer-to-peer electronic cash towards a settlement layer for banks has sparked considerable debate within the community. This shift is seen as a move away from the foundational principles of censorship-resistance, decentralization, and fungibility that underpin Bitcoin. Early contributions by figures such as Hal Finney highlight the importance of privacy in maintaining Bitcoin's fungibility, noting that without strong cryptographic privacy measures, the currency's neutrality and global utility are compromised. The public and traceable nature of transactions on Bitcoin's blockchain has led to the classification of coins as &quot;clean&quot; or &quot;dirty,&quot; which undermines the principle of fungibility. The development priorities of the Bitcoin Core leadership have been criticized for neglecting privacy and scalability in favor of intermediate solutions like CoinJoin and the Lightning Network, which do not address these core issues at the base layer.
Furthermore, the concept of Tit-for-Tat in game theory is introduced as a strategy for survival against censorship, suggesting that integrating Mimblewimble through atomic swaps and sidechains could provide a robust mechanism against transaction censorship. This would enhance Bitcoin's core values by enabling seamless and trustless value transfer, rendering any attempt at censorship economically futile. However, the support from entities like the World Economic Forum for Lightning Labs raises questions about the influence of external factors on Bitcoin's development trajectory.
In parallel, the discussion extends to the technical challenges and ideological divides within the Bitcoin community, exemplified by the debate over CoinJoin and OP_RETURN functionalities. These features, while designed to enhance transaction privacy and flexibility, face challenges from advanced chain analysis techniques and regulatory scrutiny. The Monero project is highlighted as an example of continuous efforts to address privacy, security, and governance issues within cryptocurrency communities.
The Grin blockchain, utilizing the Mimblewimble protocol, presents a contrast by inherently preventing the attachment of non-transactional data, thus maintaining the fungibility and privacy of its currency units. This approach addresses concerns over blockchain bloat and the tagging of UTXOs by chain analysis tools, which can diminish their value.
The narrative also acknowledges the vulnerabilities and regulatory challenges faced by cryptocurrencies, emphasizing that privacy-oriented platforms like Monero and Grin are not immune to potential breaches or regulatory interventions. Despite their design to enhance privacy, these platforms could still be compromised, highlighting a complex interplay between regulatory efforts and the decentralized nature of these networks.
Finally, the development of Shielded CSV by Robin Linus and his team marks a significant advancement in Bitcoin privacy, aiming to reconcile Bitcoin’s widespread adoption with the need for transactional privacy. This initiative, through the implementation of BitVM2 and BitVM3, promises a superior alternative to current privacy-centric cryptocurrencies. Critics argue, however, that despite advancements, Bitcoin's base layer remains transparent and traceable, and question the feasibility of achieving true privacy through additional layers, pointing out the simplicity and elegance of Mimblewimble as a more secure and straightforward solution.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>