<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Persisting Mutable Storage Inside The "T"EE</title>
  <updated>2025-10-09T02:27:11.358592+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-10-08 16:13:19.116000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-10-08 11:29:24.545000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-10-07 17:50:26.165000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6024_Persisting-Mutable-Storage-Inside-The-T-EE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6022_Persisting-Mutable-Storage-Inside-The-T-EE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6011_Persisting-Mutable-Storage-Inside-The-T-EE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Persisting Mutable Storage Inside The "T"EE</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T02:27:11.358657+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/persisting-mutable-storage-inside-the-t-ee/2029" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens by arguing against a commonly suggested alternative for secure storage in Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs), which involves using a k-of-n signer model within n TEEs running signer code. It criticizes this approach due to the operational need to regularly update and restart the TEEs, which becomes more frequent as the complexity of the code increases. This necessity arises from the potential for security vulnerabilities that could be exposed over time or as new threats are identified. The proposed solution emphasizes the importance of minimizing TEE downtime and operational complexity by simplifying the tasks executed by the storage TEE programs to basic operations like validating requests, reading, writing, copying, and securely deleting sectors. This simplicity significantly reduces the likelihood of needing updates and restarts, thereby enhancing the system's reliability and security.

Further examination reveals an intricate strategy for mitigating known vulnerabilities in TEE designs, particularly those susceptible to rollback attacks. This is achieved through a novel storage solution that leverages multiple TEEs to create a resilient, auditable, and persistent storage array. By distributing data across these TEEs using erasure coding and employing their inherent encryption capabilities, the method ensures both data integrity and confidentiality. This approach addresses critical challenges associated with external persistent storage by internalizing the storage mechanism within a network of TEEs, thus maintaining the encrypted state of data without necessitating a dedicated encrypted tunnel for communication between the main program and the storage TEEs.

The conversation transitions into technical specifics, discussing optimal sector sizes and introducing a refined disk interface designed to prevent inconsistencies like the RAID5 write hole. This interface incorporates provisional write commands followed by commit or rollback protocols to maintain consistency and integrity throughout the array, even under partial updates or failures. Furthermore, the adoption of XOR-based erasure coding and Reed Solomon codes enhances the efficiency and reliability of the storage solution, making it capable of withstanding multiple simultaneous TEE failures without data loss.

The auditability of the storage configuration is highlighted as a critical advantage. The straightforwardness of the storage TEE program operations allows for thorough examination and verification, ensuring that they perform strictly as intended without unauthorized actions or rollbacks. This auditing process is essential for confirming the integrity and effectiveness of the storage solution, thus reinforcing its capacity to securely manage and store sensitive data, especially in applications involving cryptocurrency transactions.

In conclusion, the proposal articulates a comprehensive and innovative solution for enhancing data security and resilience in TEE-based systems. By addressing the limitations and vulnerabilities intrinsic to conventional TEE and external storage methodologies through a multifaceted strategy, it presents a robust framework for securing sensitive data against emerging threats and operational challenges. This approach not only fortifies the trustworthiness of TEE applications but also offers a promising avenue for advancing the security paradigms of cryptocurrency storage and transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-08T16:13:19.116000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
