<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-10-02T02:25:10.208620+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-10-01 10:30:46.778000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger  . 2025-09-29 20:21:58.109000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger  . 2025-09-29 19:49:26.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-26 14:34:32.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger  . 2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/5991_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5986_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5985_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5976_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T02:25:10.208701+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence delves into the intricacies and potential vulnerabilities associated with implementing a wallet system that relies heavily on the Nostr protocol, particularly focusing on the risks of storing critical data without a robust fallback mechanism. It highlights concerns over the reliance on Nostr for critical data storage, pointing out instances where relays in the Cashu network have deleted their databases, underscoring the precariousness of depending solely on Nostr for important data retention. The discussion further explores the limited adoption of NIP-17 and its implications for Stealth Addresses, suggesting that such usage might inadvertently lead to metadata leaks, thereby compromising user privacy. This conversation also speculates on the dynamics of relay networks within the Nostr ecosystem, theorizing how shared relays could potentially facilitate transactions between users while also acknowledging the inherent privacy risks involved.

Another aspect of the discourse elaborates on a proposed protocol aimed at enhancing the Stealth Address mechanism to improve privacy and efficiency in cryptocurrency transactions. This protocol outlines a complex series of cryptographic operations designed to secure transactions between parties, emphasizing the creation of a stealth component crucial for generating unlinkable addresses. It proposes advancements in the Stealth Address protocol, including signaling support for stealth transactions and integrating Silent Payments logic to alleviate scanning burdens and increase wallet interoperability. Moreover, it suggests nostr notifications as a means to address current Stealth Address implementation issues, offering a hybrid approach that seeks a balance between privacy and operational efficiency.

Further discussion addresses the challenges of ensuring reliable transaction notifications within the decentralized Nostr framework, particularly focusing on mitigating the risk of lost transactions due to relay selection and note deletion. It underscores the importance of multiple relay usage and confirmation messages to ensure message delivery, while also considering the threats posed by malicious actors and spam. The integration of Silent Payments with nostr notifications is posited as a solution to enhance privacy and efficiency in transaction alerts, despite concerns about metadata leakage and the practical challenges of implementing deterministic nonce within the protocol.

The dialogue shifts focus to the technical details of using `npub` keys for creating stealth addresses, exploring the flexibility and security implications of this approach. It scrutinizes the cryptographic methodology behind the generation of new keys for receiving bitcoin payments, highlighting the sender's inquiry into the specifics of the notification structure and the format of the public key. This section emphasizes the analytical interest in understanding the cryptographic foundation of the proposed mechanism, rather than its practical application.

Lastly, the exploration of Nostr's application in generating new keys from `npub` for Bitcoin payments illustrates an effort to overcome limitations identified in BIP 47 through encrypted messaging using NIP-17. The detailed Python code examples provided demonstrate the process for creating and utilizing stealth keys within the Nostr ecosystem, showcasing a practical implementation aimed at enhancing privacy in Bitcoin transactions. This part of the discussion not only conveys the potential of Nostr in improving transaction privacy but also serves as a guide for developers interested in incorporating stealth payment capabilities, marking a significant step towards developing more secure and private cryptocurrency payment systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-01T10:30:46.778000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
