<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:03.464981+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>nymius</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6139_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6149_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:41:03.465467+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the complexities of integrating Schnorr Protocol (SP) compatibility within Bitcoin payment solutions, focusing on BTCPayServer as a case study. The central issue revolves around crafting an effective method to encode key combinations that are fundamental for SP transactions. This encoding challenge is pivotal due to the protocol's reliance on specific key configurations for operation, marking a departure from traditional methods like extended public keys. The proposed solution involves creating a string format that can encapsulate essential combinations such as scan public plus spend master public key, alongside variants for delegated scanning and spending operations.
A noteworthy aspect of this discussion is the introduction of a structure designed to streamline SP operations by incorporating various key pairings. These include the combination of scan private and spend master public keys for enhanced transaction scanning, and the integration of scan private and spend private keys for executing transactions and generating new SP addresses. This approach aims at simplifying the user and developer experience, making the technology more accessible and efficient.
Further exploration into encoding strategies reveals parallels with previous dialogues on silent payment descriptors, as seen in the transcript from the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech meeting. This comparison highlights the ongoing exploration of how best to represent complex cryptographic operations in a user-friendly manner. A notable suggestion from these discussions includes the concept of encoding self-contained spending material for transactions, emphasizing the necessity of including tweak material alongside key information to facilitate output spending. Additionally, the idea of specifying a range or limit for applicable labels directly within the encoded string is discussed, suggesting a move towards more granified control over transaction parameters.
This dialogue underscores the collaborative effort within the developer community to address the technical challenges posed by integrating advanced cryptographic features into practical payment systems. By focusing on the development of intuitive encoding formats for key combinations, these discussions contribute to the broader goal of enhancing cryptocurrency protocols and systems for widespread use. The discourse exemplifies a proactive approach to solving the inherent complexities of merging cutting-edge cryptography with user-centric payment solutions.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>