<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-10-30T02:44:40.032317+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 16:09:26.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-16 16:45:25.792000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ftw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 14:38:17.246000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>Abdel</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-29 13:49:36.191000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6071_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6080_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6097_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6100_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6156_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T02:44:40.033108+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The proposal of introducing `OP_STARK_VERIFY` into Tapscript marks a significant advancement in integrating zero-knowledge proof capabilities directly into Bitcoin, catering to applications like Validity rollups, post-quantum signatures, and privacy-preserving transactions. The initiative leverages STARK proofs for their advantages such as transparency, post-quantum security, and efficiency in verification and proof size relative to computation. However, challenges such as selecting a specific STARK protocol without bias, managing larger proof sizes, and the technical risks of embedding a particular proof system into Bitcoin's consensus mechanism are acknowledged.
The discussion extends to the practical aspects of implementing such proof systems, emphasizing the balance between proof sizes, verification times, and the impact on decentralized network activities like block building and relay. Concerns about the feasibility of adopting proof systems with large proof sizes are raised, particularly regarding the unpredictability of mining timings and the potential strain on blockchain efficiency. The dialogue suggests the necessity for a defined target for &quot;average&quot; block size to maintain consistency across various implementations and explores the resource demands of Circle STARKs within Bitcoin Script.
Further analysis delves into the optimization trade-offs involved in STARK implementation, highlighting the relationship between proving speed, proof size, and verification efficiency. Various stages of a multistage pipeline for proof processing are described, from fast proving techniques to proof compression strategies aimed at making proofs as verifier-friendly as possible. The discourse compares several proof compression approaches, outlining their implications for on-chain costs and practical deployment within the Bitcoin ecosystem.
An alternative approach to integrating ZK verification into Bitcoin through a metaprotocol layered over the base protocol is presented, offering advantages such as reduced risk, market-driven adoption, and the flexibility to adapt to superior technologies. This model relies on existing witness space for embedding STARK proofs and employs open-source indexers for off-chain management, presenting a compelling case for its consideration.
Contrasting perspectives highlight the proven efficacy of STARK-based systems like Starknet, which has demonstrated robustness in processing a substantial volume of transactions and securing significant value. Despite the theoretical appeal of metaprotocols for risk mitigation and incremental adoption, the practical success of STARK technology in operational environments offers a noteworthy argument for its direct integration into Bitcoin. This juxtaposition underscores the need for careful consideration of both innovative proposals and empirical evidence in advancing Bitcoin's capabilities.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>