<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:15.033292+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 11:42:34.724000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>marathongary  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 12:50:39.487000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 18:15:40.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>marathon-gary</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 16:56:09.263000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ilghan</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 18:40:47.408000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>scoresby</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 19:01:58.254000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6048_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6049_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6051_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6102_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6106_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6107_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T02:23:15.034204+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-11 11:42:34.724000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Francesco Madonna has introduced an innovative concept known as B-SSL — Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer, aimed at revolutionizing self-custody solutions for Bitcoin. This new framework is designed to address the critical issue of key loss while ensuring transactions can be executed directly on the blockchain, enhancing both security and user autonomy. By leveraging existing Bitcoin technologies such as Taproot and the `CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY` (CSV) and `CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY` (CLTV) operations, B-SSL provides a secure and flexible infrastructure for managing digital assets. It introduces three distinct spending paths: one initiated by the user with customizable delays, a fallback recovery option, and a custodian recovery or inheritance mechanism, each offering different layers of security and accessibility.
The user-initiated path allows transactions after a delay, employing CSV for timing flexibility, whereas the fallback and custodian paths use CLTV to ensure funds are recoverable in unforeseen circumstances, like key loss, after predetermined periods. The system incorporates mirrored backup keys for added redundancy and security. Additionally, B-SSL proposes an optional off-chain &quot;Convenience Service&quot; to implement these delays and send secret notifications, further protecting users against coercion and physical threats.
The whitepaper detailing B-SSL is shared for peer review, emphasizing its potential to redefine the landscape of cryptocurrency storage and transactions. It aims to gather feedback on its Miniscript structure, policy expressiveness, and safety features to refine the concept before implementation. A notable aspect of the B-SSL concept is its reliance on a miniscript template found on GitHub, suggesting a method for joint custody coordination beneficial for institutions and a sovereign vault solution for individual users, highlighting its versatility and broad applicability.
Criticism arises regarding the belief that distributing keys to oneself could prevent key loss, pointing out the fundamental challenge of single-handedly managing recovery in a trustless environment. B-SSL is presented as a pioneering solution that bridges the gap between non-custodial and custodial services, positioning itself as a trustless key recovery system. This system could dramatically change the current dynamics by allowing users to retain non-custodial control over their assets without the fear of key loss, potentially benefiting a significant portion of the global population interested in self-custody but deterred by the risk of losing access to their funds.
A specific inquiry about the primary spending path under B-SSL reveals a curiosity about the operational mechanics of the CSV timelock when initiating a transaction. The question highlights a scenario where, after setting a timelock for one day, the necessity for both A and C keys to sign without delay post-timelock expiration is questioned, probing into the timelock's actual utility within the vault's spending protocol. This reflects a deeper inquiry into how B-SSL envisions the practicality of delayed transactions, emphasizing a need for clarity on the intended security benefits and user experience implications of implementing such a timelock feature within the B-SSL framework.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>