<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-30T02:45:59.194295+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 16:05:57.221000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 19:00:40.609000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>garlonicon  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-28 07:51:38.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>REDBaron  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-28 18:07:55.377000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>vazertuche</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-29 20:02:51.004000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6146_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6148_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6151_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6152_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6154_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6159_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T02:45:59.195331+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The ongoing discourse within the Bitcoin community, particularly around the Core vs. Knots debate on censorship, delves into issues that strike at the very heart of what Bitcoin stands for: censorship-resistance, decentralization, and fungibility. A critical concern is the apparent shift from Bitcoin's original purpose as &quot;Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash&quot; towards becoming more of a &quot;Settlement Layer for Banks,&quot; indicating a move towards regulatory compliance and centralization. This shift is at odds with Bitcoin's foundational principles, as highlighted by early contributor Hal Finney, who stressed the importance of privacy for fungibility, noting that without strong cryptographic privacy measures, Bitcoin could not serve as a neutral, global currency.
The categorization of coins as &quot;clean&quot; or &quot;dirty&quot; due to the public and traceable nature of transactions undermines Bitcoin's fungibility. This issue is exacerbated by Bitcoin Core leadership's development priorities, which have largely ignored privacy and scalability in favor of intermediate solutions like CoinJoin and the Lightning Network. These solutions, while aiming to address privacy concerns, fall short of solving them at the base layer. The post argues for the integration of Mimblewimble through atomic swaps and sidechains as a robust mechanism against censorship, preserving Bitcoin's core values by enabling trustless value transfer and making censorship economically infeasible.
Furthermore, the discussion extends to CoinJoin, highlighting its challenges, such as vulnerability to de-anonymization, and exploring technical proposals like covenants to increase control over Bitcoin transactions. The broader debate encapsulates deeper ideological divides within the Bitcoin community, touching upon concerns over governance and censorship, as well as the potential for implementing privacy-enhancing technologies.
The discourse also covers the `OP_RETURN` opcode, emphasizing the balance between data storage mechanisms and Bitcoin's fungibility. The Grin blockchain, utilizing the Mimblewimble protocol, is presented as a solution for maintaining fungibility by preventing the attachment of metadata to transaction units, thereby addressing issues related to blockchain bloat and ensuring all units remain equivalent and untraceable to their history.
Addressing vulnerabilities and regulatory challenges faced by privacy-oriented cryptocurrencies like Monero and Grin underscores the tension between regulatory efforts and the decentralized nature of these networks. Despite designs aimed at enhancing user anonymity, these digital assets could be compromised, highlighting the complexities of maintaining privacy amidst potential regulatory interventions.
The narrative shifts towards the innovative approach of newer blockchain designs, such as Mimblewimble, which contrasts with traditional blockchains through its efficient handling of data, resistance to spam, and sustainable scalability. This discussion reflects broader tensions between the desire for open, unregulated value networks and the push for regulation and compliance, indicating a potential shift towards integrating KYC practices directly onto the blockchain.
In conclusion, the emerging technology of Shielded CSV is introduced as a promising solution for enhancing privacy on Bitcoin, deemed superior to Mimblewimble and other privacy-focused technologies. Robin Linus's work on implementing BitVM2 and BitVM3 to enable Shielded CSV suggests a future where Bitcoin can fulfill its potential as private money, marking an exciting development for advocates of financial privacy.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>