<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-10-10T02:26:40.649613+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-10-09 06:43:07.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-09-12 13:22:41.990000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-09-12 10:08:39.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-09-12 06:35:51.054000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-09-11 16:30:35.810000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 11:59:35.986000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-22 11:34:53.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 04:46:39.787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-21 22:14:16.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-20 05:26:23.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-19 21:42:50.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-19 20:45:19.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hodlinator  . 2025-08-19 20:19:33.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-18 00:41:33.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-15 21:15:37.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 21:52:52.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-08-14 20:18:27.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 01:45:43.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2025-08-06 18:12:22.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-06 12:29:34.302000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>portlandhodl  . 2025-08-06 11:25:57.048000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-05 19:08:31.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6032_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5866_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5863_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5862_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5861_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5765_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5764_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5762_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5758_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5753_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5751_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5750_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5749_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5731_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5722_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5713_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5711_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5703_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5666_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5660_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5659_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5654_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T02:26:40.649775+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with an examination of a proposed method for handling Bitcoin transactions, specifically addressing concerns about privacy and the potential for unauthorized access to transactions deemed private by miners. The crux of the concern revolves around the integration with the GETDATA function, which might allow users to access transactions that miners have marked as valuable despite their poor propagation properties, thus raising significant privacy and security issues. This scenario highlights the complexities within the blockchain framework, particularly regarding the treatment of transactions by major mining pools and service providers like Antpool, MARA Pool, and Rebar Labs. These entities prioritize certain transactions based on perceived value, which may compromise user privacy and network integrity, signaling a broader industry trend that necessitates a reassessment of standards or protocols to safeguard against privacy breaches.

Moreover, the conversation delves into recent shifts in mempool policies among Bitcoin nodes and miners, such as the implementation of full replace-by-fee, enhanced spam filtering by Bitcoin Knots, uncapped data carrier capacities, and adjustments to minimum fee rates. These changes reflect the dynamic nature of Bitcoin's transaction policies and their implications for network operations, particularly concerning block relay efficiency and the dynamics of mining centralization. Compact block relay, notably improved with Bitcoin Core version 0.13.0, is highlighted for its role in accelerating block propagation across the network, thereby reducing relay times and mitigating risks associated with increased orphan rates and potential centralization. This advancement demonstrates the efficacy of compact block relay in enhancing network performance, as evidenced by reduced block propagation times and alignment with observed trends in decreased expected orphan rates.

The dialogue further explores alternative solutions to address challenges posed by diverse mempool policies on compact block relay, including weak blocks and template sharing. Weak blocks aim to provide peers with insights into ongoing mining efforts through the publication of incomplete proof-of-work shares, whereas template sharing entails the regular generation and exchange of block templates among peers. This approach not only aids in the efficient reconstruction of compact blocks but also bolsters network robustness and efficiency. Template sharing, in particular, offers multiple benefits, such as enabling nodes to swiftly populate their mempools with high-fee transactions, enhancing privacy through automated rebroadcasting, and allowing for more effective analysis of network behavior and transaction relay issues. A proof of concept for template sharing underscores its potential to improve block reconstructions and update node templates with relevant transactions promptly. These discussions and explorations underscore the Bitcoin community's dedication to optimizing network performance and security in response to evolving challenges and opportunities, reflecting a commitment to continuous improvement and innovation within the ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-09T06:43:07.676000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
