<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-10-09T02:25:11.357062+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake.112000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  ..464000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik  ..123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake  ..724000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6020_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5914_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5898_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5865_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T02:25:11.357110+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available/1980" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent communication highlights the availability of a third release candidate for Bitcoin Core version 30.0, which can be accessed at [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-30.0/test.rc3/). The finalization of the release notes is underway and can be reviewed on GitHub at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33559). This update addresses an overflow bug that importantly does not affect the muhash value, maintaining its consistency across different versions. Despite initial considerations, the final code version will not include a migration function. Instead, a simpler solution has been recommended for tackling the specified issue: utilizing an updated index from a fast machine and transferring it to the `index/coinstatsindex/` directory on a slower node, provided that the slow node's last block precedes the last block of the copied index. This method aims to bypass the need for complex migration scripts or manual intervention.

The necessity for a more efficient solution arises from the significant time and resources required to rebuild Coinstatsindex on pruned nodes, particularly those with low-power CPUs. The rebuilding process is akin to an Initial Block Download (IBD), which is inherently slow and challenging, especially in environments susceptible to power failures. A proposed solution includes creating a migration script that ensures the synchronization of muhash values with a recent, accurate version. This approach leverages the consistency of muhash values across versions to facilitate a smoother and quicker update or migration process for Coinstatsindex on systems with limited hardware capabilities or in operational environments prone to interruptions.

Moreover, the latest release candidate, v30.0rc1, of Bitcoin Core is now available for download at [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-30.0/test.rc1/), with its source code accessible under a signed tag on GitHub at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v30.0rc1). Community members are encouraged to review the changes, submit feedback, issues, or comments via the GitHub issues page at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/33368). Release candidates like v30.0rc1 play a critical role in the software development lifecycle by undergoing thorough testing to identify and rectify any critical problems before transitioning to a final release version. This process is instrumental in ensuring the upcoming major version release's stability and reliability before its official integration into the Bitcoin Core software suite.</summary>
    <published>2025-10-08T09:33:06.112000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
