<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-11-14T02:47:16.551207+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>nymius  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 03:50:00.461000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 05:26:14.844000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>pyth  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:41:23.310000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:57:57.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 14:49:16.312000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 15:56:16.956000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 03:59:38.435000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>craigraw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 09:06:49.270000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 16:03:55.856000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6139_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6149_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6181_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6182_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6220_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6223_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6224_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6228_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6230_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6231_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6232_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T02:47:16.552747+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The integration of Schnorr Protocol (SP) compatibility into Bitcoin payment solutions like BTCPayServer necessitates a nuanced approach to encoding key combinations. This is vital for facilitating transactions, as the architecture and operational requirements of such protocols demand the ability to handle various keys efficiently. The discussion proposes a structured string format to encapsulate essential combinations for SP operations, including scan public plus spend master public key, scan private plus spend master public key, and scan private plus spend private key. These configurations aim to streamline processes, making them more intuitive for users and developers. This initiative reflects the broader effort within the developer community to refine and expand the applicability of cryptocurrency protocols, enhancing both usability and security.
Further exploration into silent payment descriptors during the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024 conference shed light on potential enhancements to current encoding methodologies. The conference transcript introduced the idea of a format that includes &quot;self-contained&quot; spending material for individual outputs, suggesting a combination of tweak and b_spend derived from label, b_scan, and a shared secret. This concept aims to address limitations where b_scan and b_spend keys alone fall short without the originating transaction's tweak material. By proposing a method that incorporates a range or limit for labels directly onto the string, the enhancements seek to increase flexibility and functionality, thereby improving transaction efficiency and bolstering security and privacy.
The discourse extends to proposed modifications in the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), focusing on the handling of labels and per-transaction information during wallet imports. By including a block number or &quot;birthday&quot; for labels and per-tx data, the process could be streamlined, informing wallets that verification of transactions before this block is unnecessary. The conversation also touches on standardizing output formats across different wallets to mitigate user confusion, advocating for a simplified, standardized approach to data encoding. This would potentially enhance the wallet recovery process by providing clearer hints to scanners and reducing the risk of errors through tampering with data components.
A notable advancement in the Bitcoin Improvement Proposals landscape is marked by the creation of a new BIP PR, indicating a proactive step towards refining the Bitcoin network. This move invites community feedback and collaboration, emphasizing the importance of consensus in protocol modifications. Through transparent review and discussion facilitated by platforms like GitHub, the initiative underscores the collective effort to evolve and optimize Bitcoin, reflecting the dynamic and collaborative nature of its development community.
In summarizing these discussions, it's clear that the focus remains on enhancing the effectiveness and user-friendliness of Bitcoin-related technologies. From refining encoding strategies to proposing modifications in BIP for better wallet recovery, the ongoing dialogue highlights a commitment to innovation and improvement within the cryptocurrency space. The emphasis on community engagement and open-source collaboration further demonstrates the collective endeavor to advance Bitcoin's protocol, ensuring its growth and adaptability to meet emerging challenges and opportunities.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>