<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-12-04T02:51:28.493031+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>nymius  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 03:50:00.461000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 05:26:14.844000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>pyth  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:41:23.310000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:57:57.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 14:49:16.312000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 15:56:16.956000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>pyth  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 03:59:38.435000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>craigraw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 09:06:49.270000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>pyth  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-13 16:03:55.856000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>craigraw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 11:19:23.092000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6139_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6149_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6181_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6182_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6220_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6223_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6224_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6228_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6230_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6231_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6232_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6367_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T02:51:28.494967+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</published>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin payment solutions, a significant technical discourse is dedicated to enhancing support for BTCPayServer with Schnorr Protocol (SP) compatibility. The challenge centers around the encoding of scan private keys and spend public keys, which is vital for executing seamless transactions within the SP's architectural framework. An innovative approach is proposed to create a string format that can encapsulate various key combinations crucial for SP operations. These include combinations outlined in BIP352, such as scan public plus spend master public key (B_scan + B_m), as well as configurations like scan private plus spend master public key (b_scan + B_m) for delegated scanning, and the scan private plus spend private key (b_scan + b_spend) for spending operations and generating new SP addresses. This structured format aims to simplify and make the process more intuitive for both users and developers, highlighting the community's efforts to refine cryptocurrency protocols for broader usability.
Further exploration into the intricacies of encoding for silent payment descriptors, as detailed in a transcript from the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024 conference, suggests advancements to the existing framework. The enhancement involves a format that encompasses “self-contained” spending material for individual outputs by combining `tweak` with `b_spend`, derived from elements like `label`, `b_scan`, and a shared secret. This proposal addresses limitations where keys alone do not suffice for spending outputs without tweak material from the originating transaction. By proposing a self-contained methodology, the aim is to streamline transactions while bolstering security and privacy in cryptocurrency transactions.
The conversation also extends to the refinement of the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) concerning wallet imports. It highlights the importance of including a block number or &quot;birthday&quot; for labels and per-tx data, which informs the wallet that it need not verify transactions prior to this block, thereby streamlining the restoration process. Encoding labels as an array at the end of transaction data could enable efficient organization and retrieval, simplifying the restoration process for users. This dialogue reflects a proactive engagement within the community to improve the protocol based on technical insights.
A notable development in the Bitcoin Improvement Proposals landscape is the establishment of a new BIP PR, marking a step forward in advancing Bitcoin's protocol. This PR invites community feedback, collaboration, and contribution, demonstrating a commitment to the evolution of Bitcoin. It serves as a platform for transparent examination, discussion, and improvement suggestions, embodying the open-source nature of Bitcoin and encouraging community engagement.
On the topic of output descriptors, a clear understanding of their roles and limitations is essential. Output descriptors describe outputs but require external data from scanned transactions to generate meaningful output, underscoring the need for precise definitions and comprehensive documentation. The discussion also covers the functionality and application of SP descriptors regarding the inclusion of private key information, suggesting an adaptation to allow encodings that encompass private key material for secure and efficient transmission.
Moreover, there's a push towards modifying Bitcoin transaction descriptor formats to aid in wallet recovery processes. The proposal suggests excluding complex UTXO and ECDH information deemed unnecessary for a descriptor, advocating for standardized output formats to prevent user confusion. The inclusion of birthday and maximum label hints is proposed to enhance scanner efficiency and user experience. Additionally, the impact of adding labels on transaction processing efficiency is analyzed, showing a significant increase in processing time and a decrease in transactions per second with the addition of labels, highlighting the computational cost associated with each additional label.
This comprehensive analysis underscores the ongoing efforts to optimize the Bitcoin network, focusing on improving security, privacy, and user experience through technical enhancements and community collaboration.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>