<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
  <updated>2025-10-26T02:44:12.000294+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 11:42:34.724000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>marathongary  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 12:50:39.487000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-11 18:15:40.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>marathongary  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 16:56:09.263000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 18:40:47.408000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>scoresby  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 19:01:58.254000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-18 06:45:22.323000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>scoresby  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-18 16:28:06.353000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>ilghan  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-18 18:20:02.145000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>Bicaru20</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 22:40:46.810000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6048_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6049_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6051_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6102_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6106_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6107_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6108_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6109_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6110_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6143_Concept-Review-B-SSL-Bitcoin-Secure-Signing-Layer-Covenant-Free-Vault-Model-Using-Taproot-CSV-and-CLTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Concept Review: B-SSL (Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer) — Covenant-Free Vault Model Using Taproot, CSV, and CLTV</title>
    <updated>2025-10-26T02:44:12.001908+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/concept-review-b-ssl-bitcoin-secure-signing-layer-covenant-free-vault-model-using-taproot-csv-and-cltv/2047/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-11 11:42:34.724000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Francesco Madonna has developed a novel concept called B-SSL — Bitcoin Secure Signing Layer, which addresses the significant challenge of key loss in self-custody solutions while ensuring transaction enforceability directly on the blockchain. This system utilizes Bitcoin technologies such as Taproot and timelock features like `CHECKSEQUENCEVERIFY` (CSV) and `CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY` (CLTV), offering three distinct spending paths: user-initiated transactions with delays, fallback recovery after one year, and custodian recovery or inheritance protection after three years. The architecture includes mirrored backups for enhanced security and introduces an optional off-chain &quot;Convenience Service&quot; to implement delays and send secret notifications, aiming to protect against coercion.
The inquiry about mint-005 from the GitHub repository suggests a connection between the discussed Miniscript and the ongoing conversation about B-SSL, emphasizing the importance of reviewing such resources for a comprehensive understanding. Miniscripts represent a flexible, efficient way to implement logic in Bitcoin scripts, facilitating operations with distributed keys and enhancing security by decentralizing control over digital assets. This programming technique is pivotal for creating robust, secure systems that can handle complex functionalities with improved readability and maintainability.
B-SSL aims to mitigate the fear of key loss by introducing a trustless key recovery system that maintains user control over assets without compromising security or privacy. It represents a potential shift in self-custody solutions, making them more accessible by eliminating the risk of fund loss due to misplaced keys. The system's development reflects a significant effort to enhance the safety and usability of digital asset management, potentially influencing widespread adoption of non-custodial solutions.
The discussion also delves into the operational specifics of cryptocurrency transactions within a vault-like wallet setup, focusing on the CSV timelock mechanism and its implications for security and transaction management. This mechanism initiates a 15-day countdown upon coin deposit, during which key C cannot authorize transactions. However, the practical application and effectiveness of CSV timelocks raise questions, especially regarding their integration with other components like the Custodial Service and the role in preventing immediate withdrawals, highlighting a need for clarification or reevaluation of the system’s design to ensure it meets security objectives effectively.
Finally, the concern about preventing collusion between custodians underscores the complexity of designing a secure, decentralized system. It emphasizes the importance of a holistic view when assessing the system's integrity and the potential vulnerabilities arising from custodian collaboration. The upcoming Bitcoin Optech audio recap discussion offers an avenue for further exploration of these challenges, inviting community engagement to develop more comprehensive solutions and enhance understanding of the mechanisms in place to safeguard against such risks.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>