<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2026-01-18T03:09:32.187858+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>AdamISZ</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>AdamISZ</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-26 14:34:32.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-29 19:49:26.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-29 20:21:58.109000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-01 10:30:46.778000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-15 23:29:44.543000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>1440000bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-17 05:54:00.310000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5976_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5985_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5986_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/5991_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6627_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6636_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2026-01-18T03:09:32.189838+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The integration of Nostr's cryptographic techniques, akin to those used in Bitcoin, into the process of generating new keys for secure transaction notifications represents a pivotal advancement in enhancing privacy within cryptocurrency transactions. This method provides a solution to the limitations encountered in previous versions, such as BIP 47, by eliminating the need for OP_RETURN in notifications and the challenges associated with silent payment scanning. By allowing for the generation of new keys communicated through encrypted messages via NIP-17, the user experience is significantly improved without compromising security. This novel approach facilitates the creation of stealth public and private keys, leveraging shared secrets between parties to ensure private and secure transactions. The Python code examples provided illustrate the practical application of this method, demonstrating the generation and validation of stealth keys and random keypairs within the Nostr framework.
The detailed inquiry into the cryptographic mechanism behind this process highlights the complexity and efficiency of secure key exchanges. It delves into the mathematical structure of generating a public key that involves Bob's nostril public key and a unique hash function, indicating the robustness of the security measures employed. This focus on understanding the theoretical underpinnings emphasizes the desire to grasp the proposal's efficacy purely from a cryptographic perspective.
Moreover, the conversation explores operational aspects, such as avoiding scanning by Bob and utilizing `npub` keys, suggesting a nuanced approach to privacy and security in the system. The potential for creating stealth addresses without universally sending specific keys underscores the flexibility and tailored security measures within Nostr's platform.
Discussions around the integration of nostr notifications with Silent Payments shed light on the complexities of ensuring reliable transaction notifications in a stateless protocol like nostr. Concerns about data integrity, metadata leakage, and the challenges posed by relay networks are addressed, pointing towards ongoing efforts to refine and secure Nostr's functionality. Notably, the adoption of NIP-17 in projects like amethyst and the exploration of NIP-EE or MLS highlight the dynamic nature of development in this field.
The initiative to merge Silent Payments with Nostr notifications marks a significant step forward in financial technology, aiming to improve transactional communication while maintaining privacy and efficiency. This endeavor is supported by a community-driven platform for collaboration and development, reflecting a broader trend towards interconnected digital services. The creation of an Electrum plugin to test this concept, along with the innovative idea of using color addresses, showcases the practical application and potential of these advancements in enhancing the user experience in digital finance.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>