<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T02:42:08.458747+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>REDBaron</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>1440000bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 16:05:57.221000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>REDBaron</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 19:00:40.609000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6146_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6148_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6151_Bitcoin-Embracing-MimbleWimble.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T02:42:08.459346+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-27 12:04:16.225000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The ongoing debate between Core and Knots concerning censorship in Bitcoin signals a deeper, systemic issue that threatens the foundational principles of Bitcoin: censorship-resistance, decentralization, and fungibility. This situation is described not merely as a moment of contention but as indicative of a &quot;fatal cancer&quot; within the structure of Bitcoin, undermining its intrinsic value and utility as envisioned by its creators.
Bitcoin was initially conceptualized as &quot;Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash,&quot; a Shelling Point that represented a natural, decentralized solution for financial transactions. However, the development direction steered by Core has gradually shifted Bitcoin away from this foundation towards becoming a &quot;Settlement Layer for Banks.&quot; This shift is critiqued for moving Bitcoin into a position where it could become more susceptible to regulatory control and centralization, betraying its original purpose and compromising its value for broader, global use.
Central to the argument presented is Hal Finney’s perspective on privacy and fungibility as indispensable elements of Bitcoin. The lack of robust cryptographic privacy mechanisms within Bitcoin's architecture is seen as a fundamental flaw, paving the way for potential discrimination between &quot;clean&quot; and &quot;dirty&quot; coins based on transaction history. This flaw could lead to scenarios where Bitcoin ownership becomes a liability, questioning the security and neutrality of the currency. The introduction and potential integration of Mimblewimble through Grin is proposed as a solution, offering enhanced privacy, scalability, and fungibility without compromising decentralization.
The discussion extends to the strategic implications of adopting or rejecting privacy-enhancing technologies like Mimblewimble. Drawing on game theory, particularly the Tit-for-Tat strategy, the necessity for a cryptographic response to regulatory and censorship pressures is emphasized. Such a built-in mechanism would safeguard the network's core values by making censorship attempts economically futile, thereby preserving Bitcoin's censorship-resistance and ensuring its viability and growth.
Moreover, the critique addresses the inadequacies of existing privacy solutions like CoinJoin, highlighting their limitations and vulnerabilities to de-anonymization tactics. This reinforces the argument for a more fundamental, integrated approach to privacy and fungibility within Bitcoin’s protocol to counteract the trend towards centralization and regulatory capture.
In conclusion, the correspondence underscores an urgent need for the Bitcoin community to realign with its original principles by adopting technologies that ensure privacy, fungibility, and decentralization. Failure to do so might not only diminish Bitcoin's utility and value but could also render it obsolete in the face of evolving digital currencies that prioritize these critical attributes. The call to action is clear: integrate Mimblewimble or risk betraying the revolutionary ideals at the heart of Bitcoin.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>