<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
  <updated>2025-04-02T02:36:28.027310+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-01T15:16:54.918000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
    <updated>2025-04-02T02:36:28.027347+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/40" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the complexity and limitations faced by miners in setting timestamps within blockchain operations, highlighting that such a task remains unpredictable due to its nature as a Poisson process. This unpredictability challenges any efforts to manipulate or precisely control timestamp settings through computational means. In exploring the adaptation of Sjors' scheme, which is detailed at [this link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/37), to a practical algorithm for timestamp decisions, it becomes clear that an earlier proposed scheme, accessible [here](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/32), has been put to test. The simulation results indicate that this scheme does not lead to a compounding effect on the attackers' ability to produce blocks, primarily due to the negative feedback from the difficulty adjustments triggered by their actions.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the potential concerns related to a compounding effect that might empower attackers through manipulative actions like deliberately reducing their hash rate. However, it is concluded that even if such a compounding effect were possible, it would not present a significant concern. This perspective underscores the resilience of the system against specific types of manipulations aimed at affecting block production rates through artificial means. It reinforces the notion that the inherent challenges and mechanisms within blockchain timestamping and difficulty adjustments provide a form of protection against certain adversarial strategies.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-01T15:16:54.918000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
