<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-04-06T02:39:26.317419+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lagrang3</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-05T21:26:50.550000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T02:39:26.317456+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/65" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on an implementation of a proof of concept related to the Generalized Geometry Theorem (GGT), as demonstrated in a specific GitHub repository ([max-density-closure](https://github.com/Lagrang3/max-density-closure/blob/e298019aac6b4b7725d68156737aaff20b87968b/examples/maxfeerate-ggt.cpp)). The sender proposes an optimization approach based on the bipartite nature of the graph involved in the GGT. They suggest segregating nodes into two distinct sets: N1, which comprises nodes connected directly to the source, and N2, consisting of nodes that have connections to the sink. This classification leverages the unique property of the graph where nodes are exclusively linked either to the source or the sink, but not both.

The proposed optimization hinges on the insight that arcs connecting nodes within the same set (either N1-N1 or N2-N2) may not significantly contribute to the optimal solution of the graph's flow problem. For arcs within N1, if any arc does carry flow, it implies that there must be a node in N2 that is indirectly connected to the nodes in N1 through another arc. This observation leads to the suggestion that flows could be redirected directly from nodes in N1 to this intermediary node in N2, bypassing the need for intra-set arcs among N1 nodes due to their infinite capacity. This logic equally applies to arcs within N2, positing that such connections might be redundant for the purpose of optimizing the overall flow from source to sink.

This idea prompts a reevaluation of traditional approaches to solving flow problems in bipartite graphs by possibly eliminating unnecessary computations and leading to more efficient algorithms. The sender acknowledges potential oversights in their reasoning but maintains that the concept merits further exploration for its potential to refine and optimize solutions in graph theory applications specifically tailored to bipartite graphs.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-05T21:26:50.550000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
