<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-04-06T02:39:15.487155+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-05 23:30:05.339000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T02:39:15.487193+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/66" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion brings to light significant considerations regarding the adaptation of a generalized graph traversal (GGT) algorithm. One pivotal concern is the impact of dynamic changes to $\lambda$, the algorithm's parameter during recursion, which could potentially disrupt the intended partition logic by allowing transactions to switch between the sink and source sides. This deviation from the original constraint, where only sink-to-node and node-to-source capacities are allowed to change, might nullify the anticipated $n$ factor improvement in worst-case performance. 

Furthermore, the necessity for edges within the graph to be expanded to their transitive closure introduces additional complexity. Specifically, if one node is dependent on another, an indirect dependency through a third node requires direct representation as an edge, thereby increasing the graph's density. Given that practical applications often present graphs where the number of edges $m$ is proportional to the number of nodes $n$, expanding to full transitive closure could escalate the number of edges to the order of $n^2$. This expansion, in turn, could exacerbate computational demands, particularly in light of the discussed algorithm’s complexity being $\mathcal{O}(n^2 \sqrt{m})$. This situation becomes more challenging considering realistic scenarios where $m = \mathcal{O}(n)$, but with transitive closure, $m$ potentially grows to $\mathcal{O}(n^2)$.

The discourse also touches upon specialized bipartite-graph min-cut algorithms, hinting at the possibility of more tailored solutions or optimizations that could mitigate some of the identified challenges. Additionally, there's anticipation for further development and exploration, especially concerning data representation. The idea of representing edge data in an $n\times n$ matrix to facilitate the use of bitsets for more efficient matching signifies ongoing experimentation aimed at optimizing the approach. This experimentation reflects a continuous effort to refine and enhance the algorithmic strategy under consideration, indicating that while initial hurdles are recognized, the pursuit of innovative solutions remains unabated.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-05T23:30:05.339000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
