<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Cluster mempool partitioning attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-04-15T02:44:57.001559+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-14 12:04:34.878000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Cluster mempool partitioning attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T02:44:57.001589+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-partitioning-attacks/1548/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring peer-to-peer (P2P) extensions for relaying linearization information in clusters presents a nuanced debate. A notable approach involves utilizing an algorithm discussed on [DelvingBitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/spanning-forest-cluster-linearization/1419), which leverages the understanding of "active" dependencies to ascertain an optimal state within a computational complexity of $\mathcal{O}(n^2)$. This method contrasts with the traditional evaluation of linearization optimality, typically reliant on computing a single min-cut—a process that theoretically operates at a complexity of $\mathcal{O}(nm)$ and practically at $\mathcal{O}(n^2 \sqrt{m})$, assuming the linearization comprises a single chunk.

However, the integration of these states poses significant challenges, particularly in the absence of a mechanism to combine differing states effectively. For linearizations, there exists a merging algorithm, accessible at [this link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209), which facilitates the synthesis of two suboptimal linearizations into a superior composite version. This algorithm's utility is underscored in P2P environments, where it accommodates the assimilation of disparate good linearization data among peers, albeit without ensuring optimality.

The discourse surrounding the potential for achieving optimal linearization through practical applications remains speculative. The absence of a parallel methodology for merging spanning-forest states underscores the complexities inherent in extending P2P protocols to enhance cluster linearization processes. This exploration reflects a broader contemplation on the feasibility and efficiency of advanced encoding and algorithmic strategies in optimizing network structures, highlighting the ongoing evolution of computational approaches within distributed systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T12:04:34.878000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
