<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>How CSFS+PAIRCOMMIT enables mass delegated introspection</title>
  <updated>2025-04-15T02:46:31.925303+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh.008000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-14T20:59:02.008000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>How CSFS+PAIRCOMMIT enables mass delegated introspection</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T02:46:31.925333+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-csfs-paircommit-enables-mass-delegated-introspection/1599" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of new capabilities in blockchain technology, particularly regarding the efficiency and flexibility of transaction authorizations, brings to light innovative concepts such as *mass delegated introspection*. This concept allows for the authorization of a broad spectrum of potential transactions with a single signature, enhancing the adaptability and efficiency of operations like coinjoins, channel updates, or UTXO purchases. The integration of CSFS (Cross-Input Scripting using the Taproot Annex) and PAIRCOMMIT opcodes stands out as a promising solution to commit efficiently to many possible sighashes with a single signature. This approach negates the need for hash cycles while enabling commitments to new sighashes dynamically.

The technical implementation involves signing a merkle root using CSFS and employing multiple PAIRCOMMITs to verify a leaf on a merkle tree of fixed height. Further verification is completed using CSFS and CHECKSIG on a dummy private key to ensure the leaf equals the desired sighash. Although this script, which credits its design to @reardencode, demonstrates complexity, its application extends to multi-signature inputs by duplicating the merkle root and verifying the threshold number of signatures. Importantly, the data type of the leaf hash isn't restricted to sighashes, offering versatility through the introspection opcode's ability to verify various data types.

However, limitations exist, notably the requirement to pre-commit to the merkle tree's height, possibly leading to inefficiencies. Users can attempt to circumvent this by committing to multiple tapleafs with varying numbers of PAIRCOMMITs, albeit at certain costs. Additionally, the approach is incompatible with key path spends and requires users to have wallets pre-committed to necessary tapscripts, which may not be ideal for all users. An alternative method involving the use of the annex to commit to additional scripts was discussed, potentially offering greater flexibility without the need for pre-committed tapscripts.

Several questions arise from this exploration, including the practicality improvements mass delegated introspection could bring to coinjoins, channel factories, and the likelihood of PAIRCOMMIT's inclusion in a soft fork. Furthermore, the necessity of pre-committing to CSFS and the merkle tree's height poses a question of efficiency and elegance, prompting consideration of annex-based alternatives for delegation across signatures without complex requirements. This discussion encapsulates not only the technical advancements but also the community's considerations and the ongoing dialogue surrounding the evolution of blockchain transaction protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T20:59:02.008000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
