<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How CSFS+PAIRCOMMIT enables mass delegated introspection</title>
  <updated>2025-04-16T02:45:08.128081+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-15T17:14:20.070000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How CSFS+PAIRCOMMIT enables mass delegated introspection</title>
    <updated>2025-04-16T02:45:08.128113+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-csfs-paircommit-enables-mass-delegated-introspection/1599/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The primary advantage of PAIRCOMMIT (PC) extends beyond its capacity for byte savings, focusing on how it limits the possibilities for recursive covenants compared to CAT. This characteristic is crucial because recursive covenants complicate matters by not addressing the central issue effectively. The discussion points out that if covenants can carry state and self-replicate (quine), they pave the way for creating assets akin to "native" tokens within a contracting language. These native tokens could significantly impact Automated Market Makers (AMMs) and similar mechanisms by allowing direct interaction through the contracting language.

However, introducing such a concept could be challenging for community acceptance. The underlying concern is that while PC aims to facilitate multi-commitments and enable Merkle proofs, it carefully avoids crossing a specific line. It does not permit excessively detailed introspection or inspection of ancestor transactions. This restraint is deliberate, aiming to prevent the complexities and potential security concerns associated with allowing overly granular control over or visibility into transaction histories. This approach seeks to balance innovation with maintaining a manageable level of complexity and safeguarding against unintended consequences in transaction handling and contract execution.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-15T17:14:20.070000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
