<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-04-17T02:38:43.495881+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-16T10:58:29.928000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T02:38:43.495918+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with a technical insight into Bitcoin scripting, highlighting a unique aspect of the `scriptSig` component. The main point revolves around the possibility of including the `CHECKSIG` opcode directly within the `scriptSig`, which is contrary to the typical standardness rules governing Bitcoin transactions. This unconventional approach stems from an original concept within the Bitcoin protocol, particularly in relation to Pay-to-Script-Hash (P2SH) transactions.

In traditional P2SH transactions, the redeem script, which is revealed and evaluated during the transaction verification process, primarily consists of push operations. These operations are designed to place data onto the stack without performing any logical evaluations until execution. The suggestion implies that by adhering to this principle, a scenario could arise where the scriptPubKey (spk) might be left empty. This would theoretically allow a transaction to pass validation under certain conditions due to the non-enforcement of the clean stack rule as a consensus mechanism.

The clean stack rule, while not a part of the Bitcoin network's consensus rules, plays a significant role in ensuring that only the intended operations are executed and that no extraneous data remains on the stack after script execution. However, the discussion points out that since this rule is not strictly enforced at the consensus level, there exists a potential flexibility in how scripts are constructed and verified, especially in the context of P2SH transactions.

This exploration into Bitcoin's scripting nuances sheds light on the intricate balance between protocol standardness and the creative possibilities afforded by the underlying scripting language. It opens up discussions on the implications for transaction validity, security considerations, and the evolutionary trajectory of script standards within the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-16T10:58:29.928000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
