<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-04-17T02:38:17.426000+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-16T13:49:57.554000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T02:38:17.426031+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of implementing a "stack sentinel" within the context of Bitcoin transactions, specifically focusing on the use of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) as a mechanism to ensure script integrity. The primary concern highlighted is the potential vulnerability in using CTV with Pay to Script Hash (P2SH) types, where the absence of a stack sentinel could allow for the replacement of the intended script with a legacy script, leading to unintended consequences. This issue underscores the necessity for better documentation to mitigate confusion and enhance security.

To address the limitations associated with legacy requirements, the discourse suggests a practical approach involving the use of a legacy input (denoted as B) that incorporates a specific script structure (scriptSig), including operations like Dup and checksig. This framework allows for the inclusion of additional inputs to facilitate the transmission of more data. Further elaboration is provided on the concept of utilizing a taproot-adapter to generate an output (referred to as X). This output employs a Taproot construction (tr) with a nested structure that includes a general program and a checksig operation within a 1-in-1-out context, combined with CTV.

The mechanism of binding input B from another input A, through A's commitment to B's Outpoint via B's signature, ensures the execution of output X. This process is critical for verifying that certain validation properties have been met, effectively relocating much of the validation workload into the witness data space. This strategy highlights a sophisticated method of leveraging Bitcoin's scripting capabilities to secure transaction integrity and demonstrates a nuanced understanding of Bitcoin's scripting nuances to address specific security concerns.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-16T13:49:57.554000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
