<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-04-18T02:28:09.272379+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-18 01:21:40.897000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-04-18T02:28:09.272408+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/70" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the complexities of transaction ordering within systems, highlighting the process and challenges involved in achieving an efficient linearization. It focuses on a specific method of transaction organization known as CSS (Candidate Set Search) and its interaction with a concept called Ancestor Set Sort. The approach taken by CSS is not to start with a pure ancestor sort based linearization but rather to use an earlier, existing linearization for a cluster as its input. This method acknowledges that initial linearizations can vary greatly in quality; they can be either highly efficient if the cluster was previously well-organized and only minor changes have occurred, or they can be less efficient, particularly when two clusters merge and their linearizations are naively combined despite significant transaction interactions.

The process described for CSS involves a series of steps aimed at refining the transaction order. Initially, it identifies the best ancestor set and the best prefix from the existing linearization remaining within the cluster. The choice between these options is made based on which has a higher fee rate. This selection serves as the starting point for further refinement through CSS, with additional adjustments made to ensure the final output aligns closely with the initial linearization. This iterative process, termed LIMO (Linearization Improvement Methodology), enhances the quality of the transaction sequence, aiming to match or exceed the efficiency of the input linearization.

One critical aspect of this methodology is its reliance on incremental improvements by integrating various sources of candidate sets, including ancestor sets and existing prefixes. This approach contrasts with a purely theoretical sorting method like Ancestor Set Sort, emphasizing practical performance and adaptability. Despite this intricate process, the system does not guarantee an outcome that surpasses pure ancestor set sort results in every instance. However, it often achieves superior efficiency through its dynamic and flexible nature.

Ultimately, the conversation underscores the importance of utilizing existing cluster linearizations as a foundation for further optimization rather than starting anew with Ancestor Set Sort. This strategy reflects a pragmatic approach to transaction ordering, focusing on leveraging prior organizational efforts to expedite the linearization process. The dialogue also hints at a broader uncertainty regarding the optimal integration of these methodologies into SFL (Sequential Forward Linearization), suggesting an area ripe for further exploration.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-18T01:21:40.897000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
