<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Some problems with current bitcoin core `MODERATION.md`</title>
  <updated>2025-04-19T02:28:23.219293+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard.920000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-19T01:13:47.920000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Some problems with current bitcoin core `MODERATION.md`</title>
    <updated>2025-04-19T02:28:23.219319+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/some-problems-with-current-bitcoin-core-moderation-md/1616" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A recent initiative led to the opening of a pull request aiming to eliminate the moderation guidelines within the Bitcoin Core metadata repository, challenging the necessity and appropriateness of such rules in the context of Bitcoin's development. The proponent argues against formal governance structures, especially those that could influence consensus rules, drawing on philosophical considerations reminiscent of past conflicts such as the block size debate. This perspective is supported by references to "The Tao of Bitcoin Development," an essay advocating for a decentralized approach to Bitcoin protocol development, free from hierarchical control.

The opposition to moderation guidelines also finds roots in legal considerations, notably the Berne Convention of 1886, which upholds the concept of joint authorship among contributors to projects across its member countries. This principle, relevant to open-source initiatives, underscores the collective ownership and rights of contributors, suggesting that the modest number of contributors who have acknowledged the guidelines does not represent the wider contributor base. Furthermore, a UK judicial ruling in 2023 involving former and current Bitcoin maintainers emphasized the decentralized and unstructured nature of their roles within the project, challenging the notion of significant control or power over the network.

The existence of a document outlining moderation policies, including behavioral guidelines and distinctions between what is considered on-topic or off-topic, raises concerns about the imposition of undue control or influence over the project's direction. The discussion points out a perceived contradiction between the stated janitorial roles of moderators and maintainers and the actual enforcement capabilities granted by the document.

Finally, while civility and respect are highlighted as important values within the Bitcoin community, the current approach to moderation is questioned for potentially not aligning with those principles. The call to discuss this issue reflects a belief in the importance of openness and fairness in community interactions, emphasizing the need for a more inclusive and respectful approach to governance within the Bitcoin development ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-19T01:13:47.920000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
