<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2025-04-22T02:38:08.727038+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors.628000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-21T14:57:21.628000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T02:38:08.727074+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/86" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Stratum v2 specification introduces significant advancements in the mining protocol by detailing how ASICs should operate within the network. According to the spec, ASICs are encouraged to roll the version bits as outlined in BIP320, a process that allows for the modification of certain bits in the block's version field to signal readiness to enforce soft fork upgrades without affecting the core operations of the hardware. This method is deemed efficient for devices with a hashing power of up to 280 TH/s. For devices exceeding this threshold, the specification suggests alternative strategies to avoid overburdening the ASICs with the need to manipulate the block merkle tree directly.

One such strategy involves slightly rolling the timestamp, although there are concerns within the community about the potential risks associated with this approach, notably the fear of enabling time warp attacks. A discussion on the matter highlights the debate around the advisability of allowing such practices, indicating a preference among some experts for maintaining stringent control over timestamp adjustments to prevent exploitation ([Timewarp Attack - 600 Second Grace Period](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/8)). Another suggested method for accommodating higher hash rates involves handling multiple jobs in parallel, which would enable an ASIC to continue functioning efficiently without direct interaction with the block's merkle tree component.

Furthermore, it's important to note that these provisions primarily concern the role of pool software in updating the coinbase extraNonce, a critical element in the mining process that ensures each block mined is unique and secures the integrity of the blockchain against double-spending and other forms of attack. By delineating specific roles for ASICs and pool software in the management of nonce values and other block attributes, the Stratum v2 specification aims to streamline mining operations, enhance security, and improve the overall efficiency of cryptocurrency mining activities.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-21T14:57:21.628000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
