<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-04-22T02:42:02.756777+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin.268000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-21T16:18:03.268000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T02:42:02.756809+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain technology, particularly in scripting and transaction validation, a detailed method has been proposed to enhance the security and integrity of transactions. The core of this methodology involves the intricate use of OP_NOP codes within the scriptSig following the signature. Specifically, a sequence consisting of an OP_DEPTH check followed by an OP_1, OP_EQUALVERIFY, OP_DUP, a public key, and OP_CHECKSIGVERIFY, subsequently padded with 197 OP_NOP codes, is crafted. This construct is deliberately designed to restrict the malleability of transactions by ensuring that no additional pushdatas can be introduced post-signature due to the OP_DEPTH check. Furthermore, the strategic placement of NOPs at the end acts as a safeguard against the arbitrary insertion of the signature within the OP_NOP segment, bolstering the transaction's resistance to unauthorized modifications.

The significance of this arrangement lies in its commitment to the B'd signature's scriptcode, thereby eliminating the possibility of duplicating or sneakily injecting another copy of the signature through manipulation techniques like FindAndDelete. By preventing any alterations before the execution of the second stack size check in the scriptPubKey, it ensures the authenticity and intended functionality of the transaction. However, an important clarification made is that while this setup prevents the scriptSig from being altered by third parties in a way that could cause the associated outputs to be spent unintentionally, it does not strictly mandate that the scriptSig conforms exactly to this template. It is highlighted that the entire scriptSig logic could potentially be bypassed, leaving only the signature on the stack, which points to an inherent flexibility within the scripting mechanism.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-21T16:18:03.268000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
