<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Betting on Bitcoin Upgrades: A Smart Contract Wager on OP_CAT Activation</title>
  <updated>2025-04-24T02:43:54.138787+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt 2025-04-23 22:55:06.036000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Betting on Bitcoin Upgrades: A Smart Contract Wager on OP_CAT Activation</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T02:43:54.138818+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/betting-on-bitcoin-upgrades-a-smart-contract-wager-on-op-cat-activation/1632/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of `SCRIPT_VERIFY_DISCOURAGE_OP_SUCCESS` plays a critical role in determining the outcome of scripts that contain `OP_SUCCESSx` operations within the Bitcoin protocol. This rule essentially dictates that any script featuring `OP_SUCCESSx` is set to fail immediately, contradicting the assumption that it would succeed. The implementation of this standardness rule is significant for the security and reliability of script execution in Bitcoin transactions. The detailed code references provided, located at [Bitcoin's GitHub repository](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/e5a00b24972461f7a181bc184dd461cedcce6161/src/policy/policy.hL126) and [here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/e5a00b24972461f7a181bc184dd461cedcce6161/src/script/interpreter.cppL1803), offer insight into how this policy is applied within the Bitcoin codebase.

Further exploration of this topic updates an original article which discusses the implications of betting on Bitcoin upgrades, particularly focusing on the activation of `OP_CAT`. This discussion is available through an updated post found at [the original article](https://scryptplatform.medium.com/betting-on-bitcoin-upgrades-a-smart-contract-wager-on-op-cat-activation-607c8f12da91). The article delves into the nuances of smart contract wagers related to the future activations and enhancements within the Bitcoin network, emphasizing the practical applications and potential pitfalls of relying on certain operational codes. The consideration of miner collusion with entities like Bob by disabling `SCRIPT_VERIFY_DISCOURAGE_OP_SUCCESS` highlights the complexities and risks associated with script execution policies and their enforcement in the decentralized landscape of Bitcoin mining and transaction validation.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-23T22:55:06.036000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
