<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-04-26T02:28:53.601429+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-25T15:55:43.571000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-04-26T02:28:53.601455+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation revolves around a specific technical challenge concerning transaction inputs within a cryptographic context, specifically the notion that "inputA is spendable only together with inputB." This implies a requirement for transaction inputs to be jointly authorized in order to be utilized, suggesting a layered complexity in transaction validation and execution mechanisms. The solution proposed involves the utilization of signatures through a concept referred to as SIGHASH_GROUP. This approach would ostensibly allow for a straightforward resolution to the issue at hand by enabling grouped or linked inputs to be signed collectively, thereby satisfying the condition that both inputs must be authorized simultaneously.

However, the discourse highlights a significant obstacle: the SIGHASH_GROUP solution, while theoretically viable, has not been implemented or formally proposed within the relevant technological frameworks. This gap between conceptual solution and practical application underscores a broader theme in cryptographic development and blockchain technology, where innovative solutions often face hurdles in implementation due to the nascent state of the field or the complexity of deploying new protocols on existing networks.

Moreover, there's an ongoing debate within the community regarding the best path forward. While the signature-based solution offers one avenue, there's a contrasting preference for a method known as introspection over signatures. This alternative approach suggests a diverging viewpoint on how best to address the requirement for linked input authorization, reflecting the dynamic nature of technological evolution and the variety of perspectives within the field. Each approach carries its own set of implications for security, efficiency, and compatibility, underscoring the multifaceted challenges involved in advancing cryptographic technologies and blockchain infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-25T15:55:43.571000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
