<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
  <updated>2025-04-28T02:44:25.047126+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-27T12:48:37.275000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T02:44:25.047163+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-path-to-general-computation-on-bitcoin-with-op-cat/1106/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the capabilities and limitations of LNhance in the context of STARK proof verification, particularly focusing on its compatibility with `CTV` and `CSFS` protocols, and the `PAIRCOMMIT` function. The exploration begins by acknowledging LNhance's support for covenant mechanisms through `CTV` and `CSFS`, alongside its provision for multi-commitments via `PAIRCOMMIT`. However, it highlights a significant gap in enabling functional STARK proofs, an advanced cryptographic proof system designed for scalability and efficiency.

STARK proof verification necessitates specific functionalities to be viable, including the ability to carry data across transactions. This is crucial to divide the verifier process into manageable segments, given the constraints imposed by limited stack sizes, such as those encountered with a 1000-element stack. Moreover, the process requires the capability to decommit data from Merkle trees and conduct algebraic checks on this decommitted data, ensuring integrity and correctness. Additionally, deriving randomness from a Fiat-Shamir hash accumulation is essential for the security and unpredictability of the proofs.

The analysis points out a potential shortfall in `PAIRCOMMIT`’s design, suggesting it may not adequately support the second requirement of Merkle-decommitment and algebraic validation of data. This limitation raises concerns about its applicability in achieving the third necessity of deriving randomness, especially considering the protocol's reliance on large hash elements for generating subsequent data critical for the remainder of the protocol.

Furthermore, the challenge of transporting data between transactions, as required for splitting the verifier into multiple manageable transactions, remains unresolved with just `CTV` and `CSFS`. This indicates a need for additional mechanisms or enhancements to fully realize STARK proof verification within the discussed framework, underscoring the complexity and multifaceted nature of implementing such cryptographic proofs effectively.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-27T12:48:37.275000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
