<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
  <updated>2025-04-29T02:40:43.613120+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.398000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-04-28T21:44:53.398000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
    <updated>2025-04-29T02:40:43.613158+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-path-to-general-computation-on-bitcoin-with-op-cat/1106/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the intricacies of utilizing PAIRCOMMIT in conjunction with a storage strategy that limits elements to 4 bytes each. This limitation raises questions about its applicability, particularly in relation to the M31 field and how such a constraint might influence the distribution of funds. The discussion highlights a common challenge: constructing a CTV (Constructive Transaction Verification) hash or a hash of a signature on stack, which, although simplified by the use of CAT (Concatenation Authenticated Tree), remains a point of complexity.

Further exploration reveals an interest in leveraging CAT not just for its basic functionality but for its potential to facilitate SPLIT operations. This involves segmenting a cryptographic hash into arithmetically manageable pieces, suggesting a nuanced approach to dealing with large data elements within the constraints of the protocol.

The dialogue also touches upon the limitations of existing technologies like LNhance, noting its lack of generic data carrying capabilities. This limitation underscores a broader challenge in achieving certain technical objectives, such as item 1, through the combined use of CTV and CSFS (Cryptographic Sequenced Fragment Sharing), indicating a gap in current methodologies or tools available to developers in this context.

Overall, the exchange encapsulates a technical discourse focused on optimizing data storage and manipulation techniques within blockchain protocols while navigating the constraints and capabilities of current cryptographic and data structuring solutions.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T21:44:53.398000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
