<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2025-04-30T02:41:33.763145+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2025-04-29 23:42:53.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T02:41:33.763176+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recommendation to remove SQIsign from BIP-360 stems from two primary concerns. Firstly, the lack of standardization presents a significant drawback. Standardization is crucial for ensuring that protocols and algorithms can be widely adopted and implemented consistently across different platforms and applications. Without this, the integration and interoperability of technologies become challenging, impeding their adoption and utility.

Secondly, there have been reports indicating that the verification times for SQIsign are notably slow. In the context of blockchain and cryptographic applications, efficiency and speed are vital. Slow verification times can lead to bottlenecks, affecting the overall performance and user experience of the system. This aspect is especially critical in environments where timely processing of transactions or data is required to maintain system integrity and trust.

Considering these factors, the removal of SQIsign from BIP-360 appears to be a prudent decision aimed at enhancing the protocol's efficiency and reliability. It reflects an acknowledgment of the importance of both standardization and performance in the development and implementation of cryptographic protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-29T23:42:53.979000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
