<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
  <updated>2025-04-24T02:42:37.716894+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-23 11:11:19.978000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-04-18 12:31:09.945000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-07 20:20:58.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-05 01:08:43.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4861_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4826_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4223_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4171_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T02:42:37.716949+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/spanning-forest-cluster-linearization/1419" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The analysis of the spanning-forest linearization (SFL) algorithm presents an in-depth comparison with other algorithms like the GGT and CSS, focusing on optimizing linearization processes within computational systems. The SFL algorithm is highlighted for its potential to guarantee optimal linearization outcomes upon successful termination. However, concerns are raised regarding its consistency in achieving termination. Fuzzing tests indicate that the heuristic approach of merging chunks based on maximum feerate differences could mitigate the risk of repetitive states, attributing to the finite nature of possible states and suggesting a path towards ensuring algorithmic termination. Despite this, the complexity bound of the SFL algorithm remains a challenge, with a basic upper limit deduced from the finite state space providing little practical insight due to its vastness. A more refined approach considers the active dependencies arranged as a spanning forest, yielding an exponential complexity bound but within a slightly more constrained context.

The discussion further delves into the issues surrounding equal-feerate chunk splitting within the SFL algorithm's framework. The current design necessitates a delicate balance between splitting and merging chunks based on their feerate differences to circumvent infinite loops or non-topological outcomes. This underscores an ongoing quest for an efficient method to split chunks into topologically valid, separate equal-feerate components. Additionally, the granularity within chunks poses another layer of complexity, as the SFL framework lacks a mechanism for ordering transactions at a sub-chunk level, thus impacting block building processes that require finer granularity. The exploration of LIMO-like improvements is deemed valuable, suggesting that directed steps within an SFL state could result in linearizations at least as beneficial as rearranging subsets, thereby enhancing the algorithm's efficiency through ancestor set integration.

The programmer’s contribution to improving the `Linearize()` function in Bitcoin Core is notable, with the updated version demonstrating significant performance enhancements over the master branch across various challenging clusters encountered on the network. Benchmark comparisons reveal substantial reductions in processing time, highlighting the new implementation's efficiency gains and its potential in handling transactions previously considered difficult by existing standards.

A work in progress on a cluster linearization algorithm, specifically the spanning-forest cluster linearization algorithm, introduces a novel approach potentially superior for real-life applications compared to existing algorithms. The simplicity, speed, and elegance of this new method, despite lacking known complexity bounds, provide a promising alternative. The concept of cluster linearization as a Linear Programming (LP) problem facilitates a polynomial-time solution via LP solving algorithms, such as Interior Point Methods. This revelation that the problem is not NP-hard opens avenues for employing linear programming techniques. Moreover, the simplex algorithm's adaptation to this problem area showcases an iterative process that partitions the transaction graph into "chunks," optimizing the LP problem within a feasible time frame.

Significant modifications to the simplex algorithm have led to the development of the spanning forest linearization algorithm. This algorithm maintains a boolean for each dependency in the graph, with operations of merging and splitting chunks based on feerate comparisons aiming for optimal linearization. The output is an ordered set of chunks, sorted from high to low feerate, each in a valid topological order. The refinements made to ensure correctness and efficiency, including prioritizing merges over splits and selecting dependencies to activate or deactivate based on specific criteria, underscore the algorithm's potential for real-world application. The pragmatic focus remains on achieving a "good enough" linearization swiftly for defined cluster sizes, considering improvement per unit of time as essential for evaluating the algorithm's practical utility.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-23T11:11:19.978000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
