<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core 29.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-04-03T02:28:42.814750+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow.251000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  ..819000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4680_Bitcoin-Core-29-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4595_Bitcoin-Core-29-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core 29.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T02:28:42.814788+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-29-0-release-candidate-is-available/1536" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Bitcoin Core project has progressed with the release of its latest version, v29.0rc3, further advancing from its previous iteration, v29.0rc2. This development is accessible through the project's [official website](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-29.0/test.rc2) and marks a pivotal upgrade in the Bitcoin Core software. The availability of this release candidate signifies an important phase in the software’s lifecycle, reflecting its readiness for broader testing and feedback from the community.

Significantly, the source code for this version has been shared on [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v29.0rc2), inviting contributions and reviews from developers and users alike. The community's participation is deemed essential for refining the software, as feedback and issue reporting are highly encouraged through the project's [GitHub Issues page](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/32052). This collaborative approach aims to identify and resolve any critical problems that could impede the software's performance or security.

Assuming the testing phase concludes without uncovering major issues, v29.0rc3 is set to be officially released as version 29.0. This step is crucial for the evolution and stability of the Bitcoin Core software, demonstrating a commitment to continuous improvement and reliability. The process from a release candidate to an official release underscores the meticulous development and testing regimen adopted by the Bitcoin Core team to ensure the highest standards are met.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-02T17:22:03.251000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
