<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Satoshi Style Message Signing</title>
  <updated>2025-04-04T02:28:07.001771+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>satsie  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>satsie  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4686_Satoshi-Style-Message-Signing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2365_Satoshi-Style-Message-Signing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2362_Satoshi-Style-Message-Signing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2361_Satoshi-Style-Message-Signing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2360_Satoshi-Style-Message-Signing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Satoshi Style Message Signing</title>
    <updated>2025-04-04T02:28:07.001827+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/satoshi-style-message-signing/850" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an acknowledgment of the clarification provided by @sipa regarding a series of steps related to Bitcoin's message signing and encoding mechanism, which was not originally developed by Satoshi Nakamoto. This clarification was crucial in resolving a query, and the interaction also appreciates the contributions from @ajtowns and mentions the intention to update a wiki with this newfound information to share with a broader audience. There is an emphasis on the collaborative effort that led to the resolution of the mystery, highlighting the value of community engagement in the cryptocurrency space.

The email references a specific pull request on GitHub by sipa, which serves as a key resource for understanding the discussed mechanism. This pull request, along with extended discussions on the BitcoinTalk forum, is pointed out as essential for those looking to delve deeper into the project's documentation needs. The absence of comprehensive documentation within the project is noted, suggesting that an update could enhance clarity and accessibility for the community.

The technical procedure for signing a message with Bitcoin involves several steps, starting with the serialization of the string "Bitcoin Signed Message:\n" followed by the intended message. This serialized data is then double SHA-256 hashed, and an ECDSA signature is generated using the private key associated with a legacy P2PKH address. This method is widely adopted across various hardware and software projects due to its ability to verify the integrity of hardware controlling keys, underlining its significance in protecting against bit rot. However, despite its widespread use and origin within Bitcoin Core code developed by Satoshi Nakamoto, there is a notable lack of comprehensive technical documentation, with some attempts made to document the process on the Bitcoin Wiki and other resources.

The email further explains that while there are tools and resources available that attempt to support message signing across different address types, the original "Satoshi format" remains inadequately documented. This situation indicates either a challenge in deciphering existing materials or highlights the considerable effort required to understand Satoshi's message signing technique without a consolidated guide. The existence of BIP-137, BIP-notatether-messageverify, and BIP-322 demonstrates significant advancements in addressing message signing for other address types, yet the comprehensive documentation and understanding of the original format continue to be elusive.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T04:41:01.391000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
