<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-04-06T02:42:36.617849+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T02:42:36.617904+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discourse around enhancements to the Lightning Network's handling of Hash Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs) illuminates a multifaceted approach to optimizing transaction protocols. A key focus is on addressing the inherent latency issues introduced by a bug fix in the protocol. This fix inadvertently extends the transaction resolution time, thus amplifying the latency from 1.5 round-trip times (RTTs) to 2.5 RTTs for certain transactions. Notably, a proposed solution to mitigate this latency involves a nuanced two-step update process for commitment transactions, which suggests an integration of increased burn funds before the addition of the HTLC output. This methodology aims at streamlining the transactional flow by enabling downstream nodes to provide consecutive updates without necessitating additional RTTs. This adjustment not only seeks to preserve the original latency benchmarks but also introduces a refined mechanism for managing hold fees within the framework of not-immediately-settled payments.

The dialogue further delves into the strategic implementation of hold fees, highlighting their potential to equitably compensate nodes involved in the delayed transmission of payments. This concept is explored through the lens of Modified Adjusted Duration (MAD)-based Optimistic Payment Routing (OPR) protocols, which advocate for a balance between immediate settlement and deferred payment facilitation. The introduction of [hold invoices](https://bitcoinops.org/en/topics/hold-invoices/) emerges as a pivotal element in this discussion, underscoring the significance of ensuring fair remuneration for nodes facilitating the payment forwarding process.

On the other hand, concerns are raised regarding the manipulation of held HTLCs, exposing vulnerabilities within the network's operational protocol that could lead to financial exploitation. An illustrative scenario depicts a manipulative strategy where a node, referred to as Bob, becomes ensnared in a scheme orchestrated by another node, Mallory, resulting in undue financial burdens on Bob through accumulated hold fees and potential force-closure of channels. This exploitation underscores the critical need for a reliable mechanism to address unwarranted hold fees and safeguard against such manipulative tactics.

Building upon foundational proposals by Jager and Teinturier, subsequent enhancements aim to fortify the network against spam and inefficiency while ensuring equitable fee distribution among nodes. These improvements introduce mechanisms like secrets for payment confirmation and burn outputs, designed to deter fee misappropriation and encourage cooperative behavior across the network. The delineation of Upfront Fees, Hold Fees, and Success Fees constitutes a comprehensive fee structure that compensates nodes for their varying contributions to the payment process. The innovative use of a burn output, claimable after two decades, emerges as a novel incentive for adherence to cooperative principles within the network.

In summary, the ongoing evolution of the Lightning Network's protocol embodies a concerted effort to refine transaction processes, mitigate vulnerabilities, and foster a more secure, efficient, and equitable ecosystem. Through a combination of technological innovation and strategic protocol adjustments, these developments herald a promising trajectory towards optimizing the network's performance and user experience.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-05T19:42:07.993000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
