<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-05-25T02:54:19.318370+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-05-24 18:41:51.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-21 09:45:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh  . 2025-05-21 06:34:14.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5113_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5072_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5070_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-05-25T02:54:19.318467+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>An innovative rust library named `descriptor-encrypt` has been introduced, designed to encrypt any descriptor ensuring that only authorized spenders can decrypt it. This library aligns the access control policy with the spending policy of the descriptor, supporting all descriptor types alongside miniscript. It features a tag-based and variable-length encoding scheme to minimize encrypted data size. Notably, its "full secrecy" mode allows for the encrypted data to be stored publicly without revealing any information about the descriptor or even its existence unless sufficient seeds are compromised to spend the funds. This development aims to address complex wallet setups incorporating elements like hash-lock or time-lock, presenting a solution to previous concerns about handling such configurations. Further details and demonstrations of this library can be found on its [GitHub page](https://github.com/joshdoman/descriptor-encrypt) and through a dedicated [demo website](https://descriptorencrypt.org).

The conversation extends into the broader subject of cryptographic backups, particularly focusing on the importance of backing up public keys and descriptors/wallet policies. This shift from focusing solely on secret protection highlights the critical role of public keys and wallet configurations in maintaining operational continuity and security in digital asset management. The lack of extensive documentation on this subject underlines the need for a robust backup strategy that addresses the recoverability and management of these components, suggesting an area ripe for further exploration.

In comparing the discussed encryption method to Superbacked, a tool aimed at enhancing developer productivity, several key distinctions emerge. Superbacked stands out for its comprehensive feature set, collaboration facilitation, and strong community support. Its adaptability across different programming environments and emphasis on security demonstrate its utility as a valuable resource for developers. The comparison sheds light on Superbacked’s role in streamlining workflow and promoting effective collaboration among programming teams.

The proposed encryption scheme for multisig wallets introduces a nuanced method for managing and recovering critical information, highlighting a balance between security and recoverability. It incorporates Shamir's Secret Sharing to ensure that encrypted data can be accessed only by individuals possessing specific extended public keys (xpubs). This approach adds complexity but increases manageability, suggesting a thoughtful balance between securing wallets against unauthorized access and ensuring legitimate users can recover their assets under adverse conditions.

Error correction mechanisms are emphasized for prolonging the viability of data storage, acknowledging the inherent limitations and challenges of backup strategies. A nuanced understanding of data storage and preservation is advocated, balancing advanced error correction techniques with practical considerations of backup strategies.

The correspondence also explores enhancing security through selective generation of component keys and leveraging different entropy sources for key generation. Concerns regarding the accessibility of backups and the integration with hardware signers are discussed, pointing towards a more controlled access system and the necessity of incorporating error correction mechanisms for reliability.

Furthermore, the discussion highlights the critical difference between seeds and descriptors in cryptocurrency wallets, emphasizing the unique risks associated with not properly backing up wallet descriptors, particularly in multisig setups. A potential scheme combining symmetric and asymmetric encryption techniques is proposed to minimize backup size while ensuring determinism and security.

Lastly, there is a suggestion for collaborative improvement of backup schemes, integrating standardization efforts with innovative features to enhance security and reliability comprehensively. This proposition suggests a communal effort towards developing a more robust solution for the cryptocurrency community.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-24T18:41:51.470000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
