<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-04-11T02:36:44.212718+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ekrembal 2025-04-10 16:09:12.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Cyimon 2025-04-10 14:28:23.711000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4747_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4746_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-04-11T02:36:44.212755+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion focuses on a transaction graph designed for a system that aims to enhance the efficiency of collateral usage by operators within a specific framework, presumably associated with blockchain or cryptocurrency transactions. This system allows operators to provide signatures at the time of deposit, which are represented by red arrows in the provided transaction graph. A key feature of this system is that every kickoff must be finalized before an operator can send a "ready-to-reimburse transaction." Finalization can occur through either a "challenge timeout transaction" or a "disprove timeout transaction," providing flexibility in handling transactions.

One of the strengths of the proposed system is its ability to process kickoffs in parallel. This means that multiple withdrawals can be managed simultaneously using a single collateral, potentially increasing throughput and efficiency. However, there's a critical safeguard in place: if any one of the kickoffs is disproven, all reimbursements are halted. This mechanism likely serves as a risk management strategy to protect against fraudulent or erroneous transactions.

Despite the innovative approach, the system faces certain limitations that are acknowledged in the communication. Notably, the integration of a Bitcoin light client is necessary to prove the inclusion of the payout transaction and the state of the side system. The development team is still working on this aspect, indicating ongoing efforts to overcome technical challenges. Furthermore, the need for publishing all operators' signatures poses a challenge due to the limited block space available on Bitcoin, suggesting data availability issues that could impact the system's reliability and scalability.

The sender also mentions an attempt to integrate OP_CTV in BitVM2 Bridge, inspired by an idea from the recipient, and provides a graph illustrating their implementation. They seek feedback on potential mistakes in their approach, indicating a collaborative effort to refine and improve the transaction system. This exchange highlights an active process of development and problem-solving aimed at enhancing the functionality and efficiency of the proposed system.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-10T16:09:12.124000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
