<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Betting on Bitcoin Upgrades: A Smart Contract Wager on OP_CAT Activation</title>
  <updated>2025-04-23T02:44:39.414310+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt 2025-04-22 21:35:03.943000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-22 19:39:02.776000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-04-22 19:38:02.801000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt 2025-04-22 18:50:56.557000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-04-22 18:18:47.811000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin 2025-04-22 15:49:36.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt-ts 2025-04-22 09:42:38.587000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4860_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4858_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4859_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4857_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4855_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4853_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4852_Betting-on-Bitcoin-Upgrades-A-Smart-Contract-Wager-on-OP-CAT-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Betting on Bitcoin Upgrades: A Smart Contract Wager on OP_CAT Activation</title>
    <updated>2025-04-23T02:44:39.414379+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/betting-on-bitcoin-upgrades-a-smart-contract-wager-on-op-cat-activation/1632" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an innovative approach to betting on Bitcoin's future upgrades, a smart contract wager specifically focuses on the activation of OP_CAT, a proposal under BIP 0347 that aims to enhance Bitcoin’s scripting capabilities. This feature would allow for the concatenation of two stack elements, paving the way for more complex covenants and smart contracts within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The unique aspect of this bet lies in its trustless, oracle-free nature, relying solely on existing Bitcoin opcodes to ensure a fair resolution between two parties, Alice and Bob, who are betting on whether OP_CAT will be activated by a certain block height.

The smart contract designed for this bet is crafted to overcome the challenges posed by OP_SUCCESS126, a placeholder opcode which, prior to OP_CAT's activation, would automatically cause any script executing it to succeed. This behavior could potentially disrupt the logic of the bet by allowing funds to be claimed prematurely. To counteract this, the contract incorporates specific conditions that differentiate between the pre-activation state of OP_SUCCESS126 and the post-activation functionality of OP_CAT, without the need for external data.

The contract utilizes a Taproot output with a single script path/tapleaf containing two conditional branches. These branches include mechanisms such as an absolute timelock, set through OP_CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY (CLTV), to prevent either party from spending before the agreed-upon deadline. A notable detail is the addition of a time delay (`delta`) for Alice, ensuring that Bob has the opportunity to claim the bet should OP_CAT not be reactivated by the specified block height, thereby preventing Alice from front-running Bob.

This betting mechanism not only demonstrates the potential for creating self-enforcing prediction markets within the Bitcoin network but also highlights the technical considerations and safeguards necessary to implement such a system effectively. It eliminates the need for soft forks or reliance on third-party arbitrators like traditional betting platforms, offering a purely Bitcoin-native solution. The discussion also briefly touches upon the concept of Miner Extractable Value (MEV) and its implications for the bet, although it concludes that MEV risks are considered limited and out of scope for this particular analysis.

The proposition underscores the evolving landscape of Bitcoin and the broader cryptocurrency ecosystem, where such innovations can foster new forms of financial commitment and speculation based on protocol developments. This method sets a precedent for future bets on cryptocurrency protocols, illustrating the practical application of Bitcoin’s scripting language to create novel, decentralized financial instruments.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-22T21:35:03.943000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
