<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-05-22T02:50:06.326245+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-05-21 09:45:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh 2025-05-21 06:34:14.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5072_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5070_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T02:50:06.326334+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers on the nuanced strategies for backing up cryptographic information, particularly within the Bitcoin environment, focusing on the balance between security and recoverability. The innovative approach discussed involves leveraging public keys and wallet descriptors to facilitate a secure yet accessible backup solution. This method contrasts with traditional methods by emphasizing the conditional secrecy based upon not having a specific descriptor, which introduces a unique mechanism for managing critical information such as multisig wallet descriptors and BIP policies. It explores the resilience of this strategy in scenarios like loss due to unforeseen circumstances, utilizing a recovery process that allows for the retrieval of information using any remaining signing device. The technical aspect entails generating a secret from a public key to decrypt the backup payload, highlighting an experimental decryption process that requires multiple candidate keys or hints for identifying the correct decryption key.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the challenges of data storage decay over time, advocating for the inclusion of self-healing mechanisms in backups to ensure longevity and reliability. It suggests expanding the backup format to incorporate more data types through a simple JSON structure for greater flexibility. The security implications of storing encrypted descriptors publicly or on compromised servers are discussed, acknowledging the trade-off necessary for recoverability. The use of Shamir's Secret Sharing and encryption with xpubs is mentioned as adding complexity to the recovery process while enhancing security.

The dialogue also addresses enhancing security through selective generation of component keys and controlled access to encrypted backups, contrasting simpler schemes with no such restrictions. The need for physical presence of hardware signers during backup creation introduces limitations for certain wallets, suggesting the incorporation of error correction mechanisms for increased reliability. Various alternatives for creating multiple backup copies are proposed, including cloud storage, direct messaging, and decentralized networks.

In an effort to improve multisig wallet security, a distinct encryption scheme is proposed, tying the accessibility of the wallet's encrypted descriptor to the possession of specific extended public keys (xpubs). This method aims to mitigate risks associated with compromised server storage by ensuring only individuals with the required xpubs can decrypt and access the multisig descriptor. The use of Shamir's Secret Sharing algorithm is central to this strategy, dividing the secret for accessing the multisig descriptor into several shares, each encrypted with a unique xpub. This introduces a layer of security that distinguishes authorized users from attackers.

The importance of careful language use in documentation to prevent misunderstandings is underscored, alongside the necessity for backing up wallet descriptors in cryptocurrency wallets, especially multisig configurations. The risk of irreversible fund loss due to improper backup practices is highlighted, proposing a combination of symmetric and asymmetric encryption techniques for a secure backup scheme. The project [liana](https://github.com/wizardsardine/liana) is recommended for effective timelocked recovery mechanisms, addressing seed mismanagement risks.

Lastly, the potential privacy and security vulnerabilities associated with descriptors, particularly when they include private keys, are discussed. This emphasizes the requirement for stringent security measures to protect against unauthorized access. A shared GitHub repository and detailed posts provide resources for developers and users interested in enhancing multisig security. The correspondence also suggests a collaborative effort to standardize one method before integrating aspects of another, aiming to combine strengths for a more comprehensive backup solution.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-21T09:45:02.701000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
