<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-04-15T02:43:47.713931+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>neha  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4759_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4642_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4601_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4594_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4590_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4589_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4583_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4560_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4559_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T02:43:47.714013+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency transactions, particularly within the Ark protocol, there are significant discussions around the challenges and solutions associated with ensuring secure and efficient payment processes. The primary concerns revolve around mitigating Denial of Service (DoS) attacks and managing liquidity lockup risks. DoS attacks pose a threat by potentially causing transaction rounds to fail, necessitating retries and thus affecting all round participants. Liquidity lockup becomes an issue when servers hold funds in anticipation of a transaction completion that may never occur due to users not revealing preimages. A proposed mitigation strategy involves servicing only users with a proven record of good behavior or those who can prove ownership of existing assets, albeit both approaches have their limitations.

The utilization of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) is highlighted as a crucial mechanism for enhancing security and efficiency in such transactions. CTV facilitates the reduction of vulnerability to DoS attacks by eliminating the need for receiver participation in transaction rounds. However, the risk associated with non-revelation of preimages persists, calling for innovative strategies like those found in Just-In-Time (JIT) channels. These strategies involve varying levels of trust in the Lightning Service Provider (LSP) and include splitting payments into two invoices to mitigate risks associated with preimage disclosure.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the dual roles of participants in communication networks, emphasizing the importance of active engagement in sending and receiving messages. This dynamic is pivotal for the effective exchange of information and underscores the necessity for participants to be present for both actions.

Another aspect discussed is the option for users to refresh their Unspent Transaction Output (VTXO) during a transaction round. This process restores the trust level of the VTXO, as outputs directly from a round carry a standard trust assumption. This mechanism simplifies transactions on the client's side and enhances security and trust in the process.

The Arkoor model offers insights into managing liquidity costs associated with refreshing VTXOs. Users face a decision between opting for full trustless ownership by refreshing early, which incurs higher fees, or accepting a temporary trust assumption to save on fees. The model also addresses vulnerabilities to DoS attacks by requiring active user participation and implementing penalties for non-cooperative behaviors.

Lastly, the discussion explores the statechain model, where a VTXO remains trustless as long as the server does not collude with any previous owner. This model reduces trust requirements and allows users to refresh their VTXO, exiting the reduced trust model. Yet, it also introduces a liquidity fee structure that encourages users to delay refreshing their VTXOs to reduce costs.

In conclusion, the integration of CTV within the Ark protocol presents a multifaceted approach to addressing security and efficiency in cryptocurrency transactions. From mitigating DoS attacks and managing liquidity lockups to facilitating secure and non-interactive transactions, the ongoing developments in Ark signal significant advancements in the landscape of cryptocurrency protocols. Additional resources and discussions on these topics are available through links such as the [original thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), the [Ark case for CTV](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733), and the [Ark protocol introduction](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/vtxos/index.html), providing further avenues for exploration and understanding in this evolving field.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T12:24:36.269000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
