<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
  <updated>2025-04-30T02:40:58.030862+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Laz1m0v.925000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..398000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  ..275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  ..574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..168000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Lazmv  ..575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  ..206000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4892_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4890_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4886_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4879_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4880_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4784_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4714_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3081_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T02:40:58.030935+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-path-to-general-computation-on-bitcoin-with-op-cat/1106" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around Bitcoin's script functionality, particularly concerning statefulness and the implementation of smart contracts or covenants, reveals a complex landscape of technical challenges and innovations. The core of the discussion is the assertion that Bitcoin scripts are inherently not stateful, a characteristic that can be augmented through external mechanisms such as indexers and trackers. This opens up the possibility for Bitcoin nodes to evolve in a manner that allows them to handle evolving states, though it raises questions about the direct storage of state information within nodes and the potential need for integrating covenants trackers.

One key point of contention is the use of the term "covenant" rather than "smart contract." The critique suggests a nuanced understanding of smart contracts as requiring automatic transaction triggers, a feature absent from Bitcoin due to the lack of an `OP_CALL` function. This limitation underscores a fundamental difference between Bitcoin's capabilities and those of platforms designed to support complex decentralized applications. However, covenants are presented as a viable alternative for embedding programmable logic within Bitcoin transactions, albeit with constraints compared to traditional smart contracts.

The conversation also explores the technicalities of implementing such features on the Bitcoin blockchain, including the management of state information and the specifics of covenant-based systems. Notably, the use of OP_CAT for concatenation and its implications for both covenant implementation and STARK proofs are discussed. STARKs, or Scalable Transparent ARgument of Knowledge, represent a cutting-edge approach to enhancing Bitcoin's utility by enabling the verification of off-chain computations on-chain. This is seen as a critical step toward achieving more sophisticated applications on Bitcoin, further emphasized by the potential re-enablement of OP_CAT. This opcode, disabled since 2010, is identified as a simple yet powerful tool that could unlock nearly unlimited expressibility and computational capabilities on Bitcoin through a soft fork.

Moreover, the email addresses the practical application of these concepts through the example of a Circle-STARK verifier, demonstrating the feasibility of verifying states on Bitcoin. This serves as a tangible illustration of the ongoing efforts to expand Bitcoin's functionalities beyond mere transactions. Despite the enthusiasm for these advancements, there is a call for clarity and accuracy in discussing Bitcoin's capabilities, specifically urging a distinction between the terms "covenants" and "smart contracts" to maintain conceptual integrity.

In essence, the dialogue encapsulates a broader debate on enhancing Bitcoin's blockchain technology. It reflects an exploration of leveraging existing mechanisms and emerging technologies to push the boundaries of what is traditionally achievable on Bitcoin, aiming to increase its utility without compromising core principles. The focus on OP_CAT, alongside the integration of covenants and STARK proofs, highlights a pathway towards realizing advanced computational and contractual capabilities on the Bitcoin network, signaling a future where Bitcoin could accommodate a wider array of decentralized applications and functionalities.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-29T11:11:55.925000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
