<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-04-25T02:43:18.415103+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-04-25T02:43:18.415180+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion spans across various aspects of enhancing cryptographic systems, specifically targeting the security and reliability of generating and storing secrets in a multi-key setup. A significant focus is on controlling access to secrets by not generating key parts for individuals who should not have access, thereby directly managing who can obtain the secret. This method underscores the importance of utilizing different entropy sources or paths for generating these keys, aiming to standardize the process and potentially integrate hardware features for future security enhancements. However, this introduces a requirement for all devices involved to contribute their key parts for the backup process, marking a shift from the current setup where any single participant can initiate an encrypted backup.

A noteworthy proposal centers on the encryption scheme designed for multisig wallets, which intricately ties the accessibility of a wallet's encrypted descriptor to the possession of specific extended public keys (xpubs). This scheme leverages Shamir's Secret Sharing algorithm to divide the secret necessary for accessing the multisig descriptor into several shares, each encrypted with a unique xpub. This method ensures that decryption requires possession of at least a specified number of xpubs, hence adding a layer of complexity while maintaining manageability. The scheme addresses the risk of storing encrypted data on compromised servers by ensuring that only individuals with the required xpubs can decrypt and access the multisig descriptor.

Additionally, the dialogue touches upon the criticality of backing up wallet descriptors in cryptocurrency wallets, especially those not employing a single-signature mechanism. The lack of a standardized method for wallet backups is highlighted, alongside the flawed approach of treating descriptors as seeds due to their differing levels of sensitivity and associated risks. A proposed backup scheme combines symmetric and asymmetric encryption techniques, aiming to minimize backup size while simplifying the encryption process. This deterministic encryption approach, although deviating from traditional semantic security standards, is deemed sufficiently secure within the specific context of wallet backup.

The conversation further explores the privacy and security implications of descriptors and xpubs in the realm of cryptocurrency, emphasizing the need for stringent security measures to safeguard these elements from unauthorized access. Descriptors, capable of including private keys, pose a heightened risk as they essentially serve as gateways to accessing and controlling cryptocurrency funds directly.

Moreover, the correspondence sheds light on an alternative backup scheme for multisig wallets that utilizes shamir secret sharing to enhance security by encrypting each share of a secret with one xpub. This innovative method obfuscates the number of participants in the multisig setup from potential attackers and opts to keep derivation paths in plaintext for ease of xpub derivation. Resources such as GitHub repositories and detailed posts provide valuable insights into the operational intricacies and benefits of this backup scheme, alongside aspirations to extend support to more advanced multisig configurations.

Lastly, the discussion hints at a collaborative effort to combine the strengths of distinct methods proposed by individuals named Josh and Salvatore, suggesting an interest in creating a comprehensive solution that includes both standardized processes and innovative elements. This strategy emphasizes the potential benefits of integrating unique attributes such as inscription and location attributes, further contributing to the overarching goal of enhancing cryptographic system security.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-24T11:04:04.197000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
