<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
  <updated>2025-04-13T03:47:09.102975+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-04-12 20:12:21.932000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-04-12 15:37:45.129000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-04-09 16:06:58.169000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-03-17 18:49:16.589000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-03-17 18:25:33.005000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2025-03-17 16:59:40.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-03-17 13:42:37.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-03-17 12:29:05.169000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4752_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4751_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4738_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4562_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4561_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4555_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4553_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4551_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
    <updated>2025-04-13T03:47:09.103049+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkcontractverify-and-its-amount-semantic/1527" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with a focus on the potential issues arising from UTXOs with mutually exclusive spend conditions, specifically through examples involving `OP_CLTV` scripts that use block height and wall clock time. These conditions create scenarios where UTXOs cannot be simultaneously spent due to their reliance on the `nLockTime` field for validation, highlighting the limitations of Bitcoin's transaction validation mechanism. The critique underscores the importance of transactions as the fundamental unit of validation within the Bitcoin network, advocating for the introspection of anything within a transaction without extending this principle to external factors like block time or height. The conversation then explores the indirection used in BIP65/BIP112, which cleverly validates `nLockTime`/`nSequence` values before entering the interpreter, allowing for transactions that are valid under relay policy but may face mining issues due to `BIP113`'s median-time-past rules.

Further, the email delves into concerns regarding the proposal to introduce spillover effects across transaction inputs via amount checks, arguing against adding more complexity to the already intricate `CLTV`. Instead, it suggests an alternative approach leveraging a form of indirection akin to `CSV`, proposing constraints on output amounts enforced through new fields in each input, potentially within the annex section. This method would allow for pre-script execution validation of transaction inputs based on specified constraints, thus streamlining transaction validity checks at a granular level.

The discourse extends to the application of Conditional Close Verifiability (`CCV`) in state machines, emphasizing its utility in aligning input and output scripts through vault constructs and fee management strategies within covenant-based transactions. It presents CCV's adaptability in handling fees either through exogenous means or by incorporating features such as anchor outputs and package relay. The conversation further elaborates on the operational specifics of introducing input amounts onto the stack and the subsequent implications for script execution and transaction validation, specifically highlighting the potential for error when aggregating amounts without support for arbitrary-precision numbers.

In addressing transactions characterized by specific opcode applications, the discussion evaluates the feasibility and implications of "fan-in" and "fan-out" transaction patterns, probing into the opcode's flexibility in managing transaction fees and the potential for direct fee allocation through a "deduct" feature. Additionally, the email outlines a proposed enhancement to Bitcoin Script, aiming to improve the introspection of aggregate output amounts and the explicit forwarding of values, thereby refining the scripting language's functionality while acknowledging the inherent complexities and error risks.

Conclusively, the exploration of `OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` (`OP_CCV`) underscores its significance in advancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, particularly in enabling UTXOs to carry data and rules for introspection and modification upon spending. The integration of `OP_CCV` with Pay-to-Taproot (P2TR) inputs and outputs facilitates efficient keypath spending and data embedding, offering a robust framework for complex contract designs. The discussion encapsulates the community's engagement in refining the BIP proposal, reflecting on the theoretical and practical advancements it represents for Bitcoin's scripting environment.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T20:12:21.932000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
