<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
  <updated>2025-04-19T02:27:16.703560+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-18 12:31:09.945000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-07 20:20:58.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-05 01:08:43.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4826_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4223_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4171_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
    <updated>2025-04-19T02:27:16.703605+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/spanning-forest-cluster-linearization/1419" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The programmer's exploration into optimizing Bitcoin Core's `Linearize()` function has yielded substantial advancements, as illustrated through their updated version hosted on [GitHub](https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/spanning_tree_linearization). This new implementation significantly enhances performance in linearizing challenging transaction clusters encountered within the network. Such improvements are quantified by benchmark comparisons, which demonstrate considerable reductions in processing time for a range of transaction scenarios. For instance, one example showcased a reduction from 70.6 microseconds to 21.1 microseconds, with other transactions experiencing even more dramatic decreases in processing time. These enhancements indicate not only increased efficiency but also the potential for improved robustness in handling complex transactions.

In parallel, there is ongoing work on developing a new cluster linearization algorithm, identified as the spanning-forest cluster linearization algorithm. This novel approach has shown promise over existing algorithms employed in Bitcoin Core and various discussions within the domain. The algorithm's foundation lies in treating the linearization problem as a Linear Programming (LP) challenge, aiming to identify the highest-feerate topologically-valid subset of transactions within a cluster. Utilizing LP solving techniques such as Interior Point Methods indicates that the problem can be resolved in polynomial time, thus suggesting it is not NP-hard. This revelation paves the way for applying linear programming solutions more broadly in this context.

The article further delves into specifics about how the simplex algorithm is adapted for this purpose, detailing the process of partitioning the transaction graph into chunks connected by a spanning tree of free variables. The crux of the spanning forest linearization algorithm is its ability to merge and split these chunks based on feerate comparisons, striving for an optimal linearization. The algorithm ensures correctness by terminating with an optimal linearization, where no higher-feerate chunk depends on a lower-feerate one.

Moreover, the discussion touches upon several pivotal areas of concern and potential improvement within the current state of the algorithm. These include issues related to termination guarantees, complexity bounds, equal-feerate chunk splitting, sub-chunk linearization, LIMO-like improvements, and merging states. Each area presents its own set of challenges and opportunities for further refinement of the algorithm. Despite the absence of definitive complexity bounds, the focus remains on achieving practical, "good enough" linearizations swiftly for specified cluster sizes.

This dual narrative of technical enhancement and theoretical exploration underscores the dynamic evolution of Bitcoin Core's transaction processing capabilities. Through rigorous benchmarking and conceptual innovation, the programmer is actively contributing to the scalability and efficiency of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-18T12:31:09.945000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
