<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:23:49.768819+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ekrembal  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Cyimon  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5344_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4898_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4894_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4888_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4883_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4882_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4876_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4850_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4848_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4842_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4841_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4840_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4812_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4806_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4804_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4801_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4800_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4799_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4765_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4749_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4747_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4746_How-CTV-CSFS-improves-BitVM-bridges.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - How CTV+CSFS improves BitVM bridges</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:23:49.768979+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-ctv-csfs-improves-bitvm-bridges/1591/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an innovative exploration of Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, a novel method has been proposed to enhance transaction security and specificity through the use of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV). This technique facilitates a unique transaction condition where one input (inputA) is designated to be spendable only in conjunction with another specific input (inputB). To achieve this, inputB is initially defined as a legacy Pay to Script Hash (P2SH) output. A signature, presigned using the `ANYONECANPAY|NONE` sighash flag, commits exclusively to inputB, embedding the signature within inputB’s scriptSig due to P2SH's exclusion from SegWit. Subsequently, inputA is established as a Pay to Taproot (P2TR) output containing a CTV condition that commits to the scriptSigs, encapsulating the pre-signed signature for inputB. This effectively ensures that inputA commits to the signature for inputB, which in turn commits to inputB itself, thereby mandating that inputA can only be expended alongside inputB.

However, this method encounters limitations regarding its implementation, notably if inputA and inputB originate from the same transaction, resulting in a hash cycle that renders the method impractical. Additionally, the approach does not apply to child inputs derived from either inputA or inputB if connected through a series of CTV hashes, limiting the flexibility of this technique. Despite these challenges, the method highlights a sophisticated approach to leveraging Bitcoin's scripting language to secure transaction integrity, underscoring the ongoing evolution of blockchain technologies in addressing complex transaction conditions.

Further discussions delve into the broader implications and potential applications of Bitcoin covenants, showcasing their utility in creating more secure wallet technologies, facilitating inheritance solutions, and constructing vaults to safeguard against theft or loss. These advancements underscore a significant leap in programmability for Bitcoin transactions, allowing users to stipulate specific conditions for fund transfers, thereby enriching the security framework around digital currencies.

The discourse also corrects a crucial aspect concerning the usage of sighash flags in Bitcoin transactions, specifically highlighting the replacement of `SINGLE|NONE` with `ANYONECANPAY|NONE`. This correction is pivotal for developers and parties involved in constructing Bitcoin transactions where selective signing is critical, illustrating the nuanced functionalities provided by Bitcoin's sighash flags to foster flexible and secure transaction protocols.

Moreover, an intricate mechanism designed to optimize collateral utilization within a given system is examined. This setup requires operators to provide signatures at the deposit phase, enabling the processing of multiple withdrawals concurrently from a single collateral source. However, challenges such as the need for a Bitcoin light client to verify transaction inclusion and the sidesystem's current state, along with issues related to the publication of all operators' signatures, are identified. These obstacles highlight the ongoing efforts and complexities involved in enhancing the efficiency and security of Bitcoin transactions, reflecting the dynamic nature of cryptographic and blockchain development.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-25T19:39:15.940000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
