<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2025-09-06T02:20:55.122615+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kravens.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-05T11:25:31.138000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T02:20:55.122644+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/25" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release of Wasabi Wallet, version 2.7.0, has introduced features that significantly facilitate the operation of an anonymous coordinator via an onion service, exclusively accessible over the Tor network. This development is particularly notable against the backdrop of increasing instances where public or clearnet coordinators are being shut down. The expectation is that this will lead to a surge in the number of anonymous Tor-only coordinators, ensuring continued access to these services despite any adverse actions taken against public coordinators. The relevant details and access to the new wallet version can be found on their GitHub page, which is available at [https://github.com/WalletWasabi/WalletWasabi/releases/tag/v2.7.0](https://github.com/WalletWasabi/WalletWasabi/releases/tag/v2.7.0).

In light of these advancements, there's a significant advisory for users of BTCPay Server, specifically concerning the Coinjoin plugin. It appears that this plugin is no longer under active development, prompting a recommendation for users to transition to using Wasabi Wallet for running a coordinator. However, it's noted that the existing versions of the plugin can still be utilized, provided they remain compatible with future iterations of Wasabi Wallet. Despite the discontinuation of active development, there remains a noticeable demand for the Coinjoin plugin among users. As such, there's an open call for developers who are capable and willing to contribute towards its maintenance. Those interested in contributing or learning more about the current state of the plugin can do so by visiting [https://github.com/Kukks/BTCPayServerPlugins/tree/master/Plugins/BTCPayServer.Plugins.Wabisabi](https://github.com/Kukks/BTCPayServerPlugins/tree/master/Plugins/BTCPayServer.Plugins.Wabisabi). 

These developments underscore a pivotal moment for users and developers within the cryptocurrency community, emphasizing a shift towards enhancing privacy and security measures amidst a landscape of regulatory and technical challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T11:25:31.138000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
