<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:40.415402+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-05T11:40:27.839000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:40.415433+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/eclipsing-bitcoin-nodes-with-bgp-interception-attacks/1965/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the pursuit of enhancing security measures for Bitcoin nodes, the discussion revolves around the detection of BGP (Border Gateway Protocol) attacks through effective monitoring strategies. The utilization of honeypot monitoring nodes is highlighted as a proactive approach to safeguard these critical network components. The suggestion points towards the integration of an external monitoring tool specifically designed for Bitcoin Core. This tool would be instrumental in conducting periodic traceroutes to peers, alongside gathering essential data related to network reachability and Autonomous System (AS) path length. Such measures are deemed crucial for accumulating real-world data, which is imperative before any implementation within node software can be considered.

The reference to [b10c.me/projects/024-peer-observer](https://b10c.me/projects/024-peer-observer/) underscores the importance of leveraging current projects aimed at observing and analyzing the behavior of Bitcoin nodes under various network conditions. The proposal emphasizes not only the necessity of identifying potential BGP attacks but also the broader objective of enhancing node resilience through comprehensive monitoring and data collection strategies. By focusing on such aspects, the discussion contributes valuable insights into the development of more secure and robust Bitcoin network infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T11:40:27.839000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
