<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-09-07T02:37:43.341335+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-09-06 04:29:41.146000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-07T02:37:43.341375+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/eclipsing-bitcoin-nodes-with-bgp-interception-attacks/1965/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>When considering the implementation of countersign, it's highlighted that attacks would be significantly detectable by a small number of nodes if they employ authentication. This is primarily because an attacker wouldn't easily differentiate between connections that use authentication and those that do not, making it challenging to carry out man-in-the-middle (MITM) attacks on authenticated connections. The current landscape allows for some level of security through manual methods; for instance, if one knows some of their peers, they can manually compare session IDs to verify authenticity.

Furthermore, the utility of having an alternative internet connection is underlined as extremely valuable for enhancing security measures. Although acquiring an additional internet service might be expensive in many regions, the feasibility of installing a satellite feed receiver for the Blockstream satellite presents an innovative solution. This alternative not only offers another viewpoint but also adds an extra layer of security by diversifying the means through which data is received, thereby reducing reliance on a single internet source. This approach underscores the importance of employing diverse strategies to bolster security in the face of potential cyber attacks.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-06T04:29:41.146000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
