<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v29.1 Released</title>
  <updated>2025-09-11T02:26:37.354628+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-10T15:35:43.084000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v29.1 Released</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T02:26:37.354655+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v29-1-released/1978" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release of Bitcoin Core version 29.1 is now available, marking a significant update that encompasses various bug fixes, performance enhancements, and updated translations. This version introduces notable changes aimed at improving the overall functionality and security of Bitcoin transactions and operations. Users are encouraged to upgrade from older versions by shutting down their current application and then either running the installer on Windows or replacing the application files on macOS and Linux. This process also applies to users upgrading from versions of Bitcoin Core that have reached their end of life (EOL), although they should anticipate a possible delay if a data directory migration is necessary. Compatibility for this update is broad, supporting Linux Kernel 3.17+, macOS 13+, and Windows 10+ operating systems. However, it's recommended to avoid using Bitcoin Core on unsupported systems due to less frequent testing on such platforms.

One of the key updates in this release is the mempool policy change, which now limits the maximum number of potentially executed legacy signature operations in a single standard transaction to 2500. This adjustment is designed to prepare for a potential future deployment of BIP54 by making pathological transactions packed with legacy sigops non-standard. Additionally, adjustments to the minimum block feerate (`-blockmintxfee`) to 1 satoshi per kvB and changes to the default minimum relay feerate (`-minrelaytxfee`) and incremental relay feerate (`-incrementalrelayfee`) to 100 satoshis per kvB have been implemented. These changes aim to enhance transaction processing efficiency but require widespread adoption across the network to ensure lower fee rate transactions propagate or confirm successfully.

Furthermore, unconditional logging to disk has been rate-limited to manage disk space usage more effectively, and the `dumptxoutset` RPC command now necessitates specifying a `type` parameter to maintain behavior consistent with pre v29.0 releases. Adjustments have also been made to startup parameters such as `-maxmempool` and `-dbcache`, particularly for 32-bit systems, to enhance performance and stability.

The wallet and peer-to-peer (P2P) functionalities have seen improvements and fixes, including crash prevention measures during double block disconnection and the addition of more bad ports to improve network security. The testing framework has been refined to address intermittent failures and enhance the accuracy of test outcomes, contributing to the reliability of Bitcoin Core software.

In terms of development infrastructure, there have been updates including accommodations for migration to codeberg and adjustments in the build system to better support user-provided flags and configurations. Noteworthy documentation updates have been made to clarify procedures and configurations, enhancing the accessibility of information for developers and users alike.

This release represents a collaborative effort involving numerous contributors who have collectively advanced the Bitcoin Core project through code contributions, testing, documentation, and translation work. Their dedication ensures the continued development and refinement of Bitcoin Core, cementing its position as a foundational component of the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T15:35:43.084000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
