<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-09-12T02:21:37.916397+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-09-11 16:30:35.810000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T02:21:37.916437+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion highlights concerns and suggestions regarding the efficiency of transaction relay mechanisms in blockchain technology. The sender expresses skepticism about the utility of the `sendtemplate` feature, arguing that it merely complicates the process without offering substantial benefits over direct transaction relays. They point out that generating a template is cost-free and thus could potentially be used to flood the orphan pool with unnecessary or junk transactions, questioning the method's effectiveness in distinguishing between legitimate miners and those attempting to exploit the system.

Further, the conversation shifts towards exploring alternative strategies to enhance the transaction relay process. One proposed solution is to increase the size of the orphan pool, which could help accommodate more transactions temporarily disconnected from their parent block. However, this suggestion comes with its own set of challenges, particularly concerning the risk of denial-of-service (DoS) attacks, where malicious actors might deliberately attempt to clog the network with irrelevant transactions.

To address these concerns, the concept of `blockreconstructionextratxn`, a mechanism designed to streamline the reconstruction of blocks by specifying additional transactions not included in the initial block proposal, is introduced. This approach is suggested as a means to improve the efficiency and security of block reconstruction, potentially mitigating some of the vulnerabilities associated with larger orphan pools.

The email also includes a reference to a GitHub pull request comment ([some comments on the PR](https://github.com/ajtowns/bips/pull/7issuecomment-3258608404)), indicating the sender's previous attempt to engage with the community on these issues. This reference suggests that the sender has been actively involved in discussions around improving blockchain transaction processing, though they express doubt about the community's engagement with their contributions.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-11T16:30:35.810000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
