<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-09-13T02:17:11.523640+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake 2025-09-12 10:10:56.724000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:17:11.523673+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available/1980" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest version of Bitcoin Core, v30.0rc1, has its binaries now available for download at [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-30.0/test.rc1/). This version is a release candidate for the upcoming major version release, indicating a significant update in the software. For those interested in reviewing the changes and updates included in this release, the source code is accessible under a signed tag on GitHub at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v30.0rc1).

To assist users and developers with navigating through the new features and modifications, preliminary release notes have been prepared and can be found at [Bitcoin Core's development wiki](https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/v30.0-Release-Notes-Draft). Additionally, a detailed testing guide has been provided to facilitate the exploration and examination of the release candidate. This guide is available at [Bitcoin Core's development wiki](https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/30.0-Release-Candidate-Testing-Guide), offering instructions and areas of focus for testers.

Feedback, issues, or comments regarding this release candidate are encouraged to be submitted to Bitcoin Core's GitHub issues page, available at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/33368). It's important to note that release candidates serve as test versions for upcoming releases. The transition from a release candidate to a final release version, in this case, v30.0, will occur once no critical problems are identified during the testing phase. This approach ensures the stability and reliability of the version before it officially becomes part of the Bitcoin Core software suite.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T10:10:56.724000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
