<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Open letter to core devs (reflections/questions from the op_return saga and proposal to establish a well-organized channel/link between devs and users)</title>
  <updated>2025-09-15T02:41:29.366137+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>FernandoTheKoala</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-14T13:19:01.562000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Open letter to core devs (reflections/questions from the op_return saga and proposal to establish a well-organized channel/link between devs and users)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T02:41:29.366170+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/open-letter-to-core-devs-reflections-questions-from-the-op-return-saga-and-proposal-to-establish-a-well-organized-channel-link-between-devs-and-users/1982" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post aims to bridge the gap between core developers and users within the Bitcoin community, focusing on non-technical aspects that have contributed to the current state of disconnect. It presents a comprehensive analysis of the concerns raised by both parties, emphasizing the need for a clearer and more respectful dialogue.

The discussion highlights several key issues that have led to a rift between core developers and a section of the Bitcoin user base. One major concern is the perceived attempt by some core developers to enforce changes on nodes, reducing node configurability. This move has been criticized for taking away a degree of autonomy from users, which is contrary to the decentralized ethos of Bitcoin. Additionally, there is a sentiment that criticisms and suggestions from non-technical users are often dismissed. The insistence on prioritizing technical considerations without incorporating other relevant aspects into discussions has left many feeling sidelined, fostering an environment where users' opinions feel rejected.

Another significant issue is the approach to public engagement by core developers. Statements suggesting that those who disagree with core decisions should simply not run the code have been interpreted as a lack of openness to dialogue. This stance, coupled with instances where authority has been called upon to defend positions without fostering a verify-don't-trust environment, stands in opposition to the foundational principles of Bitcoin and has contributed to distancing core developers from the broader user community.

The post also raises questions concerning the recent decisions made by core developers, specifically regarding node configurability and the limited scope of conversations to technical aspects only. It calls for reflection on whether these decisions align with the community's values and questions if such practices will continue in the future. Moreover, it underscores the absence of a coherent and organized platform for public engagement, highlighting the inefficiency and confusion resulting from scattered conversations across various forums. The need for a spokesperson or a dedicated forum to express the majority stance of the core team is suggested as a solution to improve communication and reduce misunderstandings.

Concerns about conflicts of interest among core developers are also brought to light, particularly regarding interactions with businesses like Citrea. The practice of evaluating contributions based solely on their technical merits, regardless of potential conflicts of interest, is challenged. The post argues that ignoring real-world implications of such conflicts undermines the integrity of the development process and raises legitimate suspicions among users.

In conclusion, the blog post serves as a call to action for core developers to engage more openly in non-technical discussions and address the fundamental concerns outlined. It emphasizes the importance of re-establishing a productive dialogue between developers and users to bridge the growing divide and ensure the continued success and integrity of the Bitcoin project.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-14T13:19:01.562000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
