<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T02:22:21.815074+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-15T18:38:45.887000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T02:22:21.815112+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal in question revolves around a cryptographic method where Alice generates a new key for Bob, which she then communicates through an encrypted message using NIP-17. The core of the inquiry seeks a detailed breakdown of the equations underlying this mechanism, specifically asking for clarity on the structure of the notification and the precise format of the public key that Alice would pay to. The given formula, $P = B_{nostr} + H(aB_{nostr}|i)G$, suggests a complex interaction between various cryptographic elements, indicating that the public key ($P$) consists of Bob's nostril public key ($B_{nostr}$), modified by adding the hash of a multiplied nostril public key and an index ($i$), further combined with a generator point ($G$). This equation implies a layered security approach, blending hash functions with elliptic curve cryptography to ensure secure key exchanges.

Further, the inquiry touches upon operational specifics, such as the strategy for avoiding the need for scanning by Bob. It hints at a system where Bob maintains a batch of addresses for Alice, enabling him to monitor transactions without direct scanning, which could potentially streamline the process for Bob by reducing the computational overhead typically associated with address monitoring in cryptographic systems.

The email indicates a deep interest in understanding the structural intricacies of the proposed cryptographic solution from a theoretical standpoint. The sender expresses a clear preference for dissecting the proposal's mathematical and cryptographic framework over evaluating its practical applicability or design choices. This focus underscores a desire to grasp the underlying principles and the efficiency of the proposed scheme purely from a crypto-analytical perspective.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T18:38:45.887000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
