<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T02:23:58.855549+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2025-09-15 20:15:08.073000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T02:23:58.855580+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-cp-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights a significant aspect of the MultiPTLC advantage over sender-created stuckless payments, emphasizing that it requires Ursula, the end-user, to lock only the necessary amount for payment plus routing fees. This feature is presented as beneficial, particularly in light of the assumption that end-users like Ursula may not have substantial liquidity in their MultiChannel accounts. The rationale behind this presumption is compared with typical spending behavior observed across various payment methods, including physical cash, Lightning Network (LN) satoshis, and bank credit facilities. It's noted that, typically, transactions are made well within the user's available liquidity range—often less than half or even one-tenth of what they have access to.

The conversation further delves into the practicality of user-initiated stuckless payments under normal liquidity conditions, suggesting that such a mechanism should suffice for most transactions without necessitating additional third-party liquidity. This assertion is backed by personal experiences shared in the email, where smaller, routine purchases do not warrant significant waiting times or complex payment processes. Conversely, it acknowledges that for larger transactions, which may occasionally stretch the limits of an individual's liquidity, users might be more amenable to longer processing times. An example cited is the difference in transaction completion times and patience levels between buying a $5 hot beverage and making a $2,000 purchase like airline tickets, where security measures such as bank verification via text message can introduce delays that are generally deemed acceptable by the user. 

This nuanced exploration of payment mechanisms and user liquidity preferences suggests a thoughtful consideration of the balance between convenience, security, and the practical realities of everyday financial transactions. It underscores the potential advantages of adopting the MultiPTLC system for certain user segments, particularly those with lower liquidity on hand, while also recognizing the adequacy of simpler payment solutions for the majority of typical consumer spending scenarios.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T20:15:08.073000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
