<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T02:23:43.071074+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-16T00:25:18.250000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T02:23:43.071103+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-cp-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of technology and programming, an important consideration is the resilience of PTLCs (Payment Trustless Channel) against quantum computing attacks. There is a growing concern among experts that PTLCs, which are pivotal in facilitating secure and trustless transactions, may not be quantum-resistant. This vulnerability poses a significant risk to their reliability and security as quantum computing continues to advance. It's crucial for developers and stakeholders to evaluate these risks thoroughly to ensure the robustness of PTLCs in the face of evolving technological threats.

Additionally, there's a keen interest in databases and their architecture, particularly among those who value the CAP theorem, which outlines the trade-offs between consistency, availability, and partition tolerance in distributed systems. However, the terminology used to describe these systems should be chosen carefully. The term “global CP database” has been suggested, but given the current sensitive discourse surrounding CSAM (Child Sexual Abuse Material), it's advisable to consider alternative nomenclature. The use of such terms could inadvertently align with or evoke discussions on topics of a highly sensitive nature, potentially leading to misunderstandings or backlash within the tech community and beyond. This highlights the importance of language and context in technical communications, underscoring the need for careful consideration of the implications and interpretations of the terms used in discussing technological solutions and architectures.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:25:18.250000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
