<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Evolving the Ark protocol using CTV and CSFS</title>
  <updated>2025-09-17T02:22:34.985084+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-09-16 16:52:32.598000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Evolving the Ark protocol using CTV and CSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T02:22:34.985116+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/evolving-the-ark-protocol-using-ctv-and-csfs/1602/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses an innovative approach to optimizing transactions within a particular blockchain context, focusing on the structure of forfeit transactions. The current model involves inputs and outputs where the output can be either sent to 'S' with a secret or to 'A' with an added time delay, Δt. This setup suggests a potential area for improvement by incorporating a key-spend level adaptor signature, which would allow for late-binding of 'R' to the 'secret'. Such a modification means that the output could directly go to 'S', eliminating the need for the Alice clause since Alice would have already received her 'secret'.

Further elaboration on this idea reveals that transforming the 'secret' hash into a curve point could lead to maximal savings. This is achieved by having the leaf policy in the new tree also utilize a key-level adaptor spend rather than revealing a tapscript hash image, thereby leaking the same 'secret'. An alternative method mentioned involves using a single Alice CSFS based signature for late-binding the 'secret', which maintains the secret in a hash-based form. This technical discussion highlights a nuanced exploration of transaction optimization techniques that could potentially enhance efficiency and security in blockchain transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T16:52:32.598000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
