<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T02:23:30.884891+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-17T08:51:38.470000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T02:23:30.884924+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/37" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent updates on the reconstruction stats of the `bob` node in the [peer.observer](https://public.peer.observer) network provide insightful data into its performance following significant updates. The node was updated to a recent `master` version, incorporating changes from a specific pull request ([#33106](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106)) on August 22, 2025. This update was pivotal for the node, which previously lacked transactions smaller than one satoshi per byte in its mempool, resulting in an initial delay in the observed improvements in reconstruction rate.

Despite experiencing suboptimal reconstruction performance during the early days of September 2025, specifically from the 6th to the 8th, a noticeable enhancement in performance was recorded afterward. This turnaround highlights the effectiveness of the update in enhancing the node's ability to reconstruct compact blocks without needing to request missing transactions as frequently as before. The graphical data provided showcases a higher rate of successful reconstructions per day, indicating a robust improvement post-update.

Moreover, another aspect of improvement is visible in the average size of requested transactions for the `bob` node. A downward trend in this metric suggests that the node has become more efficient at handling transactions, thereby reducing the need for requesting additional data to complete block reconstructions. This efficiency not only speaks to the technical improvements brought about by the update but also underscores the potential for optimized network performance moving forward.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T08:51:38.470000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
