<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T02:23:00.759004+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-17T12:29:01.185000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T02:23:00.759044+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/40" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of compact block relay performance in relation to recent modifications and observations within the Bitcoin network. Greg Maxwell's contribution highlights how changes to the `minrelaytxfee` parameter still influence compact block relay due to peer behavior, as detailed in a GitHub pull request ([see the comment here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106issuecomment-3169815863)). This insight points toward the nuanced relationship between network parameters and their practical impact on node communication.

Additionally, an update from the `nico` node, which runs knots, introduces significant alterations with the implementation of `blockreconstructionextratxnsize` in version 29.1. This change sets a new default at 10 MB and raises the `blockreconstructionextratxn` limit to 32,768 transactions. These adjustments are likely to affect compact block relay statistics, although the exact implications remain partially explored. The mention of these developments suggests that there could be multiple factors at play influencing the observed changes in compact block relay statistics, some of which may not be fully understood yet. This situation underscores the complexity of managing network parameters and the importance of continuous observation and analysis to grasp their full impact on the network's performance.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T12:29:01.185000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
