<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:17.652957+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj.366000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-18T16:32:29.366000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:17.652986+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the potential of lattices in cryptography reveals an interesting parallel with Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC), particularly in terms of achieving features akin to Point Time Lock Contracts (PTLCs). The intriguing aspect of lattices lies in their ability to perform homomorphic operations within the public-key space, enabling functionalities that could revolutionize cryptographic protocols. However, the complexity and mathematical rigor required to fully understand and innovate within this space are substantial, often necessitating expertise beyond the conventional programmer's skill set. This acknowledgment underlines the dependency on specialists in the field to drive advancements in lattice-based cryptography.

In another vein of technological exploration, the resilience of Lightning Network forwarding nodes has been highlighted as a critical area of study, particularly in the context of maintaining high availability and strong consistency in distributed databases. The specific mention of YugabyteDB underscores its significance in achieving these objectives. YugabyteDB exemplifies a database designed with partition tolerance and consistency as core principles, adhering to the "CP" classification within the CAP theorem. The emphasis on requiring at least three nodes for ensuring high availability and strong consistency in YugabyteDB setups provides practical insights into the architectural considerations necessary for robust distributed systems. This detailed examination not only sheds light on the technical requirements for supporting advanced network functionalities like those in the Lightning Network but also illustrates the importance of precise documentation and understanding of foundational concepts in distributed computing. For more information on YugabyteDB's architecture and design goals, refer to their documentation [here](https://docs.yugabyte.com/preview/architecture/design-goals/partition-tolerance-cap).</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T16:32:29.366000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
