<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-22T09:09:55.038131+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger 2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T09:09:55.038166+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the integration of Silent Payments with nostr notifications, a concept intriguing due to nostr's lack of global state which could potentially complicate transaction notifications. The concern is raised that without a shared relay between the sender and receiver, transactions might go unnoticed. This necessitates an agreement on common relays to ensure notifications are received. Furthermore, the possibility of a relay deleting a note before it reaches the intended recipient introduces the risk of lost transactions. A suggested workaround involves the sender rebroadcasting the notification until the receiver acknowledges receipt, assuming there is some overlap in their relay selections.

Another point of interest is the challenge presented by the statelessness of nostr. Without a reliable method for a receiver to discover missed transactions, such as a brute-force search for new payments, the system's reliance on continuous and successful notification delivery is highlighted. The vulnerability to malicious actors flooding receivers with fake notifications is also identified as a potential flaw, contrasting with Silent Payments’ built-in protections against such abuses, like Proof of Work (PoW) for confirmed transactions.

The conversation touches on the issue of transaction identifiers (`i`) being accidentally reused or lost, suggesting the adoption of a deterministic nonce to mitigate these risks, though its implementation within the nostr framework remains uncertain. Despite these challenges, the proposal’s advantage of reducing scanning efforts compared to traditional Silent Payments is acknowledged, offering a more streamlined process at the risk of missed transactions due to the platform's inherent design.

Finally, the dialogue shifts towards the exploration of how nostr's recent advances in private messaging with minimal metadata leakage could complement Silent Payments. This pairing could offer a robust notification system while allowing for fallback procedures like full chain scans to capture any transactions that might have been missed. The conversation ends with a call for further opinions on managing the risk of metadata leakage, a critical aspect when considering privacy-preserving payment notifications.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-21T17:50:10.995000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
