<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T13:51:56.590987+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-09-22 14:50:02.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:51:56.591020+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the intricacies of implementing MultiPTLCs (Multipath Payment Time-Lock Contracts) within a blockchain network, specifically addressing how these contracts facilitate competition among Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) for routing transactions to receivers. This competitive mechanism is enabled through a modification of the RAFT algorithm, incorporating a proof-of-work-based random timeout for leader selection. This adjustment is crucial in the context of a relativistic universe where the concept of a "global event ordering" does not hold. The unique requirement for LSPs to participate in this leadership race is their ability to demonstrate that the receiver has requested the "receiver-can-pay" scalar from them, highlighting a tailored approach to ensuring transaction integrity and participant accountability.

Further examination is given to the limitations of current channel designs, as exemplified by the referenced work on Spilman channels, which are noted for their unidirectional nature. This characteristic presents a significant challenge in transaction reversibility, where failed HTLCs (Hashed Time-Lock Contracts) cannot be simply returned to the sender. In light of this, a proposed alternative emphasizes the importance of preliminary probing by LSPs. Such an approach would allow for the identification and selection of a suitable LSP based on successful probe outcomes, thereby mitigating risks associated with transaction failure or stagnation. The suggestion is to bypass the need for trampoline routing, considering that the transaction involves a single hop, thus simplifying the process.

For further reading and details, the discussion includes a reference to an article that delves into multi-channel strategies for reducing trust dependencies between LSPs, accessible at [this link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a decker wattenhofer multichannel for reduced inter lsp trust/1994p 5910 ursula to lsp payment hop 7). This resource contributes to the broader dialogue on enhancing efficiency and reliability in decentralized payment networks, providing insights into both theoretical and practical advancements in the field.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-22T14:50:02.329000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
