<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>[Proposal] Guardian Address + GASPv1</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T13:52:58.704692+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>guardian 2025-09-22 16:45:52.307000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>[Proposal] Guardian Address + GASPv1</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:52:58.704717+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-guardian-address-gaspv1/2006" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) aim to introduce a novel security mechanism for bitcoin users, focusing on mitigating the risk of theft through coercion or physical threats. By establishing a Guardian Address and defining a signaling protocol, these BIPs enable bitcoin wallets to enter a locked state upon receiving an activation signal from a designated external control address. This mechanism allows for a security lockdown across multiple unrelated wallets without necessitating any on-chain linkage between them, thereby preserving user privacy and avoiding alterations to existing spending rules.

The Guardian Address serves as a discrete entity that can signal lock state changes via a transaction embedding data in an `OP_RETURN`, which separates key material between the user's spending wallet and the Guardian Address. This design facilitates emergency responses without exposing user spending addresses or balance information. It requires minimal overhead for wallet developers to adopt and is intended to be optional, ensuring compatibility with current wallet and node setups. 

Motivation behind these proposals stems from the increasing number of physical attacks on bitcoin users, highlighting a need for enhanced security measures that do not compromise user privacy or result in potential loss of funds under duress. The current self-custody solutions, including decoy wallets, have significant downsides, such as the possibility of attackers suspecting or knowing about the existence of a larger balance than what is displayed. These BIPs aim to provide a safer alternative for responding to physical threats without risking asset loss.

The two drafts, BIP A: Guardian Address Signal Protocol and BIP B: Guardian Address Wallet Implementation, detail the technical aspects of the signaling protocol and wallet integration respectively. BIP A focuses on the lightweight OP_RETURN based protocol for lock/unlock signals, incorporating nonce-based replay protection without necessitating consensus changes. BIP B outlines integration guidance for wallet developers, addressing state machines, polling mechanisms, and potential attack scenarios to encourage widespread adoption.

Feedback is sought to refine these drafts before formal submission, with various resources provided for community review, including GitHub links to the proposals, wallet implementation, Guardian CLI tool, and demo wallet screenshots showcasing testnet transactions. The community's input is considered crucial for enhancing the proposals' effectiveness in protecting bitcoin users from theft while maintaining usability and privacy.

[Bitcoin BIPs pull request for Guardian Address Signal Protocol](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1973)

[Bitcoin BIPs pull request for Guardian Address Wallet Implementation](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1972)

[Electrum wallet implementation on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoinguardian/electrum)

[Guardian CLI tool on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoinguardian/GASPv1-draft)

[Demo wallet screenshots with testnet transactions](https://github.com/bitcoinguardian/electrum/tree/master/demo)

References include a study on Wrench Attacks and resources detailing incidents of physical attacks on bitcoin users, alongside statistics on the usage of bitcoin, providing context for the proposals' relevance and urgency.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-22T16:45:52.307000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
