<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T13:51:38.304528+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-09-22 23:17:46.225000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:51:38.304562+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The RAFT-inspired MultiPTLC competition algorithm presents an innovative approach to enhancing the efficiency and reliability of payment routing in a network that supports Payment Points and Hashed Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs). The essence of this approach lies in its ability to utilize multiple Liquidity Service Providers (LSPs) for probing parallel paths before initiating a transaction. This method significantly improves the chances of successfully finding a viable path for payments by allowing the sender, referred to as Ursula in this scenario, to dispatch the transaction across all successfully probed paths simultaneously, rather than being restricted to a single path as necessitated by traditional HTLC or PTLC systems.

The underlying mechanics of MultiPTLC involve a series of cryptographic and networking procedures designed to securely and efficiently determine the most suitable path or paths for a payment. At the core of this process is the requirement for the sender to provide a nonce within the onion routing protocol. Additionally, the receiver is tasked with obtaining a blinded path to the sender, which in the context of MultiPTLC, typically refers to an LSP rather than the actual initiating party. This setup facilitates a stateless design, notably exemplified by the Lightning Development Kit (LDK), where the receiver's claim to the payment is validated through a HMAC process involving the node's secret and the receiver's request nonce.

A critical aspect of the MultiPTLC algorithm involves the formation of a quorum among LSPs to agree on the successful path or paths. This is achieved through a proof-of-work mechanism, inspired by blockchain technology, where LSPs compete to form a consensus on the longest chain of validated blocks. These blocks are constructed by appending a counter to the receiver-request nonce and its hash, then continuously hashing and incrementing the counter until a predefined work target is met. In scenarios where multiple LSPs receive responses from the receiver almost simultaneously, a policy of concession is implemented to prevent redundant work and ensure timely agreement. The policy dictates that any LSP recognizing another's lead in the proof-of-work competition will cease their efforts and support the leading LSP's chain, thus promoting efficiency and reducing unnecessary computational expenditure.

This proof-of-work-based consensus mechanism not only facilitates agreement among LSPs on the payment path but also inherently enhances the security of the system. By necessitating a demonstrable expenditure of computational resources, it ensures that the leadership and decision-making within the network cannot be easily manipulated or monopolized by any single LSP. This approach mitigates the risk of collusion and fosters a more distributed and trustless environment, aligning with the decentralized ethos of blockchain and cryptocurrency technologies.

In summary, the MultiPTLC competition algorithm represents a significant advancement in the field of payment routing for blockchain and similar decentralized networks. By leveraging parallel path probing, cryptographic verification, and proof-of-work consensus, it offers a robust framework for enhancing the speed, reliability, and security of transactions. This methodology not only addresses the limitations inherent in previous systems like HTLC and PTLC but also introduces a scalable solution capable of adapting to the evolving demands of digital finance.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:17:46.225000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
