<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Revisiting Multi-Commitments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-24T02:25:47.289236+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-23T11:55:30.574000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Revisiting Multi-Commitments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T02:25:47.289269+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/revisiting-multi-commitments/2009" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on multi-commitments in Bitcoin script, inspired by conversations with notable figures such as Jeremy Rubin, salvatoshi, and reardencode, delves into the trade-offs among various proposed approaches. These include `OP_CAT`, `OP_PAIRCOMMIT`, `OP_VECTORCOMMIT`, `OP_TWEAKADD`, and `OP_SHA256` related operations. Each of these opcodes presents unique advantages and disadvantages, particularly when considering their application in a scripting environment that either includes or excludes `OP_CAT`.

In scenarios where the script is restored to its Global State Replication (GSR) form, `OP_CAT` emerges as a naturally occurring opcode, thus rendering any concerns regarding introspection irrelevant. However, it's notable for its witness malleability issues, which often necessitate added inefficiencies in scripts leveraging this opcode. On the other hand, `OP_TWEAKADD` is highlighted for its utility, especially in state carrying and making the process more streamlined, albeit with worse witness malleability compared to `OP_CAT`. Furthermore, `OP_SHA256STREAM` is recognized for enhancing `OP_CAT` and `OP_SHA256` heavy scripts by eliminating stack element size limitations and ensuring execution safety post-GSR.

The analysis then categorizes `OP_PAIRCOMMIT` and `OP_VECTORCOMMIT` as less suitable due to their reliance on a consensus around `OP_CAT`, which is challenged by its computational completeness with other opcodes, complicating second-order effect considerations. Conversely, in environments lacking `OP_CAT`, `OP_PAIRCOMMIT` falls short in enabling fine-grained introspection, state-carrying covenants, and new arithmetic capabilities, among others. Meanwhile, `OP_VECTORCOMMIT` is acknowledged for its optimization benefits over multiple calls to `OP_PAIRCOMMIT`, particularly for managing larger numbers of smaller pieces.

The exploration further extends to a world without `OP_CAT` but with access to [MATT](https://merkle.fun), where `OP_TWEAKADD` and `OP_VECTORCOMMIT` are essential for vector state carrying, despite potential witness malleability issues as outlined in the [BIP](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1944). In this context, `OP_PAIRCOMMIT` is seen as potentially useful for more complex state scenarios envisioned by MATT, whereas `OP_SHA256TAGGED` serves as a reasonable yet mildly inefficient alternative.

Lastly, the discussion underscores the problematic nature of `OP_SHA256STREAM` in contexts devoid of `OP_CAT`, primarily due to its facilitation of transaction and parent transaction introspection, which could reintroduce complexities and vulnerabilities initially mitigated by excluding `OP_CAT`.

This summary encapsulates a nuanced examination of various opcode proposals within the Bitcoin scripting landscape, reflecting a collaborative effort to weigh their respective merits and limitations in pursuit of enhanced functionality and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-23T11:55:30.574000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
