<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-09-24T02:24:22.836012+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vazertuche</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-23T20:48:55.551000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T02:24:22.836049+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811/30" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of cryptographic security in the face of quantum computing advancements, a significant vulnerability has been identified with P2TR (Pay to Taproot) addresses that are associated with NUMS (Nothing Up My Sleeve) points. This vulnerability centers on the ability of a Cryptographically Relevant Quantum Computer (CRQC) to compromise the tweaked key of a P2TR address without prior knowledge of whether the primary path utilizes a NUMS point or not. The implications of such an attack extend beyond mere theft, as it would serve as cryptographically provable evidence of a quantum computer's existence and its capability to break elliptic curve cryptography.

The process for demonstrating that a quantum computer was responsible for stealing funds from a wallet involves the original user revealing a valid script path spend alongside the NUMS point. This revelation would allow any external observer to verify conclusively that the funds were indeed stolen by a quantum computer breaking the tweaked key, rather than through traditional cryptographic failures. This scenario underscores a critical consideration in the ongoing dialogue about quantum resistance in cryptographic protocols and the urgent need for developing systems that can withstand the potential threats posed by quantum computing technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-23T20:48:55.551000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
