<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Limiting OP_RETURN at consensus level</title>
  <updated>2025-09-26T02:25:50.289932+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon.541000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-25T06:20:32.541000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Limiting OP_RETURN at consensus level</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T02:25:50.289966+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/limiting-op-return-at-consensus-level/2013/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the inefficacy of a proposed solution to mitigate spam transactions within the blockchain network, emphasizing that such a remedy might introduce more problems than it seeks to solve. The suggestion mentioned involves altering the behavior of nodes in relation to broadcasting transactions, which, while aimed at reducing spam, could inadvertently enable spammers to circumvent these measures by embedding spam in 160-bit hashes or fake public keys. Further, the conversation touches on the potential for certain addresses to push significant amounts of data onto the blockchain, highlighting a specific example with a link to a transaction ([5ffa5dc557d57f5f2dd45879f6dc3ba9bd7682bffe32f3d38e28c3928a0b118e](https://mempool.space/tx/5ffa5dc557d57f5f2dd45879f6dc3ba9bd7682bffe32f3d38e28c3928a0b118e)) and an address ([bc1sw50qgdz25j](https://mempool.space/address/bc1sw50qgdz25j)) as evidence of this capability.

The proposed countermeasures involve technical adjustments to how nodes handle transactions. One suggestion is to configure nodes to stop relaying transactions altogether while still accepting new blocks, a change that could be implemented immediately by modifying node configuration files. This approach would ensure compatibility with the current protocol without necessitating a broader network consensus on the change. Additionally, the concept of pruning is introduced as a means to manage historical transactions, thereby allowing nodes to limit the data they serve to only the most recent blocks, specifically the latest 288 blocks as mentioned.

A more nuanced long-term solution presented focuses on the privacy of transactions and the overall efficiency of the network. It suggests a shift from broadcasting transactions in plaintext to a system where the validity of transactions can be proven without disclosing their content. This method would allow nodes to accept proofs of validity, thus eliminating the need to store or transmit the full transaction data unless directly involved in the transaction. This approach not only addresses concerns related to spam but also proposes a fundamental shift towards enhancing privacy and reducing unnecessary data transmission across the network. Such a model relies on consensus for validation rather than the storage of transaction data, ensuring the integrity of the blockchain while potentially improving its scalability and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T06:20:32.541000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
