<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-27T02:20:10.486659+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-09-26T14:34:32.020000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-27T02:20:10.486697+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of nostr, a decentralized communication protocol, there are considerations to ensure that transactions do not go unnoticed or "lost." A primary method to prevent transaction loss involves wallet behavior; notifications do not require permanent storage by relays and can be saved offline once received by a wallet. This strategy is complemented by the use of multiple relays by both sender and recipient, significantly reducing the likelihood of transaction loss. In scenarios where Alice and Bob do not use a common relay, Bob may miss notifications from Alice, suggesting a need for users to have some agreement on relay usage. This could naturally occur if both parties use the same wallet, which might employ its relay or if different wallets agree on a standardized list of relays to facilitate broader communication.

The potential for a relay to delete a note before it reaches the intended recipient represents a challenge, though this risk can be mitigated through the use of confirmation messages. By rebroadcasting the notification until acknowledgement is received from the recipient, users can ensure message delivery as long as there is an overlap in the relay sets used by both parties. Concerns also extend to the possibility of malicious actors flooding receivers with fake notifications, a problem addressed through existing spam filtering techniques and the implementation of protections within the protocol, such as Proof of Work (PoW) for confirmed transactions, to guard against such attacks.

The integration of silent payments with nostr notifications presents an intriguing proposition for enhancing privacy and efficiency in transaction notifications. Silent Payments, designed to check transactions accepted by a node with built-in protections against flooding, could leverage nostr notifications as a mechanism to inform receivers of new transactions while offering fallback options like full chain scans for missed transactions. However, concerns about metadata leakage persist, despite efforts to mitigate these issues within the protocol's development, specifically referenced in NIP 4. The dialogue surrounding these developments includes discussions with contributors like @moonsettler, highlighting ongoing efforts to refine and secure the protocol's functionality.

Electrum, a well-known wallet, has already integrated nostr relays, indicating a path forward for broader adoption of nostr-based notification systems. The potential for nostr to serve as a foundational technology for transaction notifications, particularly when paired with innovations like silent payments, underscores the dynamic and collaborative nature of development within the cryptocurrency and decentralized communications landscapes.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-26T14:34:32.020000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
