<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Flattening Nested 2-of-2 Of a 1-of-1 And a k-of-n</title>
  <updated>2025-09-30T02:25:04.039576+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-09-29 13:00:20.261000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Flattening Nested 2-of-2 Of a 1-of-1 And a k-of-n</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T02:25:04.039609+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/flattening-nested-2-of-2-of-a-1-of-1-and-a-k-of-n/2018/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue opens with an acknowledgment of the simplicity yet overlooked logic in the presented writeup, contrasting it with the complexities often encountered in cryptography and coding. The writer appreciates the clarity brought forth in discussing specific logical structures, acknowledging that while some configurations like "A of B and C of D" or "1 of 1 or A of B" present insurmountable challenges due to their inherent complexity and overlapping thresholds that prevent a generalized solution, the structure discussed in the writeup is not only solvable but also practically beneficial. This insight hints at the nuanced understanding required to navigate the intricate landscape of logical structuring within the realm of programming and cryptography.

Furthermore, the conversation veers into a critique of Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs), with the writer expressing a principled stance against them based on both theoretical concerns and practical experiences. The mention of TEEs serves as a segue into a broader discussion on security vulnerabilities, particularly highlighting the risks associated with the recovery of supposedly deleted keys from old backups. This point underscores the persistent challenge of ensuring data privacy and security in the digital age, especially when dealing with sensitive information.

The writer's personal journey, starting as an underpaid engineer in a third-world country, adds a layer of authenticity and relatability to the discussion. It provides a backdrop to their skepticism towards hardware wallets, which is not rooted in their physical construction but in their specific utility for bitcoin storage. This skepticism is further amplified by the recognition of the limitations imposed by devices designed with a narrow focus, such as bitcoin-specific hardware wallets, regardless of the security measures like the "1-round cut and choose" method implemented to safeguard them.

In conclusion, the email reflects a deep dive into the intricacies of logical structures within programming, the practical challenges of securing digital assets, and a personal narrative that informs the writer's perspectives on technology and security. The interplay between abstract principles and hands-on experiences enriches the discussion, offering insights into the complex considerations that guide opinions and practices in the field of cryptography and beyond.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T13:00:20.261000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
