<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-20T02:20:12.829193+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-09-19 14:05:48.916000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-18 16:32:29.366000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-17 04:37:50.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5939_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5918_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5888_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-20T02:20:12.829237+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of lattices in cryptography draws a parallel to Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) through its capacity for homomorphic operations, offering a potential foundation for advancements akin to Point Time Lock Contracts (PTLCs). This emerging field underscores the necessity for specialized knowledge beyond that of a typical programmer, highlighting the intricate and complex nature of lattice-based cryptographic development. The discussion extends into the domain of network resilience, specifically within the Lightning Network, emphasizing the critical role of high availability and strong consistency in distributed databases. YugabyteDB is presented as a pertinent example of a database system designed with these requirements in mind, adhering to partition tolerance and consistency principles classified under the "CP" category of the CAP theorem. The documentation for YugabyteDB offers further insight into its architecture and design objectives, aiming to support advanced network functionalities with at least three nodes to ensure robustness in distributed systems setups.

The proposed MultiPTLC scheme introduces a significant reduction in complexity and communication overhead for payment transactions across networks by necessitating only 1.5 roundtrips for transaction completion. This streamlined process is facilitated by the Lightning Service Provider's (LSP) selection of a receiver-can-claim scalar post the irrevocable commitment of the MultiPTLC, thereby eliminating initial request roundtrips. This mechanism sidesteps traditional TCP acknowledgment requirements, potentially leveraging UDP alongside forward error correction to halve the communication needed in certain scenarios. This approach not only enhances payment transmission efficiency across multiple parties without direct acknowledgment packets but also aligns with the intent to ensure only one payment path succeeds, thus simplifying the system design compared to conventional PTLCs.

Furthermore, MultiPTLC introduces an innovative method for LSPs to verify payment delivery to the receiver using a challenge nonce included in the final onion payload. This nonce functions similarly to a payment secret in stateless frameworks, providing proof of payment delivery. The inclusion of distinct nonces for separate paths and the requirement for the successful LSP to reveal the nonce's preimage as evidence of completing their specific path introduce added layers of security and trust to the payment process. This setup not only reassures all participating LSPs but also facilitates a smoother fund claiming process by revealing the corresponding receiver-can-claim secret.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T14:05:48.916000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
