<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:06.280541+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2025-09-18 11:59:34.464000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik  . 2025-09-17 14:14:25.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake  . 2025-09-12 10:10:56.724000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5914_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5898_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5865_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:06.280586+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available/1980" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions and experiments surrounding the Coinstatsindex have highlighted a significant issue with the overflow bug not occurring on muhash, implying that muhash values remain in sync. Despite this, there's an absence of a migration function in the final version of the code, which was considered but ultimately not included. The suggestion to circumvent the laborious effort of writing and executing an external script for index migration leans towards a more practical solution. This involves transferring a synced, updated version of the index from a fast machine to the `index/coinstatsindex/` directory of a slower node, ensuring the slow node is updated beyond the last block of the index. This method seems viable given the considerable challenges associated with rebuilding the Coinstatsindex on pruned nodes, especially those running on low-power CPUs. The process resembles the Initial Block Download (IBD) but is hindered by the slow nature of these systems and potential power failures, thus highlighting the need for efficient update or migration strategies.

An innovative approach proposed to address these challenges involves leveraging a script that can synchronize with the muhash values from a recent, accurate version. This strategy is exemplified through a comparison of muhash values from an older coinstatsindex version against those from a pruned node equipped with the latest software (version 29.1). The comparison includes vital blockchain statistics such as block height, best block hash, and detailed transaction outputs, among others. If muhash remains consistent, this could significantly streamline the process of updating or migrating the Coinstatsindex, particularly beneficial for systems limited by hardware capabilities or susceptible to operational interruptions due to power issues.

Furthermore, the release of Bitcoin Core v30.0rc1 marks a pivotal moment, with binaries now available at [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-30.0/test.rc1/). This release candidate represents a critical step towards the major version release, underscoring a substantial update in the software. Interested parties are encouraged to review the changes and provide feedback via the designated GitHub issues page found at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/33368). It's crucial to understand that release candidates like v30.0rc1 serve as preliminary versions, allowing for testing and identification of any critical problems before transitioning to the final release. This process ensures the version's stability and reliability, reinforcing the importance of community involvement in refining Bitcoin Core's software suite.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T11:59:34.464000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
