<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T02:27:16.633737+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-09-17 14:14:25.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake  . 2025-09-12 10:10:56.724000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5898_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5865_Bitcoin-Core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v30.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T02:27:16.633776+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v30-0-release-candidate-is-available/1980" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of rebuilding Coinstatsindex on pruned nodes equipped with low-power CPUs is notably time-consuming, often requiring several days to complete due to the intensive nature of an Initial Block Download (IBD). In light of this, there's a proposition for a migration script that could facilitate the update process for those instances where the muhash remains synchronized with a recent, known state. This suggestion is underscored by an example demonstrating that the current state of muhash in the old coinstatsindex aligns with the output from another pruned node running version 29.1, showcasing potential compatibility and synchronization between versions.

Bitcoin Core has announced the availability of its latest release candidate, version 30.0rc1, highlighting a significant step forward in the software's development cycle. The binaries for this new version are accessible for download at [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-30.0/test.rc1/), offering an opportunity for the community to engage directly with the latest enhancements and modifications prior to the final release. Further, the source code for v30.0rc1 is available on GitHub, providing a transparent view into the changes being introduced ([GitHub link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v30.0rc1)). The Bitcoin Core team encourages the submission of feedback, issues, or comments through their GitHub issues page ([Feedback link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/33368)), emphasizing the collaborative effort in refining and perfecting the release candidate. Release candidates serve a critical role in the software development lifecycle, acting as test versions that precede the official release. The transition from a release candidate, such as v30.0rc1, to a final release version is contingent upon the identification and resolution of any critical issues during the testing phase. This meticulous approach ensures that the final product is both stable and reliable, reinforcing the integrity of the Bitcoin Core software suite upon its official incorporation.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T14:14:25.123000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
