<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Flattening Nested 2-of-2 Of a 1-of-1 And a k-of-n</title>
  <updated>2025-09-30T02:25:21.105019+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5983_Flattening-Nested-2-of-2-Of-a-1-of-1-And-a-k-of-n.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5981_Flattening-Nested-2-of-2-Of-a-1-of-1-And-a-k-of-n.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Flattening Nested 2-of-2 Of a 1-of-1 And a k-of-n</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T02:25:21.105061+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/flattening-nested-2-of-2-of-a-1-of-1-and-a-k-of-n/2018" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of flattening nested quorum signing groups, particularly a structure that combines a single signer with a k-of-n quorum signer into a unified layer, presents a significant advancement in cryptographic procedures. This innovative approach involves recalibrating the share distribution within the group to transform it into a larger, singular k-of-n entity. This adjustment is mathematically grounded in increasing the total participant count by one, thereby establishing a new required quorum size and recalculating the total share count to ensure equilibrium. Such measures are put in place to prevent any subgroup from overpowering the essential single signer.

One practical application illustrated includes transforming a 2-of-3 configuration into a 4-of-5 setup, where Ursula, acting as the single signer, holds two shares. This example underscores the critical role of the single signer in the new quorum formation, making their participation indispensable for reaching quorum decisions. The methodology ensures a balance of power within the group, enhancing the security and simplicity of the quorum signing process. Various scenarios further elaborate on how changes in the initial conditions affect the share distribution and configuration of the newly formed group, demonstrating the flexibility and applicability of this method across different contexts.

The discussion extends into real-world applications, highlighting the method's relevance in cryptographic and blockchain contexts, such as the Lightning Network operations. It also addresses security improvements in statechain operations and mitigates resharing issues found in nested k-of-n structures. The conversation raises awareness about the security vulnerabilities associated with hardware wallets and the limitations of relying solely on technical safeguards. It advocates for a comprehensive approach to security, combining technical solutions with pragmatic verification methods to ensure device integrity.

For readers interested in delving deeper into advancements in multi-signature protocols and broader cryptographic security considerations, the article recommends visiting [MultiChannel](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983). This resource sheds light on efforts to enhance the global availability, consistency, and partition tolerance of Bitcoin payments through cutting-edge cryptographic techniques, offering valuable insights into ongoing developments in the field.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T13:00:20.261000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
