<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Measuring minrelaytxfee across the Bitcoin network</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T02:28:55.778987+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-09-17 13:47:18.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>danielabrozzoni 2025-09-17 13:22:50.674000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5897_Measuring-minrelaytxfee-across-the-Bitcoin-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5896_Measuring-minrelaytxfee-across-the-Bitcoin-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Measuring minrelaytxfee across the Bitcoin network</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T02:28:55.779032+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/measuring-minrelaytxfee-across-the-bitcoin-network/1989" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of the Bitcoin network's fee filter messages reveals significant insights into the distribution and behavior of nodes across different network types (i.e., i2p, IPv4, ipv6, and onion_v3). The primary source for this analysis was a modified version of virtu’s p2p-crawler, specifically tailored to parse and record `FEEFILTER` messages from reachable nodes. This tool was instrumental in capturing the minimum relay fee advertised by nodes, a crucial piece of data for understanding transaction costs within the network.

During two comprehensive scans conducted on September 10 and 15, it was observed that a majority of the nodes across all networks adhered to a minimum relay fee of 1000 satoshis, with notable variations across different network types. For instance, the proportion of nodes not sending a `FEEFILTER` message was significantly higher within the IPv4 network, raising questions about their functionality or intentions. Among these, suspicions were raised about the presence of spy nodes, particularly due to the discovery of several clusters of nodes sharing the same subnet yet failing to send `FEEFILTER` messages. Further investigation into these nodes is necessary to understand their exact purpose and whether they represent a security concern.

Anomalies were also detected in the form of nodes advertising an unusually high minimum relay fee of 9170997 satoshis, a finding that remains unexplained but has been verified through direct connection and inspection using Bitcoin Core. This peculiar data point raises open questions regarding its significance and calls for further exploration to ascertain the reasons behind such an abnormal value.

The study acknowledges the contributions and insights from various individuals, including Peter Todd for his suggestions and Murch for inspiring the post through tweets. While the analysis provided a broad overview of the network's state regarding fee filters, it also highlighted areas requiring deeper examination and validated the importance of continuous monitoring and research to maintain a healthy and secure Bitcoin network.

For those interested in the technical details or looking to conduct their own analysis, the modified p2p-crawler used for this study can be found at [this GitHub repository](https://github.com/danielabrozzoni/p2p-crawler/tree/feefilter_parsing).</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T13:47:18.979000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
