<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-09-07T02:37:56.477455+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2025-09-07 00:56:20.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-09-06 08:25:15.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cedarctic 2025-09-06 08:02:28.989000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-09-06 04:29:41.146000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-09-05 11:40:27.839000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cedarctic  . 2025-09-04 14:08:14.531000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5843_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5842_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5841_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5840_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5838_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5832_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-07T02:37:56.477516+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/eclipsing-bitcoin-nodes-with-bgp-interception-attacks/1965" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around bolstering Bitcoin node security is increasingly pertinent in light of potential network-level attacks, particularly those involving the manipulation of BGP (Border Gateway Protocol). A proposal has been laid out for employing honeypot monitoring nodes as a proactive defense mechanism. The integration of an external monitoring tool tailored to Bitcoin Core could play a pivotal role in this strategy. This tool would facilitate periodic traceroutes to peers and gather data on network reachability and Autonomous System (AS) path length, which are crucial for compiling real-world insights before any implementation within node software. The importance of existing projects, such as [b10c.me/projects/024-peer-observer](https://b10c.me/projects/024-peer-observer), is highlighted for their role in observing and analyzing Bitcoin nodes under various network conditions. This approach aims not only to identify potential BGP attacks but also to enhance overall node resilience through detailed monitoring and data collection.

Further exploration into the vulnerabilities exposed by BGP hijacking sheds light on the feasibility of eclipse attacks, where attackers intercept Bitcoin nodes' traffic by controlling multiple peers within an AS. These attacks leverage BGP communities to minimize announcement spread and remain undetected, allowing attackers to forward traffic to legitimate destinations while intercepting or altering it at will. Such control over connections can lead to significant abuses, including mining power wastage, selfish mining practices, and double-spending incidents. A proof-of-concept demonstrates the practicality of these attacks, showing how specific IP prefixes associated with Bitcoin nodes can be targeted and hijacked. Over half of all reachable Bitcoin nodes were found to be located within just 1000 IP prefixes, highlighting a concentrated risk. Despite the high volume of daily BGP announcements, the stealthy nature of these hijackings doesn’t trigger alarms, blending malicious activity with benign misconfigurations.

The research identifies a considerable portion of Bitcoin node prefixes as vulnerable to hijacking, attributed to either non-existent or overly permissive Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs). In such cases, malicious announcements could prevail based on the BGP best path selection criteria, notably AS path length. Proposed mitigations include leveraging observable networking data by nodes for defense purposes, such as periodically rotating peers and favoring connections to RPKI-protected prefixes. Introducing traceroute capabilities into Bitcoin Core could enable route-aware peer selection, prioritizing path diversity to reduce the attack surface significantly. These measures underscore the importance of implementing robust defenses against sophisticated interception attacks to improve the resilience of Bitcoin's peer-to-peer network against external threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-07T00:56:20.186000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
