<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T02:23:34.025054+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-09-22 23:17:46.225000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-09-22 14:50:02.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-09-19 14:05:48.916000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-18 16:32:29.366000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-17 04:37:50.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5954_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5949_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5939_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5918_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5888_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T02:23:34.025110+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on MultiPTLC (Multi-Part Payment Locking Conditions) within the context of blockchain transactions emphasizes a nuanced approach towards enhancing transaction efficiency and security. At its core, the discussion pivots around leveraging the trampoline routing methodology to simplify and secure payment processes in blockchain networks. Trampoline routing, known for mitigating the complexities associated with direct channel connections, is posited as a foundational technology that, when integrated with MultiPTLC, could significantly streamline payments. This integration promises improvements in scalability and privacy for transactions, underscoring a broader implication for optimizing blockchain transaction mechanisms. By capitalizing on existing technologies like trampoline routing, the development of sophisticated solutions such as MultiPTLC appears more feasible, indicating a promising avenue for future research and development in blockchain functionalities.

Parallelly, the dialogue explores the potential of lattices in cryptography, drawing an intriguing comparison with Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) and their utility in enabling Point Time Lock Contracts (PTLCs). The unique capacity of lattices to support homomorphic operations within public-key spaces points towards revolutionary possibilities in cryptographic protocols. Yet, the complexity inherent in lattice-based cryptography necessitates specialized expertise, highlighting the reliance on domain specialists for advancement. Furthermore, the resilience of Lightning Network forwarding nodes is scrutinized, especially regarding maintaining availability and consistency in distributed databases. In this vein, YugabyteDB is spotlighted for its design principles focused on partition tolerance and consistency, adhering to the 'CP' model within the CAP theorem. The requirement of at least three nodes for high availability and strong consistency in YugabyteDB setups provides practical insights into designing robust distributed systems, reinforcing the importance of precise documentation and foundational understanding in distributed computing. For more information on YugabyteDB's architecture and design goals, one can refer to their documentation [here](https://docs.yugabyte.com/preview/architecture/design-goals/partition-tolerance-cap).

The proposed MultiPTLC scheme introduces an innovative mechanism that streamlines the communication required for transaction completions in the network, notably reducing it to merely 1.5 roundtrips. This efficiency gain stems from a process where the Lightning Service Provider (LSP) selects a receiver-can-claim scalar post the irrevocable commitment of the MultiPTLC, sidestepping the need for preliminary request roundtrips. Such a method suggests bypassing traditional acknowledgment systems, potentially utilizing UDP alongside forward error correction techniques, akin to compact block encodings in prior protocols. This refinement in the communication process could halve the number of necessary roundtrips, exemplified in hops like those from Ursula to Alice, Bob, and Carol. Moreover, the MultiPTLC inherently ensures that only one payment path succeeds, aligning directly with user needs while simplifying system design compared to parallel plain PTLCs, which demand additional mechanisms to guarantee exclusive claimability by the receiver. Lastly, MultiPTLC introduces a novel proof mechanism for LSPs to verify payment delivery to the receiver through a challenge nonce included in the final onion payload, paralleling the function of a payment secret in stateless LDK designs. This inclusion not only strengthens the security framework of the MultiPTLC setup but also facilitates a streamlined process for claiming the provided funds, thereby enhancing the overall trust and efficiency of the system.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-22T23:17:46.225000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
