<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
  <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:05.216397+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kravens.690000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake  ..343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  ..695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5836_Bitcoin-Core-v29-1-release-candidate-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5780_Bitcoin-Core-v29-1-release-candidate-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5585_Bitcoin-Core-v29-1-release-candidate-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:05.216442+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v29-1-release-candidate-available/1881" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release candidate for Bitcoin Core, version v29.1rc1, has been officially made available, marking a significant step towards the forthcoming minor version release of this foundational cryptocurrency software. Users interested in exploring or testing the new features and improvements can download both the binaries and the source code. The binaries are accessible through the [Bitcoin Core's official website](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-29.1/test.rc1/), while the source code can be found on the project’s GitHub repository under the signed tag [v29.1rc1 on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v29.1rc1). This release is part of the ongoing efforts to enhance the overall stability and functionality of Bitcoin Core.

Preliminary release notes have been published, offering detailed insights into the updates and enhancements that have been incorporated into this release candidate. These notes are crucial for users and developers alike to understand the changes made. For an in-depth look at what version v29.1rc1 entails, interested individuals can refer to the [release notes document](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/565af03c37d8262632543a078b2d8d29459d0b91/doc/release-notes.md) directly. Release candidates are instrumental in the development cycle of software like Bitcoin Core, serving as a final check to identify and rectify any lingering issues before the official release. They ensure that once a version is released, it operates smoothly and securely within the intended environments.

Developers and users are encouraged to actively participate in the testing of this release candidate. Reporting any encountered issues through the [GitHub issue tracker](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues) is highly valued as it aids in further refining the software. Active community participation not only accelerates the stabilization process but also enhances the quality of the final product. The development team promises to provide continuous updates about this release candidate and any subsequent ones, ensuring that all stakeholders are kept informed about the progress and developments leading up to the eventual release of the new minor version of Bitcoin Core. This collaborative approach between the developers and the community aims to foster a robust and secure platform for Bitcoin operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T11:10:30.690000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
