<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:33.056599+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-09-18 16:32:29.366000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-17 04:37:50.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5918_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5888_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-Consistent-Partition-Tolerant-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability Consistent/Partition-Tolerant Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T02:27:33.056639+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-consistent-partition-tolerant-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of advanced cryptographic and network protocols presents a compelling narrative towards enhancing digital transaction efficiency and security. Within this context, the investigation into lattices as a potential parallel to Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) offers intriguing possibilities, such as the emulation of Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs) through homomorphic properties. This approach suggests a future where public-key operations could integrate additive features, akin to those provided by ECC, thereby expanding the toolkit available for secure digital transactions. However, the practical application and development of these theoretical constructs depend significantly on expertise in mathematical foundations, highlighting the collaborative nature of advancements in cryptographic technologies.

In addition, the resilience of Lightning Network forwarding nodes has been analyzed, with particular attention to the employment of highly-available databases like YugabyteDB. These databases are essential for replicating data across nodes while maintaining strong consistency, a critical requirement for the robust operation of financial networks. The documentation for YugabyteDB elucidates the necessity of a three-node configuration to achieve high availability and strong consistency, emphasizing its adherence to the "CP" aspect of the CAP theorem, which prioritizes consistency and partition tolerance in distributed systems.

A novel proposition in the form of the MultiPTLC scheme aims to drastically reduce the complexity and communication overhead associated with executing payment transactions across networks. By requiring only 1.5 roundtrips for a transaction's completion, the MultiPTLC scheme introduces an innovative mechanism where the Lightning Service Provider (LSP) determines a receiver-can-claim scalar post-commitment, thus obviating the need for initial request roundtrips. This method leverages the potential of using UDP in conjunction with forward error correction for further efficiency, hinting at significant reductions in communication requirements and enhancing overall system throughput. Importantly, the design of the MultiPTLC inherently ensures that only one payment path is successful, simplifying the transaction process and aligning closely with user expectations.

The scheme also integrates a novel verification mechanism for LSPs to demonstrate successful payment delivery through a challenge nonce included in the final onion payload. This nonce functions similarly to a payment secret in stateless setups, providing a robust framework for proving payment completion while adding a layer of security through the requirement for the winning LSP to reveal the preimage of the nonce. This feature not only facilitates a more streamlined claiming process for receivers by releasing the necessary secrets but also instills a greater degree of trust and reliability within the MultiPTLC framework.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T16:32:29.366000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
