<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:56.743013+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-09-05 11:40:27.839000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cedarctic  . 2025-09-04 14:08:14.531000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5838_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5832_Eclipsing-Bitcoin-Nodes-with-BGP-Interception-Attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Eclipsing Bitcoin Nodes with BGP Interception Attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T02:23:56.743052+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/eclipsing-bitcoin-nodes-with-bgp-interception-attacks/1965" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of a more covert form of BGP hijacking has shed light on the Bitcoin network's susceptibility to eclipse attacks, where attackers intercept Bitcoin nodes' traffic by manipulating BGP routes. This kind of attack employs BGP communities to constrain the spread of announcements, thereby evading detection while still redirecting traffic to legitimate destinations for interception or alteration. Such maneuvers allow attackers complete control over a node's incoming and outgoing connections, opening avenues for various exploits including wasteful mining activities, selfish mining practices, and double-spending attacks. A proof-of-concept demonstration confirmed the feasibility of these attacks on the Bitcoin network by targeting specific IP prefixes of Bitcoin nodes and using BGP communities to limit the visibility of malicious announcements. This strategy proved effective in hijacking traffic meant for a significant number of reachable Bitcoin nodes, exploiting the concentration of these nodes within a small range of IP prefixes.

Further analysis revealed that a large portion of Bitcoin node prefixes are vulnerable to hijacking, primarily due to either non-existent or excessively permissive Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs). In instances where ROAs were lacking or too lenient, malicious announcements could outperform legitimate ones, leveraging the BGP's best path selection criteria, such as AS path length, to their advantage. The daily high volume of BGP announcements helps these malicious activities blend in with normal misconfigurations, making them harder to detect.

To mitigate such vulnerabilities, several strategies have been proposed. These include using networking data observable by nodes, such as periodically changing peers to break the sequence of hijacked connections, employing dynamic port negotiation to thwart passive fingerprinting attempts, and preferring connections to peers within RPKI-protected prefixes or those using maximum-length prefixes. Moreover, integrating traceroute capabilities into Bitcoin Core could facilitate route-aware peer selection, significantly reducing the success rate of potential attacks by emphasizing path diversity and reducing the overall attack surface. This comprehensive approach highlights the urgent need for improved security measures within the Bitcoin network to safeguard against sophisticated interception threats, ensuring the resilience of Bitcoin's peer-to-peer network against external dangers.

For individuals running monitoring systems like the "honeypot" nodes mentioned in the [Peer Observer project](https://b10c.me/projects/024-peer-observer/), incorporating external monitoring tools that perform tasks such as periodic traceroutes and gather information on reachability and AS path length can offer valuable real-world data. This, in turn, could inform the implementation of enhanced security features directly within node software, adding an additional layer of defense against BGP hijacking attempts.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T11:40:27.839000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
