<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-10-01T02:45:53.142910+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-09-30 23:04:08.254000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-29 04:29:14.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-25 14:04:33.516000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-24 08:35:32.946000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-07 10:51:28.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-07 03:03:18.023000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-06 22:40:48.497000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-02 17:18:14.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-02 16:16:16.902000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 12:01:51.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-06-05 20:26:39.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5990_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5589_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5555_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5551_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5411_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5410_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5409_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5398_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5396_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5365_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5233_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-10-01T02:45:53.142995+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on blockchain technology's nuances reveals several critical insights into the dynamics of mining, network latency, and the integrity of blockchain operations. The analysis begins with an observation of the increase in stale blocks over time, suggesting a potential slowdown in block relay due to inconsistencies in mempool views across the network. This phenomenon underscores the importance of efficient network communication for the stability of blockchain systems.

A significant shift is anticipated as Bitcoin transitions from reward-based to fee-based incentives for miners. This transition introduces a complex interplay between block production rates, transaction space, and miner revenue, fundamentally altering the economic landscape of cryptocurrency mining. The discussion elaborates on how increased block production could either significantly boost miners' revenues or reduce them, based on the market's response to changes in transaction space availability. The concept of manipulating the difficulty algorithm to enhance transaction throughput without inflating the currency supply was explored, highlighting its implications for the economics of mining operations.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the critical role of accurate timestamping in maintaining the blockchain's integrity. Accurate timestamps are paramount in preventing selfish mining practices and ensuring the orderly release of coins. Various methods for nodes to maintain precise timekeeping are discussed, including adjustments based on the most-work chain's timestamps and innovative approaches like astronomical observations. These methodologies aim to fortify the blockchain against attacks that seek to manipulate local timestamps.

The challenge of synchronizing node operation times is also examined, with a focus on balancing continuous operation with catching up from inactivity. Strategies for improving time synchronization include setting nodes' "tip" headers to the highest common block among peers and investing in stratum 1 NTP servers by miners and pools. These efforts aim to enhance the fairness and consistency of blockchain operations across all nodes.

Network latency's impact on block propagation and the creation of stale blocks is critically analyzed. The discussion proposes recharacterizing network performance to more accurately reflect the conditions leading to stale blocks, emphasizing the need for fairness and strategic behavior optimization within the computational realm. Additionally, the subtle advantage gained by Fibre miners through superior connectivity highlights broader concerns about equity and fairness in the mining ecosystem.

In summary, these discussions illuminate the intricate balance required to maintain the integrity, fairness, and efficiency of blockchain networks. From the economics of mining incentives to the technical challenges of timestamp accuracy and node synchronization, each aspect contributes to the ongoing evolution and security of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-30T23:04:08.254000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
