<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-09-12T02:22:23.895502+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-09-11 16:30:35.810000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 11:59:35.986000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-22 11:34:53.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 04:46:39.787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-21 22:14:16.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-20 05:26:23.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-19 21:42:50.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-19 20:45:19.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hodlinator  . 2025-08-19 20:19:33.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-18 00:41:33.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-15 21:15:37.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 21:52:52.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-08-14 20:18:27.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 01:45:43.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2025-08-06 18:12:22.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-06 12:29:34.302000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>portlandhodl  . 2025-08-06 11:25:57.048000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-05 19:08:31.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5861_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5765_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5764_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5762_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5758_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5753_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5751_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5750_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5749_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5731_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5722_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5713_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5711_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5703_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5666_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5660_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5659_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5654_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T02:22:23.895628+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse underscores the nuanced aspects of blockchain transaction processing, particularly emphasizing the balance between security measures and efficiency in transaction relay policies. A critical point raised challenges the utility of sendtemplate as a mechanism, suggesting that a focus on enhancing transaction relay by increasing the orphan pool size could be more beneficial. The argument is rooted in the observation that generating a template is cost-effective but introduces unnecessary complexity without guaranteeing that the sender is actively mining the block. This leads to potential vulnerabilities, such as the intentional flooding of an orphan pool with non-standard transactions, highlighting the need for a more robust relay policy against Denial of Service (DoS) attacks. Further examination reveals the strategic value in optimizing the handling of short ids in transaction processing. By shifting the responsibility of choosing the salt for hashing to the recipient, who can effectively cache it, the system becomes less susceptible to attacks aiming to induce hash collisions. This method enhances the resilience of the transaction processing mechanism against targeted attempts to disrupt the hashing process, proposing a periodic change in the salt and reindexing transactions within the mempool to prevent exploitation by attackers.

The utilization of minisketches emerges as a promising technique for improving the accuracy of decoded data. Minisketches offer a refined method for identifying and correcting errors associated with short-id collisions, facilitating a more efficient error correction process without imposing significant computational costs. The discussion highlights the importance of selecting an appropriate minisketch size to minimize the risk of false decodes, suggesting that even lower sizes could be explored based on further verification. This approach not only addresses known collisions efficiently but also streamlines the reconstruction of transaction templates, proposing a tiered method for data exchange that could potentially reduce network bandwidth consumption.

Exploring the dynamics of computational costs reveals an imbalance between the sender and receiver in managing transaction identifiers, with the receiver bearing a disproportionate workload. This discrepancy exposes the receiver to potential security threats, underscoring the necessity for continuous vigilance against attacks exploiting this vulnerability. The conversation also delves into strategies for enhancing blockchain efficiency and censorship resistance through improved block propagation techniques, focusing on maintaining a small subset of peers' top blocks in the mempool. Such methodologies underscore the critical role of compact blocks and the extrapool in mitigating one hop divergence issues, albeit acknowledging their limitations in fully addressing policy divergence concerns.

The dialogue navigates through the complexities of network policies and their alignment with miner activities, presenting a spectrum of scenarios ranging from uniform adherence to diverse policy coexistence within the network. This diversity, while posing challenges, also harbors advantages in fostering a resilient network structure capable of accommodating multiple divergent policies without compromising operational efficiency. In addition, the concept of pre-sharing Proof of Work (PoW) block templates among nodes is examined for its potential to facilitate quicker block reconciliation, raising questions about its effectiveness for indirectly connected peers.

Innovative approaches to optimizing bandwidth usage for blockchain transactions are discussed, with a focus on employing sorted transaction short identifiers and leveraging Golomb-Rice coding for more efficient data transmission. This strategy, complemented by the application of edit encoding relative to previous templates, presents a compelling case for rethinking traditional methods to achieve significant bandwidth savings. Furthermore, the exploration of Minisketch's utility in block relay processes and set reconciliation introduces new perspectives on optimizing communication between peers, emphasizing the potential benefits of sharing transaction templates and considering novel solutions for handling larger datasets efficiently.

The document concludes by inviting feedback on a draft Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), signaling an open call for community engagement to refine and enhance Bitcoin's protocol. It also references Stratum's infrastructure for template timing insights and discusses concerns regarding the potential misuse of a proposal combined with the GETDATA function, highlighting privacy risks associated with accessing transactions deemed private by miners. The involvement of entities like Antpool, MARA Pool, and Rebar Labs in practices prioritizing certain transactions underscores the need for greater scrutiny and the development of standards to protect user privacy and network integrity. Lastly, the text reflects on recent shifts in mempool policies among Bitcoin nodes and miners, indicating a broader trend towards optimizing network performance and security through innovative solutions like weak blocks and template sharing.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-11T16:30:35.810000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
