<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN routing and caveats</title>
  <updated>2025-09-29T02:28:46.036123+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>aqua 2025-09-28 15:09:26.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>aqua  . 2025-09-22 13:20:14.767000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5980_LN-routing-and-caveats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5947_LN-routing-and-caveats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN routing and caveats</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T02:28:46.036162+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-routing-and-caveats/2003" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry presents a detailed exploration of the mechanics involved when executing transactions over the Lightning Network (LN) without an established direct channel between the sender and recipient. It spotlights the process beginning with Alice, who must first open a channel on the LN, often choosing the ACINQ node due to its Trampoline Node capabilities. This particular node holds an extensive map of the LN, enabling it to make informed routing decisions by employing algorithms like Dijkstra’s for optimal pathfinding through the network's existing channels. By funding this entry channel, Alice is essentially woven into the LN's mesh network, allowing her to initiate payments.

Alice's payment process to Bob involves entering his LN invoice into Electrum and dispatching the transaction. This act generates a contract between Alice and ACINQ, earmarking 1 BTC to ACINQ contingent upon the successful settlement of the invoice. Utilizing its Trampoline Node functionality, ACINQ then identifies the best route for the transaction to reach Bob, engaging in sequential contracts with intermediary nodes along the selected path. Each node in this sequence agrees to forward the transaction closer to Bob, ensuring the payment's progression through the network.

Several technical questions emerge from this procedural outline. Concerns are raised regarding the potential refusal of ACINQ or intermediary nodes to open a channel with Alice, possibly due to AML regulations. The autonomy of the sender or an intermediary in selecting the routing path is questioned, given the existence of multiple feasible routes. The discussion extends to the concept of "capacity" within the LN, examining how the total capacity connected to a node influences the ability to route large transactions, the impact of node connectivity on transaction efficacy, and strategies for transmitting substantial sums, possibly by segmenting them into smaller transactions.

Furthermore, the discourse probes into the practicality of leveraging the LN for business-to-business transactions, especially those involving significant amounts potentially surpassing 1000 BTC. It delves into the technical constraints and requirements necessary for efficient LN utilization in a commercial setting, including considerations for entry channel capacity, expected fees, and transaction times. This comprehensive examination aims to demystify the operational limits and possibilities for using the LN in scenarios requiring the movement of large value sums, thereby seeking clarity on its suitability for commercial applications.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-28T15:09:26.699000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
