<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T02:22:34.978830+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T02:22:34.978868+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the implementation of NIP-17 within the Nostr protocol to enhance Bitcoin's privacy and user experience for transactions. The proposal suggests that Alice can create a new key for Bob, notifying him through an encrypted message using NIP-17. This method aims to address and improve upon the limitations found in the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) 47 version 1, particularly concerning the use of OP_RETURN for notifications and the challenges associated with scanning for silent payments.

A significant aspect of this proposal involves the generation and notification process of new keys. Specifically, it examines how Alice can generate a new public key for Bob by combining Bob's Nostr public key (`B_nostr`) with a hash of a shared secret multiplied by the generator point `G`, following the equation `$P = B_{nostr} + H(aB_{nostr}|i)G$`. This formula is crucial for understanding how stealth addresses are created within the Nostr framework, allowing for private transactions between parties.

Furthermore, the proposal suggests that by utilizing these techniques, users like Bob can store a batch of addresses related to Alice, which he can monitor for transactions. This approach aims to circumvent the need for scanning each transaction, thereby enhancing both privacy and user experience.

The technical underpinnings of Nostr and its application to Bitcoin transactions demonstrate a potential advancement in cryptographic practices. With Python code examples provided, the proposal showcases the practical steps required to generate stealth public and private keys, derive stealth private keys from public ones, and validate the correctness of hex keys. These examples serve not only as a proof of concept but also as a guide for developers looking to integrate enhanced privacy features into their applications.

By adopting the methodologies outlined in this proposal, developers have the opportunity to create payment systems that significantly protect user identities and financial transactions. The emphasis on privacy, security, and user experience positions Nostr's approach as a promising solution for the future of cryptocurrency payments. This initiative encourages further innovation in the domain of crypto payments and privacy, offering a concrete foundation for developers interested in exploring the intersection of cryptography and digital currency transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T18:38:45.887000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
