<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T02:24:11.970135+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2025-09-16 00:25:18.250000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2025-09-15 20:15:08.073000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2025-09-14 21:43:32.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5881_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-CP-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5880_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-CP-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5870_MultiChannel-and-MultiPTLC-Towards-A-Global-High-Availability-CP-Database-For-Bitcoin-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultiChannel and MultiPTLC: Towards A Global High-Availability CP Database For Bitcoin Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T02:24:11.970179+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multichannel-and-multiptlc-towards-a-global-high-availability-cp-database-for-bitcoin-payments/1983" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens with an examination of Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs), indicating they are not quantum resistant, which poses a significant risk in the evolving landscape of cryptographic security. This concern merits consideration, especially in the development and implementation of secure payment protocols in distributed networks. Further, it touches upon the interest in databases and the CAP theorem, advising caution in using the term “global CP database” amidst ongoing discussions related to content safety and management.

In discussing the advantages of MultiPTLC over sender-created stuckless payments, it is highlighted that this mechanism requires users, like Ursula the end-user sender, to lock in only the exact amount intended for payment plus routing fees. This specificity is seen as beneficial, given the presumption that users on the MultiChannel possess limited liquidity. The conversation pivots to question the basis of expecting users to have minimal liquidity and draws parallels with common payment practices across different mediums, where transactions seldom approach the limit of one's available liquidity. It suggests that user-initiated stuckless payments might offer convenience without necessitating additional third-party liquidity, especially under normal spending conditions where payments typically represent a small fraction of one’s total liquidity.

Delving into the CAP Theorem, the narrative elucidates its foundational principle in distributed computing, which posits that it is infeasible for a distributed data system to simultaneously achieve consistency, availability, and partition tolerance. This theorem is essential in understanding the design choices behind many databases, particularly those facilitating financial transactions such as Bitcoin, which operates on an AP (availability and partition tolerance over consistency) model. This choice ensures robustness against network downtimes at the expense of potential temporary inconsistencies. The exposition transitions to the Lightning Network, which adopts a CP (consistency and partition tolerance) database model atop Bitcoin’s AP framework, utilizing channels and Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLCs) to maintain local and global consistency for secure and rapid financial transactions.

The discussion on the Lightning Network further explores its architectural evolution to enhance availability and address the inherent limitations of two-node channels through innovative multi-signature schemes and contractual arrangements. This evolution underscores the network’s attempt to balance high availability with cryptocurrency’s core principle of self-custody. The introduction of PTLCs within this ecosystem is presented as a significant advancement over HTLCs, primarily for their ability to enable stuckless payments, thereby reducing end-user liquidity requirements and improving payment success rates.

In summary, the narrative intricately weaves through the implications of PTLCs' lack of quantum resistance, the nuanced application of the CAP theorem in blockchain technology, and the strategic advancements within the Lightning Network. It portrays a detailed picture of the ongoing efforts to refine digital payment systems, balancing between security, efficiency, and the fundamental principles of decentralized asset management.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:25:18.250000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
