<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-09-13T02:16:39.684887+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-09-12 13:22:41.990000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-09-12 10:08:39.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-09-12 06:35:51.054000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-09-11 16:30:35.810000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 11:59:35.986000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-22 11:34:53.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-22 04:46:39.787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-21 22:14:16.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-20 05:26:23.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-19 21:42:50.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-19 20:45:19.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hodlinator  . 2025-08-19 20:19:33.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-18 00:41:33.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-08-15 21:15:37.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 21:52:52.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-08-14 20:18:27.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-14 01:45:43.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2025-08-06 18:12:22.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-06 12:29:34.302000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>portlandhodl  . 2025-08-06 11:25:57.048000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-05 19:08:31.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5866_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5863_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5862_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5861_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5765_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5764_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5762_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5758_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5753_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5751_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5750_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5749_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5731_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5722_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5713_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5711_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5703_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5666_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5660_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5659_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5654_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T02:16:39.685028+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion delves into the intricacies of blockchain transaction relay mechanisms, focusing on the challenges and proposed enhancements to improve efficiency and security. Initially, skepticism surrounds the utility of the `sendtemplate` feature, with concerns about its potential to complicate transaction relays without offering substantial improvements. The discourse further explores the idea of increasing the orphan pool size to better manage transactions temporarily disconnected from their parent block. However, this raises concerns about vulnerability to denial-of-service attacks by malicious actors. References to GitHub pull requests and comments indicate an active engagement in community discussions around optimizing blockchain transaction processing, albeit with doubts about the community's receptiveness to such contributions.

A significant portion of the conversation addresses the optimization of handling short ids in transaction processing. It suggests that allowing the recipient to choose the salt for hashing and caching it effectively can reduce resource intensity and protect against targeted hash collision attacks. This strategy underscores the balance between operational efficiency and robust security practices in managing transaction identifiers.

The utilization of minisketches is highlighted as a novel method for verifying the accuracy of decoded data, particularly beneficial in resolving short-id collisions with minimal errors. Despite computational simplicity, the practicality of employing advanced decoding techniques remains under debate, considering the current limitations of decoder technology and the effectiveness of simpler solutions like periodic salt changes and reindexing transactions within the mempool.

The concept of using a minisketch for enhancing transaction template reception and reconstruction in blockchain technology is discussed. Its ability to detect unknown collisions and optimize the reconstruction process by identifying missing wtxid suffixes presents a promising avenue for improving transaction integrity and processing efficiency. Additionally, strategic communication methods for reducing bandwidth usage through tiered data exchange protocols are considered.

The dialogue transitions to discussing the computational cost dynamics between sender and receiver in transaction processing, emphasizing the necessity of a low-cost strategy like transmitting a small minisketch to enhance reliability in the face of potential collisions. Furthermore, the importance of maintaining a small number of peers' top blocks in the mempool is examined in relation to quick block propagation, censorship resistance, and the mitigation of policy divergence effects.

Exploring the extrapool's role in addressing one-hop divergence illustrates its potential effectiveness, though not without limitations, especially concerning policy divergence related to minimum fees. The diversity of network policies and their alignment with miner activities are also scrutinized, showcasing the benefits of a balanced ecosystem where multiple divergent policies coexist without hindering operational harmony.

The efficiency of propagating Proof of Work (PoW) block templates and the impact on both direct and indirect peers is questioned, alongside the exploration of optimizing bandwidth usage through transaction ordering techniques and Golomb-Rice coding. These approaches suggest innovative ways to enhance bandwidth efficiency and transaction processing.

Minisketch's utility in block relay processes is acknowledged, highlighting its efficiency despite quadratic complexity relative to set differences. Alternatives to full reconciliation, like using edits from recent templates, are considered for improving peer-to-peer communication efficiency.

The concept of set reconciliation, specifically with the application of minisketch and BIP330, faces challenges due to developmental status and computational inefficiency with larger datasets. A simplified method for updating peers on the latest template by indicating which transactions to omit or add offers a more efficient transmission strategy.

Finally, the document outlines a draft for a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) inviting community feedback and reviews. It also references Stratum's infrastructure for template timing data points and discusses concerns regarding the potential misuse of the GETDATA function, highlighting privacy risks associated with transaction accessibility. The involvement of major mining pools in prioritizing certain transactions underscores the need for new standards to safeguard user privacy and network integrity. The dynamic shift in mempool policies among Bitcoin nodes and miners reflects an evolving landscape aimed at optimizing network operations and addressing challenges like mining centralization and security threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T13:22:41.990000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
