<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin PIPEs: Introducting Covenants without Soft Forks</title>
  <updated>2024-10-08T02:23:32.765316+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MishaKomarov 2024-10-07 20:25:10.452000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin PIPEs: Introducting Covenants without Soft Forks</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T02:23:32.765350+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-pipes-introducting-covenants-without-soft-forks/1183" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>This post introduces Bitcoin PIPEs (Polynomial Inner Product Encryption), a groundbreaking approach to implementing covenants on Bitcoin without necessitating a soft fork. Covenants are mechanisms that enable users to set specific conditions on how their coins can be spent in the future, thereby unlocking advanced spending rules and new use cases such as the native verification of Zero-Knowledge Proofs, the creation of native tokens with complex behaviors, and restaking mechanisms to pool Bitcoin for securing other networks. Traditionally, introducing covenants into Bitcoin has been challenging due to the need for network upgrades, making PIPEs a significant innovation.

Polynomial Inner Product Encryption (PIPE) is a cryptographic method allowing for the emulation of missing opcodes, such as `OP_CAT` for concatenating elements or `OP_CTV` for predefining transaction templates, without altering Bitcoin's core protocol. This capability facilitates complex transaction conditions, efficient batch transactions, and scalable cryptographic proofs like Zero-Knowledge Proofs, thereby enhancing Bitcoin’s scalability and performance without the risks associated with soft forks.

Bitcoin's scripting language is inherently simple and secure but limited in handling complex transaction types and advanced cryptographic operations. Covenants overcome these limitations by enabling more intricate transaction rules. For instance, they allow for advanced transaction structuring, batch payments, restaking mechanisms, and Zero-Knowledge Proof verification, contributing significantly to security, privacy, and functionality within the Bitcoin ecosystem.

The architecture of Bitcoin PIPE involves an off-chain FH-MIPE-based processor for an encrypted transaction signing key, which generates a signature if certain predicate logic is satisfied, such as verifying a zk-proof or correctly performing concatenation. This process enhances Bitcoin's programmability by allowing for application-specific covenants without requiring protocol changes or additional trust assumptions. Furthermore, it minimizes trust assumptions through a one-time trusted setup (DKG), making Bitcoin PIPEs effectively trustless after this setup is complete, thus avoiding the need for asset movement off-chain or reliance on custodians.

In conclusion, Bitcoin PIPEs mark a pivotal advancement in Bitcoin’s development by facilitating complex, secure, and flexible transaction rules without consensus on new opcodes or the implementation of soft forks. This innovation not only adheres to Bitcoin's foundational principles but also significantly expands its functional capabilities, preparing it for advanced financial and contractual applications while upholding its core attributes of security and simplicity.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-07T20:25:10.452000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
