<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-10-12T02:16:21.432832+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-10-11 22:34:21.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-10-12T02:16:21.432863+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/30" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse raises concerns about the potential corporate capture of communication channels and venues dedicated to the Lightning protocol, a technology collaboratively developed since a meeting in Milan around Scaling Bitcoin in 2016. The protocol specifications have been released under Creative Common License 4.0, emphasizing an open and communal approach to its evolution. Traditionally, meetings and discussions around the Lightning protocol have focused on technical developments rather than commercial product presentations, as exemplified by Lightning Labs' handling of their Lightning Pool product release. This tradition contrasts with actions by Block Inc., which has presented its SuperScalar construction without clear disclaimers regarding patent protection or its commercial nature, potentially leading to conflicts with community norms around open-source development and transparency.

Furthermore, there are questions about the openness and inclusivity of discussions surrounding Lightning developments, particularly concerning how Block Inc. has communicated about the SuperScalar construction at industry events. Queries have been raised regarding whether attendees were adequately informed that SuperScalar is a Block Inc. product and given the choice to opt-out of discussions if they preferred. This situation brings back memories of past controversies over closed-door meetings, highlighting the importance of maintaining open-source standards and practices within the Lightning community.

Technical and legal concerns are also mentioned, illustrating the complexity of developing and implementing protocols like Lightning and the SuperScalar construction. Issues such as the forced expiration spam problem highlight the technical challenges facing the Lightning Network, especially in terms of scalability and security. The discussion underscores the need for solutions that minimize trust and maximize security within the network.

The conversation reflects a broader debate on the balance between corporate involvement in open-source projects and the preservation of a community-driven development ethos. It underscores the value of transparency, open communication, and adherence to established open-source principles in fostering healthy and inclusive technological ecosystems.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-11T22:34:21.936000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
