<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin PIPEs: Covenants on Bitcoin Without Soft Fork</title>
  <updated>2024-10-15T02:21:37.709219+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MishaKomarov.532000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-10-14T20:27:07.532000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin PIPEs: Covenants on Bitcoin Without Soft Fork</title>
    <updated>2024-10-15T02:21:37.709244+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-pipes-covenants-on-bitcoin-without-soft-fork/1195" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin PIPEs (Polynomial Inner Product Encryption) introduce a method for implementing covenants in Bitcoin without necessitating a soft fork, thereby enhancing Bitcoin's capabilities by allowing users to set specific conditions on how their coins can be spent in the future. This innovative approach enables advanced spending rules such as restricting coins to be spent only at certain addresses or after specific conditions are met, paving the way for new use cases like native verification of Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs), native tokens with complex behaviors, and restaking mechanisms to secure other networks. This development is significant as it offers a way to make Bitcoin more versatile without requiring changes to its core protocol, which has become increasingly difficult.

Covenants, facilitated by cryptographic techniques like PIPE, can significantly enhance Bitcoin's functionality by enabling more complex transaction rules. This includes advanced transaction structuring, efficient batch transactions, scalable cryptographic proofs, and support for applications such as Zero-Knowledge Rollups (zkRollups) which aggregate many computations into a single proof. By utilizing opcodes like `OP_CAT` for concatenation of elements and `OP_CTV` for predefining transaction outputs, covenants can improve security, privacy, and efficiency within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The introduction of restaking mechanisms further exemplifies the potential of covenants to enable new functionalities such as participation in staking-like mechanisms directly on the Bitcoin blockchain.

The core technology behind this advancement, Polynomial Inner Product Encryption (PIPE), is a full-hiding multi-input inner product encryption scheme that allows for the creation of predicates. These logical statements can sign Bitcoin transactions using an encrypted signing key if certain logic is satisfied without revealing the key itself. This technology emulates missing opcodes and allows for the execution of complex logic, making transactions more sophisticated without the need for protocol upgrades or soft forks. The architecture of Bitcoin PIPE includes a setup phase where a functionality is defined, a zero-knowledge proof is created, and a PIPE (Covenant) is submitted as a Taproot transaction into Bitcoin. This setup ensures that transactions are signed and submitted securely, adhering to predefined conditions.

Bitcoin PIPEs operate under minimal trust assumptions, becoming effectively trustless after a one-time trusted setup, thus minimizing the reliance on custodians, bridging, or sidechains. This advancement preserves Bitcoin's foundational principles while expanding its functional capabilities, readying it for more sophisticated financial and contractual applications without compromising on security or simplicity. The inclusion of a [research paper](https://www.allocin.it/uploads/placeholder-bitcoin.pdf) provides further insight into the technical underpinnings and potential applications of Bitcoin PIPEs, marking a significant leap forward in Bitcoin's evolution towards enabling complex, secure, and flexible transaction rules without consensus on new opcodes or soft forks.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-14T20:27:07.532000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
