<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Expanding on BOLT12</title>
  <updated>2024-10-17T02:19:21.834356+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>accumulator</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-10-16T09:00:18.433000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Expanding on BOLT12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-17T02:19:21.834393+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/expanding-on-bolt12/1167/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email introduces the concept of "Bundled Payments" as a significant addition to the BOLT12 specification. The core idea revolves around creating an invoice that accommodates two separate preimages and amounts. This innovation primarily targets services requiring an upfront mining fee to facilitate non-custodian exchanges. The relevance of this proposal is particularly pronounced in the context of submarine swaps and Just-In-Time (JIT) channels, which are essential for efficient and secure transactions within the blockchain ecosystem.

To elaborate further on the mechanics and utility of Bundled Payments, detailed discussions and technical specifications are accessible through provided links to the Linux Foundation's mailing list. These documents, available at [this link](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2023-June/003977.html) and [another page](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2023-June/003990.html), offer comprehensive insights into the proposal. They serve as an invaluable resource for developers, stakeholders, and enthusiasts looking to understand or implement this feature in the BOLT12 spec. This initiative underscores a commitment to enhancing the flexibility and functionality of blockchain transactions, addressing specific challenges associated with non-custodial exchanges.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-16T09:00:18.433000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
