<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_PAIRCOMMIT as a candidate for addition to LNhance</title>
  <updated>2024-10-29T02:21:18.163060+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-10-28 12:05:19.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_PAIRCOMMIT as a candidate for addition to LNhance</title>
    <updated>2024-10-29T02:21:18.163096+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-paircommit-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-lnhance/1216/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the ongoing discussion surrounding Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs), the consideration of having a CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) error if the hash is 0 bytes was brought up as a potential method to eliminate the need for the `DUP VERIFY` step. This suggestion has been acknowledged positively, reinforcing the notion that there seems to be no practical justification for allowing a 0 size argument within CTV operations. Such an update could streamline processes by simplifying the verification steps required.

Additionally, attention was drawn to an issue regarding the PC code on a specific branch, which has since been addressed and resolved. For those interested in the technical details or contributing further to this discussion, the corrected code can be reviewed at [this GitHub pull request](https://github.com/lnhance/bitcoin/pull/6). This fix highlights the dynamic and collaborative nature of development within the Bitcoin ecosystem, where community contributions lead to continuous improvements and refinements.

A noteworthy point of discussion also emerged regarding the serialization of `valtype` to `HashWriter` in the Bitcoin codebase, which was mentioned as being unexpectedly complex. This aspect underscores the intricate details developers must navigate when working with or enhancing Bitcoin's underlying technology, showcasing the depth of thought and consideration that goes into each component of its design and implementation.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-28T12:05:19.886000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
