<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-10-16T02:21:32.649374+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary 2024-10-15 21:03:35.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-07-21 19:48:40.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-04 20:21:55.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-06-04 13:47:41.528000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-06-03 17:16:36.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-02 21:08:52.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-31 20:13:43.809000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-24 13:07:52.580000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3368_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2887_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2647_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2625_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2615_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2604_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2591_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2530_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-10-16T02:21:32.649579+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation on the Stratum Mining protocol's GitHub page delves into the pivotal advancements represented by the Stratum V2 mining protocol. This protocol is seen as a significant leap forward for the mining sector, promising enhanced efficiency and security. It aims to optimize communication between miners and mining pools, addressing technical complexities such as compatibility issues, the need for industry acceptance, and the integration demands with existing systems. The technical challenges are substantial, yet the dialogue underscores the collective effort needed to surmount these barriers. Stratum V2's introduction is poised to significantly reduce bandwidth usage, improve data transmission methods, and offer better protection against attacks. These enhancements could lead to more economical operations and higher profitability for miners. Moreover, the protocol encourages a decentralized mining environment, empowering individual miners and contributing to blockchain network health by distributing power more evenly.

The discussion also touches upon an innovative payout structure proposal where miners receive e-cash tokens for their proof of work, diverging from traditional immediate payout mechanisms. This system, requiring multiple redemptions of a token to collect full payouts, introduces both technical and economic implications. It suggests a shift towards flexible payout schemes like FPPS to accommodate the evolving dynamics of transaction fees and block subsidies. While raising questions about practicality, it inadvertently explores how mining pools can adapt to changing economic landscapes without losing sight of essential technical requirements.

Braidpool's concept revolves around offering tradable shares to accommodate miners with lower hash power, presenting a unique solution within the cryptocurrency mining space. By enabling the sale of shares through Lightning or eCash, Braidpool addresses payout limitations efficiently and economically. This approach not only demonstrates Braidpool's commitment to innovation but also its responsiveness to user needs and criticisms. Furthermore, the potential for introducing various types of forward/futures contracts within the market is discussed, highlighting Braidpool's ambition to enhance profitability and attractiveness for miners through novel financial instruments.

The critique of a proposal aiming to facilitate payouts using lightning or e-cash mechanisms highlights its perceived complexity relative to its objectives. The discussion opens up broader considerations for making pool shares tradable, suggesting that if creating a market for shares is the goal, employing e-cash might offer considerable advantages. This approach could potentially transform how shares are traded and owned, enhancing liquidity and accessibility for investors in the pool.

Cryptographic attestation emerges as a critical method for ensuring the integrity and authenticity of pool shares, offering a robust mechanism against unauthorized alterations. This process, proposed to be seamlessly integrated into existing protocols like Sv2, underlines the importance of maintaining privacy in payout processes without adding unnecessary complexity. The emphasis on timely redemption in ecash transactions further illustrates the need for secure, efficient management of digital assets, particularly in safeguarding against double-spend attempts.

The detailed examination of incorporating cryptographic protocols into mining operations showcases a keen interest in bolstering the security, privacy, and auditability of these systems. By soliciting technical feedback on potential vulnerabilities, the discussion reflects a profound engagement with applied cryptography, aiming to refine and strengthen the proposed protocol.

Lastly, the exploration of Cashu's integration into mining payout systems through Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange mechanism presents a nuanced approach to enhancing privacy and auditability. This proposal, focusing on small payouts, suggests rotating `block_keysets` based on network activity, ensuring a confidential and verifiable transaction record. Such initiatives underscore the continuous evolution of digital currency systems, emphasizing privacy, security, and efficiency in cryptocurrency mining rewards distribution.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-15T21:03:35.515000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
