<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-02-22T02:17:02.290964+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vazertuche 2025-02-21 20:04:43.378000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xfffffffa  . 2025-02-13 08:39:33.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-10 18:01:14.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xfffffffa  . 2025-02-10 15:37:09.807000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2025-01-11 22:13:01.683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-01-02 19:14:16.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-10-22 19:51:57.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4361_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4293_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4270_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4266_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4037_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3922_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3397_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-02-22T02:17:02.291041+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse pivots around a preemptive strategy to fortify Bitcoin against the potential threats posed by quantum computing, underscoring an innovative solution that operates alongside the existing blockchain infrastructure. This proposed system is akin to the Lightning Network in its parallel operation but distinctively aims at transitioning into a new foundational layer if quantum advancements threaten the original blockchain’s integrity. The solution envisions a seamless shift from the traditional Layer 1 (L1) to a quantum-resistant Layer 2 (L2) platform, ensuring continuity and security for Bitcoin transactions against quantum computer attacks. By employing FIPS240 ML-DSA cryptographic standards approved by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), this approach not only anticipates future quantum vulnerabilities but also adheres to current security protocols.

Another facet of the discussion acknowledges the inherent vulnerabilities within the Level 1 (L1) Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), which could potentially undermine Bitcoin's value retention and overall security despite the introduction of L2 solutions. The critique emphasizes that adding layers may inadvertently inflate the system's complexity and susceptibility to attacks, thereby questioning the efficacy of such solutions in bolstering Bitcoin’s resilience against quantum threats. Furthermore, recent incidents where post-quantum cryptography candidates were compromised highlight the ongoing challenges and the necessity for continuous scrutiny in cryptographic security.

In parallel, the development of BitcoinQS as a Layer 2 (L2) solution marks a significant stride towards quantum resistance, leveraging ML-DSA/Dilithium cryptographic operations. This initiative introduces a bridge for converting Bitcoin to Quantum Wrapped Bitcoin (BQS), facilitating secure transitions between layers without necessitating forks—a strategic avoidance of the time-intensive BIP process. Additionally, the project's non-custodial nature emphasizes user autonomy by allowing transaction signatures within the user’s browser. Planned support for BRC20 tokens and smart contracts on BitcoinQS suggests a versatile framework for future-proofing Bitcoin against quantum advancements.

Further discussions present an alternative soft fork proposal by Matt Corallo, aiming to disable key-spending on P2TR addresses while validating a post-quantum signature within a taproot script-path spend branch. This proposition seeks to leverage hash-based signatures, like Winternitz One-Time Signature (WOTS) or FORS, for enhanced efficiency and future-proof transaction signing. The conversation underscores the importance of community consensus on adopting these measures, documenting the processes in a BIP for broader validation.

The narrative also touches upon Adam Back's advocacy for cautious integration of new algorithms in high assurance products, reflecting a nuanced approach towards updating cryptographic standards. The dialogue extends to operational considerations under the Hybrid Blockchain System (HBS) model and explores the feasibility of incorporating different signature types without deprecating existing secp256k1 keys. This inclusivity highlights a strategic pivot towards hybrid cryptography to address signature validation under quantum-threatened scenarios.

Collectively, these discussions frame a proactive stance on quantum resistance in cryptography, emphasizing the need for early preparations and flexible strategies to adapt to future quantum advancements. The discourse revolves around safeguarding Bitcoin through layered security models, quantum-resistant cryptographic protocols, and community-driven proposals for soft forks. These initiatives underscore a comprehensive effort to preempt quantum threats, balancing immediate actions with long-term strategic planning for Bitcoin's security and scalability amidst the evolving quantum computing landscape.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T20:04:43.378000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
