<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Anonymous discount coupons using chaumian ecash</title>
  <updated>2024-10-30T02:20:22.522144+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-10-29 09:36:00.867000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-10-15 09:50:03.068000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3434_Anonymous-discount-coupons-using-chaumian-ecash.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3365_Anonymous-discount-coupons-using-chaumian-ecash.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Anonymous discount coupons using chaumian ecash</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T02:20:22.522181+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/anonymous-discount-coupons-using-chaumian-ecash/1197/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions at the bitcoin++ conference shed light on the innovative applications of the ecash protocol, extending its use beyond traditional monetary transactions. The focus was particularly on the potential for utilizing blind signatures, as seen in the coinjoin by Wabisabi, for applications like discount coupons. This novel approach not only offers a unique method to incentivize participation in open-source projects but also enhances privacy and security. By issuing discount coupons to users and contributors, open-source projects can motivate engagement while maintaining privacy. Paid nostr relays were highlighted as a practical example where such incentives could be beneficially applied.

The underlying mechanism of this inventive application involves a series of cryptographic operations that facilitate the creation, signing, and verification of blinded messages. This is done without the need for a custodian or depositing bitcoin to mint ecash, thereby enabling the gifting of ecash to other users. This process ensures a more private and secure way to offer discounts and incentives. For instance, market makers in joinstr could leverage this protocol to provide discounts to regular users, improving the user experience while preserving privacy.

A proof of concept code has been shared [here](https://xcancel.com/not_nothingmuch/status/1846660499460837742), illustrating the technical foundation of how the ecash protocol can be adapted for non-financial applications. Through generating key pairs, blinding and signing messages, and verifying and redeeming proofs, this code demonstrates the adaptation of the ecash protocol for uses beyond financial transactions. It leverages blind signatures to maintain privacy and security, offering developers a framework to create an engaging and incentivized environment within their projects or platforms without compromising on privacy.

In essence, the application of the ecash protocol and blind signatures to areas such as discount coupons and incentives within open-source projects signifies a notable advancement in cryptographic techniques. These methods can foster community engagement and enhance privacy, as underscored by the discussions and examples presented at the bitcoin++ conference. This highlights the versatility and potential of these technologies in revolutionizing digital transactions and interactions, moving beyond their conventional financial roles.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-29T09:36:00.867000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
