<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T02:21:45.793394+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-10-04 01:03:09.114000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-10-03 20:00:20.743000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2024-10-03 14:19:37.759000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3321_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3319_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3315_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T02:21:45.793454+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd/1177/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent communication highlights a consensus bug discovered in the btcd project by Niklas Gögge and another individual. This issue, fixed in [btcd v0.24.2](https://github.com/btcsuite/btcd/releases/tag/v0.24.2), is of critical importance for btcd users as it could allow an attacker to hard fork btcd nodes with a simple transaction, posing minimal cost. Despite its potential impact, the overall effect on the network is considered minor, but the discovery was significant enough to warrant a bounty award from the project maintainers. Users are strongly encouraged to upgrade to the latest version to mitigate this vulnerability.

The process of reporting and disclosing this security flaw has stirred some controversy, especially regarding the timing of public disclosure. The original plan was to announce this finding publicly on September 23rd. However, there were requests to postpone this announcement to allow more time for users to update their software. This request for delay was based on various factors, including concerns over the number of nodes that remained vulnerable; approximately 20 out of 60 btcd nodes were running versions known to be susceptible at the time of the initial disclosure plans. Despite these requests, the decision was made to proceed with the disclosure, underscoring the importance of transparency and the need for timely updates to maintain trust in the software's security. 

Furthermore, the narrative explores the ethical considerations surrounding security disclosures within the infosec community, particularly the dilemma of accepting monetary rewards for such findings. The writer shares a personal stance on prioritizing end-user interest over financial gains from software vendors when disclosing security vulnerabilities. This discussion reflects on broader practices within the security field, emphasizing the delicate balance between responsible disclosure and the pursuit of incentives.

Lastly, the communication also mentions a precedent set by other full node implementations, which have historically opted for longer delays before disclosing critical issues, suggesting that a more cautious approach might be warranted in certain cases. Despite differing opinions on the exact timeline for disclosure, the ultimate refusal to delay beyond three months highlights a commitment to prompt transparency, balanced against the practical considerations of ensuring sufficient time for users to apply necessary updates. This case thus illustrates the complexities involved in handling security disclosures responsibly, navigating between ethical considerations, technical implications, and community expectations.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-04T01:03:09.114000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
