<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
  <updated>2024-10-10T02:20:47.866096+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-10-09 06:24:15.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-10-04 10:01:47.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-10-04 09:09:33.447000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-10-04 01:03:09.114000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-10-03 20:00:20.743000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-10-03 14:19:37.759000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3336_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3325_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3324_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3321_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3319_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3315_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T02:20:47.866153+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd/1177/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse primarily revolves around the contentious issue of the appropriate timing for the disclosure of a critical security vulnerability within the `btcd` implementation. The contention arose from a divergence in expectations between the maintainers of `btcd` and individuals named Niklas and AntoineP, regarding when to publicly disclose a patched security flaw. The `btcd` maintainers advocated for a six-month delay following the patch's implementation before making the details public, aiming to align with precedents established by other full node implementations that often extend disclosures well beyond six months for critical issues. This conservative approach is contrasted with the stance taken by Niklas and AntoineP, who insisted on adhering to a three-month post-patch disclosure timeline, rejecting the proposed extension. This disagreement underscores a broader debate within the cryptocurrency ecosystem about balancing transparency and security in the context of managing critical software vulnerabilities.

The narrative further explores the intricacies of developing and releasing patches for software vulnerabilities, emphasizing the importance of timely and transparent communication with the user base to ensure widespread adoption of security fixes. A specific instance cited involves the discovery of a consensus bug in `btcd`, which was addressed with the release of btcd v0.24.2 ([btcd v0.24.2](https://github.com/btcsuite/btcd/releases/tag/v0.24.2)). Despite the perceived minor impact on the overall network, the vulnerability posed a significant risk to `btcd` users, potentially allowing attackers to cause a hard fork of `btcd` nodes through standard transactions. The process of disclosing this information became a point of contention due to last-minute requests to delay the agreed-upon announcement date, highlighting the challenges and ethical considerations involved in handling security disclosures.

Moreover, the discussion delves into the broader implications of such vulnerabilities and the response strategies employed by different projects within the Bitcoin ecosystem, comparing them to industry practices like those outlined by Google's Project Zero timeline. The comparison illuminates differing philosophies and practices concerning vulnerability disclosure timelines, with Bitcoin Core adopting a more cautious approach compared to Google's more aggressive schedule. This variance reflects the diverse attitudes towards risk, security, and transparency across the software development and information security communities.

Additionally, the email touches on personal ethics and practices within the infosec community regarding the reporting of vulnerabilities. It mentions the author's decision not to accept monetary rewards for vulnerability disclosures, choosing instead to focus on the safety and integrity of the user community. This stance highlights a fundamental ethical consideration in vulnerability reporting: the prioritization of end-user security over potential financial incentives offered by software vendors.

Finally, an analysis of the current state of the Bitcoin network, in light of the discovered vulnerability, is provided. It reveals that a small fraction of the network's nodes were running versions of `btcd` known to be vulnerable, yet the authors argue that this did not justify an exceptional delay in public disclosure. They advocate for adherence to scheduled disclosure dates unless compelling reasons dictate otherwise, emphasizing the need for transparency and trust in the software release process. The call to action for all `btcd` users to upgrade to the latest version ([btcd v0.24.2](https://github.com/btcsuite/btcd/releases/tag/v0.24.2)) serves as a precautionary measure to mitigate the risk posed by the identified vulnerability, reinforcing the value of proactive security measures in maintaining the resilience and security of the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-09T06:24:15.956000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
