<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
  <updated>2024-10-24T02:19:18.000324+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>real-or-random</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3400_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3341_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3336_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3325_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3324_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3321_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3319_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3315_Non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-disclosure of a consensus bug in btcd</title>
    <updated>2024-10-24T02:19:18.000392+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-disclosure-of-a-consensus-bug-in-btcd/1177" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The refusal of Niklas and AntoineP to delay the disclosure of a significant vulnerability, identified as CVE-2024-38365, against the wishes of the `btcd` maintainers has sparked a discussion on the ethics and responsibilities surrounding the discovery and reporting of security flaws. The vulnerability in question, known as the "findanddelete" bug within the btcd environment, was detailed shortly after btcd released their security advisory, with comprehensive information made available through a [detailed disclosure](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cve-2024-38365-public-disclosure-btcd-findanddelete-bug/1184?u=antoinep) and btcd's [security advisory page](https://github.com/btcsuite/btcd/security/advisories/GHSA-27vh-h6mc-q6g8). This incident underscores a broader debate regarding the appropriate timing for the disclosure of software vulnerabilities, balancing the need for transparency with the time required for patch deployment and adoption.

The evolving landscape of security practices within the open-source community is highlighted by contrasting approaches to vulnerability disclosure. Google's Project Zero, for example, adheres to a structured timeline, starkly differing from Bitcoin Core's more conservative stance, which opts for longer intervals before publicizing critical security flaws. This contrast illuminates the varied interpretations of responsible disclosure and emphasizes the necessity for clear, consistent policies that safeguard users while promoting rapid response and openness within the development ecosystem.

A specific instance illustrating the disparities in security reporting norms among bitcoin implementations arose from a situation where the `btcd` maintainers preferred a delayed disclosure for a patched security issue. This preference clashed with Niklas and AntoineP's decision to adhere to a previously agreed-upon schedule, leading to tensions. The insistence on this schedule, despite requests for an extension, highlights the importance of established protocols in managing security vulnerabilities effectively and the challenges in coordinating disclosures across different projects within the cryptocurrency space.

Further complicating the discourse on vulnerability management is the ethical dimension of security disclosures. The personal stance of choosing not to accept monetary rewards for disclosures reflects a commitment to prioritizing end-user interests over financial incentives, a perspective that adds depth to the ongoing debate about the motivations behind vulnerability reporting. This choice points to a broader ethical consideration within the infosec community regarding how vulnerabilities should be reported and addressed.

In March 2024, the discovery of a consensus bug in btcd by Niklas Gögge and the author, subsequently fixed in [btcd v0.24.2](https://github.com/btcsuite/btcd/releases/tag/v0.24.2), further exemplifies the intricate balance between security and transparency. Despite awarding a bounty for the discovery, the request for a delayed disclosure was met with resistance, underlining the assertion that trust in the software's release process is crucial. The analysis revealing a minor proportion of the Bitcoin network operating vulnerable btcd nodes informed the decision against an exceptional disclosure delay, advocating instead for immediate upgrades to mitigate risk. This scenario illustrates the nuanced considerations involved in the timing of patch releases and public disclosures, aiming to protect users while fostering an environment of openness and rapid response to security threats.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-23T20:35:37.116000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
