<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-10-23T02:19:45.250060+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>conduition 2024-10-22 19:51:57.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3397_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-10-23T02:19:45.250103+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation around introducing quantum resistance into the Bitcoin protocol is gaining momentum, driven by the escalating concerns over the potential threats quantum computing may pose to the cryptocurrency's security infrastructure. The proposed Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) seeks to preemptively address these threats by incorporating a suitable signature algorithm that would prepare Bitcoin for the advanced capabilities of quantum computing. This initiative is crucial given the typically slow process of development and activation within the Bitcoin network, highlighting the need for early discussions and actions to safeguard against quantum vulnerabilities.

The proposal outlines a novel approach that allows Bitcoin users to transition to post-quantum secure keys without necessitating near-term consensus changes. It suggests deriving a secret key from a seed value using a hash-based signature algorithm (HBS), then computing the corresponding HBS public key. This key, if necessary, can be hashed into a 32-byte value to fit certain requirements. The approach further involves interpreting the HBS public key hash as an secp256k1 secret key, allowing the computation of a secp256k1 public key for standard spending methods. In anticipation of the advent of viable quantum computing, a consensus rule change could be activated to disable current signature methods in favor of requiring signatures from the inner HBS key. This method provides flexibility and a fallback authentication mechanism through the use of algorithms like Winternitz OTS, which supports relatively small signatures.

This BIP emphasizes the importance of not prematurely standardizing a post-quantum (PQ) address format based on today's cutting-edge Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) algorithms due to the likelihood of them not aging well through decades of optimization and attacks. Instead, it proposes using established algorithms like WOTS as an emergency fallback, with plans to select a more efficient primary PQ signing scheme when needed. The proposal advocates for this fallback HBS key format to be standardized immediately as a client-side change, deferring consensus modifications until necessary.

The document detailing this proposal is dynamic, with ongoing revisions accessible via GitHub. This open-source approach invites the Bitcoin development community to engage with the proposal, offering validation, feedback, and contributions to refine and enhance the quantum-resistant measures suggested. By making the draft available for public review, the proposer aims to foster a collaborative effort to assess the feasibility of these quantum-resistant strategies and their importance in the current technological landscape. Interested parties are encouraged to consult the latest version of the document for the most accurate and up-to-date information, available at [this link](https://github.com/cryptoquick/bips/blob/e1fa27cb25deee8d58bdb9a64c112dfdf09e216d/bip-p2qrh.mediawiki).</summary>
    <published>2024-10-22T19:51:57.030000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
