<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:25:32.268877+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vnprc 2025-01-07 22:41:04.066000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vnprc 2025-01-07 22:29:36.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-10-15 21:03:35.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-07-21 19:48:40.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-04 20:21:55.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-06-04 13:47:41.528000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-06-03 17:16:36.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-02 21:08:52.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-31 20:13:43.809000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-24 13:07:52.580000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4014_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4013_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3368_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2887_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2647_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2625_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2615_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2604_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2591_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2530_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:25:32.269089+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the nuances of cryptocurrency mining, a set of open questions and suggestions have been put forth, touching on innovative concepts like hashpool operations, payout mechanisms, block template markets, and strategies to minimize risks associated with Miner Extractable Value (MEV). The discourse delves into creating a Proof of Assets protocol adaptable for both hashpool and traditional mining pools, highlighting the potential shift back to proportional payouts facilitated by authentication methods which could mitigate pool hopping issues. Furthermore, it discusses establishing a block template selection market that allows miners to sell their mining shares, accompanied by merkle proofs, to those wishing to purchase block templates, thereby introducing a novel approach to transaction acceleration.

A pivotal area of focus is the proposal for building a coinbase output market, addressing the complexities involved in paying for coinbase outputs with eHash tokens due to their fluctuating value and historical tie to past block templates. An alternative suggested involves selling coinbase outputs directly for bitcoin, ensuring transparent profit distribution among miners through crafted on-chain transactions. However, this raises concerns about the feasibility of such a system, given potential consensus rules against circular payment structures within the coinbase transaction.

The conversation transitions into detailing an ecash token system designed to emulate Full Pay-Per-Share (FPPS) payouts without introducing trust assumptions, potentially revolutionizing payout calculations and auditing in mining pools. By defining epochs and issuing eHash tokens within these periods, a dynamic contract-like ecosystem could emerge, offering a fresh perspective on mining share validation and compensation. This setup promises a futures market for hash rates, aiming to address the longstanding issue of share validity proof within the mining industry through a combination of block template, header, nonce data, and a merkle sum tree.

Furthermore, the dialogue extends to strategizing about distributing block production capabilities, fostering a self-hostable, KYC-free bitcoin onramp, and enabling smaller-scale miners to participate more feasibly. This involves reimagining the mining pool model to support pseudonymous and transparent PPLNS payouts, potentially decentralizing the mining process. Ideas around paid template selection and coinbase output markets are introduced as means to innovate within the space, suggesting a transformation in how mining pools operate and contribute to privacy and efficiency in blockchain technologies.

Amidst these discussions, a critique emerges on the complexity and perceived redundancy of linking shares directly to e-cash or proposing intricate schemes for miner payouts. There’s a call for simplicity in utilizing digital payment systems for payouts, while also recognizing the potential benefits of making pool shares a tradable asset through e-cash, thus opening up discussions on enhancing liquidity and accessibility for investors in the mining pool.

The inquiry into cryptographic attestation proposes a method where pools authenticate individual shares, ensuring integrity and authenticity. This concept aims at enhancing transparency and trust within mining operations, allowing for independent verification of pool claims regarding payouts and activities. Moreover, the dialogue highlights the challenges and possibilities of executing multiple redemptions for an eHash, exploring operational frameworks and redemption processes that maintain security and integrity within the digital asset space.

Lastly, a detailed critique and exploration of cryptographic protocols reveal an emphasis on technical feedback to identify vulnerabilities and strengthen the system's design. The discussion encapsulates a broader narrative on enhancing privacy, auditability, and flexibility in mining rewards distribution, suggesting a thorough investigation into integrating privacy-enhancing technologies like the Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange into existing protocols. These conversations underscore a collective effort towards innovating and improving practices within cryptocurrency mining, emphasizing the need for transparency, security, and efficient reward mechanisms.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T22:41:04.066000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
