<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin PIPEs: Covenants on Bitcoin Without Soft Fork</title>
  <updated>2024-10-23T02:20:37.267552+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>GaloisField2718.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MishaKomarov  ..532000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3396_Bitcoin-PIPEs-Covenants-on-Bitcoin-Without-Soft-Fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3361_Bitcoin-PIPEs-Covenants-on-Bitcoin-Without-Soft-Fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin PIPEs: Covenants on Bitcoin Without Soft Fork</title>
    <updated>2024-10-23T02:20:37.267601+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-pipes-covenants-on-bitcoin-without-soft-fork/1195" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the innovative implementation of covenants in Bitcoin through the use of Polynomial Inner Product Encryption (PIPE), which does not necessitate a soft fork, enhancing the blockchain's capabilities by allowing for advanced spending rules. These rules can specify conditions under which coins can be spent, such as restricting transactions to certain addresses or after particular conditions are met. This advancement introduces the potential for native verification of Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs), creation of native tokens with complex behaviors, and mechanisms for restaking to secure other networks, thereby significantly increasing Bitcoin's versatility without altering its core protocol.

Covenants, enabled by cryptographic techniques like PIPE, extend Bitcoin's functionality to include more sophisticated transaction structures, efficient batch transactions, scalable cryptographic proofs, and applications such as Zero-Knowledge Rollups (zkRollups) which consolidate multiple computations into a single proof. The employment of opcodes like `OP_CAT` and `OP_CTV` enhances security, privacy, and efficiency within Bitcoin's ecosystem by supporting advanced transaction capabilities. Additionally, restaking mechanisms demonstrate the covenant's potential to facilitate staking-like activities directly on the Bitcoin blockchain.

Polynomial Inner Product Encryption (PIPE) underpins these developments, offering a full-hiding multi-input inner product encryption scheme that allows the creation of predicates. These predicates authorize Bitcoin transactions based on encrypted signing keys if specific logical conditions are met, without disclosing the key itself. This method effectively simulates missing opcodes and executes complex logic in transactions without necessitating protocol upgrades or soft forks. The architecture of Bitcoin PIPE involves a setup phase where a functionality is defined, a zero-knowledge proof is created, and a PIPE (Covenant) is submitted as a Taproot transaction into Bitcoin, ensuring secure and condition-adherent transaction submissions.

Bitcoin PIPEs minimize trust assumptions, requiring only a one-time trusted setup to become virtually trustless, thus reducing dependence on custodians, bridging, or sidechains. This technology aligns with Bitcoin's original principles while broadening its functional scope for more intricate financial and contractual applications, all without compromising security or simplicity. The inclusion of a [research paper](https://www.allocin.it/uploads/placeholder-bitcoin.pdf) further elucidates the technical foundations and possible applications of Bitcoin PIPEs, highlighting a significant progression in Bitcoin's evolution towards accommodating complex, secure, and flexible transaction rules without consensus on new opcodes or soft forks.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-22T13:52:11.352000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
