<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_PAIRCOMMIT as a candidate for addition to LNhance</title>
  <updated>2024-10-30T02:21:01.151297+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-10-29 11:36:58.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-10-29 10:52:30.693000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-10-29 09:38:38.311000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-28 12:05:19.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-10-28 11:16:51.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-25 21:50:45.243000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-10-25 19:22:36.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-25 19:11:15.643000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-25 19:06:11.290000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-10-25 17:57:14.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-25 14:38:37.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-10-25 14:34:33.286000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3437_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3436_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3435_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3431_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3430_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3409_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3407_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3406_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3405_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3404_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3402_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3401_OP-PAIRCOMMIT-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-LNhance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_PAIRCOMMIT as a candidate for addition to LNhance</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T02:21:01.151438+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-paircommit-as-a-candidate-for-addition-to-lnhance/1216/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current discussion on the OP_PAIRCOMMIT specification, destined for a PR against BINANA, is accessible through a [shared gist](https://gist.github.com/moonsettler/d7f1fb88e3e54ee7ecb6d69ff126433b). The emphasis is on maintaining constructive dialogue and avoiding the deletion of threads unless they are non-contributory. Open discussions and presentations, rather than comprehensive document updates, are encouraged for sharing developments. A request was made to @ajtowns to delete or archive a confusing topic in favor of a more clear presentation regarding the PAIRCOMMIT thread, acknowledging an update to the spec that moves away from its draft status.

In the realm of Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs), a potential optimization involves eliminating the `DUP VERIFY` step through a CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) error when encountering a 0-byte hash argument. This proposal reflects a consensus against unnecessary complexity in CTV operations. A resolution to a specific PC code issue has been achieved, as detailed in a [GitHub pull request](https://github.com/lnhance/bitcoin/pull/6), showcasing the collaborative and iterative nature of Bitcoin development. Additionally, the complexity encountered in serializing `valtype` to `HashWriter` highlights the intricate considerations developers navigate to enhance Bitcoin's technology.

The discussion also explores SHA256 iteration optimization for LN-Symmetry, suggesting a method minimizing hashing while accommodating preimage sizes that prevent length redistribution attacks and support future CTV upgrades. An inquiry into hashing methodologies underscores a desire for efficient and secure practices, emphasizing the balance between innovation and established protocols within project development dynamics. Furthermore, the concept of adopting a mini-hashing technique for byte distribution in stack elements proposes a shift from static padding, aiming for more adaptable data manipulation methods.

Bitcoin script optimizations include comparisons between employing `OP_CAT` for `OP_PAIRCOMMIT` emulation and other redundancies aimed at efficiency improvements. The debate extends to new opcode proposals like OP_CAT and their implications on project simplicity and advancement, with a preference for prioritizing foundational opcodes such as OP_CTV before integrating more complex functionalities. Vector Commitments using `OP_PAIRCOMMIT` are advocated for enhancing security and simplifying contract scripting by guarding against witness malleability and streamlining script interactions.

Lastly, the optimization of SHA256 iterations for LN-Symmetry involves pre-computing the Tag as a mid-state, facilitating efficient validation processes. This includes handling scenarios with specific byte commitments and addressing potential length redistribution attacks through innovative hashing techniques. A custom hash function example demonstrates an approach to altering output significantly with minor input changes, offering a solution to enhance security and efficiency in LN-Symmetry applications with CTV. For technical details and proposed code adjustments, reference is made to a [GitHub pull request](https://github.com/lnhance/bitcoin/pull/7/files), which further elucidates on the subject.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-29T11:36:58.752000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
