<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-02-11T02:21:42.619040+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-10 18:01:14.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>0xfffffffa 2025-02-10 15:37:09.807000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2025-01-11 22:13:01.683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-01-02 19:14:16.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-10-22 19:51:57.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4270_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4266_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4037_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3922_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3397_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T02:21:42.619110+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing Bitcoin's resistance to potential quantum computing threats has led to the exploration of Layer 2 (L2) solutions over altering the foundational Layer 1 (L1) network through soft or hard forks. A significant development in this area is the introduction of BitcoinQS, a non-custodial platform that aims to bridge traditional Bitcoin with Quantum Wrapped Bitcoin at a 1:1 ratio, ensuring quantum safety without necessitating changes to Bitcoin's original architecture. This initiative leverages ML-DSA/Dilithium for its signature algorithm and employs SHA3 256 and base58 for address generation on the testnet, with plans to upgrade these systems for the mainnet launch. The approach taken by BitcoinQS reflects a swift method to implement quantum resilience, circumventing the historically slow process of Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) implementation.

Matt Corallo's proposal offers an alternative approach by suggesting modifications within the existing Bitcoin protocol to incorporate post-quantum cryptographic standards. This involves disabling key spending on P2TR addresses and utilizing `OP_SUCCESS` opcodes for post-quantum signature validation within a taproot script-path spend branch. Corallo's vision extends the benefits of taproot to achieve greater efficiency and security, proposing the use of hash-based signatures like Winternitz One-Time Signature (WOTS) or Forward Secure Sealed Sender (FORS) for their balance of efficiency and future-proofing capabilities.

The conversation also touches upon the importance of careful integration of new algorithms into high-assurance products, echoing Adam Back's call for prudence. Flexibility in updating BIP-360 and the consideration of hybrid cryptography models signify a thoughtful approach to enhancing Bitcoin's security against quantum advances. This includes maintaining secp256k1 keys alongside new signature types to ensure operational consistency and exploring the DASK model for a more focused enhancement of the protocol.

A strategic, long-term perspective is evident in the discussion of transitioning Bitcoin to post-quantum secure mechanisms. This entails using a hash-based signature algorithm (HBS) to derive secret keys from a seed value, preparing for a seamless switch to quantum-resistant signatures when necessary. Such preparations underscore the need for a cautious but proactive stance in addressing the quantum threat without rushing into consensus changes or the standardization of new protocols.

Finally, the evolving nature of these discussions is highlighted by references to ongoing revisions and updates to the proposed Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), which seeks to introduce quantum resistance into Bitcoin's framework. The continuous development of this proposal reflects an open invitation to the community for feedback, aiming to refine and adapt the strategy based on collective insights and technological advancements. This collaborative effort underscores the importance of early and thoughtful preparation to safeguard Bitcoin against emerging quantum computing capabilities, demonstrating a commitment to the cryptocurrency's long-term security and viability.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T18:01:14.393000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
