<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-12-03T02:49:49.967965+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-02T11:51:51.421000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T02:49:49.967999+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/51" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the handling of transactions in a blockchain context, specifically focusing on those that are categorized as orphans until they are included in block reconstruction. Transactions designated as orphans indicate a missing parent transaction, which is essential for their validation and integration into the blockchain. In instances where an orphan transaction is also part of a block, it suggests that its parent must be within the same block. This scenario necessitates a round-trip communication to fetch the missing parent transaction, implying that merely avoiding the download of an additional copy of the orphan transaction offers minimal bandwidth savings and does not significantly expedite the process.

The efficiency of the system might be compromised if there exists a bug within the orphanage mechanism or if a parent transaction has been replaced yet remains in extra transactions, making it available for block reconstruction but not for orphan resolution. This situation highlights potential areas for optimization in how orphan transactions are managed and suggests that improvements could be made in the process of block reconstruction and orphan resolution to enhance overall transaction processing time and reduce unnecessary bandwidth consumption.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-02T11:51:51.421000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
