<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Building a vault using blinded co-signers</title>
  <updated>2025-12-05T02:56:34.928905+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Nuh 2025-12-04 14:08:06.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Building a vault using blinded co-signers</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T02:56:34.928940+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/building-a-vault-using-blinded-co-signers/2141/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email commences with an acknowledgment of the recipient's recent announcement and prototype, along with an appreciation for their work on Elf trace, indicating a positive reception from the sender. The sender expresses a strong belief in the potential of blind co-signers to replicate certain functionalities on the Bitcoin platform, particularly emphasizing the emulation of specific Bitcoin script op_codes necessary for Elf-trace and other fraud-proof applications. This suggestion is rooted in the idea that leveraging these op_codes could significantly enhance the protocol's functionality and its wider acceptance within the ecosystem.

The sender critiques the challenge of establishing trust in co-signers, highlighting it as a fundamental issue regardless of the signing context. They propose a strategic approach to maximize the utility of co-signers by suggesting the emulation of essential Bitcoin script op_codes. This strategy is believed to enable the development of a more robust protocol that might not solely rely on Risc0 but could also be implemented using Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs) or a combination of TEEs and slashable bonds on alternative chains. The simplicity of this proposed implementation would allow for its verification across different programming languages like Solidity or Cairo, enhancing the protocol’s credibility and adoption.

Furthermore, the sender argues for the visibility of these op_code executions on-chain, positing that this transparency could validate the demand for such features while potentially countering arguments related to Miner Extractable Value (MEV). They emphasize the importance of maintaining a track record of the honesty and liveness of co-signers as a critical component of the system's trustworthiness.

Conclusively, the sender expresses a desire for the project to gain significant adoption and usage, acknowledging that while the intricacies of the protocol are essential, the broader challenge lies in achieving widespread acceptance within the industry. They suggest that the efforts made towards bootstrapping trust in co-signers could also provide valuable data on which op_codes should be considered for soft forks in the future, thereby contributing to the overall growth and improvement of the ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-04T14:08:06.744000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
