<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
  <updated>2025-12-05T02:57:05.841070+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse.406000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-04T20:02:58.406000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T02:57:05.841108+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-lnd-0-19-0/2145" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent update to LND version 0.19.0 addresses critical security vulnerabilities that users must be aware of to safeguard their funds effectively. This version, accessible through [LND 0.19.0](https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lnd/releases/tag/v0.19.0beta), introduces fixes for one denial of service (DoS) and two theft of fund vulnerabilities, marking a significant step forward in the platform's security measures.

The Infinite Inbox DoS vulnerability presented a severe risk by exploiting large internal queue sizes alongside an unrestricted incoming connection policy. This flaw allowed attackers to deplete LND's memory resources rapidly, leading to potential crashes or hanging processes. The issue was thoroughly detailed in a dedicated [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-infinite-inbox-dos/), emphasizing the importance of updating to mitigate such risks.

Furthermore, the Excessive Failback Exploit 2 emerged as a variant of a previously identified bug, posing a direct threat to users' funds by enabling unauthorized fund theft from LND nodes. Despite efforts to amend BOLT 5 with an [update](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1233) aimed at preventing similar future exploits, this particular variant managed to bypass existing safeguards. Additional insights into this exploit are available in a specific [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-excessive-failback-exploit-2/).

Lastly, the Replacement Stalling Attack vulnerability uncovered weaknesses within LND's sweeper system. These shortcomings could be exploited by attackers to delay LND’s attempts at claiming expired Hash Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs) on the blockchain. If not addressed, after an 80-block stalling period, an attacker could potentially seize nearly the entire balance of a channel. This vulnerability's discovery during a code review of LND's sweeper rewrite in 2024 underscores the continuous need for vigilance and regular updates. Further details on this attack are elaborated in another [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-replacement-stalling-attack/).

In summary, these updates highlight the evolving nature of threats facing the Lightning Network and the ongoing efforts required to secure it against both known and emerging vulnerabilities. Users are strongly encouraged to upgrade to LND 0.19.0 or later versions to protect their investments against these identified security flaws.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-04T20:02:58.406000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
