<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:25.629982+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-12-05 15:10:52.986000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:25.630012+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation/2139/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the optimization of internal operations within mining pools, a significant bottleneck has been identified in the current infrastructure. This bottleneck's impact on efficiency and performance is highlighted through a discussion on the advantages of adopting Stratumv2 for pools. Stratumv2 is presented as a solution that can enhance the performance of mining pools by addressing issues such as propagation delay and mining centralization, which are pivotal in modeling stale rates. The model's validity is supported by instances of inefficiency within existing systems, where some mining pools have inadvertently made their own blocks stale. This problem is exemplified by Antpool and ViaBTC, both of which have experienced instances of mining two blocks at the same height, an issue that not only demonstrates the existence of bottlenecks but also underlines the potential benefits of transitioning to Stratumv2.

Further insight into these challenges and proposed solutions is available through discussions and analyses shared within the community. For example, a detailed comment on stale rate modeling provides a comprehensive overview of how Stratumv2 could mitigate these issues, offering a direct link to the broader discussion ([this comment](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/propagation-delay-and-mining-centralization-modeling-stale-rates/2110/3?u=antoinep)). Additionally, specific instances highlighting the problem are documented, including Antpool and ViaBTC's experiences with mining two blocks at the same height, which can be found at [here](https://bnoc.xyz/t/antpool-mines-two-blocks-at-height-925051/60?u=antoine) and [here](https://bnoc.xyz/t/viabtc-mining-pool-mines-multiple-blocks-at-same-height/48?u=antoine), respectively. These examples underscore the practical implications of the bottleneck and the urgency of adopting more efficient technologies like Stratumv2 to improve the overall effectiveness of mining operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-05T15:10:52.986000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
