<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
  <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:56.630186+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-05T15:33:08.635000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:56.630214+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-lnd-0-19-0/2145/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency transactions, particularly those involving Lightning Network Daemon (LND), there exists a significant security concern that needs to be addressed. The issue at hand revolves around how the channel balance within these transactions can become vulnerable to theft by attackers. Specifically, if a channel is configured to permit its entire balance to be used in concurrent Hashed Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs), it opens up a pathway for malicious entities to potentially siphon off the entire balance of the channel. This concern raises questions about the default configurations within LND related to capping the usage of the channel's balance in such contracts. 

Understanding the mechanics behind this vulnerability is crucial for both users and developers engaged with LND. It highlights the need for stringent security measures and thoughtful configuration settings that can safeguard against such exploits. By addressing this potential risk, the integrity of transactions conducted over the Lightning Network can be maintained, ensuring that users' assets are protected from unwarranted theft. This situation underscores the broader challenges faced in securing digital transactions on blockchain networks, emphasizing the importance of continuous vigilance and improvement in security protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-05T15:33:08.635000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
