<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>BIP The Cat - Draft discussion</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T02:57:02.639924+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Claire.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-09T23:52:00.191000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>BIP The Cat - Draft discussion</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T02:57:02.639956+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-the-cat-draft-discussion/2153" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal titled "The Cat," available for review at [GitHub](https://github.com/ostromcode/The-Cat/tree/main), introduces a novel strategy aimed at limiting non-monetary applications of Bitcoin, such as inscriptions and Stamps-style protocols. These applications currently constitute over 40% of the Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) set in widely adopted implementations. The document is comprehensive and includes a rationale section along with a Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) part to address potential concerns regarding the proposed Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). Given its innovative approach, the proposal is anticipated to stir considerable debate within the community due to its unprecedented nature.

The initiator of this proposal has diligently worked on the draft, incorporating feedback from a small group of technical peers and friends. Now, they seek broader input from the global Bitcoin development community, emphasizing the value of open discussion and critique. By inviting wider scrutiny, the proposer aims to refine the initiative, acknowledging that constructive criticism from the community will contribute significantly to its evolution or dismissal based on its merit.

Moreover, the proponent clarifies their human origin of the proposal, countering any speculations of AI authorship that have arisen in discussions. This clarification underscores the personal effort and consultation invested in the proposal, highlighting outreach to numerous individuals during the drafting phase. Despite encountering diverse viewpoints and criticisms regarding the proposed methods, the proposer remains open to dialogue, aiming to enhance the proposal through active engagement with the community.

This invitation for review and critique reflects a commitment to leveraging collective expertise to navigate the challenges posed by non-monetary uses of Bitcoin. Through fostering an environment of transparent and rigorous review, the proposer aspires to advance towards a more effective solution that addresses the identified issue while benefiting the broader Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-09T23:52:00.191000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
