<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:00.021621+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-09T20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:00.021651+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion explores the concept of obscuring the actual creation time of a transaction on a blockchain network, contrasting client-side versus node-level implementation. The primary focus is on the potential advantages of implementing this feature directly within the nodes rather than relying on client-side solutions. This strategy could offer enhanced security or anonymity features by making it more challenging to trace transactions back to their origin based on timing.

A key proposal within this context is the introduction of a new Remote Procedure Call (RPC) named `schedulerawtransaction`, designed to function similarly to the existing `sendrawtransaction` RPC but with added capabilities for scheduling transactions. This functionality suggests that transactions can be programmed to occur only under specific predefined conditions, such as the occurrence of another transaction. To fully support this feature, additional RPCs would be necessary. These would include commands to list currently scheduled transactions and to cancel any that are no longer required or desired. The necessity for these additional RPCs underscores the complexity and potential utility of incorporating scheduled transactions into the node's capabilities, potentially offering users greater flexibility and control over their transaction timings.

This approach raises several questions and considerations regarding the practical implementation of such features, including the technical challenges of integrating them into an existing blockchain infrastructure and the potential impact on network performance and security. The introduction of scheduled transactions and the ability to hide transaction creation times at the node level could significantly alter how transactions are conducted, potentially leading to more strategic and less predictable transaction flows.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-09T20:15:20.209000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
