<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Dust Expiry: Clean the UTXO set from spam</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T02:54:07.317926+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>simul 2025-12-09 21:33:48.427000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Dust Expiry: Clean the UTXO set from spam</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T02:54:07.317966+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dust-expiry-clean-the-utxo-set-from-spam/1707/36" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the security implications related to blockchain re-organization events, particularly focusing on the risks associated with extended periods such as a one-year re-org. It highlights the increased motivation for attackers when the potential reward from such an attack includes confiscating significant assets versus minor quantities or "dust." This consideration points towards the need for evaluating the incentive structures built within blockchain protocols, especially as they pertain to the feasibility and attractiveness of launching attacks aimed at rewriting the chain's history over prolonged durations.

The analysis suggests that the underlying security model of blockchain technology must account for the scale of potential rewards available through successful attacks. The greater the value that can be extracted by manipulating the chain's history, the more attractive it becomes for malicious actors to invest resources into achieving such feats. This scenario underscores the importance of designing blockchain systems in a way that either minimizes the possible gains from extensive re-organization events or significantly increases the difficulty and cost of attempting them.

In summary, the conversation sheds light on a critical aspect of blockchain security concerning the balance between the flexibility of chain modifications and the prevention of malicious rewrites. Ensuring the integrity of blockchain histories requires careful consideration of how incentive mechanisms can influence the behavior of potential attackers, particularly in scenarios where substantial assets are at stake.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-09T21:33:48.427000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
