<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:46.919778+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>optout.234000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-10T10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:46.919810+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of scheduling transactions in the blockchain environment, focusing on the scenarios where such a feature would be beneficial and the technical considerations involved. A key point highlighted is the possibility of executing transactions at a predetermined time, either based on actual clock time or block height, without the need for manual intervention by the user. This approach is particularly appealing for users who require transactions to be executed automatically, following the reception of an incoming payment, thus necessitating independence between the scheduling of a transaction and its execution.

Further examination reveals that current wallet solutions do not inherently support this functionality, pushing towards the utilization of a dedicated node for users with advanced needs. Such a node would not only stay operational continuously but also host the logic required for scheduling transactions. This setup caters to "power users" who operate their own nodes and can benefit from automating transaction broadcasts without direct oversight.

The conversation also touches upon the necessity of extending the existing RPC interface to manage scheduled transactions effectively. This includes functions for listing pending transactions, cancelling scheduled actions, and potentially verifying the outcome of broadcasted transactions. Although the primary use case is described as "fire-and-forget," implying minimal need for post-transaction confirmation, the ability to cancel a transaction before it executes was acknowledged as a valuable feature.

This dialogue underscores the intersection of user convenience and technological capability within the blockchain ecosystem, illustrating the demand for more sophisticated client-side features that accommodate the dynamic requirements of users beyond simple transaction initiation and receipt.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T10:00:43.234000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
