<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
  <updated>2025-12-11T02:56:46.557051+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>coinjoinkillua 2025-12-10 13:13:55.378000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Embracing MimbleWimble</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T02:56:46.557086+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-embracing-mimblewimble/2081/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Atomic swaps represent a critical innovation in the field of cryptocurrency, allowing for the exchange of one cryptocurrency for another without the need for a trusted third party. However, the process becomes significantly more complicated if miners are actively censoring transactions. The challenge here lies in ensuring that your transaction is successfully mined despite such censorship.

One approach to circumvent miner censorship involves utilizing privacy-enhancing technologies or networks, such as Tor or VPNs, to mask the origin of a transaction, making it harder for miners to identify and block it. Additionally, leveraging cryptocurrencies that offer higher degrees of privacy and anonymity can also be beneficial. Cryptocurrencies like Monero or Zcash have built-in privacy features that obscure transaction details to outside observers, potentially bypassing miner scrutiny.

Another strategy entails splitting the transaction into smaller, less conspicuous parts, spreading them out over time to avoid detection. This method relies on the principle that smaller, more frequent transactions might fly under the radar of censoring entities. It's a technique akin to the concept of "smurfing" in money laundering, where large sums of money are broken down into smaller, less suspicious amounts.

Engaging with mining pools directly, especially those known for prioritizing privacy and opposing censorship, could also provide a pathway for executing atomic swaps amid censorship. By establishing relationships with these entities, one might find willing partners to mine their transactions regardless of external pressures to censor. This direct engagement underscores the importance of community and ideological alignment within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.

Finally, the utility of decentralized exchanges (DEXs) cannot be overstated. DEXs operate without a central authority, offering an alternative platform for atomic swaps that might be less susceptible to the influences driving censorship among traditional miners. Utilizing a DEX for atomic swaps may offer a more resilient path forward, leveraging the inherently decentralized nature of blockchain technology to uphold principles of freedom and open exchange.

In summary, overcoming miner censorship during atomic swaps requires a multifaceted approach that includes employing privacy tools, breaking down transactions, directly engaging with sympathetic mining pools, and utilizing decentralized exchanges. Each of these strategies offers a potential solution to ensure that atomic swaps can be executed even in the face of adversarial conditions, thereby preserving the decentralized, permissionless ethos of the cryptocurrency space.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T13:13:55.378000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
