<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Building a vault using blinded co-signers</title>
  <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:17.229499+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-10T14:15:51.084000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Building a vault using blinded co-signers</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:17.229537+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/building-a-vault-using-blinded-co-signers/2141/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the potential for enhancing the flexibility and functionality of blockchain transactions through the integration of more sophisticated Zero-Knowledge (ZK) proofs within a protocol setup. It outlines a method whereby a taproot address commits to a zk-verifier, controlled by co-signers. This structure allows for spending from the address with the assurance that it complies with a predetermined policy, akin to emulating a covenant, thus broadening the scope of how transactions can be secured and validated.

The discussion further explores the possibility of utilizing any proof system desired for this purpose, including Trusted Execution Environments (TEE), with the unique commitment serving to identify the chosen system. This approach could significantly enhance security and flexibility in transaction verification and policy enforcement on the blockchain.

Moreover, the email suggests that the establishment of a reputation system for co-signers could be crucial. By assembling multiple highly reputable co-signers, who are unaware of each other's participation, it is possible to form robust quorums. This idea introduces a novel layer of trust and reliability into the process, potentially elevating the integrity and resilience of blockchain transactions and policies.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T14:15:51.084000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
