<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2025-12-12T02:56:21.483969+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.819000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-11T17:25:49.819000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T02:56:21.484000+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussion of post-quantum cryptography (PQC), the adequacy of a 128-bit security level is critically analyzed, especially in the context of its resilience against quantum attacks facilitated by Grover's algorithm. The essence of this examination hinges on the understanding that a 128-bit key effectively offers a 64-bit security level against such quantum computational attacks, assuming each byte is accounted for in the calculation. This level of security, while potentially sufficient for thwarting short-range attacks, raises questions regarding its overall robustness and long-term viability in safeguarding information against adversaries equipped with quantum computing capabilities.

The conversation underscores the necessity of evaluating cryptographic strength not just in conventional terms but through the lens of quantum-resistant metrics. This involves a nuanced consideration of how current encryption standards might fare when faced with the unprecedented computational power promised by quantum technology. The focus on "per envelope bytes" further delves into the specifics of data protection mechanisms, emphasizing the importance of assessing security at a granular level to ensure comprehensive defense strategies are in place against both present and future threats.

In this contemplation of PQC's readiness against quantum challenges, the dialogue serves as a reminder of the ongoing evolution required in cryptographic practices. As the landscape of digital security shifts in anticipation of quantum advancements, it becomes imperative to continually reassess and fortify encryption methodologies to stay ahead of potential vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T17:25:49.819000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
