<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Writing version 2 of my Bitcoin Game Theory book with de Gruyter, what should I cover?</title>
  <updated>2025-12-13T02:48:42.447295+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>micah541</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-12T23:39:21.239000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Writing version 2 of my Bitcoin Game Theory book with de Gruyter, what should I cover?</title>
    <updated>2025-12-13T02:48:42.447333+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-version-2-of-my-bitcoin-game-theory-book-with-de-gruyter-what-should-i-cover/2161" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of updating a book is underway, with an invitation for feedback on its contents and any areas where improvements or changes could be needed. This initiative aims to refine and enhance the material presented in the book, ensuring it meets the highest standards of relevance and accuracy for its readership. The book in question focuses on topics detailed within its table of contents, which can be reviewed [here](https://micah-warren.ghost.io/book-table-of-contents/). The author has made the book available online, facilitating easy access to its full content through the provided link, which leads to the publisher's site at [De Gruyter Brill](https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/9783110772845/html).

In seeking feedback, the author emphasizes the importance of community input in the revision process. By doing so, the objective is to identify areas that may require updates, additional information, or correction. This collaborative approach not only enhances the quality of the work but also ensures that it remains relevant and useful to its intended audience. The engagement with readers and potential contributors through their feedback is a crucial step in the book’s ongoing development process.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T23:39:21.239000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
