<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
  <updated>2025-12-16T02:59:50.788482+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-15 03:13:31.693000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
    <updated>2025-12-16T02:59:50.788514+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/modifying-bip54-to-support-future-ntime-soft-fork/2163/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a nuanced aspect of blockchain technology, particularly focusing on the implications of a specific type of soft fork. This soft fork is noted for potentially causing significant delays in the blockchain's median time compared to real-time. Such delays can adversely affect transactions that are set to become spendable at specific times based on timestamps (nTimeLock), rather than block height. This situation could be particularly problematic for transactions where the timelock setting is enforced by OP_CLTV, as it could unintentionally restrict access to funds earlier than anticipated.

To address the issue of nTime overflow, a proposed solution involves the calculation of a 64-bit nTime64 from the existing 32-bit nTime. The method for this includes combining the upper 32 bits of the previous block's median time with the lower 32 bits of the current block's nTime. If this calculated time is less than the median time of the previous block, an adjustment is made by adding a specific value. This approach essentially constitutes a hard fork, albeit one viewed as relatively minor except for the fact that it would avoid the complete halt of the chain. Moreover, this solution implies the necessity for a 64-bit replacement for the timestamp-based nLockTime feature to maintain its functionality post-implementation.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-15T03:13:31.693000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
