<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
  <updated>2025-12-17T02:54:31.671075+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-16 16:14:28.256000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
    <updated>2025-12-17T02:54:31.671108+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/modifying-bip54-to-support-future-ntime-soft-fork/2163/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the considerations around mitigating the risk of cryptocurrency confiscation through the strategic use of timelocks, suggesting that by signaling activation far in advance, for instance, several decades, the associated risks can be significantly reduced. It is pointed out that it is unlikely for many coins to have a single spending path timelocked beyond 2050, indicating a thoughtful approach to future-proofing cryptocurrencies against potential legal or regulatory challenges. The argument further elaborates on maintaining the risk of confiscation at levels no higher than those already established for BIP54, which includes a technical stipulation limiting to 2500 `CHECKSIG` operations, suggesting that under these conditions, the threat of confiscation should not deter future planning.

Moreover, the narrative underscores the importance of avoiding hard forks whenever possible, highlighting a preference for making amendments to existing protocols, such as BIP54, that would allow for adaptations through soft forks rather than more disruptive changes. This reflects a strategic and cautious approach to blockchain protocol evolution, emphasizing the need for foresight and minimal adjustment costs. The conversation implies that while immediate decisions may not be necessary, there is value in considering how current standards can be adjusted with minimal disruption to maintain flexibility and security in the face of potential future challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-16T16:14:28.256000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
