<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
  <updated>2025-12-18T02:53:40.983144+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-17 15:05:14.661000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Modifying BIP54 to Support Future nTime Soft Fork</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T02:53:40.983172+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/modifying-bip54-to-support-future-ntime-soft-fork/2163/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the approach towards protocol design decisions within the Bitcoin community, particularly focusing on the preference between hard forks and soft forks. The argument presented suggests that while there is a general tendency to avoid hard forks in favor of soft forks, this should not be considered an absolute rule. The emphasis is on making the best protocol design decisions based on the specific circumstances at hand rather than adhering strictly to a general avoidance of hard forks. 

In particular, the conversation points out that concerns about potential issues that might arise 80 years into the future should not deter the community from making decisions that are deemed best for the protocol today and in the coming decades. It's argued that the possibility of a chain split, a common concern associated with hard forks, is trivially preventable in the discussed context. Therefore, the focus should be on optimizing protocol decisions for the current era of Bitcoin's lifespan rather than being overly cautious about speculative future problems. This perspective challenges the conventional wisdom within the Bitcoin development community, advocating for a more flexible approach to protocol updates that prioritize immediate and medium-term benefits.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-17T15:05:14.661000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
