<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-Statechains Without States</title>
  <updated>2025-12-18T02:54:46.408952+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>evd0kim</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-17 21:17:23.977000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-Statechains Without States</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T02:54:46.408990+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-statechains-without-states/2166/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an exploration of the technical aspects and privacy considerations in statechain-like designs, a specific transaction was examined to understand the practical implications. The transaction in question was accessed by making a request to a public node using the TxId, which returned detailed information including a proof and hashes. This examination underscores the balance between privacy enhancement and the necessity for thorough analysis of trade-offs in proposed architectural improvements.

The command executed to retrieve the transaction data was ```curl http://63.176.138.198:8091/v0/transactions/19094a66fc30f775d7cc3279862c3c166caa70061dd8a1cd51613e91fb442ca6 | jq```, which fetched a comprehensive JSON response detailing the transaction's elements such as the proof, public inputs like input and output commitments, messages, index in block, hash, block height, and timestamp.

The transaction's proof, formatted in a long string of characters, along with its public inputs—comprising input and output commitments and an array of messages—highlight the intricate details involved in such transactions. Specifically, the input commitments and output commitments are presented as arrays, indicating the data points necessary for validating the transaction without compromising on privacy. Additionally, the transaction details include its unique hash, the block height at which it was included in the blockchain, and the exact time of the transaction, pinpointing its position within the blockchain's ledger.

This detailed breakdown not only provides insights into the transaction's structure but also illustrates the complexity and the depth of information required to analyze privacy and security within blockchain transactions. It further emphasizes the importance of scrutinizing the trade-offs involved in enhancing privacy through architectural changes, especially in the context of statechain designs where the balance between transparency and privacy is critical.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-17T21:17:23.977000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
