<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-21T03:03:13.560029+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>optout</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-20 05:24:25.185000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-21T03:03:13.560059+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bmax-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-l1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles/2165/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the comparison between BMAX and Hashpool, focusing on their approaches to addressing the valuation of probabilistic future mining shares. Hashpool introduces a solution through the concept of mining futures, which essentially creates a marketplace for valuing the current worth of mined shares that will be realized fully in the future when a block is found. This system allows participants to trade shares at a discounted price now, with the expectation of achieving the full price once a block is successfully mined.

In evaluating BMAX's position relative to Hashpool, it's essential to understand the foundational principles and mechanisms each platform employs to tackle the inherent challenges of mining share valuation. The comparison seeks to highlight the unique aspects and potential advantages of BMAX in this competitive landscape. By analyzing the methodologies and market strategies of both platforms, one can gain insights into their effectiveness in solving the stated problem and their value proposition to users within the cryptocurrency mining community.

For further information on Hashpool and its approach to mining futures, interested parties are encouraged to visit [Hashpool](https://hashpool.dev/). This resource provides a comprehensive overview of the platform's goals, technological infrastructure, and how it aims to innovate within the domain of blockchain mining by offering a novel solution to the issue of future share valuation.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-20T05:24:25.185000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
