<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
  <updated>2025-12-21T03:02:31.055070+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-20 13:25:35.482000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
    <updated>2025-12-21T03:02:31.055104+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/understanding-and-mitigating-a-op-ctv-footgun-the-unsatisfiable-utxo/1809/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussion highlights a significant issue with small-amount Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) being frozen due to spam, however, it's important to note that larger funds remain unaffected and spendable thanks to the `OP_CTV` script, indicating this situation does not constitute an attack vector. This incident underscores the critical importance of selecting appropriate data types for financial calculations in programming. Specifically, the use of floating-point numbers for handling monetary values is strongly discouraged due to the inherent risk of rounding errors. Instead, the recommendation is to employ unsigned 64-bit integers (`u64`) for representing currency values in smaller units like satoshis or millisatoshis, which can safeguard against such inaccuracies.

This advice is not only applicable to traditional software development environments but also extends to modern web technologies. For example, JavaScript, a language historically limited by its floating-point arithmetic, now supports `BigInt` - a data type that allows for precise integer arithmetic without the limitations of floating-point precision. This advancement makes `BigInt` an excellent choice for financial computations in web applications, ensuring accuracy when dealing with cryptocurrency transactions or any financial operations requiring high precision.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-20T13:25:35.482000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
