<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-12-21T03:01:46.804888+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>coinjoinkillua</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-20 17:48:33.624000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-12-21T03:01:46.804918+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scaling-noncustodial-mining-payouts-with-ctv/1753/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the domain of cryptocurrency mining, there's a nuanced debate regarding the preferences of miners, also known as hashers, when it comes to choosing between custodial services and self-sovereignty. A common assumption prevails that most miners would opt for a custodian that charges slightly higher rewards fees in exchange for managing the complexities associated with mining. This belief, however, does not universally hold true. There exists a notable segment of the mining community that values the principle of decentralization inherent in cryptocurrency's ethos more highly than the potential financial gains offered by custodians. These individuals are willing to accept lower fees in favor of maintaining greater control over their mining operations and supporting a decentralized mining network.

This sentiment underscores a broader discussion within the cryptocurrency sphere about the trade-offs between convenience and control. While custodial solutions offer ease of use and potentially higher immediate returns, they do so at the cost of centralizing power within the hands of a few service providers. On the other hand, self-sovereignty aligns with the foundational principles of blockchain technology by promoting a more distributed and democratic approach to mining. The inclination towards self-sovereignty among a significant portion of hashers reflects a conscious decision to prioritize long-term values of decentralization and autonomy over short-term financial incentives. 

The ongoing dialogue between these two perspectives is crucial for understanding the evolving dynamics of cryptocurrency mining and the values that guide the decisions of those within the network. It highlights the diversity of thought within the community and suggests that the future of mining could lean towards more decentralized practices if the voices advocating for self-sovereignty continue to gain traction.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-20T17:48:33.624000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
