<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-12-29T03:09:21.698082+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-28 05:09:37.658000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T03:09:21.698121+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/25" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the exploration of Braidpool's approach to mining shares, which is distinct from traditional perspectives. The emphasis is on understanding the economic implications as highlighted in an ongoing thread accessible at [this thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bmax-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-l1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles/2165). Despite reviewing Braidpool's documentation, there remains a lack of clarity regarding their claim and how it aligns with the goals of creating a system that does not require custodial intervention or the use of oracles.

In attempting to address these uncertainties, the focus shifts towards developing an alternative model that eschews the need for signing aspects commonly associated with share distribution. Instead, the proposed solution leans heavily on the principles of game theory and the mechanism of random share selection. This approach aims to preserve the non-custodial nature of the transaction process, thereby eliminating reliance on intermediaries and enhancing the system's integrity and trustworthiness. Through this exploration, there is an evident pursuit of innovative methodologies to reconcile economic interests with technological feasibility, ensuring that the model remains accessible and beneficial to a broad spectrum of participants within the digital currency landscape.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-28T05:09:37.658000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
