<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2025-12-31T02:59:54.610951+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-30 13:23:39.118000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2025-12-31T02:59:54.610983+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses concerns and potential alternatives related to address reuse in the context of blockchain technology. The sender expresses skepticism about initiatives that might encourage address reuse, highlighting the ongoing efforts to avoid such practices within the blockchain community. They point out that [Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA)](https://cisaresearch.org/), which utilizes Schnorr signatures, offers not only similar benefits in terms of savings but also presents additional advantages. The sender acknowledges their involvement with the CISA project, indicating a possible bias towards its merits.

Furthermore, the email introduces `OP_CIV`, a proposal by Tadge Dryja, as a more flexible solution especially in the realm of post-quantum scenarios. This proposal is mentioned to share certain similarities with the discussed concept yet differentiates itself by offering greater flexibility. A link to a Google Groups discussion ([Bitcoindev](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/oFbEQb_DB3I)) provides further insights into this proposal, suggesting an ongoing dialogue within the community regarding innovative solutions to address reuse and the broader challenges it entails. 

In summary, the communication reflects a blend of caution against practices like address reuse, while simultaneously exploring and contributing to advancements in cryptographic techniques and blockchain technology. Through discussing alternatives like CISA and `OP_CIV`, the email embodies a forward-looking perspective aimed at enhancing efficiency and security in blockchain operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-30T13:23:39.118000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
