<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2025-12-31T03:00:07.019545+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>billymcbip</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-30 14:39:49.147000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2025-12-31T03:00:07.019568+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the ongoing discussion about optimizing the economic bandwidth of blockchain's base layer without necessarily increasing block size, the concept of OP_CC has emerged as a significant proposition. This method is highlighted for its potential to facilitate these enhancements by leveraging an opt-in feature, which seems to be a compromise many are willing to make despite the privacy concerns it raises. This willingness is evidenced by the current trends in address reuse, suggesting that the trade-off between privacy and efficiency is considered manageable by numerous stakeholders within the ecosystem.

The dialogue also brings to light an alternative proposal named `OP_CIV`, developed by Tadge Dryja. Despite its relevance and similarities to the topic at hand, it is acknowledged that Dryja’s proposal might not offer advantages in terms of space savings when compared to elliptic curve signatures (EC sigs), a crucial aspect of blockchain transactions and data storage efficiency. The point is further elucidated with a reference to a resource ([watch here](https://youtu.be/cqjo3rmd6hY?t=1154)), where Dryja himself acknowledges the limitations of his proposal regarding space efficiency.

Furthermore, the ease of implementation for wallet developers is underscored as a notable advantage of OP_CC over alternatives like `OP_CIV`. This ease of adoption could play a critical role in its acceptance and widespread use, making it a preferable option for enhancing the base layer's economic bandwidth. The conversation reflects a nuanced analysis of the trade-offs and technical considerations that must be navigated to improve blockchain technology's foundational layers, emphasizing the importance of community feedback and expert input in these discussions.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-30T14:39:49.147000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
