<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
  <updated>2025-12-31T02:59:16.954913+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-30 19:14:33.031000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A quantum resistance script only using op_ctv/op_txhash and no new signatures</title>
    <updated>2025-12-31T02:59:16.954947+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures/2168/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges associated with a specific construction in cryptocurrency technology. A notable issue is that both the transaction (T) and expenditure (E) amounts must be predetermined at the creation of Phase0 outputs, necessitating that these outputs be precisely consolidated to match the total CTV (CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) output values. This requirement complicates the process as it limits flexibility and foresight into future transactions.

Another significant concern raised is the quantum vulnerability due to the reliance on secp256k1. Since NUMS (Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve) points are susceptible to being compromised by a quantum adversary, this presents a security risk that cannot be overlooked. The reliance on this cryptographic method means that in its current form, the construction would not be considered quantum safe, making it vulnerable to advancements in quantum computing.

Furthermore, the current model does not allow users to redirect funds to a new, quantum-safe address upon withdrawal. This limitation underscores a lack of adaptability to emerging security needs and restricts users' ability to protect their assets in the face of evolving technological threats.

A proposed solution to these issues involves the adoption of CCV (Conditioned Commitment Verification) instead of relying on TXHASH for transactions. Utilizing CCV could effectively address the initial concerns by allowing for value flow enforcement and the integration and extraction of the CTV reveal spend at the time of spending rather than at creation. Additionally, CCV could facilitate an escape spend with value flexibility, thereby enhancing the security and usability of the construction. By incorporating CCV, the structure could mimic a standard vault construct while uniquely embedding a hash and preimage for the reveal-spend, potentially overcoming the highlighted challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-30T19:14:33.031000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
