<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-01T03:11:25.780969+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>billymcbip</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-31 12:16:33.056000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T03:11:25.781010+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the context of smart contract consolidations, particularly focusing on the `OP_CCV` operation, it is noteworthy to mention that this operation facilitates consolidations by accepting specific input parameters. These parameters include `mode`, set to `CCV_MODE_CHECK_OUTPUT`; a `taptree` identifier, marked as `-1` indicating the current input taptree merkle root; a `pk` parameter also set to `-1` denoting the current input internal key; along with an `index` value of `0` which points to the first output, and an empty `data` field. This structured approach allows for the effective consolidation of transactions within the same contract framework.

However, a limitation arises when the objective shifts towards making payments to a third party, identified through a new script pubkey (SPK). In such instances, the consolidation process facilitated by `OP_CCV` remains insufficient on its own. To successfully transfer value to a third party, an additional transaction becomes necessary. This secondary transaction is responsible for spending the consolidated output, thereby enabling the transfer of value outside the original contract's confines. This requirement underscores a critical aspect of smart contract operations on platforms supporting `OP_CCV`, highlighting the need for strategic planning in transaction structuring for third-party payments.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-31T12:16:33.056000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
