<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:11.145766+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-31 22:29:20.555000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:11.145802+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse elucidates the intricacies of a consolidation transaction, which inherently limits its functionality to transferring value within the same contract, a concept commonly recognized in the blockchain community. This limitation sparks a suggestion for an alternative approach termed 'delegation.' Delegation is described as a process where one Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) grants authorization to other UTXOs for spending. The technical implementation of such delegation could be achieved through a specific Script, detailed in the discussion. This Script, leveraging the `CCV_MODE_CHECK_INPUT` flag, essentially checks that the first input adheres to a predefined condition, thereby facilitating a compact form of delegation if the conditions are met.

However, the practical application of this Script and the concept of delegation via Contract-Constraint Verification (CCV) raises concerns regarding its efficiency and security. For instance, the script's length of 38 bytes suggests that the benefits of byte-saving through CCV-based delegation would only manifest in scenarios involving significantly larger scripts. Moreover, the possibility of delegating authorization "to itself" is critiqued for lacking safety due to its tautological nature, implying that such a method would always validate the first input without genuine verification of its authenticity or intent.

In summary, while the proposal introduces a novel use of CCV for script-based delegations to potentially streamline transactions within the blockchain framework, it simultaneously underscores the necessity of cautious consideration regarding the method's applicability, especially in terms of security and practical utility. The discussion concludes with the acknowledgment that the original proposition for an operation code (OP_CCV) might not fulfill the intended purpose of enhancing transaction consolidation through delegation, hence inviting further exploration into alternative solutions.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-31T22:29:20.555000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
