<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:20.752243+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-12-31 23:01:47.551000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:20.752276+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical aspects of implementing transactions in a blockchain context, specifically focusing on the efficiency and cost implications of different methods for consolidating transactions. The current system only allows consolidation transactions to move value forward within the same contract, necessitating an additional transaction for payments to a third party or new SPK (Smart Property Key). This requirement stems from the need to spend the consolidated output, which introduces complexities in terms of transaction management and costs.

The conversation highlights the comparison between two operational codes (opcodes), OP_CCV and OP_CC, used within this blockchain mechanism. OP_CCV is noted for requiring 5 extra bytes per consolidated input, alongside a transaction that consists of one input and one output. Despite these additional requirements, OP_CCV is presented as a more cost-effective solution compared to the traditional method of consolidation. The enhanced efficiency of OP_CCV is attributed to its ability to be broadcast as a TRUC transaction through package relay, eliminating the need for a separate fee input if the consolidated output is utilized immediately. This characteristic significantly reduces the overall transaction fees and resource usage, making it a preferable option for managing blockchain transactions efficiently.

Overall, the focus is on optimizing transaction consolidation by leveraging specific operational codes that streamline the process and reduce associated costs. By examining the technical specifications and potential benefits of OP_CCV over OP_CC, the discussion sheds light on innovative approaches to enhance transactional efficiency within blockchain frameworks.</summary>
    <published>2025-12-31T23:01:47.551000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
