<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Writing version 2 of my Bitcoin Game Theory book with de Gruyter, what should I cover?</title>
  <updated>2026-01-06T03:00:47.971565+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>micah</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-12 23:39:21.239000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>chness</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-06 00:39:07.093000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6424_Writing-version-2-of-my-Bitcoin-Game-Theory-book-with-de-Gruyter-what-should-I-cover-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6568_Writing-version-2-of-my-Bitcoin-Game-Theory-book-with-de-Gruyter-what-should-I-cover-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Writing version 2 of my Bitcoin Game Theory book with de Gruyter, what should I cover?</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T03:00:47.972080+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-version-2-of-my-bitcoin-game-theory-book-with-de-gruyter-what-should-i-cover/2161/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-12 23:39:21.239000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The current initiative to update a book underscores the significance of community feedback in refining its contents. This process aims at ensuring the material's relevance and accuracy by inviting suggestions on potential improvements or corrections. The book covers a range of topics, which can be explored in detail through its table of contents available [here](https://micah-warren.ghost.io/book-table-of-contents/). Moreover, the full content of the book has been made accessible online by the author, with a direct link to the publisher's site at [De Gruyter Brill](https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/doi/10.1515/9783110772845/html), facilitating ease of access for a thorough review.
The call for feedback is part of a broader strategy to engage the community in the book’s revision process. By soliciting input from readers and potential contributors, the author aims to identify areas that may benefit from updates, additional information, or corrections. This collaborative approach not only aims to enhance the quality of the work but also ensures its continued relevance and utility to the intended audience. Through this engagement, the book’s development process becomes a shared endeavor, leveraging the collective knowledge and perspectives of its readership to foster a more comprehensive and accurate body of work.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>