<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:18.130088+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>arminsdev</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 17:00:01.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-23 15:32:50.927000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6670_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6678_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T02:58:18.131026+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The exploration into the feasibility of implementing a scheduled transaction broadcast in Bitcoin Core highlights an innovative approach aimed at enhancing user privacy and flexibility within the network. This feature would allow transactions to be set for future execution, either based on a specific time or block height, providing users with the ability to mask the actual time of transaction creation. Such functionality is seen as beneficial for situations where current bitcoin scripts are insufficient for addressing future conditions or when users wish to obscure their transaction timings for privacy reasons. The proposed `schedulerawtransaction` RPC is modeled after the existing `sendrawtransaction` RPC but is designed to accommodate the scheduling aspect, which would necessitate additional commands for managing these transactions effectively.
This discussion also delves into the broader implications of transaction timing and the potential vulnerabilities associated with it. There's a significant focus on anti-snipping techniques and the importance of concealing the timing details of transactions to protect against information leakage. By obscuring when a transaction was initiated, blockchain networks can enhance their security posture and mitigate risks that could be exploited by malicious actors. This concern underscores the ongoing challenges and efforts required to maintain privacy and security within blockchain technology, emphasizing the need for continuous innovation in combating sophisticated attacks.
Another critical aspect discussed involves the comparison between client-side and node-level implementation of transaction scheduling. The preference leans towards integration at the node level to achieve enhanced security and anonymity, making it harder to trace transactions back to their origins based on timing alone. The introduction of such features directly into nodes could significantly alter transaction flows, offering users more strategic control over when their transactions are executed. This approach not only presents technical challenges but also raises questions about its impact on network performance and the broader blockchain ecosystem.
Furthermore, the concept extends to practical applications, particularly for &quot;power users&quot; who operate their own nodes and require advanced functionalities like automated transaction broadcasts. The necessity for a dedicated node setup reflects the demand for more sophisticated wallet solutions beyond the basic capabilities currently provided. This scenario highlights the intersection of technological capability and user convenience, advocating for enhancements that cater to the diverse needs of blockchain network participants.
Lastly, the motivation behind these discussions is primarily centered on improving privacy within peer-to-peer (P2P) communication networks by delaying transaction broadcasts. This strategy aims to complicate the efforts of adversaries in analyzing and correlating transaction patterns, thus offering a layer of protection to network participants. Despite its potential benefits, this method is acknowledged as part of a larger array of privacy strategies, given its limitations in completely obfuscating participant activities from external observation. The overarching theme is the pursuit of greater privacy and security in blockchain transactions, emphasizing the need for innovative solutions to address the evolving landscape of digital currency and its inherent challenges.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>