<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:12.243720+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:12.244214+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the introduction of a new feature in Bitcoin Core, aimed at enabling users to schedule transactions for future broadcast to the bitcoin network. This functionality seeks to address various needs, such as disguising the actual time a transaction was created or accommodating future conditions that cannot be met through current bitcoin scripts. The proposed mechanism would allow the bitcoin node to hold transactions designated for later broadcasting, relying on a distinct memory structure and a separate file to ensure consistency even after restarts. This feature would be facilitated by a new RPC named `schedulerawtransaction`, which would work similarly to the existing `sendrawtransaction` but with added scheduling capabilities. However, it's highlighted that this feature is still in the conceptual stage, with ongoing efforts to assess its feasibility through prototype testing.
There are several considerations and potential challenges associated with this feature. One concern is the historical context of such a feature within the bitcoin development community and whether there have been prior attempts to introduce similar functionalities. The interaction of scheduled transaction broadcasting with existing features, particularly the issue of broadcasting over temporary connections as outlined in PR 29415, raises questions about possible conflicts. Moreover, the deferred nature of transaction broadcasting implies that the success or failure of these transactions will not be immediately evident, necessitating subsequent monitoring by users to determine their status on the network.
The feature's effectiveness and implementation might confront significant hurdles, including addressing anti-sniping measures to prevent information leaks regarding the transaction's origination time. The suggestion to implement transaction scheduling on the client-side rather than at the node level poses a question about the real benefits of such an approach. Furthermore, the complexity of the feature suggests that additional RPCs might be necessary to manage scheduled transactions effectively, such as commands for listing and canceling scheduled broadcasts. These aspects underscore the need for thorough exploration and feedback from the development community to refine the feature and ensure its utility and reliability in meeting users' needs.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>