<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:57.402613+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T02:58:57.403296+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The concept of Scheduled Transaction Broadcast in Bitcoin Core is being explored to enhance the flexibility and anonymity of blockchain transactions. This feature would allow users to schedule their transactions for future broadcast based on absolute time or block height, introducing a strategic element to transaction timing that could obscure the actual creation time and cater to future conditions unaddressable through bitcoin scripts. The proposed implementation would utilize a new RPC, `schedulerawtransaction`, which would function similarly to `sendrawtransaction` but with added scheduling capabilities. Transactions under this scheme would be stored separately and persist across restarts, highlighting the effort to maintain consistency and reliability in transaction broadcasting without immediate delivery guarantees.
The discussion extends into the realm of anti-snipping, focusing on the importance of concealing the timing details of transactions to mitigate risks associated with information leakage. Anti-snipping measures are crucial for enhancing privacy and security within blockchain networks, aiming to prevent potential vulnerabilities that could be exploited through the analysis of transaction timestamps. This consideration reflects the broader challenges of ensuring data confidentiality and integrity in blockchain technology, emphasizing the need for continuous improvement in security practices against evolving threats.
Furthermore, the dialogue touches upon the advantages of implementing scheduled transaction broadcasting at the node level rather than relying on client-side solutions. Integrating this feature directly within nodes could offer superior security and anonymity by complicating the traceability of transactions based on their timing. The proposal suggests additional RPCs would be necessary to support the full functionality of this feature, including commands for listing and canceling scheduled transactions. These considerations underscore the technical and practical complexities of incorporating such features, potentially offering users more control over their transactions while raising questions about network performance and the overall impact on blockchain infrastructure.
The acknowledgement of these discussions indicates a recognition of both the potential benefits and challenges associated with scheduled transaction broadcasts. It highlights the ongoing efforts to address user needs for flexibility and privacy while also considering the technical feasibility and implications for the wider bitcoin network. The exploration of this feature represents a step towards more strategic and secure transaction management within the blockchain space, catering to advanced users who require detailed control over their transaction timings without compromising on security or anonymity.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>