<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP The Cat - Draft discussion</title>
  <updated>2025-12-11T02:59:40.079987+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>Claire  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 23:52:00.191000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 13:34:20.100000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6402_BIP-The-Cat-Draft-discussion.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6415_BIP-The-Cat-Draft-discussion.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP The Cat - Draft discussion</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T02:59:40.080454+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-the-cat-draft-discussion/2153/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-09 23:52:00.191000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The proposal under discussion, labeled &quot;The Cat&quot; and hosted on [GitHub](https://github.com/ostromcode/The-Cat/tree/main), presents an innovative strategy for the Bitcoin network. Its primary goal is to curtail the prevalence of non-monetary applications, such as inscriptions and Stamps-style protocols, which currently represent a significant portion (over 40%) of the Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) set in commonly used implementations. The document is detailed, featuring a rationale for the approach, alongside a Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) section designed to address potential enquiries and concerns regarding this Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). Given its groundbreaking nature, it is expected to ignite substantial debate within the cryptocurrency community.
The person behind this proposal has engaged in extensive preparatory work, involving consultations with a close-knit group of technical peers and friends prior to seeking broader feedback from the global Bitcoin development community. This step underscores a commitment to open discourse and critical evaluation, with an understanding that such engagement is crucial for the proposal's refinement. By encouraging a wide array of perspectives, the initiator demonstrates a readiness to consider constructive criticisms that could either significantly shape or lead to the abandonment of the proposal based on its merits.
Furthermore, the proposer has made efforts to clarify the human origin of the proposal, directly addressing any rumors or speculations about potential artificial intelligence (AI) authorship. This clarification aims to highlight the personal investment and wide-ranging consultations undertaken during the drafting process. Despite facing varied opinions and critiques regarding the proposed methods, there remains an openness to dialogue and improvement through continued interaction with the community. This approach reflects a desire to collaboratively find an effective solution to the challenges posed by non-monetary uses of Bitcoin, thereby contributing positively to the ecosystem as a whole.
However, the proposal has elicited concerns, notably regarding the precedent it may set for consensus-level confiscation of UTXOs, signaling a significant point of contention that could influence its reception and future discussions within the community.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>