<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-03T02:53:08.871034+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>marathongary  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-03-05 17:21:57.602000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>ariard  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-03-05 22:59:10.884000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ariard  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-03-06 22:19:10.503000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-02 01:24:28.721000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4414_BIP-119-OP-CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY-no-activation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4416_BIP-119-OP-CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY-no-activation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4421_BIP-119-OP-CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY-no-activation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6360_BIP-119-OP-CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY-no-activation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-03T02:53:08.871687+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-119-op-checktemplateverify-no-activation/1494/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-03-05 17:21:57.602000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The ongoing discussion in the Bitcoin community, particularly around Bitcoin Core's Pull Request 31989 and related proposals like BIP-119 (CheckTemplateVerify), delves into the technical intricacies and potential impacts of introducing new functionalities to the Bitcoin protocol. The key focus is on enhancing the protocol's capabilities through careful, incremental innovations that aim to preserve the network's security and efficiency. The debate underscores the importance of evaluating such proposals based solely on their technical merits, setting aside any biases stemming from historical challenges associated with similar enhancements.
BIP-119, spearheaded by Jeremy Rubin, introduces a conservative approach to integrating covenants into Bitcoin, aiming for a balanced expansion of the protocol’s functionality without overstepping bounds that might compromise its foundational principles. This proposal, along with its historical counterparts like OP_CHECKOUTPUTHASHVERIFY and OP_SECURETHEBAG, represents a thoughtful progression towards embedding more complex mechanisms within the Bitcoin architecture. However, concerns have been raised about the potential risks associated with combining CheckTemplateVerify with other primitives. Critics argue that this could inadvertently reintroduce vulnerabilities to specific types of attacks, such as those exploiting transaction withholding to manipulate miner incentives or disrupt time-sensitive Layer 2 protocols.
A particular point of contention revolves around the theoretical risk of costless bribe attacks, exemplified by the TxWithhold concept. Drawing parallels with the phenomenon of Miner Extractable Value (MEV) observed in other blockchain ecosystems, contributors express apprehension that unchecked expansions to Bitcoin's script capabilities might lay the groundwork for exploitative practices that could undermine the network's integrity. This perspective emphasizes the need for a cautious approach to developing and implementing new script primitives, advocating for a thorough assessment of potential threats and the identification of robust mitigations before proceeding.
Furthermore, the discussion touches upon speculative future developments, such as contracts powered by an OP_CSFS primitive, which could facilitate trust-minimized bribes to miners. Such advancements raise significant concerns about the long-term security and reliability of the Bitcoin network, highlighting the delicate balance between innovation and the preservation of a stable, secure underlying monetary system. The discourse reflects a broad spectrum of viewpoints, underlining the complexity of evolving a pioneering technology like Bitcoin in a manner that safeguards its core values while exploring avenues for meaningful progress.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>