<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T03:30:15.232874+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 12:29:24.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>bruno</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 20:15:20.209000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-10 10:00:43.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>arminsdev</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 17:00:01.020000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-23 15:32:50.927000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ArmchairCryptologist</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-24 09:09:58.466000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-26 08:27:33.713000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>ArmchairCryptologist</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-28 19:32:07.799000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6394_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6400_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6403_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6411_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6670_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6678_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6679_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6688_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6703_Scheduled-Delayed-Transaction-Broadcast.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Scheduled (Delayed) Transaction Broadcast</title>
    <updated>2026-01-29T03:30:15.234094+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scheduled-delayed-transaction-broadcast/2148/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 14:46:40.052000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discourse on integrating a scheduled transaction broadcast feature into Bitcoin Core delves into its potential to enhance user privacy and strategic transaction management. This proposed functionality allows users to set transactions for future execution, either based on a specific time or block height, addressing needs such as disguising the transaction creation time or preparing for future conditions unsuitable for current bitcoin scripts. The concept hinges on a new RPC called `schedulerawtransaction`, developed to store designated transactions until their dispatch time. Despite its utility, this feature raises concerns regarding compatibility with existing functionalities and the unforeseeable nature of transaction outcomes post-scheduled broadcast.
In parallel, discussions about anti-snipping and the confidentiality of transaction timings underscore the broader context of privacy within blockchain networks. By examining the mechanics of how transactions are timestamped, stakeholders aim to mitigate vulnerabilities that could be exploited through timing analysis. This concern extends to the design consideration of whether such privacy-enhancing features should be implemented at the client side or directly within network nodes, with a leaning towards the latter for added security benefits.
The proposal for scheduled transactions is particularly relevant for scenarios requiring automated transaction execution following specific triggers, such as incoming payments. This functionality, absent in current wallet solutions, necessitates a dedicated node setup for advanced users seeking automation without manual oversight. Extending the RPC interface to manage such transactions is crucial, highlighting the need for additional commands for comprehensive transaction management.
Enhancing privacy in peer-to-peer networks through delayed transaction broadcasting emerges as a strategy to obscure user activities from adversaries. While effective to a degree, this approach does not fully eliminate the risk of pattern analysis and identification by external observers. It emphasizes the ongoing challenge of maintaining privacy within blockchain technology and the necessity of incorporating such strategies into a larger privacy framework.
Addressing privacy in cryptocurrency transactions, the discussion identifies the transparency inherent in blockchain networks as a double-edged sword. While facilitating security and trust, it also poses privacy risks, especially when multiple transactions can be linked to an individual. Introducing random delays between transactions is suggested as a method to disrupt the linkage between them, thereby enhancing user privacy. However, the practicality of manually implementing such delays highlights the need for automated solutions within cryptocurrency systems.
The utility and implications of using nLockTime for scheduling transactions are explored, revealing a nuanced landscape of potential benefits and limitations. While nLockTime offers a theoretical mechanism for enhancing privacy by decoupling transaction initiation from its broadcast timing, practical challenges hinder its effectiveness. The existing implementation strategies within Bitcoin Core complicate the use of nLockTime for precise scheduling purposes, suggesting room for improvement in transaction management tools.
Finally, the feasibility of specifying transaction target times via block height rather than physical time is assessed, revealing complexities in achieving precision due to the variable nature of block discovery times. This evaluation provides insights into the practical considerations necessary for implementing a reliable and user-friendly scheduled transaction feature within Bitcoin or similar cryptocurrencies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>