<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2026-01-22T03:08:14.326332+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 17:25:49.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 15:19:02.087000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 21:07:53.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:23:18.752000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:40:38.988000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 01:03:07.859000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 17:14:29.961000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-20 01:32:00.101000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-20 01:54:05.383000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-21 07:53:06.011000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6418_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6421_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6437_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6446_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6447_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6443_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6644_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6649_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6650_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6651_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6656_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2026-01-22T03:08:14.327736+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The SHRINCS signature scheme represents a significant advancement in cryptographic technology, amalgamating the efficiency of stateful hash-based signatures with the resilience offered by stateless counterparts. This hybrid approach is particularly advantageous for applications requiring a limited number of signatures from a given key, striking a balance between operational efficiency and reliability. At its core, SHRINCS employs an unbalanced XMSS tree for stateful operations alongside a variant of SPHINCS+ for stateless scenarios, facilitating seamless transitions based on the state's integrity. The dual-mode functionality extends to key generation, restoration, signing, and verification processes, underscored by the innovative use of a master seed during initial setup. This methodology not only optimizes signature size through early authentication path length reductions but also introduces WOTS+C to enhance both efficiency and security.
The discourse on post-quantum cryptography (PQC) delves into the adequacy of 128-bit security levels, scrutinizing their effectiveness against quantum attacks, notably those leveraging Grover's algorithm. This analysis reveals that conventional assessments might underrepresent the computational demands of hash function circuit evaluations, essential for each Grover's algorithm iteration. Furthermore, the scalability challenges associated with Grover's algorithm accentuate the need for reevaluating cryptographic strength in the quantum era. The exploration into SHRINCS at NIST security level 3 further exemplifies this point, presenting detailed insights into signature sizes and the implications of quantum computing advancements on cryptographic practices.
An interesting facet of the conversation revolves around the checksum mechanism employed within the Winternitz One-Time Signature Scheme (WOTS) and its enhanced variant WOTS+. The inclusion of checksums is crucial for preventing specific attack vectors, demonstrating the nuanced security measures integral to these schemes. Additionally, the discussion touches upon alternative checksum strategies that prioritize efficiency and data integrity, offering a broader perspective on optimizing cryptographic protocols.
The potential vulnerability of WOTS to specialized hardware attacks, such as those facilitated by ASICs, prompts a reevaluation of signature immutability strategies. While increasing envelope and signature sizes appears as a tentative solution, the dialogue eventually shifts towards reconsidering more viable alternatives, highlighting the dynamic nature of cryptographic research and development.
SHRINCS' unique approach to wallet seed management within blockchain technology underscores the ongoing challenges in secure state maintenance. The distinction between stateful and stateless paths, dictated by the original device generating the seed, raises questions about practicality and user convenience. Moreover, the modular proposal to incorporate `OP_SPHINCS` and `OP_WOTS` separately within the Taproot tree framework reflects a thoughtful consideration of privacy, efficiency, and standardization concerns amidst evolving cryptographic landscapes.
Lastly, the issue of wallet software's inability to confirm exclusive seed usage across devices illuminates the inherent security risks associated with state mismanagement. The proposed use of secure storage slots, potentially facilitated by TPM technology, suggests an innovative yet complex solution to ensuring state integrity. However, the realization of such mechanisms requires careful attention to parallel processing vulnerabilities, emphasizing the intricate balance between user accessibility and cryptographic security.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>