<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-18T02:54:28.746793+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-17 19:44:45.900000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-18 01:06:43.788000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6444_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6452_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6455_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T02:54:28.747529+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bmax-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-l1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles/2165/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</published>
    <summary>BMAX introduces a groundbreaking approach to enhancing the Bitcoin ecosystem by addressing the economic disparity between immediate and future satoshi value, aiming to establish a decentralized base money. This initiative leverages Bitcoin's existing mechanisms to create a market-driven discovery of a discount curve for sats, without modifying Bitcoin's core protocol or relying on external financial instruments. At its heart, BMAX functions through a proof-of-work sharechain, similar to a p2pool, offering a unique internal structure that values the time aspect of sats by issuing shares and bonds. Shares represent perpetual claims on future Bitcoin rewards, whereas bonds are created by burning shares for a place in a queue to be serviced by future rewards, introducing a deflationary mechanism to the supply of shares.
The system's dynamic bonding price, adjusted via a control loop, aims to maintain bond redemption times around a specified target. This facilitates a Bitcoin-native term structure, allowing for the pricing of sats' time value internally. Economically, BMAX seeks to parallel unbonded shares with solo mining opportunities, while bonded shares offer a structured investment in Bitcoin's future value. This could lead to the establishment of a native Bitcoin pricing model for time, potentially enabling more complex economic activities based on Bitcoin's monetary foundation.
Additionally, BMAX is described as a decentralized, fair, and open lottery for future UTXO, with transferrable tickets. It operates on a network inspired by p2pool mining, making it appear to Bitcoin as any other hashrate source. This lottery is fair, equivalent in expectation to solo mining, and is perpetual, distributing the current pot every time a mainchain block is found. Unlike other lotteries within the Bitcoin ecosystem, BMAX does not require pre-enumeration of participants, emphasizing its openness and accessibility.
The necessity for a Bitcoin-native time pricing mechanism is underscored if Bitcoin is to serve as global base money. The note suggests that in a fixed supply scenario like Bitcoin, the risk-free interest rate should theoretically be 0%, with any positive rate indicating some degree of risk, such as the uncertainty of receiving Bitcoin in the future. This perspective highlights the potential risks associated with the sharechain pool's future hashrate and the sustainability of mining payouts. While BMAX may not directly discover Bitcoin's native time pricing, it offers a practical solution by providing an insurance-like feature for continuity in mining payouts, thus presenting an immediately useful enhancement to Bitcoin's economic landscape.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>