<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
  <updated>2025-12-23T02:59:10.079986+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-20 17:45:05.552000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>simul</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-21 04:37:01.593000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-22 14:07:54.236000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6466_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6469_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6472_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6481_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-12-23T02:59:10.080752+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/major-bip-360-update/2170/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Ethan Heilman, Isabel Foxen Duke, and Hunter Beast have recently revised BIP 360 in response to the need for more coherent documentation and clearer guidelines following significant technical updates. This overhaul aims to address quantum-related risks without adopting post-quantum signature schemes. They introduced a novel output type named &quot;Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH),&quot; specifically designed to omit the key path spend to protect against vulnerabilities in Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) that could be exploited by quantum computing advancements. This change is pivotal for fortifying Bitcoin's defenses against potential emerging threats to ECC, emphasizing an essential move towards enhancing cryptocurrency's quantum resistance. The revised proposal also includes test vectors in Python and Rust to aid in understanding and implementing the proposed changes, with the authors inviting community review on platforms such as the [BIP Repo](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1670) and [BIP360.org](http://bip360.org). Their efforts highlight a commitment to collaboratively refine Bitcoin's security against advanced cryptanalytic technologies.
The choice of naming the transaction type as Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH) raises questions about future compatibility and clarity, especially with the potential integration of new technologies like Simplicity into blockchain applications. The concern revolves around ensuring names accurately reflect their functionality and remain intuitive as the blockchain ecosystem evolves. As blockchain technology becomes more complex and diverse, there is a pressing need to revisit terminologies to ensure they clearly describe their functions and accommodate future developments without causing confusion or obsolescence. This approach aids in maintaining a cohesive understanding of blockchain functionalities and supports the seamless integration of new features and technologies.
Moreover, an innovative method has been discussed for protecting cryptocurrency transactions from the threats posed by quantum computing. By leveraging TXHASH for a multi-step secret reveal mechanism for transaction paths, this concept allows for the secure vaulting and spending of coins under the threat of advanced quantum technologies without the need for new signature schemes. It emphasizes a shift towards script-only transactions, notably incorporating operations like OP_CTV and OP_TXHASH, to attain quantum resistance. Interested parties can explore this idea further through resources like [Delving into Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-quantum-resistance-script-only-using-op-ctv-op-txhash-and-no-new-signatures/2168), demonstrating a proactive approach to safeguarding cryptocurrencies against quantum vulnerabilities.
Lastly, the naming convention &quot;Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash&quot; is critically assessed for potentially not being the most accurate or descriptive given the technology's specifics. The term might mislead as it refers to a Merkle root rather than a script hash and is not limited to tapscript. A more precise naming could be something reflecting &quot;pay to script tree merkle root,&quot; suggesting a need for terminology that better encapsulates the function and structure of these blockchain elements.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>