<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
  <updated>2025-12-06T02:45:21.092245+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>morehouse  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 20:02:58.406000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 15:24:40.009000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 15:33:08.635000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>morehouse</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 16:12:51.326000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6378_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6384_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6386_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6387_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-06T02:45:21.092912+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-lnd-0-19-0/2145/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-04 20:02:58.406000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent LND version 0.19.0 release addresses several critical security vulnerabilities crucial for users to update in order to protect their funds. This version, available via [LND 0.19.0](https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lnd/releases/tag/v0.19.0beta), introduces essential fixes targeting a Denial of Service (DoS) vulnerability and two theft of fund vulnerabilities, significantly enhancing the platform's security posture.
One highlighted issue is the Infinite Inbox DoS vulnerability, which posed a severe risk by exploiting the combination of large internal queue sizes and an unrestricted incoming connection policy. This flaw could allow attackers to rapidly deplete LND's memory resources, potentially leading to system crashes or hanging processes. A detailed examination of this vulnerability can be found in a dedicated [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-infinite-inbox-dos/), underlining the urgency of updating to mitigate such threats.
Additionally, the Excessive Failback Exploit 2 has been identified as a variant of a previously known bug that directly endangers users' funds by enabling unauthorized fund theft from LND nodes. Despite updates aimed at preventing similar exploits, this variant managed to bypass existing safeguards. More information on this exploit is provided in a specific [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-excessive-failback-exploit-2/).
Another critical vulnerability discussed is the Replacement Stalling Attack, which revealed weaknesses within LND's sweeper system. These vulnerabilities could be exploited to delay LND’s attempts at claiming expired Hash Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs) on the blockchain, potentially allowing an attacker to seize nearly the entire balance of a channel after an 80-block stalling period. The discovery of this vulnerability during a code review of LND's sweeper rewrite in 2024 highlights the ongoing need for vigilance and regular software updates. Further details on this attack are elaborated in another [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-replacement-stalling-attack/).
The discourse also touches upon the protocol's `max_htlc_value_in_flight_msat` channel parameter, which is designed to limit the value of concurrent HTLCs in a channel. However, it's noted that LND's [default behavior](https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lnd/blob/a76f22da9d167bb456c0828c3c723c6e41e1f01d/server.goL1599-L1605) does not impose a limit on this parameter, and there appears to be no way to override this default setting in LND.
These updates and discoveries underscore the evolving nature of threats facing the Lightning Network and the critical importance of continuous efforts to secure the network against both known and emerging vulnerabilities. Users are urged to upgrade to LND 0.19.0 or later versions to safeguard their investments against these identified security flaws.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>