<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
  <updated>2025-12-07T03:00:11.920564+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>morehouse  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 20:02:58.406000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>AntoineP  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 15:24:40.009000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 15:33:08.635000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>morehouse  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 16:12:51.326000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ariard</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-06 01:31:02.473000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>morehouse</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-06 15:31:27.660000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6378_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6384_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6386_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6387_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6390_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6391_Disclosure-Critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-LND-0-19-0.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Disclosure: Critical vulnerabilities fixed in LND 0.19.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-07T03:00:11.921619+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-critical-vulnerabilities-fixed-in-lnd-0-19-0/2145/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-04 20:02:58.406000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent release of LND version 0.19.0 marks a significant advancement in addressing critical security vulnerabilities within the Lightning Network Daemon (LND), underscoring an ongoing effort to enhance the platform’s security posture. This update, available at [LND 0.19.0](https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lnd/releases/tag/v0.19.0beta), introduces essential fixes aimed at mitigating one denial of service (DoS) vulnerability and two theft of fund vulnerabilities. The Infinite Inbox DoS vulnerability represented a considerable risk by exploiting large internal queue sizes combined with an unrestricted incoming connection policy, potentially leading to rapid depletion of LND's memory resources. This issue was thoroughly examined in a [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-infinite-inbox-dos/), which highlighted the necessity of updating to avoid such risks. Additionally, the Excessive Failback Exploit 2, a variant of a previously identified bug, posed a direct threat by enabling unauthorized fund theft from LND nodes. An effort to amend BOLT 5 with an [update](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1233) aimed at thwarting similar future exploits did not deter this variant from bypassing existing safeguards, as detailed in a specific [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-excessive-failback-exploit-2/). Furthermore, the discovery of the Replacement Stalling Attack vulnerability during a code review of LND's sweeper rewrite revealed weaknesses that could be exploited to delay LND’s attempts at claiming expired Hash Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs) on the blockchain, posing a significant risk to the channel's balance. More information on this attack is provided in another [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-replacement-stalling-attack/).
The proactive identification and resolution of these vulnerabilities underscore the critical role that responsible disclosure and patching play in maintaining the security and trust of the Lightning Network infrastructure. It exemplifies the importance of timely and efficient response mechanisms to mitigate risks, especially those that could lead to the theft of user funds. The work done by security researchers in identifying these vulnerabilities before they can be exploited is invaluable in neutralizing potential threats and averting significant financial losses for users while preserving the reputation of the Lightning industry.
A notable security concern involves the channel balance within transactions being vulnerable to theft by attackers, particularly when a channel permits its entire balance to be used in concurrent Hashed Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs). This scenario underscores the need for stringent security measures and thoughtful configuration settings within LND to safeguard against such vulnerabilities. Addressing this concern is crucial for maintaining transaction integrity on the Lightning Network and ensuring protection against unwarranted theft.
Another aspect worth discussing is the handling of the total balance within a channel through concurrent HTLCs, specifically related to the `max_htlc_value_in_flight_msat` parameter within LND. Despite LND's default configuration allowing the entire balance of a channel to be utilized without restrictions, there lacks a mechanism to modify this behavior. This operational nuance highlights the delicate balance between flexibility and risk management within the Lightning Network's ecosystem.
In discussions around security vulnerabilities, the concept of “cat-and-mouse” attacks was brought up, referencing adversarial tactics involving the aggregation and disaggregation of `option_anchors` second-stage HTLCs transactions. This approach indicates a broader challenge in securing transaction fees and optimizing fee bumping strategies to protect against replacement cycling and similar attacks. The dialogue also touches upon the ideal timeline for disclosing vulnerabilities, suggesting that extending the usual 90-day embargo to better align with the release cycles of Lightning implementations might reduce the risk of making fixes too obvious to malicious actors. There's also mention of a proposed BOLT to cover claimable outputs detection, generation of claims transactions, fee selection, and scheduled rebroadcast of claims transactions, highlighting the ongoing discussion on improving security measures and protocols within the Lightning Network ecosystem. This discourse illustrates the complexity of security in blockchain technologies and emphasizes the importance of continued vigilance and innovation to protect against evolving threats.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>