<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
  <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:33.975926+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-30 12:53:14.176000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>fjahr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-30 13:23:39.118000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-30 14:39:49.147000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>reardencode</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-30 18:44:51.990000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 12:16:33.056000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 16:59:33.626000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 17:35:57.479000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>billymcbip</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 17:54:57.957000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 21:58:32.774000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>salvatoshi</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 22:29:20.555000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>reardencode</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-31 23:01:47.551000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6487_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6488_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6489_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6490_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6498_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6501_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6502_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6503_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6504_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6500_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6505_OP-CC-A-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CC: A simple introspection opcode to enable cheaper consolidations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-01T03:12:33.977621+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cc-a-simple-introspection-opcode-to-enable-cheaper-consolidations/2177/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-30 12:53:14.176000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The new Tapscript opcode, named **OP_CHECKCONSOLIDATION (OP_CC)**, is proposed to enhance the efficiency of transactions that consolidate multiple Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) on the Bitcoin network. By altering the processing of inputs from the same scriptPubKey (SPK), **OP_CC** allows for significant space savings on the blockchain. It treats the first input spending a particular SPK normally but enables subsequent inputs to bypass individual signatures by relying on the first input's signature. This method dramatically reduces the required witness size for each additional input from the same SPK, making UTXO consolidation more space-efficient and contributing to a leaner blockchain.
Address reuse and its implications are a focal point of concern within the blockchain community, with efforts like [Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA)](https://cisaresearch.org/) offering both efficiency savings and additional benefits without encouraging address reuse. The sender expresses a preference for CISA, possibly due to their involvement in the project. Another alternative, `OP_CIV`, proposed by Tadge Dryja, offers flexibility, particularly in post-quantum scenarios, despite not providing space savings compared to elliptic curve signatures. The dialogue suggests that while OP_CC presents a viable option for improving economic bandwidth on the blockchain's base layer, alternatives like `OP_CIV` and considerations around address reuse and privacy remain critical.
The introduction of `OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` (CCV) represents another approach towards achieving efficient blockchain transactions. CCV facilitates signatureless consolidation and external fee payment, allowing for simplified transaction processes and maintaining the flexibility of traditional methods. This innovation supports the consolidation of transactions under specific parameters but requires a second transaction for payments to third parties, hinting at potential limitations in broader application scenarios.
Discussions around these technological advancements reflect a nuanced understanding of the trade-offs between privacy, efficiency, and scalability within the blockchain ecosystem. Stakeholders appear willing to compromise on privacy for efficiency gains, indicating a pragmatic approach to optimizing blockchain technology. However, there's an acknowledgment of the collective responsibility to manage privacy implications, with suggestions that incentivizing or disincentivizing certain behaviors through technological solutions can influence the system's overall privacy health. The conversation underscores the importance of continuous exploration and dialogue in developing solutions that balance efficiency, privacy, and scalability on the blockchain.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>