<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-19T02:59:18.553205+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-17 19:44:45.900000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-18 01:06:43.788000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 00:39:45.236000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6444_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6452_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6455_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6462_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T02:59:18.553902+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bmax-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-l1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles/2165/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The BMAX concept proposes an innovative solution to embed the time-value of money directly into the Bitcoin ecosystem, aiming to resolve the economic disparity between immediate and future usage of satoshis. This initiative does not require changes to Bitcoin's core protocol but utilizes Bitcoin's existing mechanisms to enable a market-driven discovery of a discount curve for satoshis, leveraging a proof-of-work sharechain similar to a p2pool. Shares in BMAX represent continuous claims on future Bitcoin rewards, while bonds are created by burning shares for a place in a FIFO queue, serviced by future coinbase rewards. This design hopes to make the supply of shares deflationary over time and introduces a dynamic bonding price to maintain expected redemption times, creating a Bitcoin-native term structure.
BMAX also functions as a decentralized lottery system, utilizing the bitcoin mining infrastructure to ensure impartiality and accessibility. It offers a perpetual lottery mechanism where the prize pool is allocated with each new block found, promoting active engagement and sustainability. The fairness of this system is ensured by aligning expected outcomes with those of solo mining, supplemented by the introduction of transferable tickets which add flexibility and strategic dynamics to participation.
The discussion further delves into the necessity for a Bitcoin-native time pricing mechanism, addressing the theoretical standpoint that Bitcoin, being a fixed supply currency, would inherently have a risk-free interest rate of zero percent. This theory stems from the understanding that positive interest rates typically reflect some level of risk, such as counterparty uncertainties or fluctuations in mining rewards. However, the actual scenario suggests that positive rates might reflect risks related to the sharechain pool's hashrate or potential decreases in fees/block rewards. Thus, the system’s approach towards mitigating these risks involves providing an insurance or continuity feature for mining payouts rather than discovering Bitcoin's native time pricing, making it a practical solution for current economic challenges.
In conclusion, the dialogue around BMAX and its potential to contribute significantly to the Bitcoin ecosystem revolves around the broader implications for Bitcoin as a global base currency and the practicalities of implementing such a system. There is an acknowledgment of the speculative nature of Bitcoin's role in the global financial system and a recognition of the challenges associated with quantifying and reducing uncertainty without relying on central authorities. The conversation underscores a collective desire to explore mechanisms like BMAX that can secure Bitcoin's future in a trust-minimized manner, expanding the capital pool for Bitcoin's security while offering investors a way to participate in Bitcoin's future value. However, there remains skepticism regarding the demand for such a system and its viability, prompting questions about its potential success or failure upon introduction.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>