<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - ZK-Statechains Without States</title>
  <updated>2025-12-18T02:55:01.226966+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>evdkim</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 19:47:15.843000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-17 14:26:34.508000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>evd0kim</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-17 21:17:23.977000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6445_ZK-Statechains-Without-States.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6450_ZK-Statechains-Without-States.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6453_ZK-Statechains-Without-States.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - ZK-Statechains Without States</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T02:55:01.227645+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-statechains-without-states/2166/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-16 19:47:15.843000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The introduction of statechains to the Bitcoin ecosystem over six years ago marked a pivotal step towards enhancing user privacy and transaction efficiency. The evolution of this concept, particularly through Commerce Block's Mercury Layer and the further innovation of incorporating blinded signing, has significantly refined the way statechains function. At the forefront of these advancements is a new protocol that integrates zkSNARKs into the statechain mechanism, offering an unprecedented level of privacy for state transitions. This integration not only addresses the inherent non-fungibility issue associated with statecoins but also introduces the capability for private zero-knowledge smart contracts.
This sophisticated approach situates itself as a Layer 3 (L3) solution within the Bitcoin network, facilitating a bridge contract on a Bitcoin rollup. It functions independently, employing a unique consensus mechanism, yet maintains the ability to connect with Bitcoin or other blockchains for efficient message passing. Central to its design is the enhancement of privacy for Bitcoin transactions, where users can engage in ownership transfers of funds deposited into a multisig wallet without compromising their anonymity. These transfers are made possible by locking funds into a 2-of-2 multisig setup and pre-signing unilateral exit transactions, which are a key feature of statechains.
The protocol proposes a novel payment flow that begins with depositing funds into a multisig address, subsequently mirrored on a ZK Ledger to enable peer-to-peer transfers validated by zkSNARK proofs. This architecture presents a significant leap in operational efficiency and privacy, with the inclusion of an advanced note structure within the ZK Ledger for secure transfers. Moreover, it introduces solutions to tackle potential double-spending issues and enhance note fungibility within a shielded pool.
One notable implementation challenge highlighted is Spark's &quot;leaf splitting&quot; feature for fractional UTXO transfers, which, despite its innovative approach, falls short in terms of blind signing, thereby posing certain privacy and operational limitations. However, by integrating zkSNARKs to validate key changes and manage timelocks, the new protocol substantially mitigates these concerns, offering a more streamlined and privacy-centric operation compared to traditional statechain models.
In conclusion, the protocol melds the flexibility of statechains with the privacy assurances of zkSNARK technology, positioning itself uniquely between existing Statechains and ShieldedCSV or ZKCoins. It paves the way for programmable market-based mechanics to facilitate seamless transitions into and out of shielded pools, heralding a new era of privacy-focused Bitcoin transactions. This initiative, backed by insights from contributors such as Janusz, Gus Gotoski, SuperTestnet, and fiatjaf, underscores a significant stride towards fostering a more private, secure, and efficient Bitcoin transaction landscape.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>