<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
  <updated>2025-12-21T03:04:15.678706+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>cryptoquick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-20 17:45:05.552000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6466_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6469_Major-BIP-360-Update.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Major BIP 360 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-12-21T03:04:15.679186+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/major-bip-360-update/2170/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-19 20:46:40.614000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Ethan Heilman, Isabel Foxen Duke, and Hunter Beast have embarked on an extensive rewrite of BIP 360, triggered by feedback from the community and a recognized need for clearer documentation. This overhaul is a departure from minor updates seen in the past, primarily because significant technical changes had been incorporated into the proposal, necessitating a fresh approach to improve clarity and effectively address strategies for mitigating quantum-related risks. The team's decision to revise the proposal was driven by the aim to enhance its comprehensibility and detail the measures for quantum resistance.
The revised version of BIP 360 retains its original position on not incorporating post-quantum signature schemes. Instead, it introduces a new output type known as &quot;Pay-to-Tapscript-Hash (P2TSH),&quot; which notably excludes key path spending to protect against vulnerabilities in Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) that could be exploited by quantum computing advancements or other cryptographic breakthroughs. This strategic modification is designed to strengthen Bitcoin’s defense mechanisms against potential threats to ECC, highlighting a pivotal move towards securing the cryptocurrency against quantum computing threats.
Furthermore, the updated proposal includes test vectors in Python and Rust, aiming to broaden the understanding and facilitate the implementation process of the proposed changes. The authors have made these modifications available for community review at the [BIP Repo](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1670) and on [BIP360.org](http://bip360.org). Their invitation to the community reflects a commitment to collaboratively refining Bitcoin's security features, with a strong emphasis on making Bitcoin resistant to quantum computing advances. This initiative marks an important step in preemptively safeguarding Bitcoin against emerging cryptanalytic technologies, underscoring the critical nature of proactive measures in cryptography and digital currency security.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>