<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:40.256784+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 10:41:11.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>mcelrath  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 12:49:27.107000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>AntoineP  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 16:01:19.711000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 09:11:56.983000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 09:12:48.225000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 09:48:04.361000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-05 15:10:52.986000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6365_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6369_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6371_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6379_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6380_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6381_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6383_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-06T02:44:40.257764+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation/2139/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-03 10:41:11.234000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The cryptocurrency community has been actively discussing the challenges associated with slow block propagation, particularly focusing on how it affects miners. An intriguing aspect of this discussion is the concept of optimistic mining, a method that allows miners to begin working on a new chain tip before its validation is completed. This approach aims to mitigate delays caused by the current process where miners have to wait for the complete validation of a new block, which includes several phases such as header validation and transaction verification. Optimistic mining, by allowing miners to proceed based on the assumption that a block will eventually be validated, potentially reduces the occurrence of orphan blocks and increases efficiency.
Another innovative solution to the issues faced in Bitcoin mining is proposed by Braidpool, which introduces a committed mempool for deterministic block templates, known to all nodes within its network. This system facilitates swift validation and share relay, using small share sizes and the UDP/QUIC protocol to minimize transmission times, thus enhancing efficiency and profitability for miners. However, the risk of centralization, particularly through a 51% attack, remains a concern with this model. Despite these risks, Braidpool's approach signifies a shift towards optimizing mining operations while attempting to mitigate potential security threats.
Validationless mining, or mining without fully validating a new chain tip, highlights significant security vulnerabilities within blockchain networks. This practice can lead to the creation of invalid chains, undermining the integrity and security of the system. To counteract these risks, making full validation more accessible and cost-effective is crucial, involving strategies such as optimizing block propagation and validation times. Proposals like signaling the extent of block validation efforts aim to balance the distribution of rewards and reduce centralization pressures, thereby strengthening the overall security of the network.
Furthermore, discussions around improving block propagation times include suggestions such as reducing relay-filtering, synchronizing next-block templates, and enhancing various aspects of block validation and state update processes. It’s noted that only a small proportion of Bitcoin nodes are involved in mining and directly motivated to lower block propagation times. The cooperation of non-mining nodes is essential for global transaction propagation, indicating a collective effort required to optimize the network's performance. Optimizing the internal operations of mining pools, as highlighted by instances of self-induced stale blocks by some pools, presents another area for potential improvement. These discussions underscore the complex interplay of factors affecting mining efficiency and security, emphasizing the need for ongoing innovation and collaboration within the cryptocurrency community.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>