<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
  <updated>2026-01-21T03:03:59.827865+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 17:25:49.819000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 15:19:02.087000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 21:07:53.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:23:18.752000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 22:40:38.988000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 01:03:07.859000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>jonasnick</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-19 17:14:29.961000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-20 01:32:00.101000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>conduition</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-20 01:54:05.383000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6418_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6421_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6437_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6446_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6447_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6443_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6644_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6649_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6650_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6651_SHRINCS-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SHRINCS: 324-byte stateful post-quantum signatures with static backups</title>
    <updated>2026-01-21T03:03:59.829192+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/shrincs-324-byte-stateful-post-quantum-signatures-with-static-backups/2158/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-11 08:40:59.575000+00:00</published>
    <summary>SHRINCS represents a hybrid signature scheme that ingeniously combines the performance benefits of stateful hash-based signatures with the resilience offered by stateless ones, catering especially to use cases where only a limited number of signatures are required from a specific key. This innovative approach utilizes an unbalanced XMSS tree for its stateful operations alongside a variant of SPHINCS+ for stateless operations, thereby enabling highly efficient operations under normal circumstances and providing a reliable fallback when the state is compromised. The seamless operation between stateful and stateless modes is facilitated through the derivation of the public key by hashing both the stateful and stateless public keys together. This dual-mode functionality extends across key generation, restoration, signing, and verification processes, ensuring adaptability in various scenarios.
The introduction of an &quot;unbalanced&quot; version of the XMSS tree within SHRINCS significantly optimizes the authentication path length for initial signatures, which in turn notably reduces the signature size for applications expecting a lower frequency of signatures, such as Bitcoin wallets. Additionally, the employment of WOTS+C (Winternitz One-Time Signature Scheme plus Checksum) for one-time signatures enhances both the efficiency and security of the stateful path. While the management of state presents a challenge, primarily due to potential security vulnerabilities arising from mismanagement, SHRINCS addresses this issue by allowing an effortless transition to stateless signatures whenever the integrity of the state is in doubt, thereby maintaining security even under compromised state management conditions.
The exploration of post-quantum cryptography (PQC) delves into the adequacy of a 128-bit security level against quantum attacks, particularly those facilitated by Grover's algorithm, highlighting a redefined perspective on cryptographic strength in the quantum computing era. The discussion around the National Institute of Standards and Technology's (NIST) evaluation criteria for PQC further emphasizes the computational demands posed by quantum attacks and the scalability challenges of Grover's algorithm. Moreover, the detailed examination of the SHRINCS signature scheme at NIST security level 3 reveals considerations for signature sizes and computational demands in light of advancements in quantum computing, underscoring the complexity of achieving quantum-resistant cryptographic security.
A significant focus is placed on the Winternitz One-Time Signature Scheme (WOTS) and its enhanced variant WOTS+, specifically regarding the role of checksums in safeguarding against certain attack vectors. The design of checksum mechanisms in these schemes proves crucial in preventing message impersonation or alteration, thereby maintaining the integrity of the communication. Furthermore, the discussion touches upon the potential vulnerabilities of WOTS to specialized hardware capable of generating alternative signatures, proposing strategies to fortify the immutability of WOTS signatures despite the increased computational requirements.
The discourse then shifts towards the practical implementation concerns of SHRINCS in blockchain technology, particularly addressing the challenges of secure state management on hardware wallets and the implications for wallet seed handling. The proposed integration of `OP_SPHINCS` and `OP_WOTS` as separate operations offers a modular approach, albeit with considerations regarding privacy and efficiency. This modularity raises concerns about identifiable patterns on the blockchain and potential impacts on transaction speed and cost, reflecting the ongoing dialogue between cryptographic innovation and its real-world application.
Lastly, the conversation acknowledges the difficulties in ensuring exclusive use of wallet seeds across devices, citing real-world scenarios where mishandling has led to financial losses. This discussion segues into the consideration of deploying XMSS as an opcode, leveraging directionless balanced XMSS trees to enhance privacy and succinctness in transactions. By obscuring the number of issued and remaining signatures, this approach aims to maintain anonymity and reduce blockspace usage, illustrating the nuanced balance between cryptographic protocol innovation and its practical implications in user privacy and security within digital ecosystems.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>