<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-20T02:48:08.511630+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-17 19:44:45.900000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-18 01:06:43.788000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 00:39:45.236000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-19 13:22:24.479000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6444_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6452_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6455_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6462_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6463_BMAX-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-L1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BMAX: pricing “sats now vs sats later” via a mining sharechain (no L1 changes, no custodians, no oracles)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-20T02:48:08.512375+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bmax-pricing-sats-now-vs-sats-later-via-a-mining-sharechain-no-l1-changes-no-custodians-no-oracles/2165/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-16 19:00:26.190000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The BMAX model introduces an innovative approach to integrating the time value of money into the Bitcoin ecosystem, aiming to reconcile the economic discrepancy between immediate and future use of satoshis. It proposes a decentralized system that leverages Bitcoin's existing infrastructure without requiring modifications to the core protocol or reliance on external custodians or financial instruments. At its heart, BMAX functions through a dual mechanism of shares and bonds, utilizing a proof-of-work sharechain that operates similarly to a p2pool from Bitcoin's perspective but enforces distinct internal regulations to emphasize the time-value of sats. Shares represent perpetual claims on future Bitcoin rewards, offering a probabilistic chance at earning full coinbase rewards, while bonds are created by burning shares for a place in a FIFO queue, promising future rewards and thus introducing a deflationary aspect to the supply of shares.
The system dynamically adjusts the bonding price to maintain a targeted redemption time horizon for bonds, enabling a market-driven discovery of a discount curve for sats. This setup fosters a Bitcoin-native term structure for pricing time value, potentially laying the groundwork for more complex economic applications based on Bitcoin's monetary base. The objective is to create a balanced environment where unbonded shares mirror solo mining prospects, and bonded shares provide a structured investment into Bitcoin's future value, enhancing Bitcoin's utility as a foundational monetary layer.
Additionally, BMAX explores a novel lottery system within the Bitcoin mining framework, promoting active participation through a fair, decentralized, and perpetually operating mechanism. This lottery parallels traditional Bitcoin mining while allowing for transferable tickets, adding strategic flexibility to participant engagement. Such a system could broaden interest in the technological and participatory aspects of Bitcoin mining, presenting an alternative to conventional lottery models.
The discourse around Bitcoin as a potential global base currency underscores the need for a native mechanism to price time, considering Bitcoin's fixed supply and the theoretical premise of a zero percent risk-free rate. This rate reflects the equal valuation of present and future values, challenged by finite lifespans and uncertainties surrounding Bitcoin's future. The BMAX proposal, with its focus on futures markets through shares and bonds tied to block rewards, addresses these uncertainties. It navigates the complexities of network reliance and the temporal scope of financial instruments, suggesting a paradigm shift towards risk management and economic sustainability within the Bitcoin ecosystem.
The conversation also touches upon the practical implications of implementing such a model, highlighting the challenges of protocol risk, economic incentives, and fostering a trust-minimized environment. Skepticism exists regarding the direct application of BMAX on Bitcoin and its reception by the community, emphasizing the importance of aligning with Bitcoin's principles of decentralization and autonomy. Through this innovative dialogue, BMAX emerges as a critical examination of Bitcoin's capacity to support diverse economic activities, proposing a model that could redefine capital allocation and security in Bitcoin's evolution as a self-sustaining global monetary system.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>