<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
  <updated>2025-12-04T02:52:49.942617+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>optout</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 10:41:11.234000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>mcelrath</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 12:49:27.107000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-03 16:01:19.711000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6365_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6369_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6371_Optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Optimistic mining tip (slow block propagation)</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T02:52:49.943225+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-mining-tip-slow-block-propagation/2139/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-03 10:41:11.234000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The practice of mining on a new chain tip while its validation is pending, colloquially known as SPV mining or spy mining, involves miners beginning to mine on top of a block after only validating its header, not its full content. This method has been a topic of discussion due to its potential to undermine the security of blockchain systems. It can lead to the extension of an invalid chain, posing risks of fake confirmations either through malicious actions or inadvertently, such as during the BIP 66 soft fork where invalid blocks were created due to validationless mining. Furthermore, it raises concerns about reliance on external means, like legal systems, to enforce block validity when the cost of trustless validation becomes prohibitively high.
Mitigating the risks associated with validationless mining is challenging but essential. Strategies include optimizing block propagation and validation times for both common and attack scenarios, and ensuring that access to full validation remains as affordable as possible, thereby minimizing the duration potentially invalid jobs are sent to hashers. These efforts aim to safeguard against the exploitation of long block validation times and improve overall system security. Initiatives like BIP 54 and proposals for miners to signal the extent of their validation efforts represent steps towards reducing the negative impacts of deferred validation by promoting transparency and accountability within the mining community.
Braidpool introduces a novel approach to address some of these issues by utilizing a committed mempool that allows for deterministic block template generation, known to all nodes within its network. This system enables faster validation by comparing the Merkle root for incoming blocks and requires validation of significantly fewer transactions than traditional methods. Additionally, Braidpool's use of UDP/QUIC technology for share relay enhances the speed of this process further. Plans to precompute templates for subsequent blocks promise to optimize miner profits, particularly in environments with high fee rates, though this is contingent on the blocks being mined within the Braidpool network. While this does not eliminate the threat of a 51% attack, it shifts the risk to the Braidpool infrastructure itself, offering a unique solution to the challenges of slow block propagation and the risks of mining on unvalidated tips.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>