<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-12-05T02:56:05.775460+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-20 16:18:51.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-22 22:48:46.117000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-23 00:35:19.795000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-26 00:46:27.546000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-27 21:01:18.494000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-29 00:01:44.200000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-01 20:19:43.253000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 04:36:13.212000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 04:38:51.748000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6299_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6312_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6314_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6347_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6353_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6356_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6358_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6374_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6375_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T02:56:05.777414+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The project's primary focus has been on monitoring the Lightning gossip network, collecting gossip messages from a variety of nodes since its inception at PlebFi Miami. The resources related to this project, including code repository, raw data, and presentation slides, are accessible [here](https://www.example.com). Observations from this endeavor revealed a notable decrease in the convergence delay for message propagation within the network, improving from around 500 seconds to 200 seconds for 75% propagation. This enhancement is attributed to Lightning Network implementations adopting more peer-to-peer connections by default. Additionally, it was found that a significant number of messages were transmitted to the observing node by less than a quarter of its peers, suggesting possible inefficiencies or selective filtering within the network. The analysis also highlighted that channel_update messages formed 60% of all messages, with 20% of channels having over 144 messages, a factor important for considering proposed rate limits for gossip.
Looking ahead, there is an ambition to expand the project by establishing permanent infrastructure to receive gossip from various geographic locations and P2P graph segments, with a focus on further studying message spread. Community engagement is encouraged, especially for suggestions on metrics calculation, tracking specific nodes' gossip propagation, or other contributions. There's ongoing exploration into making raw data available for independent analysis, particularly for unsupervised anomaly detection, despite limitations in data science expertise.
The potential transition of the Lightning Network (LN) from a message flooding protocol to a more efficient design inspired by the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) was discussed. This new approach could reduce latency and propagation delay, benefiting LN by relying on Minisketch for gossip reconciliation, aiming for a collision-resistant, short data element mapping mechanism. Challenges such as varying node filtering policies and the practicality of frequent set reconciliations were noted, emphasizing the importance of engaging with LN implementers on the feasibility of these changes.
Further discussion critiqued the superlinear decoding costs associated with Minisketch when handling large sketches, suggesting more frequent reconciliations to mitigate increased CPU usage. The potential of using Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables (IBLT) over Minisketch was considered, given their different cost-benefit dynamics, despite higher overheads. A study comparing various synchronization strategies provided insights into their trade-offs and applicability, indicating the promise of the Rateless IBLT (RIBLT) scheme for efficient encoding across different set sizes.
The conversation also touched upon the challenges of using short channel IDs in blockchain technology, proposing an innovative approach for efficient communication and data management. It included strategies for managing bandwidth, message size, and addressing reconstruction failures, highlighting the significance of strategic data management and encoding techniques in optimizing blockchain communication protocols.
In summary, these discussions reflect a comprehensive examination of methods to enhance efficiency and scalability within the Lightning Network through optimized data reconciliation and communication strategies. They underscore the importance of community involvement, the exploration of advanced technical solutions, and continuous iteration based on feedback and practical experimentation.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>