<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
  <updated>2025-12-12T02:55:28.988031+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>vostrnad  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-28 19:01:24.876000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-29 13:23:38.249000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-29 18:03:45.531000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 01:07:45.030000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>vostrnad  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 07:38:02.854000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:40:29.150000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:47:03.686000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:48:59.786000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>AntoineP  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-06-06 17:50:58.354000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 23:37:47.100000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5147_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5154_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5157_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5160_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5161_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5170_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5163_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5172_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5244_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6422_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T02:55:28.989339+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-confiscatory-transaction-weight-limit/1732/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-05-28 19:01:24.876000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The collaborative effort by several mining pools to support the mining of non-standard transactions, specifically those exceeding the standard 100 kvB weight limit like BitVM transactions, marks a significant shift in the Bitcoin transaction standards landscape. This initiative is aimed at enhancing network efficiency and reducing reliance on centralized template providers, aligning with the goals of the Consensus Cleanup proposal that addresses the issue of quadratic hashing in pre-SegWit inputs. A modified rule has been proposed to allow the inclusion of a single non-coinbase transaction weighing more than 400,000 WU in a block, which raises concerns regarding Miner Extractable Value (MEV) and the impact on smaller miners and decentralized payout schemes.
The possibility of implementing a soft fork to align maximum transaction sizes with the current relay size has been discussed, a solution that would manage the complexities introduced by transactions exceeding this size. This discussion includes hopes for BitVM to find alternatives to relying on oversized transactions, spurred by advancements in cryptographic techniques. Additionally, an alternative approach for protocols requiring large transactions to negotiate directly with miners for storage solutions within their coinbases suggests a potential workaround to the limitations posed by the proposed rule.
An innovative proposal focuses on leveraging the height of inputs at validation time to mitigate risks and introduce a dynamic element through a rule that would periodically expire and require renewal. This strategy aims to minimize potential disruptions while addressing future uncertainties, though it carries political risks due to the necessity for repeated consensus changes among stakeholders.
The complexity and functionality demands of certain protocols necessitate large scripts, highlighting the difference between simple data storage needs and comprehensive processing capabilities required by these protocols. The activation of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) could significantly alter how data and transactions are managed, particularly in relation to the coinbase transaction, by potentially limiting its size and streamlining large-scale transaction handling.
The resilience of BitVM technology in efficiently managing transaction frequencies without compromising performance is emphasized, alongside the challenges presented by the OP_RETURN function and its implications for specific protocols requiring substantial data embedding in transactions. The dialogue also explores the potential benefits of modifying policies to facilitate the creation of optimal block templates and reduce reliance on centralized template providers, despite ongoing debates about the tangible advantages of such changes.
Concerns are raised regarding the construction of block templates as transaction sizes approach block limits, highlighting the technical and economic complexities involved. The discussion proposes a hypothetical consensus cap on transaction sizes and explores the feasibility of treating large transactions distinctly within the block construction process to simplify decision-making and mitigate network congestion.
Finally, the conversation touches upon the implications of supporting large transactions within the BitVM ecosystem, acknowledging the potential for new applications that utilize large transactions to complicate regulatory efforts. The need for preemptive measures to address the challenges posed by large transactions is underscored, emphasizing the importance of maintaining network integrity and efficiency amidst evolving demands.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>