<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposal: Limit ScriptPubKey length, with one exception</title>
  <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:34.245966+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>billymcbip  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-08 18:34:00.062000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>Rob1Ham</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-09 23:56:27.317000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6396_Proposal-Limit-ScriptPubKey-length-with-one-exception.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6406_Proposal-Limit-ScriptPubKey-length-with-one-exception.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposal: Limit ScriptPubKey length, with one exception</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T02:56:34.246353+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-limit-scriptpubkey-length-with-one-exception/2150/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-12-08 18:34:00.062000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a new proposal aimed at improving the management of ScriptPubKey lengths in UTXO transactions on blockchain networks. The proposal suggests implementing a limit of 260 bytes for the ScriptPubKey length in new UTXOs, with an exception for transactions within blocks that are divisible by 256 without remainder. This approach is intended to be adopted through a soft fork as a new consensus rule within the network.
The primary motivation for proposing a limit on the ScriptPubKey length stems from the desire to enhance encoding efficiencies and reduce overhead. With the current encoding system, the maximum ScriptPubKey length that can be encoded as a single byte is 252 bytes. This size is considered optimal for chunking data while keeping overhead low. By setting the limit at 260 bytes, the proposal aims to accommodate all standard scripts without significantly increasing the overhead, which comprises 8 bytes for the amount, 1 byte for indicating the ScriptPubKey length, and an additional byte for the OP_RETURN opcode, if applicable.
An innovative aspect of the proposal is the exemption for every 256th block, which introduces flexibility into the system and addresses concerns related to the risk of data confiscation. This concern was highlighted in a previous suggestion by @Rob1Ham, who proposed a higher limit of 520 bytes. Although the proposed 260-byte cap is seen as a starting point, it is believed to effectively cover standard scripts. The originator of this proposal seeks feedback, especially regarding the exemption for certain block heights, to refine and potentially incorporate this change in future upgrades of the network's protocol.
It is important to note that this proposal was originally put forward by @portlandhodl, indicating collaborative efforts within the community to optimize blockchain functionality and performance.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>