<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2018-January-015557</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP 117 Feedback</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:32:50.686421+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Jan_2018/015557_BIP-117-Feedback.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2018/015532_BIP-117-Feedback.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2018-January-015557</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP 117 Feedback</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:32:50.686421+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2018-January/015557.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the bitcoin-dev mailing list revolves around various proposals and their potential consequences. One proposal involves the use of a native MAST output type, which would eliminate the need for the alt stack hack currently in use for segwit script version 0. However, some are questioning the benefits of introducing tail call semantics before implementing a native MAST output type. Additionally, there is debate over the importance of static analysis in determining execution limits for smart contracts. While some argue that limits should remain in place to prevent overly expensive block validation costs, others believe that these limits are unnecessary and hinder the flexibility of future extensions. Ultimately, the applicability of any given principle depends on the specific facts of the situation. In the case of the low-s issue, the change did not result in the confiscation of funds due to mitigating factors such as the ability of third parties to malleate non-conforming transactions and the fact that the vast majority of transactions were already conforming.</summary>
    <published>2018-01-16T03:27:26+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
