<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:13:21.966163+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-02T09:00:06.358000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:13:21.966195+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current discussion revolves around a specific proposal to make modifications to the Lightning Network BOLT specifications, as indicated by a recent pull request on GitHub. The suggestion focuses on implementing changes or additions to the protocol, with a particular emphasis laid out in pull request number 1044 on the official GitHub repository of the Lightning Network BOLTs. This modification aims to improve or clarify the existing specifications.

A notable contributor, identified as @joostjager, has been specifically mentioned, suggesting that their input or feedback could be crucial for the advancement or refinement of this proposal. The mention implies a direct call for engagement, indicating that the contribution or insights from Joost Jager are being sought after in relation to the proposed changes.

Furthermore, the act of adding a sentence to the bolt specification PR (Pull Request) suggests an incremental update or clarification is being introduced to the ongoing discussion or documentation. This reflects an effort to enhance the precision, effectiveness, or comprehensibility of the specifications within the Lightning Network's development community.

This dialogue and collaborative effort underscore the open-source ethos prevalent among developers working on decentralized technologies like the Lightning Network. It highlights a process where suggestions, improvements, and critiques are openly discussed and incorporated, facilitating the evolution of the technology through community involvement. The inclusion of a direct link to the pull request ([https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1044](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1044)) within the communication further enables interested parties to directly access, review, and contribute to the discussions surrounding the proposed changes.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-02T09:00:06.358000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
