<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:12:30.288755+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager 2025-06-03 09:38:47.461000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:12:30.288781+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion emphasizes the challenge of enhancing privacy and performance in network systems, highlighting the limitations of conventional approaches such as adding granularity or enforcing minimum hold times to create friction. These methods are seen as temporary fixes that do not address the underlying issues, given that users seeking faster routes will ultimately find them, regardless of imposed restrictions. The argument suggests that latency, an essential factor for users, can be deduced through observation of multiple transactions, thereby indicating that explicit hold time data might not be necessary for identifying slower nodes within a network.

A proposed solution involves developing a scoring system to assess delays observed across route hops, which could effectively pinpoint underperforming nodes over time without relying on easily bypassed or outdated filtering techniques. This approach advocates for a shift towards transparency regarding network performance pressures, arguing that this visibility could drive the adoption of more robust and effective privacy solutions that align with user incentives.

The perspective offered leans towards designing networks that are inherently resilient and maintain privacy standards, even amidst competition on latency. It criticizes reliance on superficial measures that merely veil issues without solving them, suggesting a sustainable network design does not just obscure problems but addresses fundamental concerns about privacy and efficiency head-on. This stance encourages embracing the challenges presented by performance pressures as an opportunity to innovate stronger privacy solutions that genuinely meet user needs.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-03T09:38:47.461000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
