<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Path Queries: Addressing Payment Reliability and Routing limitations</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:07:24.904797+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>brh28.025000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-04T15:25:00.025000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Path Queries: Addressing Payment Reliability and Routing limitations</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:07:24.904831+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/path-queries-addressing-payment-reliability-and-routing-limitations/1672/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The draft PR created in the BOLTs repository, found at [https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1259](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1259), encompasses an updated proposal that seeks to introduce significant enhancements or modifications. The incorporation of this new proposal into the BOLTs (Basis of Lightning Technology standards) suggests a proactive approach towards improving or expanding the existing frameworks and protocols within this technological space. This initiative indicates a move towards refining or possibly expanding the operational capabilities of the Lightning Network by addressing current limitations, introducing new features, or optimizing existing processes to better meet user or system requirements.

The act of submitting a draft PR serves as an initial step in the review and collaboration process, inviting feedback, discussions, and contributions from other developers and stakeholders within the community. It represents a collaborative effort to ensure that any proposed changes are thoroughly vetted, technically sound, and beneficial to the broader ecosystem. By choosing to share the proposal via a draft PR, it underscores the importance of transparency, peer review, and community involvement in the development and evolution of the Lightning Network's underlying standards and technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T15:25:00.025000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
