<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:24:08.633024+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ErikDeSmedt.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-05T07:35:37.012000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:24:08.633056+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scaling-noncustodial-mining-payouts-with-ctv/1753/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring innovative solutions to reduce transaction costs in blockchain technology, a notable approach involves utilizing Ark alongside the concept of transaction trees. This method specifically addresses the inefficiencies faced by small miners who traditionally accumulate numerous small Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). By leveraging OP_CTV, mining pools can efficiently organize payments into a structured format known as a transaction tree, where each leaf represents a VTXO.

The essence of this strategy lies in its capability to aggregate multiple small VTXOs into a singular, more substantial UTXO. This process not only streamlines the transactional footprint on the blockchain but also significantly lowers the cost associated with managing numerous tiny outputs. For instance, instead of having to deal with 100 UTXOs each valued at 0.0001 BTC, a miner can consolidate these into one UTXO worth 0.01 BTC. Such consolidation is advantageous for small miners, as it enables them to offboard their accumulated funds in a single, cost-effective transaction, thereby circumventing the burdensome fees that erode their mining rewards.

This approach, detailed further through resources such as [this overview](https://docs.second.tech/protocol/intro/utxo-sharing-using-transaction-trees), showcases a promising avenue for enhancing the economic viability for small-scale participants within the cryptocurrency mining ecosystem. By adopting such innovative methodologies, the blockchain community can foster a more inclusive and efficient environment for all stakeholders involved.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-05T07:35:37.012000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
