<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:17:40.874480+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-06T17:50:58.354000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:17:40.874514+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-confiscatory-transaction-weight-limit/1732/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the implications of large transactions within the BitVM ecosystem, specifically addressing concerns that, while these transactions might be rare, their existence alone could pose significant challenges. The primary concern highlighted is the potential for miners to create a publicly accessible mechanism for submitting these large transactions directly. This development could pave the way for new applications that utilize this feature, potentially gaining popularity and thereby complicating efforts to limit transaction sizes through consensus.

The conversation acknowledges that even if the demand for large transactions remains low, the very possibility of their support can lead to unforeseen consequences. It suggests that the introduction of an application that exploits large transactions could significantly disrupt attempts to regulate transaction sizes within the network. This scenario underscores the importance of being proactive in addressing the issue before it escalates, highlighting the risk that once the "cat is out of the bag," it may become substantially more difficult to implement size caps effectively.

Overall, the dialogue underscores a cautious stance towards the management of transaction sizes in the BitVM network, emphasizing the need for preemptive measures to mitigate potential issues arising from the use of large transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-06T17:50:58.354000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
