<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:00:52.202985+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-06T20:41:37.882000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:00:52.203016+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/72" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the proposition of implementing a taproot-only push opcode and whether it necessitates the introduction of a new witness version specifically for bare tapscript. A detailed exploration of this topic is shared on a forum, with the conversation highlighting various perspectives on the potential adoption of both proposals. The forum post in question can be found at [delvingbitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/58?u=instagibbs), where the idea is presented not just in isolation but as part of a broader dialogue on enhancing the functionality and efficiency of Bitcoin's scripting capabilities. This approach underlines the importance of considering each proposal's implications separately while acknowledging the possibility of their combined adoption to pave the way towards more sophisticated covenant mechanisms within the Bitcoin protocol. The conversation underscores the necessity of a nuanced understanding and careful consideration of such advancements, suggesting that they could significantly impact the development trajectory of Bitcoin's scripting and transaction capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-06T20:41:37.882000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
