<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:00:03.680411+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-10T01:10:30.094000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:00:03.680442+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/76" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights a practical consideration for implementing CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) within witness version 0 due to the current landscape of hardware security modules (HSMs). A significant point made is that many HSMs, crucial for securing cryptographic keys and performing digital signings, do not support Schnorr signatures as of now. This lack of support is not just a temporary issue; for existing HSM installations, there may never be an upgrade or update that introduces this capability.

This situation presents a dilemma for companies currently relying on these HSMs for their operations. The overlap between organizations using such HSMs and those interested in utilizing CTV vaults for enhanced security and operational efficiency is considerable. Thus, making CTV available in witness version 0 appears to be a strategic move. It aligns with the existing technological infrastructure and meets the needs of businesses looking to leverage CTV without requiring a complete overhaul of their security hardware. This approach enables a smoother transition and broader adoption of CTV technology, ensuring that companies can enhance their security protocols without facing significant compatibility issues.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-10T01:10:30.094000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
