<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:22:07.524639+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vnprc.552000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-10T17:04:12.552000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:22:07.524670+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scaling-noncustodial-mining-payouts-with-ctv/1753/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of Ark's potential to revolutionize the way mining pool payouts are scaled through the use of OP_CTV (OP_CheckTemplateVerify) is an intriguing aspect of blockchain technology enhancements. The mechanism highlighted involves leveraging a [transaction tree](https://docs.second.tech/protocol/intro/utxo-sharing-using-transaction-trees), where the fundamental unit at the end of this tree is termed a VTXO (Virtual Transaction Output). This structure allows miners to accumulate VTXOs over time, enabling them to consolidate and transfer all funds in a single transaction. This approach not only streamlines the process but also introduces efficiency and cost-effectiveness by minimizing the number of transactions required.

Furthermore, the discussion extends into the noncustodial aspects of Ark, emphasizing the need for a detailed examination to ensure its security measures are on par with those offered by a standard CTV payment tree. The crux of this comparison lies in determining whether Ark can provide similar, if not superior, security guarantees. Should Ark prove to be effective in this regard, it stands as a promising upgrade to reduce the blockchain footprint associated with small, frequent payouts. This reduction is crucial for enhancing overall network performance and sustainability, making the investigation into Ark's capabilities a significant point of interest for developers and stakeholders within the blockchain ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-10T17:04:12.552000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
