<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:21:54.048464+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary 2025-06-10 20:14:16.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Scaling Noncustodial Mining Payouts with CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:21:54.048496+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/scaling-noncustodial-mining-payouts-with-ctv/1753/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around congestion control in blockchain networks highlights the innovative approach taken by the Lightning Network. This solution effectively addresses the issue by allowing transactions to occur off the main blockchain, thereby reducing the load and need for on-chain settlements. By doing so, it offers a practical method for users to conduct transactions without directly engaging with the congested base chain. 

Moreover, the conversation touches upon the flexibility miners have regarding transaction management within specific frameworks like Ark or bare CTV. It is suggested that miners can utilize a 0 fee transaction within their block template to simplify or adjust their position in any given transaction tree. This technique underscores a potential strategy for managing and mitigating congestion, demonstrating the nuanced ways in which blockchain networks can be optimized for efficiency and scalability. 

Overall, these insights reflect ongoing efforts and innovations aimed at improving blockchain technology's performance and user experience. Through mechanisms like the Lightning Network and miner strategies, the blockchain community continues to seek solutions to the complex challenge of congestion control.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-10T20:14:16.698000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
