<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Why CTV+CSFS and not TXHASH</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:47:18.364460+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>arshbot 2025-06-18 18:11:22.164000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Why CTV+CSFS and not TXHASH</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:47:18.364490+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/why-ctv-csfs-and-not-txhash/1781" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers on the strategic direction for a community proposal concerning cryptographic transaction verifications and commitments. It's highlighted that there's an informal consensus on adopting CTV+CSFS (Consensus Transaction Verification + Consensus Script Fragment Selection), which is aimed at enabling transactions to adhere to specific templates. This method, however, is juxtaposed with the potential benefits of integrating TXHASH, a broader approach that allows for the commitment to specific inputs and outputs thereby offering more refined control over transaction structures. This feature is seen as particularly advantageous because it mitigates risks associated with rigid fund movement requirements inherent in CTV+CSFS setups, such as the all-or-nothing movement of funds due to their fixed amounts and pre-defined templates.

Furthermore, the discussion brings into focus several projects that could benefit from the adoption of TXHASH, including LN-Symmetry, Ark, PTLCs, and DLCs. One notable application of TXHASH is its ability to facilitate transaction guarantees for projects like Magnolia, which could otherwise necessitate costly legal frameworks like Trust charters to achieve similar outcomes. The dialogue suggests that while there is an acknowledgment of the utility provided by CTV and CSFS for narrowly scoped transaction commitments, the broader applications and commitments enabled by TXHASH present clear use cases and advantages that merit consideration.

The conversation concludes by positing that before moving forward with the implementation of TXHASH, it would be prudent to first ascertain the demand for basic wholesale transaction commitments facilitated by CTV+CSFS. This step is crucial in determining whether there's a significant interest in more granular transaction commitment features as offered by TXHASH. Should there be a demonstrated need and robust adoption for the foundational transaction commitment mechanisms of CTV+CSFS, it would naturally pave the way for exploring the integration of more advanced features like those proposed with TXHASH.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-18T18:11:22.164000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
