<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:59:07.057790+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-23T15:37:14.817000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:59:07.057824+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/81" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the integration of CSFS (plus CTV) into existing protocols to address the challenges posed by PTLCs. The document provided through a [link](https://gist.github.com/instagibbs/1d02d0251640c250ceea1c66665ec163) elaborates on the complications that arise when implementing PTLCs within current systems. It suggests that while incorporating PTLCs is not an insurmountable task, the process becomes considerably simpler with the addition of rebindable signatures.

The narrative does not commit to forecasting how well these changes would be received or adopted within established protocols. Instead, it acknowledges a vast array of improvements that users prioritize over PTLCs. This indicates a clear understanding that while technical enhancements such as CSFS and CTV could streamline and simplify certain processes, user adoption and interest might not align perfectly with these technical priorities.

This approach highlights the ongoing challenge in balancing technical innovation with user demands and expectations. The emphasis on making informed decisions about incorporating new features like CSFS and CTV into protocols reflects a thoughtful consideration of both the potential benefits and the practical realities of user engagement with these technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-23T15:37:14.817000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
