<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T03:59:52.782909+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Crypt-iQ</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-24T11:35:42.325000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T03:59:52.782947+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fingerprinting-nodes-via-addr-requests/1786/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The fascination with ADDR relay over TX relay largely stems from its cost-free nature, highlighting a critical aspect of network protocols where economic factors influence technological preferences. The discussion around the potential removal of timestamps from ADDR messages introduces a nuanced approach to enhancing privacy and security within network communications. By conducting experiments, it was revealed that an attacker could exploit ADDR messages by sending unique addresses in small quantities to a target node. This method allows the attacker to gauge the connectivity between nodes based on the timing of address dissemination across the network. Such tactics underscore the vulnerabilities inherent in the current design of ADDR relay systems.

Furthermore, the introduction of an ADDR rate-limit adds another layer of complexity to the landscape, potentially mitigating some risks but also introducing new challenges. The intricacies of how ADDR-relay functions, including the manipulation of network behaviors and timestamps to limit the spread of address information, reveal deeper vulnerabilities. These can inadvertently provide attackers with more data, thereby facilitating the mapping of network topologies and identifying node relationships.

A noteworthy suggestion is the utilization of warnet simulations to assess the probability of an attacker successfully fingerprinting a node through these methods. Additionally, the referenced [paper](https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2017/file/6c3cf77d52820cd0fe646d38bc2145ca-Paper.pdf) on de-anonymization via TX relay offers valuable insights into the broader implications of relay strategies on anonymity. Although the mechanisms of ADDR relay differ, particularly in its non-flooding approach and the use of a Poisson timer for diffusion, the conceptual parallels present an opportunity for further exploration into securing network protocols against such vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-24T11:35:42.325000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
