<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T03:59:22.754901+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Crypt-iQ 2025-06-24 21:34:41.348000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T03:59:22.754934+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fingerprinting-nodes-via-addr-requests/1786/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion raises a significant point regarding the functionality of `nTime` within the Bitcoin address management system, suggesting that its ability to be refreshed could have unintended consequences on the network's address reputation mechanism. Specifically, there is an implication that the `nTime` attribute, when updated, might accelerate the process by which an address is deemed "terrible" following successive requests through the `GETADDR` command across different nodes in the network. This scenario posits a chain of requests where one node requests from another in sequence (e.g., B requests from C, A requests from B), potentially leading to a rapid degradation in the address's standing due to the frequent refreshes of `nTime`.

The underlying concern highlights a nuanced aspect of how peer-to-peer communication protocols in Bitcoin manage and evaluate the reliability of network addresses. By focusing on the mechanics of `nTime` refreshment as outlined in the linked [GitHub repository](https://github.com/mzumsande/bitcoin/blob/458720e5e98c6e9103aea1fdfcd39bafc26c27bb/src/addrman.cppL566), the discussion opens up a broader inquiry into whether this feature could inadvertently influence the perception of node reliability and trustworthiness through the lens of automated protocol interactions. The examination of such a mechanism is crucial for understanding the balance between dynamic network updates and the preservation of node reputation within decentralized systems like Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-24T21:34:41.348000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
