<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:27:12.608803+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:27:12.608836+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initially revolves around the intricacies of calculating the Bitcoin network's hash rate and how it relates to difficulty adjustments within the blockchain mechanism. A key point of analysis is the differentiation between the expected value of an Erlang distribution versus the inverse of this expected value when applied to the inverse Erlang distribution. This distinction is crucial in understanding why certain calculations, particularly those involving difficulty adjustments that rely on division by the hash rate, might not directly apply to the `getnetworkhashrateps` function. The latter is highlighted as not inherently inverting its calculations, which is a significant factor considering that difficulty adjustments are fundamentally about scaling with block duration based on the network's hashing power.

Furthermore, the explanation delves into the methodology for estimating the network's hash rate accurately. It suggests that by dividing the sum of expected hashes for blocks by the total time taken for those blocks, one can achieve an unbiased estimate of hashes per time unit. This method is underscored as more reliable because it bases its denominator on an observed quantity (time) rather than an expected one (hashes), which is a critical distinction from the approach used in difficulty adjustments where expectations play a central role.

However, it is essential to note that a subsequent [post](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/4) admits the initial conjectures were incorrect, indicating a reevaluation or correction of the earlier analysis. This addition underscores the dynamic nature of technical discussions within the cryptocurrency domain, where hypotheses are continually tested, challenged, and revised in light of new evidence or understanding.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T18:57:42.941000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
