<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Reimagining Onion Messages as an Overlay Layer</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T03:55:44.037456+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2025-06-28 18:12:18.711000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Reimagining Onion Messages as an Overlay Layer</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T03:55:44.037505+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/reimagining-onion-messages-as-an-overlay-layer/1799/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses the inefficiencies and limitations of using onion messages (OMs) within the context of the Lightning network, emphasizing that despite the conceptual fit due to the network's inherent bonding characteristics, OMs fail to offer substantial production value. This critique extends to the broader implication that any further attempts to decouple OMs from their already tenuous utility would likely exacerbate reliability issues. The sender expresses a clear preference for alternative solutions that enhance network communication without sacrificing reliability or usability.

A significant portion of the correspondence is dedicated to advocating for Nostr as a superior overlay network for communication within the Lightning ecosystem. The argument presented highlights Nostr's ability to properly separate concerns, improve web compatibility, and either simplify or completely remove the need for identity coupling depending on the specific application requirements. This is contrasted with the current reliance on mechanisms like LNURL, which are deemed obsolete in the face of more advanced protocols.

Furthermore, the email introduces [CLINK](https://clinkme.dev), a development project aimed at addressing the node-to-app coordination challenges endemic to the unreliable peer-to-peer (p2p) topology of current systems. CLINK is described as offering a solution through its support for static payment offers, which allows for the retrieval of bolt11 invoices via a straightforward static web page. This approach obviates the need for complex technologies such as WebAssembly (wasm), demonstrating a practical implementation of Nostr's principles. Additionally, the message mentions ongoing work on specifications for reverse flows (debits) and drafts for the remote management of static offers, indicating a comprehensive effort to refine and expand the capabilities of the Lightning network's communication infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T18:12:18.711000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
