<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:26:03.897373+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-30T12:45:13.061000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:26:03.897407+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the nuances of time-weighted target calculations for Proof of Work (PoW) consensus mechanisms, a significant discovery was made regarding the calculation's accuracy under varying conditions. It was found that when both the mining difficulty and the network's hashrate experienced substantial changes within short intervals, traditional methods of calculating the hashrate showed considerable errors. To address this, a revised formula, where hashrate is calculated as the total work divided by the timespan and then multiplied by (N-1)/N, was proposed. This adjustment proved to reduce error significantly in scenarios where both difficulty and hashrate fluctuated markedly.

However, this new method introduced a slight inaccuracy in situations where the hashrate changed but the difficulty remained constant. To correct for this and ensure accurate work representation in PoW consensus decisions, it became apparent that the sum of difficulties also needed to be adjusted by multiplying it by (N-1)/N. This adjustment is crucial even in the presence of accurate timestamp enforcement mechanisms designed to mitigate exploits such as selfish mining.

The significance of these adjustments extends beyond simple error correction. In distributed ledger technologies like Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs), the ordering of blocks or transactions can impact the security and efficiency of the network. The conversation with Yonatan Sompolinsky highlighted a long-standing challenge in using the sum of descendant difficulties for block ordering within DAGs. By incorporating the (N-1)/N adjustment, it becomes possible to more accurately reflect the work done, thereby addressing concerns related to block ordering and potentially speeding up the decision-making process in the face of attacks.

Moreover, this analysis suggests that the median hashrate might play a more critical role than the average hashrate in making consensus decisions. This insight underscores the complexity of designing robust PoW consensus algorithms, especially in environments where both the difficulty and the hashrate are highly variable.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-30T12:45:13.061000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
