<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:25:18.437669+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-06-30T15:56:54.666000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:25:18.437698+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the methodology of calculating the total work (W) in a system where the hashrate is assumed to be constant, and the target is static. The formula presented attempts to define the expected value of work based on the Erlang distribution's properties, a common model for the time between events in a Poisson process. Specifically, it leverages the expected value of the inverse of time to express the relationship between observed work, the hashrate, and the timespan over which this activity occurs.

The formula begins with an assertion that the total hashes can be represented as a function of the expected value of work over time, incorporating the Erlang distribution to adjust for variability in the timespan. This approach suggests that by understanding the distribution of times between blocks, one can more accurately estimate the total work done by adjusting the simple hashrate-timespan calculation to account for statistical variance inherent in block discovery times.

Critical to this analysis is the distinction between the true timespan (T) and the observed timespan (T_observed). The argument posits that while T_observed can provide a direct estimate of T, it may not accurately reflect the total work due to the randomness of block times. Consequently, the formula adjusts the straightforward multiplication of hashrate by the observed timespan with a correction factor derived from the number of events (N) to better estimate the expected work.

The conversation underscores a nuanced understanding of how blockchain mining dynamics can impact the assessment of network security and efficiency. By applying principles from probability theory, the discussion seeks to refine how we interpret mining activity beyond simplistic models. This approach highlights the challenges in estimating network parameters and the importance of sophisticated statistical methods in analyzing decentralized systems. 

Moreover, the dialogue elucidates a broader implication regarding the interpretation of observed data versus expected outcomes. It suggests that while observed data can inform about specific instances, it may not always align with long-term expectations due to natural variance in the process being studied. This distinction is crucial for those analyzing or designing systems reliant on stochastic processes, like blockchains, where accurate predictions of behavior or performance are essential for security and functionality.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-30T15:56:54.666000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
