<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:24:47.824242+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:24:47.824275+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intriguing concept of hashrate versus work within the realm of blockchain technology, specifically addressing a hypothetical Proof of Work (PoW) protocol scenario. In this scenario, miners are faced with a network partition, leading to the formation of two distinct groups each opting for different difficulty levels in their mining efforts. The first group selects a difficulty setting 50% higher than the second, resulting in both groups achieving equal work output but under varying circumstances.

A critical observation is made regarding the relationship between hashrate and work output. Despite achieving the same amount of work (W=3), the group operating at a lower difficulty level (D=1) manages to find their third block concurrently as the higher difficulty group (D=1.5) finds their second. This outcome statistically implies that the lower difficulty group possessed a 33% higher hashrate, indicating they performed a significantly larger number of hash computations over the same period.

This scenario raises questions about the efficiency and security implications of hashrate versus actual work completed in PoW protocols. It suggests that a higher hashrate, signifying a greater frequency of lottery ticket purchases in this analogy, does not necessarily correlate with an increased number of winning tickets or, in blockchain terms, successfully mined blocks. The emphasis on non-repurposable equipment for ensuring network security further complicates this dynamic, hinting at the nuanced balance between operational difficulty, hashrate, and the resultant work.

Furthermore, the email mentions a simulation running a million trials at specified hashrates to investigate the discrepancy between hashrate and work. However, it contemplates the adequacy of this approach, considering whether shifting the focus from hashrate to work across ten million trials for a fixed work output might yield more accurate insights into the timespans required for N=5 blocks. This reflective consideration underscores the complexity of accurately modeling and understanding the interplay between these critical factors in blockchain network operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-30T20:57:19.615000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
