<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
  <updated>2025-08-30T02:23:39.583061+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon.613000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  ..187000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  ..413000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  ..143000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  ..675000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  ..588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  ..907000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5784_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5194_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5193_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5156_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5155_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5153_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5145_Bitcoin-and-Quantum-Computing.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T02:23:39.583127+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-and-quantum-computing/1730" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discourse delves into the intricate relationship between quantum computing advancements and their potential impact on Bitcoin's cryptographic security infrastructure. The primary focus is on the Elliptic Curve Discrete Logarithm Problem (ECDLP), a cornerstone of current cryptographic standards, which, if compromised by quantum computational capabilities, could pose significant risks to Proof of Work (PoW) systems integral to cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin. The conversation underscores the challenges in surpassing the performance of specialized ASIC hardware currently dominating mining technologies. Historical contexts are invoked to illustrate that technological breakthroughs, often unexpected, can fundamentally alter existing paradigms, thereby introducing new vulnerabilities or threats.

The dialogue extends to analyze the existential threats quantum computing advancements pose to the very concept of Bitcoin. It suggests a potential transition from solving ECDLP to undermining PoW may not be as far-fetched as initially thought, raising concerns over Bitcoin’s future viability. The discussion further identifies discrepancies and typographical errors within a report, such as incorrect listings and dates which could affect the accuracy of its projections and historical comparisons. Notably, it critiques the strategy of privately submitting transactions vulnerable to quantum attacks, highlighting the overlooked risks of block reorganization by attackers, especially post the 2032 halving.

An optimistic view on the evolution of quantum computing is presented, acknowledging current skepticism but pointing towards promising developments. The correspondence emphasizes the need for the Bitcoin community to adopt practices that mitigate short-range attack vulnerabilities, such as moving away from address reuse and sharing extended public keys, and encourages the use of script-path Taproot where feasible. This perspective advocates for immediate community-driven actions that enhance Bitcoin's security without relying solely on the integration of Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) into the protocol.

A pragmatic approach towards reinforcing Bitcoin against quantum threats is recommended, prioritizing the deployment of PQC-based scripts as an initial safeguard while also suggesting a phased strategy that involves community engagement and incremental protocol improvements. This approach reflects a realistic expectation of resistance within the Bitcoin community to change, emphasizing the importance of preparing for the eventual inclusion of PQC solutions through gradual and comprehensive integration.

Feedback on a specific document includes the correction of a minor typo regarding a date, applauding the thorough analysis, especially on BIP32 implications. However, there's expressed skepticism about the timelines for quantum computing's impact on Bitcoin, comparing it humorously to the perennially futuristic promise of fusion technology. Despite the detailed technical analysis, there remains a sense of uncertainty about the immediacy of these threats, contrasting with some experts' views on their imminence.

The collaboration culminates in a published report available through [chaincode.com](https://chaincode.com/bitcoin-post-quantum.pdf), offering an exhaustive examination of quantum computing's challenges to Bitcoin. This report aims to elevate awareness within the Bitcoin community regarding the significant security implications posed by quantum computing. Despite the looming threat, the document posits that strategic planning and proactive measures can secure Bitcoin's future. It calls for an open dialogue within the community to explore viable solutions, stressing the urgency of addressing these challenges to ensure Bitcoin's resilience and security amidst quantum computing advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:34:57.613000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
