<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:19:25.376824+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-06-06 17:50:58.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-05-30 15:48:59.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-30 15:47:03.686000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-05-30 15:40:29.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vostrnad 2025-05-30 07:38:02.854000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-30 01:07:45.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-05-29 18:03:45.531000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-05-29 13:23:38.249000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vostrnad  . 2025-05-28 19:01:24.876000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5244_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5172_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5163_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5170_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5161_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5160_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5157_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5154_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5147_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:19:25.376902+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-confiscatory-transaction-weight-limit/1732" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the impact of large transactions on Bitcoin's block construction and network efficiency encapsulates a range of technical concerns and proposals aimed at preserving the blockchain's decentralized nature while accommodating evolving needs. The potential for infrequent yet significant large transactions, such as those related to BitVM, to necessitate a publicly accessible direct submission mechanism for miners has raised concerns about the ability to cap transaction sizes through consensus. This situation underscores the importance of proactive measures to address the complexities introduced by oversized transactions without undermining the network's foundational principles.

The complexity of block template construction for miners escalates as transaction sizes approach the block size limit, complicating the process for relay nodes to make profitability decisions ahead of time. This increased complexity challenges the network's ability to ensure that users can confirm giant transactions without resorting to private agreements with miners or incurring significant extra costs. A hypothetical consensus limit on transaction sizes is proposed to mitigate these issues, suggesting a more manageable approach to handling large transactions within the network's existing framework.

The debate extends to the practicality of storing large amounts of data across multiple transactions and the implications for optimal block template creation. The [Consensus Cleanup proposal](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/72af87fc72999e3f0a26a06e6e0a7f3134236337/bip-0054.md) addresses some of these concerns by limiting the impact of quadratic hashing, yet the conversation continues on finding the most effective rule adjustments to support necessary oversized transactions without centralizing template provision. Concerns about miner extractable value (MEV) and the equitable distribution of mining rewards further complicate the potential implementation of rules allowing significant non-coinbase transactions within blocks.

Recent collaborative efforts among several mining pools to support the mining of non-standard transactions, as reported in a [CoinDesk article](https://www.coindesk.com/business/2025/05/27/bitlayer-joins-forces-with-antpool-f2pool-and-spiderpool-to-supercharge-bitcoin-defi), highlight an evolving landscape in Bitcoin transaction standards. These developments point towards a broader dialogue within the community on balancing the need for oversized transactions with the integrity and decentralization of the blockchain. The ongoing discourse invites innovative solutions to integrate consensus checks against oversized transactions, ensuring the network remains robust and adaptable to future advancements without sacrificing its core principles.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-06T17:50:58.354000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
