<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-07T03:07:13.329457+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-07 00:45:21.764000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 10:32:27.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5668_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:07:13.329573+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correction of a significant error where 'D' and 'W' were inverted in a PDF document has led to numerous corrections across the document. This mistake had implications on the reliability of the information presented, requiring a systematic review and amendment to rectify each instance of the mix-up. The process ensured the accuracy and integrity of the document's contents, highlighting the importance of meticulous proofreading in disseminating precise information.

The relationship between chain work and the lowest hash in blockchain technology is explored through statistical analysis and mathematical modeling. The formula presented suggests an inverse proportionality between chain work and twice the value of the lowest hash observed in the network, providing a basic method for estimating chain work. However, empirical evidence indicates that actual chain work calculations can significantly deviate from this model, with calculated figures on average approximately 3.5 times higher than actual values. These discrepancies underscore the challenges in accurately modeling blockchain dynamics due to the potential large variances when small numbers are involved in the calculations. Further investigation reveals that both expected solve time and chain work can be modeled using exponential distribution formulas, offering insights into the statistical underpinnings of blockchain mining operations.

A refined approach for calculating the hashrate and total work over a given timespan in blockchain technology is introduced, offering a more accurate measurement than previous methods. By analyzing the sum of difficulties (Ds) for N blocks, it provides a revised formula for the hashrate at any given height, accounting for the actual timespan covering N+1 blocks. This methodology is particularly relevant when comparing competing blockchain tips, highlighting the importance of using the correct timespan in calculations to reflect the true amount of work done within a specific period accurately. Such refinements improve the evaluation of blockchain performance, especially regarding hashrate and computational effort expended over time.

The email discusses a hypothetical Proof of Work (PoW) protocol scenario involving a network partition and two distinct mining groups choosing different difficulty levels. Despite achieving equal work output, the group operating at a lower difficulty level manages to find their third block concurrently as the higher difficulty group finds their second, suggesting a 33% higher hashrate. This raises questions about the efficiency and security implications of hashrate versus actual work completed in PoW protocols. A million trials were simulated to investigate discrepancies between hashrate and work, contemplating whether shifting focus from hashrate to work for fixed work output might yield more accurate insights.

The methodology for estimating the number of hashes performed in a given scenario highlights the assumption of a constant hashrate as an approximation rather than a precise reflection of reality. This discussion points out the conditions under which this method yields reliable results, emphasizing the necessity of a constant hashrate assumption for the purpose of estimating the hashrate itself while acknowledging potential inaccuracies in broader applications such as work estimation.

In exploring blockchain mechanics, the concept of work pertaining to mining is analyzed, defining work as directly proportional to the difficulty level of mining a specific block and inversely proportional to the target hash rate. Summing up the work done across all blocks could offer a precise measure of the computational power expended in the mining process, potentially providing insights into the efficiency, energy consumption, and evolution of mining practices over time.

The discussion also introduces a nuanced perspective on blockchain hashrate and chain work estimation, proposing methodologies that refine accuracy by adjusting for real-time conditions and leveraging statistical properties of the lowest observed hashes. These methods offer insights into more precise and flexible ways of understanding blockchain network performance and security, underscoring the importance of adaptive techniques in the continuously evolving landscape of blockchain technology.

In summary, the email threads delve into various aspects of blockchain technology, from correcting significant errors in documentation to refining methods for calculating hashrate and work. The discussions emphasize the importance of accuracy, the challenges in modeling blockchain dynamics, and the continuous search for more reliable and sophisticated analytical methods. These conversations contribute to a deeper understanding of blockchain technology's complexities, showcasing the ongoing efforts to enhance its analysis and application.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:45:21.764000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
