<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-07T02:58:02.331961+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-07-06 22:40:48.497000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-02 17:18:14.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-02 16:16:16.902000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 12:01:51.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-06-05 20:26:39.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5409_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5398_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5396_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5365_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5233_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-07T02:58:02.332016+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The phenomenon of selfish mining within the blockchain ecosystem, particularly in relation to the use of Fibre for connectivity, represents a nuanced challenge to the fairness and efficiency of blockchain networks. Selfish mining, as it pertains to Fibre miners, does not involve the intentional withholding of blocks to gain additional mining time. However, the effect of their faster block propagation results in a marginal profit increase at the expense of non-Fibre miners. This discrepancy arises because Fibre miners can potentially release blocks with a slight delay, thereby disadvantaging non-Fibre miners. The analysis of stale block rates offers insight into these dynamics, indicating that Fibre miners might be extending the release of their blocks slightly beyond the expected timeframe, thus impacting the overall distribution of mining rewards.

In addressing the broader implications of timestamp manipulation and block propagation delays on blockchain integrity, the discussion extends to the mechanisms of handling block timestamps. It underlines the importance of adhering to strict timestamp regulations to prevent abuses such as selfish mining. The proposal suggests that maintaining timestamps within a narrowly defined range relative to the actual time could mitigate the advantage gained through selfish mining by imposing a timeout period for blocks that deviate from this range. This approach aims to reinforce the trustworthiness and reliability of blockchain operations by ensuring that all participating nodes adhere to a unified timing standard, thereby curtailing the potential for manipulative practices.

Furthermore, the discourse delves into the prerequisites for achieving a secure consensus in distributed systems. It highlights the inadequacy of simple majority rules for genuine security, advocating instead for a supermajority consensus threshold due to specific conditions that must be met, including the synchronization of clocks and the digital signing of messages. Bitcoin's approach to consensus, which deviates from these ideal conditions by allowing greater flexibility in timestamp ranges, is critiqued for its vulnerability to security breaches. The proposed solution emphasizes stricter timestamp validity to prevent manipulations that could compromise the consensus process, such as premature timestamp assignments in selfish mining.

The exploration of selfish mining strategies underscores the significance of hash rate distribution and block propagation speed in determining the profitability of such tactics. Through the lens of the 2013 research paper "Majority is not enough," the mathematical foundations of selfish mining are scrutinized, revealing that miners with substantial control over the network's hash rate can disproportionately influence the blockchain to their advantage. This analysis, supported by Markov Chain models and simulation results, establishes the critical threshold for profitable selfish mining, thereby illuminating the strategic considerations and vulnerabilities inherent in blockchain network protocols. This comprehensive examination of selfish mining, timestamp management, and consensus mechanisms elucidates the complex interplay between technology, strategy, and security in the blockchain domain, offering insights into potential avenues for enhancing system integrity and fairness.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-06T22:40:48.497000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
