<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:04:18.596935+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP.835000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  ..974000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..240000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  ..932000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..129000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  ..169000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..589000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..005000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  ..135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  ..169000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5292_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5291_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4832_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4760_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4754_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4752_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4751_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4738_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4562_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4561_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4555_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4553_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4551_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:04:18.597039+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkcontractverify-and-its-amount-semantic/1527" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the technical considerations of enhancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, focusing on parallel input validation and its implications for transaction processing efficiency. The proposed simplification of cross-input logic through the introduction of a new opcode, potentially named `OP_CHECKAMOUNT`, aims to streamline the assertion of annexed data without complicating the script engine. This approach suggests a future-proofing strategy that could simplify adding meaningful content to the annex via soft forks, thus facilitating easier assertions by CCV (Conditional Close Verifiability) mechanisms.

Further analysis is provided on different methodologies for handling input script validations, contrasting shared mutable states with pre-checks of intended amount flows and deferred checks frameworks. The discussion acknowledges the trade-offs between these methods, highlighting the complexity of implementing parallel input script validation, especially within the context of Bitcoin’s `btcd` and `bitcoind` implementations. The potential integration of CCV with other script primitives suggests an evolving landscape for Bitcoin transaction protocols, aiming at more adaptable and efficient scripting solutions.

The dialogue also explores the challenges associated with transaction malleability in the absence of signatures, proposing an annex-focused approach to simplify amount logic parsing. Despite recognizing the simplicity of this method compared to deferred checks, concerns are raised about its complexity and the reliance on mutexes for synchronization. The broader implications for batch validation and the necessity for a solution that supports CCV functionality without compromising efficiency or introducing redundant data are emphasized, underlining the importance of semantic preservation in technical decisions.

Concerns regarding the "spill-over" effects of extending validation rules across multiple inputs within transactions are discussed, with suggestions for refactoring the validation code to enhance performance and simplify implementation. The proposed indirect method, akin to CSV, for specifying constraints on output amounts represents a novel approach to addressing these challenges. However, reservations about redundancy, byte cost, and the enforceability of these constraints at the opcode level highlight the nuanced difficulties in evolving transaction validation mechanisms.

The email exchanges touch upon the design flaws of CLTV (Check Lock Time Verify) and advocate for the CCV protocol as a robust framework for managing transaction input spendability. CCV’s design philosophy, which allows for mutually exclusive spending conditions through scripting, is contrasted with CLTV’s limitations, emphasizing a preference for transparent and adaptable transaction output conditions.

In exploring the management of UTXOs with differing conditions for spendability, the inherent challenges of ensuring compatibility between block height and wall clock time determinations are highlighted. BIP65 and the indirect validation method used by `OP_CLTV` scripts offer insights into circumventing these limitations, stressing transactions as the atomic unit of validation on the Bitcoin network.

A critique of the current Bitcoin Improvement Proposal draft focuses on the complexity added by implementing value forwarding mechanisms within Bitcoin scripting. The proposed two-step process involving `OP_IN_AMOUNT` and CCV with value introspection capabilities aims to simplify value forwarding but raises concerns about the increased risk of errors due to the complexity of handling amounts on the stack.

Lastly, the development of `OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` (`OP_CCV`) is outlined as a significant advancement in Bitcoin's scripting language, offering a method for UTXOs to carry data and rules. The potential for `OP_CCV` to enable state-carrying UTXOs and facilitate complex contract designs, while fully compatible with taproot, illustrates the ongoing evolution and refinement of Bitcoin’s scripting capabilities. The community's engagement in refining this proposal underscores the collaborative effort to enhance the ecosystem's functionality and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-13T13:12:08.835000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
