<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:48:48.792734+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-06-28 12:01:51.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-06-05 20:26:39.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5365_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5233_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:48:48.792774+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of selfish mining, often misunderstood and overlooked within the blockchain and cryptocurrency communities, is a significant aspect that challenges the traditional understanding of consensus in blockchain networks. This strategy, as discussed in detail, revolves around a miner or a group of miners manipulating the system to gain more rewards than their fair share based on their network hashrate. The foundation of this approach lies in creating stale blocks for competitors while maximizing the inclusion of their own blocks in the main chain.

Selfish mining becomes a viable strategy when a miner controls a significant portion of the network's hashrate. Contrary to common belief, the threshold for this control isn't a majority but rather a substantial minority. If a miner can obtain information about new blocks faster than others and propagate their blocks more efficiently, they can ensure that other miners waste resources on blocks that won't be included in the main chain. This efficiency in block propagation lowers the hashrate threshold needed for selfish mining to be profitable.

However, the profitability of selfish mining isn't solely determined by hashrate and block propagation advantages. It also depends on the network's inability to enforce a strict consensus mechanism, particularly around the precision and synchronization of timestamps on consensus messages and blocks. Bitcoin, for example, fails to enforce tight constraints on these parameters, allowing blocks with timestamps far into the past or future relative to the actual time of discovery. This leniency opens the door for selfish miners to exploit the timing of block releases to their advantage.

The mathematics underlying selfish mining was explored through a detailed analysis of state probabilities, where states represent the selfish miner's lead over the public chain in terms of unpublished blocks. This analysis, based on Markov Chains and stationary distributions, reveals that the strategy's success hinges on complex probability dynamics across different scenarios of block discovery and publication. 

The critical finding from this mathematical exploration is that a miner can achieve increased revenue through selfish mining by controlling just over one-third of the network's total hashrate, a significantly lower threshold than the majority control often assumed necessary for such influence. This conclusion challenges the security assumptions of many blockchain protocols, highlighting the need for improved mechanisms to detect and mitigate the impact of selfish mining strategies.

Furthermore, the practical implications of these findings were demonstrated through a simulation of the Bitcoin mining process, which considered various factors including block interval times and network hashrate distribution among participants. The simulation results reinforce the theoretical analysis, showing that under certain conditions, miners with a specific range of hashrate control can indeed find it more profitable to engage in selfish mining.

In summary, the exploration of selfish mining, from its conceptual basis to mathematical analysis and simulation, underscores its potential impact on the fairness and security of blockchain systems. These insights not only contribute to a deeper understanding of blockchain dynamics but also highlight the ongoing need for research and innovation in securing decentralized consensus mechanisms against such adversarial strategies.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T12:01:51.399000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
