<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-03T02:40:10.770993+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-12-03 00:50:23.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T02:40:10.771023+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the ongoing discussion about the future of blockchain technologies, Radpool and Braidpool emerge as two significant concepts with differing timelines for realization. The preference or prediction that Radpool might come to fruition quicker than Braidpool is not unanimously accepted but stems from an individual perspective, specifically highlighted by a contributor named @jungly. This contributor, who has been primarily involved with FROST, suggests a divergence in views particularly around consensus mechanisms, which has led him to consider forking.

The dialogue also brings to light the exploration of Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) broadcasting as a potential solution to concerns raised about consensus. Although BFT broadcasting appears as a viable suggestion, its implementation, especially concerning rate limiting or difficulty adjustment, is still under deliberation. A proposed approach to rate limiting within the context of Braidpool is provided, emphasizing the need for further analysis and development ([link to proposal](https://rawgit.com/mcelrath/braidcoin/master/Braid%2BExamples.html)).

Moreover, the discussion encapsulates a broader examination of asynchronous algorithms and their application in blockchain technologies. While there exists a variety of these algorithms, such as Avalanche and HoneybadgerBFT, the conversation reflects a preference for Proof of Work (PoW) based solutions due to their distinct characteristics. This preference underscores an aversion to non-PoW algorithms despite their similarity in properties.

An important aspect discussed is the delay tolerance and adaptability of Braidpool's difficulty targeting mechanism. It's highlighted how Braidpool inherently adjusts to latency variations, potentially caused by different mining setups like using Starlink versus undersea cables. Such adaptability is seen as a strategic advantage, ensuring resilience against the variability of external factors impacting mining efficiency.

Lastly, while there exists anticipation for proposals integrating BFT broadcasting into this domain, skepticism remains regarding the complexity and readiness of such solutions. The conversation reflects a cautious optimism, emphasizing the necessity for exhaustive exploration and validation before embracing new methodologies in blockchain consensus and broadcasting strategies.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T00:50:23.967000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
