<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
  <updated>2024-12-04T02:40:20.599200+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh.475000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-03T10:46:57.475000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T02:40:20.599235+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cat-vs-op-ctv-vs-xmr/1303" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the skepticism towards Monero and the belief that Bitcoin may not fulfill the role of cash, suggesting a gap that either Lightning Network or Monero needs to fill. The focus is on the necessity for whichever digital asset serves as cash to maintain stable value, with a leaning towards Monero as the current preference. This preference is partly due to concerns about Bitcoin's fungibility, which has arguably been affected by developments like Taproot and SegWit, though the extent of this impact is questioned. Fungibility, the ability of a currency's units to be interchangeable and indistinguishable from one another, is a critical feature of cash. The sender's privacy within the Lightning Network is considered variable and potentially dependent on the trustworthiness of the nodes or channels used for transactions.

In exploring technical solutions to enhance Bitcoin's utility, the writer mentions interest in the CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) soft fork and the possibility of creating transaction pools through OP_CAT, indicating a nuanced understanding of Bitcoin's protocol and its potential evolution. These technical details underscore the ongoing debates within the cryptocurrency community about how best to achieve scalability, privacy, and functionality improvements that could enable Bitcoin to better serve as digital cash.

Moreover, the distinction between Bitcoin as "money" and Monero as "cash" highlights a nuanced view of the cryptocurrency landscape. This perspective suggests that while Bitcoin holds value and operates as a form of money, Monero's features, particularly its emphasis on privacy and fungibility, make it more suited to everyday transactions akin to traditional cash. The inclusion of a [link](https://sethforprivacy.com/posts/fungibility-graveyard/) provides further reading on the topic of fungibility, and the mention of another [GitHub link](https://github.com/taproot-wizards/purrfect_vault/issues/1issuecomment-2513445570) points readers towards specific technical discussions that illustrate the depth of engagement with these issues. Through this examination, the writer expresses a desire to provoke thought and dialogue within the community, noting the inclusion of their blog as a platform for expanding on these ideas.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T10:46:57.475000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
