<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-05T02:38:06.850715+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-04T10:54:07.064000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-05T02:38:06.850746+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Managed Service Providers (MSPs), a critical aspect of their operation involves the validation of shares, particularly those that are downstream. This process is essential in ensuring the integrity and validity of shares which meet a specified low target. One of the primary methods employed by MSPs to affirm the legitimacy of these shares among each other is through the mechanism of broadcasting. By distributing information about the shares to all concerned parties, MSPs can collectively verify their authenticity and conformity with established standards.

The concept of setting a difficulty target emerges as a fundamental principle in this context. This target acts as a benchmark for validating shares, where only those meeting or exceeding the difficulty criteria are considered legitimate. The establishment of such a target necessitates a consensus among MSPs. Achieving consensus is crucial, as it ensures uniformity in the standards applied across different entities involved in the assessment and validation of shares. This collective agreement on the difficulty target fosters an environment of cooperation and mutual verification among MSPs, facilitating the reliable identification of valid shares.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:54:07.064000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
