<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2024-12-05T02:36:30.785201+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-04T14:33:22.126000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2024-12-05T02:36:30.785239+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304/30" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the specific use and restrictions of extended public keys (xpubs) within wallet policies and descriptors. There is an initial expectation for users to utilize the same xpub with various 'endings' to delineate different spending paths, such as `xpub/&lt;0;1&gt;/*`. However, a clarification has been made, setting a limitation on this practice by restricting it solely to the usage of `xpub//*` for any derivation path. This signifies a departure from allowing optional or alternative derivation paths, which were previously considered.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the handling of key expressions within descriptors that do not involve xpubs. Given the new stipulation, there's an implication that non-xpub key expressions might either be disallowed or require specific considerations in their application, although the exact approach towards these expressions remains undecided.

The introduction of this restriction imposes a direct impact on how descriptors and wallet policies are designed and implemented, marking a significant change. It mandates that only the `xpub//*` format can be utilized in these contexts, effectively standardizing the implementation protocol across the board. This development represents a notable shift in policy, necessitating adjustments for those involved in the creation and management of digital wallets and related technologies.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-04T14:33:22.126000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
