<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-06T02:36:35.549128+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary.607000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-05T03:28:21.607000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-06T02:36:35.549156+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Radpool operates as a novel mining pool framework, diverging from the traditional centralized pool model by incorporating a syndicate of Mining Service Providers (MSPs). These MSPs collaboratively maintain a consistent database replica despite byzantine faults. They employ Threshold Signature Schemes (TSS) to sign Decentralized Ledger Contracts (DLC) payouts and are responsible for generating independent blocktemplates. This system is designed to allow an upcoming MSP to engage in providing shares without necessitating membership in the Threshold Signature Scheme (TSS), facilitated by listening to blocktemplate broadcasts reliably sent across the network.

The architecture of Radpool ensures that the operational aspects for miners remain unchanged. Specifically, the difficulty adjustment for mining operations is managed locally by each MSP, tailored to their respective miners. This approach mirrors the existing incentive and operational structure found within centralized mining pools, thus potentially easing the transition and adoption process for both miners and MSPs. The fundamental premise hinges on MSPs mitigating technical complexities for hash providers, thereby preserving the extant incentives and responsibilities characteristic of centralized mining environments.

However, questions arise regarding the unique incentives or benefits that Radpool offers to MSPs, which are not available in current mining configurations. Understanding these additional incentives is critical to comprehending the full value proposition of Radpool to potential MSPs, suggesting a need for further elucidation on what distinguishes Radpool's offering from the conventional models, thereby clarifying its advantages and potential for broader adoption within the mining ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-05T03:28:21.607000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
