<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-06T02:36:25.498647+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-12-05 22:25:36.129000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-06T02:36:25.498680+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the evolving landscape of digital asset management and mining, new mechanisms for participation and efficiency are continually being explored. One such innovation allows Managed Service Providers (MSPs) to engage in the network without needing to be part of a threshold signature scheme. This is achieved through the implementation of an echo-broadcast system, enabling MSPs to contribute shares and participate actively. Despite the open nature of this system, safeguards are in place to ensure compliance and integrity; MSPs exhibiting any form of malfeasance are promptly removed from the network by their peers.

The concept of yield generation emerges as a primary incentive for this model, drawing parallels with traditional mining pools. However, this system introduces additional versatility by facilitating MSPs to support sv2, empowering miners to independently construct blocks. This capability challenges the conventional utility of current pools while potentially reducing operational costs for miners. By adopting this approach, miners have the opportunity to bypass transaction fees entirely, provided they have the initial capital to invest. Furthermore, this autonomy allows for the creation of personalized block templates in scenarios where no MSPs utilize sv2, highlighting a significant shift towards more decentralized and miner-centric operations.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-05T22:25:36.129000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
