<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
  <updated>2024-12-07T02:27:13.397564+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>evoskuil.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-06T16:15:29.188000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
    <updated>2024-12-07T02:27:13.397596+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/libbitcoin-for-core-people/1222/45" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of downloading 850k blocks, equivalent to 582,391,632,423 bytes, has been a subject of optimization and improvement. Initially, the theoretical time to download this data over a 2.3 Gbps internet connection was estimated at 34 minutes. However, practical implementations have shown variations in this time frame. The integration of shani technology into the system has significantly improved performance, resulting in a completion time of approximately 40 minutes on a benchmark machine priced at $350. This time includes not just the download but also additional processes such as store build, startup, header sync, and full shutdown, which collectively require up to an extra minute.

Despite these improvements, there remains a gap between the actual and the theoretical download times, primarily attributed to the time-consuming processes of mmap flushing and remapping as files increase in size. It's suggested that utilizing machines with higher memory could mitigate most of these delays. Furthermore, advancements in hashing efficiency are anticipated with the introduction of an avx512 box, a recent acquisition for the test bench at a cost of $421. This upgrade is expected to further decrease the processing time, demonstrating the ongoing efforts to enhance system performance and efficiency through hardware improvements and technological integration.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-06T16:15:29.188000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
