<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
  <updated>2024-12-07T02:27:00.627347+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-12-06 17:27:39.213000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
    <updated>2024-12-07T02:27:00.627378+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/libbitcoin-for-core-people/1222/46" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an exploration of blockchain synchronization speeds, a programmer replicated a benchmark test initially conducted by another developer, @evoskuil, utilizing the same hardware setup to gauge performance. The hardware in question, a PELADN HA-4 with a 1TB SSD and 32GB RAM, was used to perform a sync using a slightly updated version of bn.exe. This test resulted in a synchronization time of 7605 seconds, translating to approximately 127 minutes or 2.11 hours. This outcome demonstrates libbitcoin's capability to achieve rapid synchronization times.

The comparison between the two tests revealed that the variance in synchronization speed could be attributed to differences in internet connectivity speeds, with the replicating programmer's internet speed at about 800Mbps versus Eric's greater than 2Gbps connection. This suggests that while hardware capabilities are crucial, internet speed plays a significant role in the efficiency of blockchain synchronization processes.

Furthermore, the cost factor associated with the hardware used for this benchmark was highlighted, noting a total expense of US$530 due to import duties. Despite this expenditure, the impressive synchronization time achieved on such a machine underscores libbitcoin's effectiveness and efficiency in handling blockchain data. The suggestion to conduct a similar synchronization test using bitcoin core on the same hardware aims to provide a baseline for comparison, which could offer further insights into the relative performance of different blockchain protocols under identical hardware conditions.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-06T17:27:39.213000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
