<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-08T02:42:09.524310+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-07T07:46:54.347000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-08T02:42:09.524343+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discussions about Radpool's method of distributing rewards have brought up concerns regarding the absence of a consensus mechanism. Contrary to these debates, Radpool does achieve consensus on the distribution of shares and rewards among miners. However, it accomplishes this without relying on the traditional Nakamoto consensus mechanism typically used at the share chain level. Instead, Radpool simplifies the process by treating it as a Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) consensus problem with a known membership base. This approach allows Radpool to utilize any standard BFT consensus solution available.

In the development of Radpool, a decision was made to select the simplest BFT consensus solution to implement, despite its potential drawbacks in terms of communication complexity. This choice was made with the understanding that a more efficient BFT system could be adopted in the future to address scalability issues should they arise. This strategic decision underscores Radpool's flexible approach to its infrastructure, prioritizing a straightforward initial design with the option for optimization based on future needs and challenges.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-07T07:46:54.347000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
