<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-08T02:41:50.878620+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly.992000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-07T17:22:11.992000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-08T02:41:50.878659+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the intricacies of managing payments within a network of Mining Service Providers (MSPs) through FROST signatures, emphasizing the necessity for consensus among MSPs regarding share contributions and message/share rates. The foundation of this system lies in the reliable broadcast to agreement reduction, ensuring that once MSPs have consistently replicated databases of shares via echo broadcast, they can accurately calculate owed amounts. This process eliminates the need for nakamoto consensus while addressing rate-limiting concerns by allowing each MSP to adjust mining difficulty and implement protective measures against potential DDoS attacks from other MSPs. Moreover, it's critical for MSPs to demonstrate their hash rate to maintain network integrity, despite challenges associated with broadcasting small shares due to high message rates.

Further elaboration reveals a mechanism for verifying share ownership, as detailed at [Radpool](https://www.radpool.xyz/1/stratum.html_verifiable_share_ownership), which enables MSPs to identify shares' origins, whether from individual miners or other MSPs. This system allows for the calculation and validation of shares tied to specific miners and block templates created by MSPs. However, this approach introduces potential drawbacks compared to existing models, such as increased transaction censorship risks and reduced accountability for miners towards their MSPs, marking a regression from previous standards like OCEAN with DATUM.

Contrarily, the structure proposed offers a novel perspective by decentralizing block template production across competing MSPs, rather than centralizing it under one entity. This competition encourages MSPs to cater to miner preferences, including support for sv2/datum, fostering greater decentralization. This model not only mitigates variance but also promotes a more distributed approach to template generation among multiple MSPs, enhancing the overall framework's resilience and appealing to a wider array of miners seeking diverse technological solutions.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-07T17:22:11.992000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
