<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
  <updated>2024-12-10T02:42:42.591851+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>HubertusVIE 2024-12-09 22:12:18.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T02:42:42.591886+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cat-vs-op-ctv-vs-xmr/1303/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the potential for Bitcoin to serve as a viable currency within the real economy, highlighting that its primary obstacle is economic rather than technical in nature. This challenge is characterized by volatility among other factors, which is not unique to Bitcoin but also affects cryptocurrencies like Monero. The suggestion put forward involves the implementation of a Bitcoin-based Chaumian ecash layer, which is posited as a strategic approach to transforming Bitcoin into a practical form of cash. This proposed system emphasizes the importance of blinded signatures, which are crucial for ensuring fungibility, a key attribute for any form of cash. Interestingly, the implementation of such a system would not require CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) for its realization, suggesting that Bitcoin's core protocol could remain unchanged in this aspect.

Further elaboration on the necessary technological infrastructure indicates that while the Lightning Network is integral to the overarching ecosystem, it does not fulfill the role of 'cash' in its own right. Instead, the combination of these technologies and approaches is seen as essential to addressing the economic hurdles facing Bitcoin's adoption as a mainstream medium of exchange.

For those interested in exploring this concept further, the author has begun detailing the economic challenges faced by Bitcoin and the proposed solutions through an ongoing series. The initial chapters of this discourse can be accessed at [https://blog.bitcr.org/p/the-bitcoin-dilemma-store-of-value-or-medium-of-exchange](https://blog.bitcr.org/p/the-bitcoin-dilemma-store-of-value-or-medium-of-exchange), offering readers an opportunity to delve deeper into the intricacies of making Bitcoin a viable currency for everyday transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-09T22:12:18.934000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
