<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-12-11T02:36:56.772120+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-10T02:18:08.314000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T02:36:56.772152+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the second quarter of 2023, a notable advancement in blockchain technology was demonstrated through the application of APO as an overridable CTV. This development was primarily showcased using a script denoted as `1 OP_CHECKSIG`. The practical demonstration of this technology utilized a spacechain toy implementation known as Soma, which can be explored further on [GitHub](https://github.com/nbd-wtf/soma). Soma represents a simplified but effective way to understand blockchain mechanisms, particularly focusing on the transfer of NFTs (Non-Fungible Tokens).

The testing of this implementation revealed its capability for facilitating transactions that are akin to blind merged-mining events. These events are unique because they are compensated separately through signet lightning, a method distinct from traditional transaction processes. Each transaction utilizing this model leads to the creation of a new spacechain block, identifiable by an OP_RETURN operation containing the hash of the corresponding spacechain block. This approach underscores a novel method of integrating blockchain technology with existing digital transaction frameworks to achieve more secure and verifiable outcomes.

However, it's crucial to acknowledge a discovered vulnerability within this system. Specifically, an issue was identified concerning the free spending mechanism due to a broken key path. This flaw was attributed to an oversight in the system's design. Despite this setback, it is important to recognize that the mentioned vulnerability occurred within a demo context, emphasizing the experimental nature of the project at this stage. Such challenges are not uncommon in the development of new technologies and serve as valuable learning points for future improvements.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-10T02:18:08.314000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
