<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-12-12T02:36:04.766242+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-12-11 11:49:09.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-12-12T02:36:04.766274+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around an examination of a spacechain demonstration, focusing on its implementation and archival aspects. The conversation highlights the decision not to use a NUMS point for the experiment, which allows for a flexible approach in updating the code through a key path spend, potentially preserving the historical data of the spacechain. This approach, however, hinges on the security of the key used; the choice of using a well-known public key (G) is critiqued since it poses a risk that funds could be compromised or the spacechain operation could be halted by anyone capable of deciphering the signature contained in the latest scriptPubKey. A more secure method would have involved utilizing an obscure public key alongside a publicly available list of signatures, enabling secure and permissionless mining.

Further analysis of the code reveals a limitation imposed on the spacechain, restricting it to a mere 50 blocks, as indicated in the Publish.scala file through the `bmm.precompute(0, 50)` function. This constraint aligns with the transaction count provided, suggesting that the only remaining action is the execution of the final transaction. This transaction involves sending the funds to a zero-satoshi OP_RETURN output, effectively concluding the spacechain's activity. The funds can either be reclaimed, used to cover transaction fees, or allocated towards initiating a new spacechain project. This exploration into the spacechain's structure and operational limitations offers valuable insights into its potential and areas for improvement, particularly in terms of security and scalability.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T11:49:09.953000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
