<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:32.991278+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode 2024-12-13 10:57:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:32.991309+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed feature, 'Post-Quantum Cryptography' (PQC), has been designed to address and neutralize the threats posed by the advancement of quantum computing to the security of Bitcoin. The initiative aims to integrate core PQC algorithms, including Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU, into the Bitcoin Core. This integration is pivotal in ensuring that Bitcoin's security infrastructure remains robust against the potential capabilities of future quantum computers.

A hybrid key management system forms a part of this new feature, enhancing the security framework further by allowing for a more versatile and secure management of cryptographic keys. Additionally, the feature introduces the capability for PQC transaction signing, marking a significant milestone in the evolution of Bitcoin's security mechanisms. To cater to diverse user needs and preferences, the feature has been designed with flexible configuration options, allowing users to tailor the functionality to their specific requirements.

The urgency and relevance of implementing Post-Quantum Cryptography within Bitcoin are underscored by the recent advancements in quantum computing technologies, such as the announcement of the Willow chip. This development highlights the growing capability of quantum computers to break traditional cryptographic schemes, exemplified by the chip's ability to factor the largest semiprime number to date.

For those interested in exploring the technical details and contributions to the PQC feature, the GitHub repository provides comprehensive insights and resources. The repository is accessible [here](https://github.com/QBlockQ/pqc-bitcoin).

This initiative not only reflects a proactive approach to safeguarding Bitcoin against emerging technological threats but also demonstrates a commitment to evolving the cryptocurrency's security in alignment with advancements in computing technologies. The implementation of Post-Quantum Cryptography is seen as a critical step forward, ensuring Bitcoin's resilience in the face of the quantum computing era.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:57:34.063000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
