<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:17.937664+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode 2024-12-13 18:42:55.375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:17.937700+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the proposal and categorization of cryptographic groups aimed at enhancing Bitcoin's security in the quantum era. Group 2, consisting of Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU, complements Group 1, which includes SPHINCS+, CRYSTALS-Dilithium, FALCON, and SQIsign. These selections are part of a broader strategy to ensure Bitcoin's resilience against quantum threats, focusing not just on securing digital communications but also on providing robust digital signature algorithms.

Group 1 is specifically tailored for Digital Signature Algorithms, vital for validating transactions securely within the Bitcoin network. This group's inclusion is strategic, preparing Bitcoin for potential future requirements such as encrypted communications between wallets or nodes. The emphasis here is on creating a quantum-safe and quantum-resistant infrastructure that can adapt to advancements in quantum computing.

The initiative reflects a proactive approach to cryptography in the context of Bitcoin, aiming to safeguard it against emerging quantum computing capabilities. By integrating these groups into Bitcoin's protocol, the community demonstrates its commitment to maintaining a secure and forward-looking blockchain ecosystem. This effort underscores the importance of evolving Bitcoin's cryptographic foundations to withstand quantum computing challenges, ensuring its permanence and reliability as a leading cryptocurrency.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-13T18:42:55.375000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
