<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
  <updated>2024-12-17T02:35:33.417936+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2024-12-16 13:14:25.104000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
    <updated>2024-12-17T02:35:33.417972+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-zk-verification-using-matt/1050/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of MATT, the opcode `OP_CAT` serves a specialized function, primarily facilitating the creation of vector commitments. This capability is crucial for verifying Merkle proofs, although it's acknowledged that alternative opcodes such as `OP_PAIRCOMMIT`/`VECTORCOMMIT` could also fulfill this role. The discussion extends to the utilization of covenants within MATT, highlighting their significance in enabling the execution of protocols as arbitrary state machines across multiple UTXOs. Each transition within these state machines has the capacity to perform computations on the state committed to it and to dynamically compute the state for subsequent steps. This innovative approach negates the necessity for presigned transactions by preprogramming all possible futures directly into Script, courtesy of the covenant.

The conversation further delves into the application of fraud proofs within this framework, providing a clear outline of how they're employed to validate computations. A detailed exposition on this subject was presented in the initial post about MATT, where the concept of commitments to computation and fraud challenges was introduced through both theoretical explanations and practical examples. Additionally, a python implementation of the bisection protocol offers a formalized description within its comments, serving as a testament to the practical applicability of these concepts.

For those seeking to explore the intricacies of MATT further, a compilation of resources has been made available at [merkle.fun](https://merkle.fun). This platform not only facilitates a deeper understanding of the discussed topics but also provides access to existing code implementations. The invitation to engage with this material indicates a welcoming stance towards inquiries, suggesting a collaborative approach to exploring the potential of MATT.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-16T13:14:25.104000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
