<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T02:30:57.376443+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-17T07:53:01.188000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T02:30:57.376474+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The [original Great Consensus Cleanup soft fork proposal](https://github.com/TheBlueMatt/bips/blob/7f9670b643b7c943a0cc6d2197d3eabe661050c2/bip-XXXX.mediawiki) introduced by Matt Corallo highlights a critical aspect of blockchain technology, particularly focusing on the limits of `nTime` rolling in Bitcoin mining. This process is deemed potentially beneficial for ASIC devices surpassing 280 TH/s performance, albeit with suggested limitations to prevent abuse. For example, a highly capable mining setup could necessitate timestamp adjustments by 10 seconds for every second, assuming template renewals occur every 30 seconds. To mitigate excessive `nTime` rolling, it's proposed that pool proxies could instead refresh the miner's template more frequently, thus reducing the need to adjust timestamps extensively.

In terms of the current testing environment, the [timewarp fix deployed on testnet4](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/f88f1e4392c871f206fe7ee70674c0a049d32ca7/bip-0094.mediawikiuser-content-Time_Warp_Fix) permits `nTime` to be adjusted backwards by up to 600 seconds. The process for determining new block templates in Bitcoin Core involves checking the current time, adjusting it if required by the Median Time Past (MTP) rule, and potentially modifying it further to account for blocks from the future at the start of a retarget period on testnet4.

However, concerns have been raised regarding the adequacy of the 600-second grace period allowed for these adjustments. Discussions suggest expanding this window to two hours to accommodate variations in node clock accuracy without compromising network security. This adjustment is crucial to prevent potential exploits by malicious miners who might set their timestamps two hours into the future. Such a scenario could jeopardize the system unless there is an overarching assumption of synchronized node clocks across the network. Furthermore, there's a call for limiting `nTime` rolling to a few minutes to avoid significant discrepancies in the network-wide tolerance for clock inaccuracies. These discussions and proposed changes aim to ensure the resilience and integrity of the blockchain against timing attacks, as detailed in discussions on platforms like [DelvingBitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062) and its continued discourse on consensus cleanup efforts.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-17T07:53:01.188000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
