<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:55.987105+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Fi3 2024-12-17 09:03:17.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:55.987135+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/45" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a theoretical attack on a cryptocurrency mining pool, where an attacker attempts to exploit the system by submitting fake fees and claiming an unearned share of the pool. Specifically, the scenario posits that an attacker could falsely claim fees amounting to 1 million BTC and aim to secure 0.0001% of the pool's distribution for a given interval, which would result in the illicit gain of approximately 1 BTC. 

However, this hypothetical attack is debunked by clarifying the operational mechanics of how mining pools validate transactions and distribute rewards. It highlights a common misunderstanding regarding the role of miners and the pool itself in the verification process. The mining pool is responsible for verifying all shares or jobs submitted by its participants, ensuring the integrity of the reward distribution. On the other hand, individual miners are tasked with validating only a random subset of these jobs. This procedural safeguard effectively mitigates the risk outlined in the initial scenario, rendering the described attack infeasible. 

This explanation sheds light on the robust security measures employed by mining pools to prevent fraudulent activities and ensure fair reward distribution among participating miners. It underscores the importance of understanding the technical workings of cryptocurrency mining operations to accurately assess potential vulnerabilities and safeguard against exploitation.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-17T09:03:17.565000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
