<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:42.237594+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Fi3.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-17T09:07:19.212000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:42.237624+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/47" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent proposal under discussion introduces a significant change in the process of declaring mining jobs by incorporating a `DeclareMiningJob` message that necessitates only a Merkle proof for the coinbase transaction, eliminating the requirement to disclose which transactions are included in the block. This approach marks a departure from traditional methods, aiming to enhance privacy and efficiency in mining operations. However, it's important to note that this system cannot function with solely coinbase transactions, indicating a need for a broader transaction base to ensure its operational viability. The details of this proposal were mentioned during an SRI call, with the minutes available for review at [Discord](https://discord.com/channels/950687892169195530/1019861139573714994/1314469730781757500:), offering a platform for further discussion and analysis within the community.

This innovative approach raises several considerations regarding the balance between privacy and transparency in blockchain transactions, particularly in the context of mining. By limiting the visibility of transactions included in a block, there could be implications for transaction verifiability and network trust. Additionally, the proposal prompts a reevaluation of current practices in declaring mining jobs, suggesting potential shifts towards more privacy-focused methodologies. As the blockchain community continues to evolve, such proposals play a crucial role in shaping the future direction of blockchain technology, highlighting the ongoing dialogue between enhancing privacy measures and maintaining a transparent, secure network.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-17T09:07:19.212000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
