<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:32.968308+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2024-12-17 11:43:26.843000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T02:28:32.968339+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/48" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the verification process of shares or jobs within a mining pool and its susceptibility to attacks. One party clarifies a common misunderstanding by stating that the responsibility of verifying all shares or jobs lies with the pool, whereas miners are only required to verify a random subset. This clarification is critical in understanding the dynamics of the system's security measures.

Further into the conversation, concerns are raised regarding the feasibility of pools verifying every job. The counter-argument acknowledges the intention behind the proposal but questions its practicality. The implementation of such comprehensive verification processes by SRI is brought into question, noting that SRI currently only verifies the presence of all transactions without delving into the completeness of these checks. This limitation is highlighted as a potential vulnerability, suggesting that incomplete checks might leave room for exploitation.

Moreover, the discussion touches on the implications of fully complete checks. While thorough verification could theoretically seal off vulnerabilities, it also raises concerns about the system's resilience against denial-of-service (DoS) attacks on the Job Distribution Server (JDS). This part of the dialogue underscores a delicate balance between securing the system from exploitation and ensuring it remains robust against DoS attacks, highlighting a key challenge in designing secure yet efficient verification processes in mining operations.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-17T11:43:26.843000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
