<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T02:30:04.290183+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP.484000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-12-17T14:44:03.484000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T02:30:04.290215+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of ensuring the security and validity of blocks in blockchain mining involves several conditional factors, particularly when dealing with the intricacies of time-stamping by miners. When a miner intentionally sets their timestamp two hours into the future compared to the node clock of others, it introduces potential risks, especially in scenarios involving ASICs (Application-Specific Integrated Circuits) designed to incrementally adjust the 'nTime' parameter by up to 600 seconds. This adjustment is predicated on the assumption that all participating nodes share synchronized clocks to avoid generating blocks that could be deemed invalid even temporarily.

The scenario unfolds further complexities under a series of specific conditions: firstly, the presence of a malicious miner; secondly, this miner successfully mines the last block of a given period; thirdly, an ASIC attempting to roll the `nTime` forward finds the first block of the subsequent period; fourthly, the ASIC discovers a solution that adjusts the `nTime` by an additional `n` seconds; fifthly, this block is discovered within `s` seconds; and finally, a significant portion of the network's hashrate operates on a clock that lags behind the miner's clock by more than `n + s - 600` seconds. This intricate chain of events highlights the delicate balance required to maintain the integrity of block creation without inadvertently producing blocks that could be rejected due to timing discrepancies among network participants.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-17T14:44:03.484000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
