<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-12-17T02:36:45.582161+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-12-16 17:04:12.435000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vostrnad 2024-12-16 13:03:52.784000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-12-16 12:42:36.884000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-12-16 11:15:42.346000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-12-14 22:17:24.777000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-12 05:57:47.375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-11 22:00:37.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-11 21:56:21.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-11 11:49:09.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-10 02:18:08.314000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-09 19:28:51.099000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-11-27 21:11:41.151000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-11-27 21:07:42.116000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vostrnad  . 2024-11-21 20:04:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2024-11-16 23:13:48.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-11-15 21:28:39.675000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-11-14 17:34:11.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3801_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3799_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3798_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3797_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3776_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3762_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3760_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3759_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3758_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3754_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3752_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3623_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3622_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3566_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3550_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3547_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3521_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-12-17T02:36:45.582282+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of blockchain technology, specifically focusing on issues related to the detection and processing of transactions that utilize bare CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) unspent outputs combined with the OP_NOP4 operation. An example provided underscores the challenges in identifying transactions involving such outputs, as demonstrated by a specific transaction available for viewing on [mempool.space](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/ab953773f8f8306567bf48357d8ca5a179909c12b2bc64ae2ef80f0850708920). The conversation transitions into exploring strategies for more efficient handling of precomputed transactions in mining, suggesting improvements in computing and caching hashes to reduce recalculations and enhance data storage efficiency.

The email also delves into the difficulties encountered in attracting engagement for demo miners and spacechain nodes, attributing the lack of widespread interest to an absence of targeted marketing strategies. It touches upon potential innovations for spacechains and the use of utreexo commitments for NFTs, discussing their limitations and suggesting reverse commitments as a solution. Concerns about the reliability of spacechains in adversarial environments, validation processes, and the risks of accepting invalid blocks are highlighted, emphasizing the need for real implementations to further explore these challenges.

Furthermore, the conversation discusses the structure and intentions behind a demo project involving a blockchain, referred to as spacechain, which was designed for long-term operation but faced engagement challenges. Insights into the mining process leveraging Lightning payments and replace-by-fee mechanisms are shared, alongside reflections on technical aspects and missed opportunities in blockchain implementation.

The email outlines a detailed examination of a spacechain demonstration, highlighting decisions related to security and scalability, including the choice of public keys and the imposed limitation on the chain's length. Also mentioned is an advancement in blockchain technology through the application of APO as an overridable CTV, exemplified by the Soma project on [GitHub](https://github.com/nbd-wtf/soma), showcasing its potential for secure and verifiable transactions despite identified vulnerabilities.

It raises concerns over the adequacy of metrics for assessing network consensus and development practices, questioning the utility of signet and critiquing methodologies that fail to capture specific transaction scripts. This part of the discussion emphasizes the importance of comprehensive testing in environments like signet to ensure correct behavior in 'rare case' scenarios.

Finally, the email introduces a new tool designed for analyzing Bitcoin Inquisition transactions and mentions a recent experiment involving pathcoin, aimed at exploring its capabilities and potential applications. The exploration of Bitcoin's technological advancements, particularly in soft forks and transaction methodologies, highlights ongoing efforts to expand capabilities and explore new possibilities through technical experimentation and proof-of-concept projects. Significant changes introduced by Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) 118, 119, and 347 are discussed, detailing their impact on scripting capabilities and outlining observed patterns and use cases in their application.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-16T17:04:12.435000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
