<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
  <updated>2024-12-16T02:39:52.423902+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2024-12-15 16:06:16.862000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2024-07-31 12:54:53.365000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3777_Optimistic-ZK-verification-using-MATT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2909_Optimistic-ZK-verification-using-MATT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
    <updated>2024-12-16T02:39:52.423941+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-zk-verification-using-matt/1050" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent enhancements to Elftrace mark a significant shift in the tool's capabilities, primarily designed to verify RISC-V execution within Bitcoin scripts. The core development team has made notable strides in improving its utility and user experience by streamlining the Rust program compilation process. This development is particularly impactful as it eliminates the need for writing custom assembly code for new programs, thereby simplifying the development process. Additionally, Elftrace has been updated to support standard input/output operations, extending the range of programs that can effectively interact with it.

A key advancement in Elftrace's functionality is its ability to compile the Winterfell STARK library as a dependency. This inclusion is pivotal because it facilitates the verification of Zero-Knowledge (ZK) proofs directly within Bitcoin Script, a feature that demands the use of CAT and a covenant for implementation. This capability enriches Elftrace's application, enabling it to perform more complex cryptographic verification tasks.

For developers keen on exploring these new features, especially the verification of ZK proofs within Bitcoin Script, a comprehensive guide along with example code has been provided. This documentation is an invaluable resource for those looking to leverage Elftrace for advanced cryptographic verification efforts. The detailed guide discusses the technical nuances involved, offering a thorough exploration of how to integrate these features into projects. Interested individuals can access this resource [here](https://github.com/halseth/elftrace/blob/831f537bc1509bd45c350e103f7fc73aa818f7dd/docs/zk_verifier.md), which promises to provide deep insights into utilizing Elftrace's enhanced capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-15T16:06:16.862000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
