<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
  <updated>2024-12-17T02:35:46.593602+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi.104000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  ..862000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  ..365000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3800_Optimistic-ZK-verification-using-MATT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3777_Optimistic-ZK-verification-using-MATT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2909_Optimistic-ZK-verification-using-MATT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Optimistic ZK verification using MATT</title>
    <updated>2024-12-17T02:35:46.593647+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-zk-verification-using-matt/1050" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the utilization of `OP_CAT` and covenants within the context of blockchain technology, specifically focusing on their applications in creating vector commitments and executing protocols as arbitrary state machines across multiple Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). The usage of `OP_CAT`, although primarily for vector commitments that facilitate Merkle proof checking, highlights its interchangeable nature with other opcodes like `OP_PAIRCOMMIT`/`VECTORCOMMIT`. The importance of a covenant is underscored by its capability to execute protocols without the need for presigned transactions, allowing for a dynamic computation of states across different nodes in a protocol’s state machine. This mechanism also supports fraud proofs for any computations within the system, thereby eliminating the necessity for presigned transactions and enabling direct preprogramming of possible futures in Script.

Further insights are provided through the examples and resources linked within the communication. These include an initial post about MATT, offering a sketch of the fraud proofs starting from "Commitments to computation and fraud challenges", alongside a toy example and a Python implementation of the bisection protocol. This implementation offers a formal description within its comments, reinforcing the practical application of these concepts. For those seeking a deeper understanding or wishing to explore the existing codebase, all related resources have been aggregated at a dedicated website, encouraging further exploration.

Additionally, the email touches upon Elftrace, a tool initially developed for verifying RISC-V execution through Bitcoin Scripts. It outlines significant updates aimed at enhancing functionality and user experience, such as simplifying the process of compiling Rust programs, negating the need for custom assembly code, and introducing support for standard input/output operations. A notable advancement includes the capability to compile the Winterfell STARK library as a dependency, enabling the verification of Zero-Knowledge (ZK) proofs directly within Bitcoin Script. However, the application of these features still requires the use of CAT and a covenant. A comprehensive guide, complete with example code, has been provided to assist developers in integrating these advanced cryptographic verification tasks into their projects, indicating a significant step forward in the utility of Elftrace for blockchain development.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-16T13:14:25.104000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
