<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-05T02:38:23.379057+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-12-04 14:09:17.570000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-12-04 10:54:07.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-12-03 14:36:07.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-12-03 13:42:34.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-12-03 07:19:56.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-12-03 01:18:20.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-12-03 00:50:23.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-12-02 18:20:14.105000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 21:34:24.602000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-11-27 21:15:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 19:30:52.026000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 17:51:11.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-11-27 16:35:31.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-11-25 17:41:41.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-16 14:58:04.341000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3710_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3708_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3706_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3705_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3703_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3697_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3696_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3679_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3625_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3624_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3620_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3619_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3617_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3599_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3548_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-05T02:38:23.379160+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the evolving landscape of blockchain and mining technologies, Radpool emerges as an innovative solution bridging the gap between traditional centralized mining pools and decentralized mining approaches. By leveraging a network of Mining Service Providers (MSPs), Radpool decentralizes block template generation and payout mechanisms, aiming to reduce miner payout variance while enhancing network stability and security. This system enables MSPs to independently manage stratum servers and block templates, providing miners with the flexibility to select or construct their own templates. Utilizing Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) for miner compensation, based on their hash rate, ensures reliable payouts. The use of FROST threshold signatures for settling these contracts underscores Radpool's commitment to security and decentralization.

The introduction of Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) broadcasts within Radpool's architecture facilitates a robust mechanism against malicious activities, ensuring integrity across the network. This feature, alongside the implementation of rate-limiting share broadcasts and difficulty adjustment mechanisms, addresses critical concerns related to scalability and Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks. Such measures are pivotal in maintaining operational efficiency and safeguarding the network from potential threats. Furthermore, Radpool's design reflects a nuanced understanding of the importance of consensus mechanisms in decentralized systems, particularly in share distribution and accounting. This understanding is evident in the protocol's alignment with Nakamoto consensus principles, applied within a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) for enhanced performance and reliability.

Comparatively, Braidpool proposes a dynamic federation of miners controlling block template creation, emphasizing democratized participation and censorship resistance. This approach contrasts with Radpool's more centralized model, where a select group of MSPs determines membership within the signing federation. Concerns about centralization risk and transaction censorship associated with Radpool are addressed through discussions on legal implications and the financialization of mining operations. Both proposals acknowledge the utility of DLCs for improving mining pool operations, indicating a shared interest in cryptographic advancements.

Discussions extend to the practicality and legality of MSPs' roles, suggesting shifts in block template selection to individual miners to mitigate risks. The conversation also touches upon the complexity of creating fair economic incentives within mining pools, with Braidpool introducing solutions aimed at stabilizing rewards distribution and discouraging pool hopping. Despite differences, there's openness to collaboration, especially in sharing technological advancements like FROST signing technology.

Radpool positions itself uniquely by offering a federated approach that combines the benefits of decentralization with the operational efficiencies of centralized pools. This hybrid model promises to enhance the competitiveness of the mining market, encouraging network expansion and fostering a more resilient blockchain ecosystem. The ongoing development of Radpool, including the FROST Federation and the implementation of DLC contracts, invites community engagement and contribution, highlighting the project's commitment to transparency and collaborative innovation.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-04T14:09:17.570000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
