<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2025-04-30T02:41:47.490293+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode  ..179000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode  ..375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  ..394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode  ..063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4899_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3774_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3772_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3771_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3770_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T02:41:47.490350+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent advancements in the Bitcoin repository have marked a significant step towards fortifying its security against quantum threats. The introduction of Groups 1 and 2, encompassing algorithms such as Kyber, FrodoKEM, NTRU, SPHINCS+, CRYSTALS-Dilithium, FALCON, and excluding SQIsign due to its lack of standardization by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and slow verification times, are at the forefront of these efforts. These groups are integral to the digital signature algorithms critical for secure transaction validation within the Bitcoin network. Their implementation is a strategic move to equip Bitcoin with a quantum-safe infrastructure, capable of adapting to the rapid advancements in quantum computing. This initiative underscores a proactive approach to cryptographic enhancements, ensuring Bitcoin's durability against quantum computational threats.

The discussion further extends to the practical integration of these algorithms into Bitcoin’s framework, particularly focusing on the compatibility with existing Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and the potential for introducing new address types. These considerations highlight an ongoing effort to clarify and refine how these quantum-resistant algorithms will be deployed within Bitcoin’s ecosystem, ensuring a seamless transition and adherence to established protocols.

Moreover, the Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) feature represents a pivotal development in Bitcoin’s evolution, designed to preemptively counteract the risks posed by quantum computing advancements. By incorporating core PQC algorithms into Bitcoin Core and introducing a hybrid key management system alongside PQC transaction signing capabilities, this feature aims to bolster Bitcoin's security infrastructure significantly. It offers customizable options to meet diverse user preferences, emphasizing the urgency of integrating quantum-resistant mechanisms in light of developments like the Willow chip, which showcases the increasing potential of quantum computers to compromise traditional cryptographic schemes. For those seeking deeper insights into this quantum-resistant initiative, the GitHub repository provides detailed documentation and resources, available [here](https://github.com/QBlockQ/pqc-bitcoin). This comprehensive approach not only highlights the Bitcoin community's commitment to safeguarding the cryptocurrency against emerging technological threats but also positions Bitcoin as a resilient and forward-thinking leader in the cryptocurrency space, prepared to face the challenges of the quantum computing era.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-29T23:42:53.979000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
