<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2024-12-04T02:36:14.577678+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-12-03 03:33:40.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-10-10 22:36:12.253000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewkozlik  . 2024-10-03 15:18:51.917000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-10-02 15:40:06.265000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2024-01-16 15:02:53.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-01-16 14:34:11.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2024-01-16 14:20:19.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-01-16 11:03:51.006000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-28 16:38:10.719000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>wydengyre  . 2023-12-28 02:34:27.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 20:05:49.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 18:56:24.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 16:59:33.416000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:22.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:16.610000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:33:53.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:30:02.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:26:33.367000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:23:41.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:21:22.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:12:37.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:09:50.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:00:06.516000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 14:55:19.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 14:52:51.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 14:49:37.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 13:35:30.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 13:29:37.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3699_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3346_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3317_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3308_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1143_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1142_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1141_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1139_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/880_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/877_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/836_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/835_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/808_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/804_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/803_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/802_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/800_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/801_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/799_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/798_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/797_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/796_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/791_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/795_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/794_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/793_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/790_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/789_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T02:36:14.577857+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse surrounding the standardization of wallet policies, especially concerning taproot and the use of Extended Public Keys (XPUBs), highlights several key challenges and proposed solutions in enhancing security and functionality within cryptocurrency systems. A notable suggestion involves sorting and removing duplicates of all XPUBs before concatenating them and applying a SHA256 hash to the result. This method aims to simplify implementation while ensuring compatibility with future wallet policies by restricting all XPUBs to specific formats without allowing optional derivation paths. Such an approach addresses the need for standardizing unspendable internal XPUBs, thereby facilitating easier integration and maintenance.

Security vulnerabilities associated with the manipulation of chain codes in XPUBs are a significant concern. The absence of hashing techniques in certain scenarios could enable attackers to skew results favorably by altering the chain code. To counter this, strategies like publishing a dummy XPUB have been considered, though their effectiveness remains debatable. The discussion also delves into methods for deriving chain code from XPUBs in a sequence-independent manner, suggesting solutions such as XOR operations or addition modulo 2^256 to prevent cancellation effects in calculations. These proposals aim to safeguard sensitive information while maintaining operational transparency.

The technical aspects of programming standards, particularly in handling key arrangement and wallet policy features, underscore the importance of adaptability and efficiency. Issues arise with descriptors that are sensitive to the order of keys, indicating a need for methods that ensure consistency regardless of key sequence. Moreover, the integration of identical placeholders within wallet policies, especially with taproot technology, necessitates a stateful parser to avoid redundancy. The complexity added by these requirements calls for careful consideration in developing programming solutions that accommodate wallet policy features without overly complicating hardware signer codes.

An emerging focus is on creating unspendable internal keys compatible with taproot, aiming to enhance user experience by obviating the need for key verification on devices. Salvatore's method, which recycles descriptor entropy for generating unspendable keys, is identified as a promising solution. This approach uses a specified `xpub` format and a deterministic chaincode generation process, aligning with the goal of seamless integration and standardized security frameworks across signing devices.

In parallel, discussions on cryptographic protocols stress the necessity of distinguishing between output descriptors and wallet policies based on their unique requirements. While output descriptors may benefit from explicitly defining entropy, wallet policies could rely on deterministic processes implicit in their structure. This differentiation acknowledges the distinct functionalities and aims to streamline transaction processes and policy generation.

Lastly, the dialogue extends to the practical challenges of address creation using partial descriptors and the implications for privacy and security in revealing script-only taproot outputs. The consensus leans towards methodologies that encapsulate all necessary information within descriptors, minimizing dependencies on external data and preserving the decentralized ethos of Bitcoin. Additionally, the exploration of digital fingerprinting and its impact on transaction privacy emphasizes the delicate balance between transparency and confidentiality in blockchain technologies.

Overall, these discussions reflect a concerted effort to address the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency security, emphasizing the need for innovative, adaptable, and secure programming practices.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T03:33:40.002000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
