<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
  <updated>2024-12-31T02:17:57.720183+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-12-30 15:15:55.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>HubertusVIE  . 2024-12-09 22:12:18.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh  . 2024-12-03 10:46:57.475000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3893_op-CAT-vs-op-CTV-vs-XMR.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3753_op-CAT-vs-op-CTV-vs-XMR.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3704_op-CAT-vs-op-CTV-vs-XMR.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - op_CAT vs op_CTV vs XMR</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T02:17:57.720227+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-cat-vs-op-ctv-vs-xmr/1303" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion sheds light on the critical challenges and potential pathways for Bitcoin and Monero in adapting to a future that might be influenced significantly by quantum computing. The narrative emphasizes that current cryptographic practices underpinning these cryptocurrencies, including Bitcoin's reliance on Taproot Schnorr signature aggregation and Monero's privacy and security mechanisms, are not inherently quantum-resistant. Specifically, the vulnerability of Bitcoin's infrastructure to quantum computing could lead to significant security breaches, such as the creation of infinite amounts of "cash" by individuals with access to such technology. Despite these concerns, Monero appears to be proactively addressing its quantum vulnerabilities through planned updates like FCMP++ that aim to bolster its privacy and forward secrecy capabilities within a three-year timeframe.

Further, the conversation transitions into an examination of Bitcoin's role in the real economy, identifying its primary challenge as economic rather than technical. Volatility, a common issue across cryptocurrencies, hampers Bitcoin's potential as a practical form of cash. A proposed solution involves the implementation of a Bitcoin-based Chaumian ecash layer, highlighting the importance of blinded signatures for ensuring fungibility—a crucial characteristic for any currency aspiring to operate as cash. This approach suggests that significant protocol changes, such as the adoption of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV), may not be necessary. Instead, it underscores the utility of the Lightning Network and other technological innovations in overcoming economic barriers to Bitcoin’s broader acceptance as a medium of exchange. Interested readers can explore these concepts further through an ongoing series available at [https://blog.bitcr.org/p/the-bitcoin-dilemma-store-of-value-or-medium-of-exchange](https://blog.bitcr.org/p/the-bitcoin-dilemma-store-of-value-or-medium-of-exchange).

The discourse also explores the distinction between Bitcoin and Monero in terms of their suitability as "cash," with a focus on stability and fungibility. Concerns about Bitcoin's fungibility have been exacerbated by developments like Taproot and SegWit, although there is debate regarding the extent of this impact. The conversation highlights the variable privacy offered by the Lightning Network and delves into potential technical enhancements that could improve Bitcoin's functionality, including the CTV soft fork and transaction pools via OP_CAT. This detailed exploration of technical solutions underscores the broader debate within the cryptocurrency community on achieving scalability, privacy, and functionality improvements.

Additionally, the narrative distinguishes between Bitcoin's role as "money" and Monero's as "cash," suggesting that while Bitcoin serves as a store of value, Monero's design makes it more suited for everyday transactions. This distinction is further explored through additional resources, including a [link](https://sethforprivacy.com/posts/fungibility-graveyard/) on fungibility and a [GitHub discussion](https://github.com/taproot-wizards/purrfect_vault/issues/1issuecomment-2513445570) that provides insights into the community's engagement with these issues. Through this multifaceted discussion, the writer encourages ongoing dialogue and investigation within the cryptocurrency community, leveraging their blog as a platform for expanding on these critical topics.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-30T15:15:55.133000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
