<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2024-12-15T02:42:43.280086+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode 2024-12-14 17:51:00.179000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode  . 2024-12-13 18:42:55.375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-12-13 15:28:09.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode  . 2024-12-13 10:57:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3774_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3772_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3771_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3770_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-15T02:42:43.280137+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent update to the repository has introduced significant enhancements to Bitcoin's security by integrating both cryptographic groups, Group 1 and Group 2, alongside updates to the PQC manager and the addition of suitable tests. This integration is aimed at bolstering Bitcoin's defenses against quantum computing threats. Group 1, featuring algorithms like SPHINCS+, CRYSTALS-Dilithium, FALCON, and SQIsign, focuses on Digital Signature Algorithms crucial for secure transaction validation within the Bitcoin network. Meanwhile, Group 2 includes Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU, further strengthening the infrastructure against quantum vulnerabilities. However, there's an ongoing debate regarding the inclusion of SQIsign, as it hasn't been standardized by NIST, raising questions about its future within the framework.

The discussion also delves into the practical implementation of these cryptographic advancements, particularly concerning new signature algorithms and the possibility of a new address type. There's a specific interest in ensuring compatibility with the P2QRH BIP, although some aspects remain unclear. This highlights a broader conversation about how these post-quantum algorithms will be integrated and utilized within Bitcoin, emphasizing the need for clarity on changes to address formats and adherence to Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs).

At the heart of these developments is the 'Post-Quantum Cryptography' (PQC) feature, designed to fortify Bitcoin against the evolving threats posed by quantum computing. By incorporating core PQC algorithms such as Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU into Bitcoin Core, the initiative aims to create a quantum-resistant security architecture. A notable aspect of this feature is the introduction of a hybrid key management system and the capability for PQC transaction signing. These advancements are accompanied by flexible configuration options to meet various user needs. The urgency of implementing PQC is underscored by recent quantum computing milestones, such as the development of the Willow chip, which poses a significant threat to traditional cryptographic schemes. For those interested in exploring the technical specifics or contributing to the project, the GitHub repository offers detailed insights and resources, accessible [here](https://github.com/QBlockQ/pqc-bitcoin). This proactive approach towards enhancing Bitcoin's security showcases a commitment to adapting the cryptocurrency's defenses in line with technological progress, ensuring its long-term resilience against quantum computing challenges.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-14T17:51:00.179000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
