<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Security soft fork deployments arent risky</title>
  <updated>2024-12-19T02:26:47.022192+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-12-18 20:57:54.014000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2024-12-18 20:54:02.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-12-18 20:42:14.450000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2024-12-18 17:48:38.857000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3833_Security-soft-fork-deployments-arent-risky.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3832_Security-soft-fork-deployments-arent-risky.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3831_Security-soft-fork-deployments-arent-risky.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3828_Security-soft-fork-deployments-arent-risky.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Security soft fork deployments arent risky</title>
    <updated>2024-12-19T02:26:47.022243+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/security-soft-fork-deployments-arent-risky/1328" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the risks associated with deploying soft forks in the Bitcoin network, particularly focusing on the nuances between feature soft forks and security soft forks, as well as their combined forms. The conversation begins by acknowledging that all changes to the consensus code, regardless of their nature, carry inherent risks and necessitate thorough review. An illustrative example provided is a pull request on GitHub, which can be viewed [here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/9049).

Soft forks are categorized into three main types: feature soft forks, security soft forks, and those that serve both purposes. Feature soft forks, such as BIP16, BIP65, and BIP66 (detailed respectively at their links), introduce new features to the Bitcoin protocol. These forks are considered risky primarily due to the possibility of chain splits, which occur when nodes that have not upgraded to the new protocol rules disagree with the validity of transactions mined in a block by nodes that have upgraded. To mitigate such risks, widespread consensus within the community is essential before deploying feature soft forks.

Security soft forks, exemplified by BIP42, BIP143, and measures against time warp attacks, focus on enhancing the security of the network. These forks are perceived to have a lower risk of causing chain splits because they aim to counteract exploits or vulnerabilities rather than introduce new features. The logic here is that if an attack is attempted during the deployment of a security soft fork, it would be an action against the network's health, thereby justifying the exclusion of the attacking entity through the soft fork itself.

Further elaboration is provided on soft forks that incorporate both security enhancements and new features, like BIP141, BIP143, and BIP341. These improvements were implemented to address specific security vulnerabilities related to sighash transactions by introducing a new witness version. Although this introduces a level of deployment risk due to the activation of new features, the primary goal remains to enhance network security.

A significant insight shared is the differentiation between the risks associated with security versus feature soft forks. While the former aims to safeguard the network from existing threats and therefore enjoys a form of inherent legitimacy and urgency, the latter involves a more nuanced approach due to the potential for disagreement among network participants. The emphasis is on the strategic deployment of security soft forks independently of feature updates to prioritize the swift and safe correction of vulnerabilities after thorough review. This stance advocates for a proactive approach towards security enhancements, separate from the introduction of new features, to maintain network integrity and user trust.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-18T20:57:54.014000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
