<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Full Disclosure: “Transaction-Relay Throughput Overflow attacks against Off-Chain Protocols</title>
  <updated>2024-12-10T02:43:14.004958+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard.487000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  ..257000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3750_Full-Disclosure-Transaction-Relay-Throughput-Overflow-attacks-against-Off-Chain-Protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3714_Full-Disclosure-Transaction-Relay-Throughput-Overflow-attacks-against-Off-Chain-Protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Full Disclosure: “Transaction-Relay Throughput Overflow attacks against Off-Chain Protocols</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T02:43:14.005010+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/full-disclosure-transaction-relay-throughput-overflow-attacks-against-off-chain-protocols/1305" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discovery of vulnerabilities within Bitcoin's transaction-relay rules has sparked considerable debate and concern. A detailed report, which can be found at [this link](https://ariard.github.io/), offers an in-depth examination of the issues at hand, revealing their broad implications for a variety of Bitcoin applications, notably including the Lightning Network. The significance of these findings is further underscored by the initiation of a request to MITRE for the assignment of a Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) ID, marking the seriousness with which this issue is being taken. Currently identified by the temporary identifier 1780258, the process for obtaining an official CVE ID is in progress, highlighting the recognized urgency and potential widespread impact of the discovered vulnerability.

The vulnerabilities identified have been acknowledged as having the capability to affect an unlimited range of use-cases within the Bitcoin ecosystem, illustrating the extensive reach and critical nature of the flaw found in the transaction-relay components. This acknowledgment not only emphasizes the severity of the problem but also the imperative need for prompt and effective resolution to mitigate the risks posed to the integrity and functionality of Bitcoin-related operations.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-09T15:11:22.487000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
