<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2024-12-31T02:18:26.263465+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T02:18:26.263509+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of Braidpool's difficulty algorithm marks a significant advancement in blockchain consensus mechanisms by eschewing traditional metrics such as timestamps, hashrate, or latency in favor of targeting the Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) width to set difficulty levels. This novel approach seeks to expedite consensus by aiming for an optimal DAG width of 1, which facilitates unanimous agreement among nodes regarding the system's state. Achieving this condition ensures a block's uniqueness by making it the sole link between two generations of blocks within a single latency period, thereby speeding up the consensus process.

The technique for measuring DAG width is notably straightforward, focusing on counting a block's parents with the aim of achieving a fixed number. It was observed that setting the target to two parents not only simplifies the consensus mechanism but also minimizes the standard deviation of parent numbers to one, contrasting sharply with the complexity found in other DAG-based systems. This simplicity is further highlighted by the discovery that aiming for exactly two parents allows for consensus to be reached roughly 2.71828 times the defined latency period. This correlation suggests a deeper mathematical relationship, indicating that the ratio of total blocks to consensus blocks is inherently significant. 

The difficulty adjustment algorithm introduced in this context adjusts the difficulty based on the average number of parents over recent blocks, increasing the difficulty if this average exceeds two and decreasing it otherwise. This adaptive mechanism maintains the desired network behavior over time, with simulations demonstrating its effectiveness through a near-ideal mean standard deviation and a consensus speed multiple closely aligned with theoretical expectations.

Comparing this DAG-based consensus mechanism with the Avalanche protocol reveals a shared emphasis on managing 'waste'—whether through network messages or hashing—to secure decentralization, highlighting the inherent costs associated with distributed security. This comparison underscores the critical balance blockchain technology must achieve between efficiency, security, and decentralization. The introduction of Braidpool's difficulty algorithm presents a promising avenue for enhancing blockchain consensus algorithms, potentially providing a more efficient alternative to traditional methodologies. For those interested in a deeper understanding, the documentation can be found at [Braidpool's GitHub](https://github.com/braidpool/braidpool/blob/6bc7785c7ee61ea1379ae971ecf8ebca1f976332/docs/braid_consensus.md).</summary>
    <published>2024-12-31T01:39:41.910000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
