<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-12-15T02:42:09.445748+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-12-14 22:17:24.777000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-12 05:57:47.375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-11 22:00:37.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-11 21:56:21.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-11 11:49:09.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fiatjaf  . 2024-12-10 02:18:08.314000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-09 19:28:51.099000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-11-27 21:11:41.151000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-11-27 21:07:42.116000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>vostrnad  . 2024-11-21 20:04:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2024-11-16 23:13:48.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-11-15 21:28:39.675000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-11-14 17:34:11.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3776_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3762_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3760_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3759_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3758_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3754_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3752_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3623_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3622_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3566_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3550_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3547_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3521_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-12-15T02:42:09.445865+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email in question explores several intricate aspects of blockchain technology, demonstrating a deep dive into various innovations, challenges, and experimental projects within the Bitcoin ecosystem. It begins by addressing an issue related to the detection of transactions that create bare CTV unspent outputs with OP_NOP4, providing a specific example for further examination.

A significant portion of the discussion is dedicated to outlining a more efficient strategy for handling precomputed transactions in mining. This strategy suggests caching every 4000th hash and its subsequent hashes up to a certain point, drastically reducing the amount of data required for storage or precalculation over long periods, such as 1000 years. The conversation then pivots to the difficulties encountered in attracting engagement for demo miners and spacechain nodes. Despite months of effort, only a small number of individuals participated, highlighting the need for a targeted marketing strategy to thrive in dynamic spaces like NFTs and memecoins.

The email also delves into potential innovations for spacechains, including new programming features and the creation of currencies pegged against established cryptocurrencies. It discusses the use of utreexo commitments for NFTs to provide verifiable ownership proofs and proposes reverse commitments as a solution for linking tokens to external data. Furthermore, it raises concerns about the reliability of spacechains in adversarial environments, specifically regarding validation processes and the risk of accepting invalid blocks.

Reflecting on personal experiences, the sender draws parallels between their efforts with early Bitcoin activities, emphasizing patience and persistence with emerging technologies. They mention a "Nothing Up My Sleeve" approach for a specific covenant to ensure cryptographic integrity and conclude with reflections on previous attempts to document blockchain data and suggestions for future projects focused on long-term, low-maintenance operations.

Additionally, the discussion touches upon the importance of linking BMM transactions in a sequence for ensuring all transactions are interconnected in a continuous chain. It details the initial setup and intentions behind a demo project involving a blockchain, referred to as spacechain, which was precomputed to last for potentially 1000 years. However, due to limited engagement, the project was eventually shut down.

Moreover, the conversation highlights a notable advancement in blockchain technology through the application of APO as an overridable CTV, with a practical demonstration provided via a project named Soma. It acknowledges a discovered vulnerability within this system due to a broken key path but emphasizes the value of such experiments in advancing knowledge and improving future implementations.

The email critiques certain methodologies for failing to capture specific transaction scripts, underscoring the importance of comprehensive testing environments like signet for exploring rare case scenarios. It also provides an analysis of CTV activity on ctv-signet, discussing the distribution of different transaction types and questioning the overall utility of signet for assessing network consensus and development practices.

Lastly, the correspondence introduces a new tool designed for exploring Bitcoin Inquisition transactions and shares insights from an experiment involving the use of pathcoin, aimed at exploring its capabilities and potential applications. This exploration reflects ongoing efforts within the Bitcoin community to expand its capabilities and explore new possibilities through technical experimentation and proof-of-concept projects.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-14T22:17:24.777000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
