<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-05T02:25:52.439650+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-01-04 23:43:19.353000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-04 08:10:18.927000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 17:05:07.824000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-01-03 15:27:10.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 13:52:30.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 12:59:20.523000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 11:51:32.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 19:16:14.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-02 17:18:06.007000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 16:04:00.283000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-02 14:47:10.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-01 01:21:03.301000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-31 04:30:09.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3967_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3959_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3947_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3943_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3942_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3940_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3931_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3923_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3921_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3920_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3917_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3909_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3903_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-05T02:25:52.439761+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The analysis begins by addressing the intricacies of Braidpool's approach to managing blockchain consensus and difficulty adjustments, emphasizing the algorithm's unique handling of latency and its implications for block orphan rates. It delves into the mathematical underpinnings and operational specifics of the Nb/Nc Dynamic Adjustment Algorithm (DAA), showcasing its efficiency in maintaining network stability even amid significant latency variations among miners. By focusing on a broader spectrum of blocks, including grandparents and great-grandparents, the DAA adeptly aligns the difficulty level with the optimal Nb/Nc ratio, thus ensuring consistent block generation times without disproportionately penalizing miners experiencing higher latencies.

Further examination reveals an innovative strategy aimed at mitigating the challenges posed by high-latency transactions within the Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) framework. This includes a proposal to exclude beads exhibiting abnormally high latency from compensation, thereby incentivizing miners to maintain low latency levels. The methodology for determining bead latency, based on median timestamps of a bead's children and parents rather than the miner's timestamp, aims to create a fairer and more manipulation-resistant system. Additionally, the discussion touches upon the implementation of deterministic block templates and UTreeXO for efficient mempool management, highlighting ongoing efforts to refine these systems through community collaboration and open-source development.

The discourse also navigates the complexities of validating DAG chains and distributing rewards through weak blocks, pointing out the potential of Utreexo-based nodes to streamline the update process for the UTXO set database. This solution is presented as a means to alleviate the storage and computational burdens associated with maintaining multiple branch states and mempool versions, suggesting that alternative node implementations, such as Libbitcoin, might offer more adaptable frameworks for handling DAG configurations.

A critical look at the adjustment of blockchain difficulty algorithms reveals attempts to address "excess grandparents" and latency inequality by fine-tuning the difficulty adjustment based on the presence of grandparent references relative to a benchmark of three parents per block. This nuanced approach reflects a deep understanding of the interplay between miner latency and network dynamics, underscoring the need for continued innovation in algorithm design to ensure equitable participation across the mining community.

In contrast to conventional methods that adjust difficulty based solely on hashrate or time intervals, the discussion advocates for a graph theory-based model that focuses on the average width of the DAG. By targeting a specific number of parent blocks, this model seeks to regulate the orphan rate effectively, offering a fresh perspective on balancing network security and miner fairness. The exploration of different algorithms' responses to changes in hashrate and latency highlights the trade-offs between computational efficiency and adaptability, presenting the Simple Moving Average (SMA) and Nb/Nc method as notable contenders in achieving optimal network conditions.

Lastly, the document sheds light on the broader implications of adopting a DAG-based consensus mechanism, comparing it to the Avalanche protocol in terms of how both manage waste to secure decentralization. This analysis provides insights into the inherent costs associated with distributed security, pointing towards a future where efficiency, security, and decentralization are more closely aligned. Through a combination of theoretical exploration and practical application, the discussions encapsulate the evolving landscape of blockchain technology and the continuous pursuit of more scalable, secure, and efficient consensus algorithms.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T23:43:19.353000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
