<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
  <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:44.468393+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode 2024-12-13 18:42:55.375000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2024-12-13 15:28:09.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QbitsCode 2024-12-13 10:57:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3772_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3771_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3770_Implemented-Post-Quantum-Cryptography-PQC-Feature-into-Bitcoin-Core-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Implemented Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) Feature into Bitcoin Core!</title>
    <updated>2024-12-14T02:25:44.468437+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/implemented-post-quantum-cryptography-pqc-feature-into-bitcoin-core/1320" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse revolves around the integration and significance of Post-Quantum Cryptography (PQC) in Bitcoin to counteract the threats posed by the advancement of quantum computing. A specific focus is placed on two distinct groups of algorithms selected for their complementary roles in enhancing Bitcoin's security. Group 1, consisting of SPHINCS+, CRYSTALS-Dilithium, FALCON, and SQIsign, is identified for its strength in digital signature algorithms, which is crucial should Bitcoin require encrypted communications, such as between wallets or nodes. This group aligns with the protective measures proposed by BIP's P2QRH. On the other hand, Group 2, featuring Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU, does not pertain to digital signatures but rather complements Group 1's functionalities, collectively ensuring that Bitcoin's cryptography remains quantum-safe and resistant.

An inquiry into how these new signature algorithms would be operationalized raises questions about potential changes to address types and compliance with the P2QRH BIP. The selection of algorithms mirrors those specified by the BIP, indicating a strategic alignment but also leaving room for clarification on implementation specifics.

A proposed feature aimed at permanently safeguarding Bitcoin against quantum-related vulnerabilities has been introduced, calling for consensus among Bitcoin developers and adherence to BIP requirements. This feature incorporates core PQC algorithms—Kyber, FrodoKEM, and NTRU—into Bitcoin Core, alongside a hybrid key management system, enabled PQC transaction signing, and flexible configuration options. The proposal is detailed within a GitHub repository ([GitHub Repository](https://github.com/QBlockQ/pqc-bitcoin)), highlighting the urgency of addressing quantum computing advancements, exemplified by the recent announcement of the Williow chip, capable of factoring large semiprimes. The initiative underscores a proactive approach to maintaining Bitcoin's security against future quantum computing capabilities, leveraging expert knowledge in the field.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-13T18:42:55.375000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
