<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:51.413390+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2023-10-04 12:01:36.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:51.413418+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bsst-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes/137" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A developer shared their recent project of creating a plugin for the `CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` opcode to explore the ease of adding new complex opcodes to B'SST and identify any API limitations. The choice of opcode was based on its complexity and the availability of scripts using it from the [mattlab repository](https://github.com/halseth/mattlab), which were utilized for testing purposes. This endeavor revealed some issues with B'SST, suggesting that developing plugins for additional opcodes could further highlight areas for improvement.

The plugin developed is accessible at [this GitHub gist](https://gist.github.com/dgpv/8e8e8f5fe12a9fae3133da9bd172c925), providing a practical example of how to work with `CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` within the B'SST framework. The developer encourages others interested in experimenting with different opcodes within B'SST to share their preferred opcodes and links to reference implementations. This approach not only facilitates the creation of more plugins by providing essential information on opcode constraints but also contributes to a collaborative effort in refining B'SST. The call for community involvement underscores the importance of accessible reference implementations for successful plugin development, highlighting the developer's openness to further contributions in this evolving area.</summary>
    <published>2023-10-04T12:01:36.929000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
