<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Draft BIP for OP_TXHASH and OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY</title>
  <updated>2024-09-26T03:20:35.626516+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode.362000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-10-09T20:14:58.362000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Draft BIP for OP_TXHASH and OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T03:20:35.626540+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/draft-bip-for-op-txhash-and-op-checktxhashverify/121/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal for a full TXHASH has garnered attention and prompted discussions around its potential implementation and integration with existing Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and cryptographic verification methods. A significant suggestion revolves around the possibility of making OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY serve as an upgrade path for handling non-32-byte hashes in conjunction with OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY. This approach leverages the readiness and existing codebase of BIP119, suggesting a more streamlined adoption process.

Moreover, there's speculation on whether incorporating OP_TXHASH alongside OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY would facilitate easier merging into the main codebase or prove to be more advantageous compared to introducing these operations as sighash modes for a new Tapscript key type/version. This comparison hints at the strategic considerations developers must weigh in optimizing transaction verification processes within the Bitcoin network.

The conversation further explores the technical design of OP_TXHASH, emphasizing the utility of having at least 2 bytes of flags for operational flexibility. The proposition includes reserving 1-byte flags for specific pre-determined modes that could align with those used in Template Key, thereby creating a cohesive system across different verification mechanisms. Such a system would accommodate various hash lengths and signature sizes while maintaining a unified approach to hash modes and flags, showcasing a thoughtful consideration of future scalability and interoperability within the Bitcoin protocol infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2023-10-09T20:14:58.362000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
