<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
  <updated>2024-09-10T03:11:00.524183+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-10-10 15:18:02.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
    <updated>2024-09-10T03:11:00.524216+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/covenant-tools-softfork/98/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical aspects of implementing and modifying certain policies within Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and the Basis of Lightning Technology (BOLT), specifically focusing on the concepts of pinning and ln-symmetry in relation to consensus changes. The author argues that modifications to the pinning mechanism and the implementation of ln-symmetry do not necessitate changes at the consensus level, similar to how ln-penalty operates within the network's framework. 

There is a proposition that policy amendments, as outlined in BOLT/BIP documentation, could achieve the desired outcomes without requiring consensus alterations. However, there's an acknowledgment that modifying BIP118 to include commitments to the number of inputs or other similar parameters could simplify the process, suggesting that while not strictly necessary, consensus changes could potentially enhance the efficiency or functionality of these protocols.

Furthermore, the author highlights ongoing efforts toward enabling package relay—a feature that would improve transaction bundling and handling—indicating a continuous development focus beyond the immediate discussion of consensus and policy adjustments. This aspect underscores the multifaceted approach to evolving Bitcoin's technological infrastructure, balancing between optimizing existing features and introducing new capabilities to bolster the network's robustness and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2023-10-10T15:18:02.223000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
