<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:37.901933+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2023-10-13 13:15:11.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:37.901964+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bsst-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes/137/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Analyzing non-static arguments for commands like `ROLL` and `PICK` in programming involves a complex process that might not always be practical. The idea of allowing for dynamic analysis by setting an upper limit on the argument values to generate multiple execution paths presents both opportunities and challenges. For each possible value of the argument, a unique execution path must be analyzed and then presented in a report as separate branches, each labeled with conditions corresponding to specific argument values. However, this approach has limitations, especially when the actual argument value exceeds the predefined limit, leading to incomplete analysis. To address this, reports could include warnings indicating that the analysis for `PICK` or `ROLL` commands with non-static arguments might be incomplete if the argument exceeds the set limit.

This method, while potentially useful, introduces complexity, particularly in terms of managing the sheer number of execution paths that might result from numerous places within a script using non-static arguments for these commands. The need for setting an upper threshold for the number of execution paths is suggested to prevent overwhelming the analysis process. This discussion opens up inquiries about the practicality of scripts that utilize non-static arguments for `PICK` or `ROLL`, hinting at the necessity for examples of practical scripts to better understand the feasibility and utility of pursuing such an analytical approach.</summary>
    <published>2023-10-13T13:15:11.468000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
