<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:28.582815+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.949000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-10-14T04:13:53.949000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T03:16:28.582847+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bsst-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes/137/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the practical applications of scripts with non-static arguments for `PICK` or `ROLL` reveals a challenge when interacting with Bitcoin Improvement Proposals, notably [`OP_VAULT`](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1421). This specific proposal introduces complexity by removing `n+5` elements from the stack, including a critical element, `n`, which dictates the number of items to be manipulated. The essence of this operation is to enable dynamic duplication of items within the stack, a task that encounters limitations without an opcode like `OP_VAULT`. Traditional approaches, such as utilizing all but one stack element or leveraging constant element consumption opcodes, render `n` virtually static, thereby restricting dynamic operations.

In the absence of `OP_VAULT`, alternatives are considerably constrained, especially within the context of tapscript where options like `CHECKMULTISIG` are not viable. A proposed workaround involves defining a range for `$n` (e.g., `[1,2,3,4,5]`) and employing a conditional verification method akin to `DUP 3 NUMEQUALVERIFY` ahead of executing `ROLL` or `PICK`. This approach, albeit feasible, shifts the computational burden onto the user, necessitating repeated analysis iterations to manage the combinatorial complexity inherent in these operations.

Ultimately, to circumvent these limitations, a reevaluation of the initial problem or query might be necessary. By reframing the question, it is possible to sidestep the inherent complexities associated with dynamic stack manipulation in the current scripting environment, thus offering a pragmatic albeit indirect solution to achieving the desired operational outcome.</summary>
    <published>2023-10-14T04:13:53.949000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
