<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T03:17:06.395284+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  . 2023-11-29 10:17:51.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2023-10-14 05:56:55.663000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-10-14 04:13:53.949000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2023-10-13 13:15:11.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-10-13 11:00:24.873000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2023-10-04 12:01:36.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/497_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2023/313_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2023/312_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2023/311_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2023/310_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2023/279_B-SST-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - B'SST plugins for covenant opcodes</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T03:17:06.395341+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bsst-plugins-for-covenant-opcodes/137/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent advancements in the bsst plugin system have introduced a new method for initiating plugins, marking a significant shift from previous practices. Users are now required to use a specific command, `./bsst-cli --plugins=plugins/op_checkcontractverify_bsst_plugin.py`, to run referenced plugins. This change aligns with the introduction of an enhanced `CAT` opcode functionality, which can be activated with the `--explicitly-enabled-opcodes=CAT` flag. These developments underscore the evolving nature of the bsst system, aiming to improve user interaction and system capabilities.

A notable discussion has emerged around the potential for analyzing scripts that utilize non-static arguments for `ROLL` or `PICK`. The complexity of such analysis is acknowledged, given that each possible value necessitates its own execution path, potentially leading to a vast number of paths for analysis. This scenario illustrates the challenges inherent in extending the bsst's analytical capabilities, particularly when dealing with opcodes that impose dynamic conditions on script execution. The possibility of setting an upper limit on variable values was suggested as a means to manage this complexity, albeit with the caveat that it might render the analysis incomplete for cases exceeding this threshold.

In an effort to explore the practical application and expand the functionality of the bsst, a plugin for the `CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` opcode was developed. This initiative was partly motivated by the desire to understand how the system could accommodate complex new opcodes and to identify any limitations within the current API. The development process revealed certain areas for improvement within the bsst system, suggesting that further plugin development could uncover additional opportunities for enhancement. The `CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` plugin serves as an example of how community contributions can facilitate the exploration of new opcodes and potentially lead to broader system improvements.

The exchange of ideas and contributions, such as the creation of the `CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` plugin and the proposal for improved opcode analysis, highlights the collaborative efforts within the community to enhance the bsst's capabilities. By addressing the challenges associated with dynamic argument analysis and expanding the range of supported opcodes, the bsst project continues to evolve, reflecting the ongoing dialogue among its users and contributors.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-29T10:17:51.698000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
