<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>0.3.24</title>
  <updated>2023-05-15T17:18:36.176479+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>0.3.24</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T17:18:36.176479+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000100.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a forum poll, a user expressed concern over the decision of whether or not to enable UPnP (universal plug and play) for Bitcoin. The poll showed an equal number of votes for "off" and "some form of on." Despite their own personal dislike of UPnP, the user felt that it should be enabled due to the potential harm of leaving it off. However, they questioned the use of a forum poll to make such decisions.The user also noted confusion between Bitcoin and bitcoind and suggested enabling UPnP only for the GUI as sufficient for network health. They speculated that most bitcoind users do not install the UPnP library anyway. The user also expressed concern over Bitcoin's default listening port and suggested that UPnP should be used to work behind NATs as well as listened to, but said that listening itself is more interesting than UPnP. They also raised concern about IRC connections and their security implications.Another user agreed with the first user and stated that UPnP is bad for individual users but good for the overall network. They suggested that someone will need to make the tough decision to turn it on despite potential backlash from users. However, they acknowledged that users who do not like it can still disable listening.Finally, the second user proposed an incentive structure to encourage listening, faster transaction processing, and earlier block notifications while reducing the effectiveness of DOS attacks. However, they noted that this was not something to be implemented in the near future.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-01T17:59:47+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
