<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Version bytes</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:42:51.396404+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Version bytes</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:42:51.396404+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000144.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>There was a discussion on IRC about standardizing the version bytes used by Bitcoin for various applications. Three components were identified to be meaningful, namely network (realnet, testnet, alternate chains), data class (address, private key, master key, etc.), and version (real version, per data class defined). While there is no technical reason why different networks and data classes would need separate version bytes, it is considered a good thing to keep them from colliding. To this end, bit 16 in the version byte is reserved for "alternate chain". When bit 16 is set, everything is up to the network itself, and no further semantics are defined. When bit 16 isn't set, testnet uses bit 1, and if bit 1 is set, XOR the rest of the version number with 111. Otherwise, odd=testnet, even=realnet. The remaining six bits (128,64,32 and 8,4,2) are used for data classes and versions. Data class 128 is used for private keys, while 224 defines an extended data class, in which another "data class" byte follows. Bit 16 defines "private", with 0 indicating bitcoin and 16 indicating alternate chain. Bit 1 defines testnet, with 0 indicating realnet and 1 indicating testnet. This discussion started when Stefan wanted to define a format for master keys from which to derive deterministic wallet keys. It was suggested to use data class 192 for that purpose, leaving lower numbers for more basic data like public keys.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-07T11:15:58+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
