<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2023-05-15T17:24:25.011823+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T17:24:25.011823+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000131.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The context is a conversation between Gavin Andresen and another individual regarding Bitcoin wallet security concerns. The individual responds off-list and mentions the concern of an attacker packing the keypool with known keypairs, relying on users to click "OK". Gavin clarifies that if the keys are loaded but not added to mapAddressBook or setKeyPool, they will not be used for new transactions or shown to the user, though the user can still receive Bitcoins to those keys. They discuss issues with backup scripts, where most backupwallet-based scripts will encrypt and upload wallet.dat, which would break if wallet.dat is renamed. A suggestion is made for wallet encryption to create a wallet_e.dat and truncate wallet.dat so that old versions of Bitcoin fail to read it. They also discuss future-proofing the wallet by adding a nMinVersion that specifies a minimum version required to read the file, so that future wallet upgrades give a reasonable message if someone tries to downgrade after an incompatible change. Though there are concerns about older versions of the wallet freaking out if they see keys they don't know about, nMinVersion works just as well. The individual closes by asking how often the wallet format will change, indicating that this should only very rarely be a problem.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-04T20:39:32+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
