<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Version bytes</title>
  <updated>2023-05-15T17:26:04.689111+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Version bytes</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T17:26:04.689111+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000144.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>After a discussion on IRC, the Bitcoin community decided to standardize the version bytes used for different applications. The three significant components of the new system are network, data class, and version number. Although there is no technical reason for different networks or data classes to have separate version bytes, it is essential to prevent them from colliding and causing confusion for users. To begin with, bit 16 in the version byte will be reserved for an alternate chain, such as Namecoin that currently uses version byte 52 for addresses. When bit 16 is set, the network itself can decide what everything means without further semantics. For cases where bit 16 isn't set, the rest of the network will use six bits, namely 128, 64, 32, and 8, 4, and 2.The testnet already uses version 111, which is not a single bit. Therefore, bit 1 will be used for testnet, and if bit 1 is set, XOR the remaining part of the version number with 111. Alternatively, they could reset testnet by changing its addresses slightly and state that odd numbers represent testnet while even numbers represent realnet. The remaining six bits of the version byte are divided into two groups: (128, 64, 32) for data classes and (8, 4, 2) for versions. Data class 0 represents addresses, while private keys are represented by data class 128. Bit 16 defines privacy, with 0 representing Bitcoin and 16 indicating an alternate chain. Bit 1 defines testnet, where 0 represents realnet and 1 represents testnet.The discussion started when Stefan wanted to define a format for master keys to derive deterministic wallet keys. Pieter suggests using data class 192 for that purpose, leaving the lower numbers for more basic data, like public keys. The standardization of version bytes will prevent confusion and ensure proper functioning of different applications in the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-07T11:15:58+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
