<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
  <updated>2023-05-11T16:02:35.066037+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T16:02:35.066037+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000217.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The pull request 349 on the GitHub repository for Bitcoin implements a multiple signature escrowed transaction. The feature has been tested on a private network and appears to work well. However, it needs more testing and discussion before being added to the client. The implementation requires a new transaction type, which won't be deployable until an updated isStandard is widely used in the network. Therefore, it is recommended to separate the IsStandard part of the patch and get it out in version 0.4. The patch also exposes an issue with multisig validation due to redundancy in script length coding opcodes that allow coding a script multiple ways. One candidate fix is to exclude the length opcodes from the comparison, but it carries a risk of creating differences in how nodes validate transactions leading to lasting forks. Another fix would be to define that OP_PUSHDATA* cannot be used to push smaller lengths that could be more efficiently encoded with direct length opcodes. This would have the benefit of being consistent with current behavior and carry no severe split risk. Another way of fixing this would be to change how the templating code works to make sure it codes the template the same way the original was coded.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-23T23:39:13+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
