<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - 0.3.24</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:38:03.832843+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-01 00:07:18</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-02 01:12:51</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-01 17:59:47</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-01 17:50:40</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-07-01 08:00:43</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-01 02:07:50</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-03 01:58:40</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-02 00:51:12</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-02 00:46:18</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-01 22:03:37</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-01 12:40:16</name>
  </author>
  <link href="July_2011/000082_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000109_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000100_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000098_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000086_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000083_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000124_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000107_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000106_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000102_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000089_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - 0.3.24</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:38:03.833849+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000082.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin developers are considering a 0.3.24 release due to flood control limits becoming an issue again. The release will include sipa's flood limit fix, dnsseed on by default, and possibly UPnP enabled by default as well. A DNSSeed has been set up with reliable hosting which dynamically fills its hostname with random nodes known to be up and accepting connections. This was added to master in 44d16327. Since it is no longer a static list, it is now time to enable dnsseed by default. Additionally, enabling UPnP by default would increase the percentage of nodes that accept incoming connections. Bitcoin developers believe this is necessary for network stability over the next 90 days.
The discussion revolves around the release of Bitcoin 0.3.24, which is intended to address flood control limits, DNS seed on by default and UPnP enabled by default. The flood control fix aims to improve bring-ups and prevent network partitioning caused by frequent flood disconnects. DNS seed has been enabled for a while, and there is no reason not to turn it on now. However, UPnP should be disabled by default on bitcoind but on by default on bitcoin. There is also a request to update the checkpoint in 0.3.24 since the difficulty has increased almost 17x since the highest one currently in there. Besides, some technical issues need fixing before release concerning build engineering. The release of 0.3.24 is seen as a minor update release, with most people testing either 0.3.23 or upstream git.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-01T00:07:18+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
