<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:41:59.716373+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-04 17:52:53</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-05 01:10:39</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-04 22:30:12</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-04 20:59:07</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-07-10 19:10:07</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-05 11:03:15</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-04 20:39:32</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-10 14:21:17</name>
  </author>
  <link href="July_2011/000129_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000135_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000134_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000132_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000163_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000138_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000131_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000161_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:41:59.716373+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000129.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>There are backward-compatibility issues with Wallet encryption in Bitcoin, as pointed out by Joric. In version 0.3.23, Bitcoin dies with "ReserveKeyFromKeyPool() : unknown key in key pool" after writing one unencrypted private key to the (otherwise) encrypted wallet. In version 0.3.22, Bitcoin opens fine and displays transactions, however, shows a total balance of what is held only in unencrypted keys. Two options were suggested to work around this: renaming wallet.dat for encrypted wallets, which could cause issues with backup scripts and old clients creating new wallets instead of using the old one; or doing nothing and letting old clients become unable to use their wallet. The latter option was preferred, with comments suggesting that error messages are better than users believing their coins are gone. To prevent this issue in the future, it was suggested that Bitcoin should not continue on as if nothing had happened when faced with unknown keys. There were two proposed solutions, and agreement needed to be reached so that 0.3.24 could be released as soon as possible.
The context discusses the intentional breaking of unsafe or badly designed backup mechanisms during the planned merging of import/export. Gavin Andresen proposed creating an encrypted wallet file, wallet_e.dat, on wallet encryption, truncating the original wallet.dat, and setting its file permissions to 000 to prevent old versions of Bitcoin or any dumb wallet backup scripts from reading it. However, renaming the file could cause issues with user restores, so Pieter suggested adding a nMinVersion that specifies the minimum version required to read the file. Matt Corallo found a data structure in wallet settings that could cause all versions since Bitcoin was in Github to crash on load, making a new wallet or opening in some bizarre half-state. He put an empty object in addrIncoming to cause this effect. This solution resolved all known issues and suggestions on newenc, except for the invalid mlock calculations, which he intended to fix.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-04T17:52:53+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
