<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - 0.3.24</title>
  <updated>2023-05-11T15:55:22.844320+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <link href="July_2011/000082_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000109_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000100_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000098_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000086_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000083_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000124_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000107_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000106_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000102_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000089_0-3-24.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - 0.3.24</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T15:55:22.844320+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000082.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Due to flood control limits becoming an issue, there is a need for a 0.3.24 release. The release will include sipa's flood limit fix, dnsseed on by default, and possibly UPnP enabled by default as well. DNS seed has been set up with reliable hosting which dynamically fills its hostname with random nodes known to be up and accepting connections. It was added to master in 44d16327. Now that it's no longer a static list, it's time to enable dnsseed by default. The idea behind enabling UPnP by default is to increase the percentage of nodes that accept incoming connections. Additionally, the commit 3a3eabb57ae41dd2162ca8230423abf4a90ef644 should be included to fix the no-connections-up segfault. There were concerns regarding testing fixes in pull 358. A bug was found where it no longer opened when the ~/.bitcoin folder was empty/not present. A vote was taken on the forum to decide if UPnP should be enabled or not, but many members felt it should not have been a vote at all. Some people are concerned about security issues with UPnP, but others feel that it is necessary to ensure network stability over the next 90 days.
The developers of Bitcoin are discussing the need for an emergency release 0.3.24 due to flood control limits and partitioning issues. They propose Sipa's flood limit fix, dnsseed enabled by default, and possibly UPnP enabled by default as well which would depend on the ability to accept incoming connections, stating that there is no public outcry against these programs automatically opening holes in firewalls. They agree that it should be clearly explained in the release notes though. Additionally, they discuss the need for more listening nodes, commenting that if current growth continues they will run out of sockets in a little over a month. They suggest updating the checkpoint in 0.3.24 since difficulty has increased almost 17x since the highest one currently in there. There is also a discussion about whether to cherry-pick the release or release upstream git + some specific fixes not yet in git. The consensus is that 0.3.23 should be released with select fixes along with dnsseed on, block send, segfault bugfix. UPnP should be enabled on Windows/Mac but remain off-by-default on Linux. Another blockchain checkpoint is suggested as a good idea.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-01T00:07:18+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
