<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
  <updated>2023-05-15T18:54:33.155448+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-08-04 20:35:53</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-23 23:39:13</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000298_Discussion-related-to-pull-349-and-pull-319-escrow-transactions-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000217_Discussion-related-to-pull-349-and-pull-319-escrow-transactions-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T18:54:33.155448+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-August/000298.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an email conversation from August 3, 2011, the topic of implementing multiple signature escrowed transactions was discussed. Pull 349 on Github contained a candidate fix for a problem with multisig validation that exposed an issue with redundancy in script length coding opcodes. The fix suggested excluding the length opcodes from the comparison but carried a risk of creating differences in how nodes validate transactions leading to lasting forks. Another solution proposed was defining that OP_PUSHDATA* cannot be used to push the smaller lengths which could be more efficiently encoded with the direct length opcodes. A third way was to change the templating code to make sure it codes the template the same way the original was coded. The discussion highlighted the need for testing and further discussion before implementation, especially since the new transaction type required an updated isStandard version. One suggestion was to split pull 319 into two pull requests - one for the IsStandard change and another for the full escrow feature set. This would ensure that when the escrow patch entered the mainline client, it would meet up with a network that could handle its transactions. The IsStandard part was deemed uncontroversial and could be added quickly.</summary>
    <published>2011-08-04T20:35:53+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
