<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2023-05-11T15:58:22.342747+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <link href="July_2011/000129_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000135_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000134_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000132_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000163_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000138_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000131_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000161_Encrypted-Wallet-Backward-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Encrypted Wallet Backward Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T15:58:22.342747+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000129.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current version of Bitcoin has backward-compatibility issues with Wallet encryption. In version 0.3.23, the error message "ReserveKeyFromKeyPool() : unknown key in key pool" appears after writing one unencrypted private key to the encrypted wallet. In version 0.3.22, Bitcoin opens and displays transactions but only shows a total balance of what is held in unencrypted keys. To work around this issue, some have suggested renaming the wallet.dat for encrypted wallets, while others propose doing nothing and letting old clients get mad. Future-proofing suggestions include adding an nMinVersion to specify a minimum version for reading files and having the older version freak out if it sees keys that it doesn't know about. There are concerns about breaking backup scripts and causing confusion for users. The priority now is to release 0.3.24 as soon as possible to address these issues.
The context discusses intentionally breaking unsafe or badly designed backup mechanisms during the import/export merge, which is seen as desirable, but silently breaking them is not. The discussion also includes a proposal to encrypt the wallet and truncate wallet.dat, making it unreadable by old versions of Bitcoin or any dumb wallet backup scripts that may try to read it. Additionally, there is a suggestion to add a version control feature that specifies the minimum version required to read the file to prevent future compatibility issues. Another solution proposed was to include an empty object in addrIncoming to cause all versions of Bitcoin to crash on load instead of opening in a half-state. The context suggests that these changes would resolve known issues and suggestions for the newenc feature.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-04T17:52:53+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
