<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Reconsider build system change?</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:39:50.803639+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-07-02 11:30:14</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-07-07 08:49:39</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-07-03 10:44:17</name>
  </author>
  <link href="July_2011/000113_Reconsider-build-system-change-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000142_Reconsider-build-system-change-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000126_Reconsider-build-system-change-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Reconsider build system change?</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:39:50.803639+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-July/000113.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on whether to use autotools or cmake as the future build system for Bitcoin began after someone submitted an autotools patch. While autotools is more standard than CMake, and because it's a shell script, there's no need to install CMake. However, the autotools stuff needs to be redone before it can be merged. CMake generates native build scripts for Make (all platforms), XCode, Visual Studio while Autoconf only does Make. In addition, CMake has a clearer syntax, and is very fast. It is supported natively in Qt Creator in the QT SDK, and is used by many other KDE/QT as well as other open source applications. Someone had already integrated a CMake build system for Bitcoin into rpcminer. Pieter Wuille expressed no preference for any particular project build system. He suggested that a build system should be easy enough to set up, allow building of the Bitcoin codebase on several Linux distros, do cross-compilation to Windows, support OSX, be easy to maintain, and not be too hard to adapt other GUIs to use it.</summary>
    <published>2011-07-02T11:30:14+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
