<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2013-January-002121</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Draft BIP for Bloom filtering</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:22:24.800399+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Jan_2013/002121_Draft-BIP-for-Bloom-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2013/002130_Draft-BIP-for-Bloom-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2013-January-002121</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Draft BIP for Bloom filtering</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:22:24.800399+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2013-January/002121.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In January 2013, Mike Hearn provided an update on the progress of bitcoinj and bitcoin-qt work. Matt had done excellent work, and after minor tweaks, all the code was expected to be in a mergeable state within a week. The remaining work included bugfixes on the bitcoinj side, adjustment of the default FP rate requested by BCJ to be 0.0001, and introduction of a new part to the filter protocol that allowed clients to control auto-expansion. With auto-expansion disabled, the FP rate adjusted and a bugfix on the bcj side, a wallet could sync using a bloom filtered chain. Although it was tight, Mike believed this work should go into 0.8 and would be much more compelling to advertise network performance for everyone. In another email, Mike updated that Matt's latest code had been tested by Andreas and seems to work correctly. After several reviews, he ACK'd the current code and requested that it be merged into 0.8. The next step would be profiling, as the performance improvement for SPV clients was not as much as anticipated, and there might be a simple bottleneck or missed optimization somewhere.</summary>
    <published>2013-01-11T03:59:11+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
