<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Combined CTV/APO into minimal TXHASH+CSFS</title>
  <updated>2025-01-27T02:17:42.127424+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.094000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..459000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..003000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..961000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob  ..813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..189000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders  ..779000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..749000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4099_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2023/180_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/142_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/140_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/139_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/136_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/135_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/134_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/133_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Combined CTV/APO into minimal TXHASH+CSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T02:17:42.127499+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/combined-ctv-apo-into-minimal-txhash-csfs/60" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers on the advancement of Bitcoin's transaction validation processes, particularly emphasizing the differentiation between hash types suitable for signature verification and those for simple comparison checks. This distinction has led to a proposal aiming to refine the implementation of ANYPREVOUT/NOINPUT hash styles, crucial for creating covenants and enabling dynamic binding capabilities within the Bitcoin protocol. The proposal advocates for a methodical approach to soft forking ANYPREVOUT and CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY, with an emphasis on developing a new hashing mode specifically designed for Tapscript version 1 keys. This would not only address the unique requirements of ANYPREVOUT but could also be extended to support CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY applications by employing a 33-byte hash to prevent misuse. The intention is to introduce a default hashing mode that differs from the current SIGHASH_DEFAULT to enhance compatibility with Tapscript version 1 keys, potentially offering byte savings in common scenarios.

The introduction of `OP_TEMPLATEHASH` is discussed as a novel mechanism to augment Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, especially in conjunction with `OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK(VERIFY)` for achieving ANYPREVOUT behavior. This concept involves generating hashes committed to various transaction elements such as version, number of outputs, and the outputs themselves, through a detailed process accommodating different input data groups. The hashing modes proposed are characterized by their selective inclusion or exclusion of certain data, facilitating a more nuanced approach to transaction validation. Such a framework aims to increase security and flexibility within the Bitcoin network by providing a comprehensive method for transaction verification.

The conversation further explores the dynamics of deleted key recursion and its implications for blockchain technology, highlighting the divergent potentials of `SIGHASH_SINGLE` and `SIGHASH_ALL` type hashes in covenant creation. It delves into the complexities of implementing protocols like Ark, suggesting limitations on incorporating broad-spectrum input-related data hashing to mitigate the risks associated with quadratic hashing. The discussion proposes excluding `SIGHASH_SINGLE`-like modes from `OP_TEMPLATEHASH` to avoid these potential issues, illustrating the community's commitment to finding balanced solutions in cryptographic practices. This active engagement is evident in the shared insights and innovative approaches towards resolving technical challenges, as showcased in a [Twitter post](https://twitter.com/brqgoo/status/1694090272009797687).

The dialogue transitions to the practical aspects of blockchain development, debating the merits of introducing new opcodes versus employing upgrade hooks for implementing changes. It critiques a suggested method for assembling sighash messages, advocating for simplicity and efficiency in script functionalities. The concept of Concrete Scriptable Functionality Sets (CSFS) is introduced, pondering its utility in unifying BIP 118 and 119 without necessitating complex scripts. This segment underscores a preference for clear and maintainable scripts over computational complexity at the layer 1 level.

Lastly, the message reflects on the intricacies of handling `OP_TXHASH` in soft fork contexts, emphasizing the importance of explicit commitment to hash types within output scripts to maintain security integrity. It revisits past discussions to extract overlooked details, advocating for continuous learning and critical analysis in system development. The blog post concludes by highlighting an updated proposal shared on the bitcoin-dev mailing list, which scrutinizes the distinctions and similarities between CTV and APO. This document is presented as a valuable resource for understanding technical developments in Bitcoin's scripting and scalability solutions, aiming to elucidate these concepts for the broader community without including any farewell statements from the original communication.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T13:47:56.094000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
