<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
  <updated>2024-01-21T02:37:29.465526+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth  . 2024-01-18 16:34:20.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob 2023-08-16 15:22:13.243000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1189_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/62_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T02:37:29.465568+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023/32/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin's intrinsic value is defined by its limited supply, transparent ledger, permissionless transactions, and ownership. Technological improvements that facilitate large block processing and honest mining could enhance Bitcoin's utility without compromising its foundational qualities.

To scale Bitcoin for 1 billion weekly users, it's suggested to employ approximately 50,000 semi-trusted off-chain entities. These could take forms such as bitcoin banks, federated sidechains like Liquid with various benefits, Chaumian ecash banks enhancing privacy, or innovative structures minimizing third-party reliance through mechanisms like coinpools or validity proof rollups.

As Bitcoin scales, users will likely depend on various off-chain services, which may interact using payment channels or atomic swaps for liquidity management. The main chain will remain vital but costly, serving as a dispute resolution and settlement layer.

The complexity of managing personal lightning nodes might deter the average user, highlighting the need for efficient auditing and custody tools to maintain security across the Bitcoin ecosystem. Additionally, contingency plans for mass withdrawals from second-layer solutions to the main chain are crucial, especially considering correlated failures. CheckTemplateVerify (CTV), proposed by Jeremy Rubin, offers an efficient exit strategy during peak congestion by decoupling fund claims from exits, potentially increasing lightning channel closures within a single block.

Bitcoin development should aim to ensure smooth transitions between layers and defend against systemic risks to preserve decentralization and scalability. In creating a scalable system akin to a checking account, around 50,000 interconnected entities may be necessary, each with different trust levels to enable fluid payments. Ensuring these entities have robust custodial patterns is key to mitigating theft and loss risks.

The `OP_VAULT` operation, detailed in its [proposed specification](https://github.com/jamesob/bips/blob/e2ff23b3f07215450e75779f7f944d24660a9d47/bip-0345.mediawiki), represents a space-efficient method for on-chain covenant enforcement, potentially aiding network congestion control. While this reflects a CISC-like computing philosophy, additional enhancements, including watchtower management and recovery processes, are needed.

Effective mempool and fee management are critical for Layer 2 protocols like Lightning. Initiatives such as BIP324 are essential for upholding Bitcoin's censorship resistance. Research into a "minimum viable coinpool" could determine if current primitives are sufficient or if new innovations are necessary.

In summary, the scalability of Bitcoin relies on establishing secure, efficient capital-managing entities, equipped with robust tools for safe operations and user capital flexibility. It also involves designing mechanisms for urgent exits to Layer 1 in emergencies and streamlining daily custodial tasks to avoid complications.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-18T16:34:20.010000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
