<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Combined CTV/APO into minimal TXHASH+CSFS</title>
  <updated>2024-08-22T03:13:17.655968+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2023-09-09 13:04:38.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2023-08-29 18:33:26.459000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2023-08-27 14:02:22.003000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2023-08-27 13:37:10.961000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob 2023-08-25 19:10:26.813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2023-08-24 17:54:26.189000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-08-24 14:44:22.779000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2023-08-23 17:50:13.749000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2023/180_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/142_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/140_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/139_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/136_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/135_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/134_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/133_Combined-CTV-APO-into-minimal-TXHASH-CSFS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Combined CTV/APO into minimal TXHASH+CSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T03:13:17.656044+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/combined-ctv-apo-into-minimal-txhash-csfs/60/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of hash-based transaction validation methods in Bitcoin has led to a nuanced understanding that different types of hashes have varied applications, especially when it comes to verifying signatures versus simple comparison checks. A new proposal is being developed to address these distinctions by introducing a unified approach to hash types that can facilitate both covenants and dynamic binding within the Bitcoin protocol. This approach considers soft forking to implement Anyprevout (APO) and CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) as they currently stand but leans towards an innovative hashing method that diverges from the existing Tapscript key signature hashing. This proposed method would involve a new Tapscript key version and potentially save space by adopting a default mode more suited to these keys, thereby addressing the awkward use of pre-signed output covenants.

Further discussions have illuminated the potential for creating covenants capable of recursion and counters, which could enable or limit various blockchain functionalities, such as Spookchains or hashrate escrow. The debates highlight concerns over enabling certain hash modes like `SIGHASH_SINGLE` due to their implications for deleted key recursion, a mechanism that some view as beneficial or detrimental depending on perspective. To mitigate issues related to quadratic hashing and to accommodate protocols like Ark, the proposal suggests limiting the inclusion of specific hash modes in transactions and refining how input-related data is hashed. 

There's a consensus among contributors that while soft forking to add new opcodes or enable new behaviors is necessary, optimizing to avoid using extra operations may not be a primary goal. The proposed `OP_TEMPLATEHASH` would take a numeric mode argument from the stack, aiming to streamline transactions without complicating script logic unnecessarily. This approach underscores a preference for concise, functional scripts over complex ones that might demand excessive computation.

The conversation also touches on the utility of CSFS (CheckSigFromStack), particularly in facilitating key delegation and possibly federations, though these applications require further exploration. The document shared ([here](https://github.com/reardencode/bips/blob/bip-template-key/bip-template-key.mediawiki)) elaborates on these ideas, presenting a detailed comparison between CTV and APO and examining their implications for Bitcoin's scripting capabilities.

In summary, this evolving dialogue among developers seeks to refine Bitcoin's transaction validation process by carefully considering the roles and functionalities of hash types, covenants, and opcode usage. By proposing adjustments to hashing methods and script execution, the contributors aim to enhance Bitcoin's scalability and flexibility while maintaining security and efficiency in transaction verification.</summary>
    <published>2023-09-09T13:04:38.002000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
