<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-02T02:55:33.601394+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-01T19:53:03.275000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T02:55:33.601435+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The refined approach to calculating the hashrate and total work over a given timespan in blockchain technology offers a more accurate measurement than previous methods. By analyzing the sum of difficulties (Ds) for N blocks, it's understood that this sum represents the work done up to the point of querying rather than just up to the most recent block's timestamp. This insight leads to a revised formula for the hashrate at any given height h in the past: \(2^{32} \times \text{sumD}(h+1 \text{ to } h+N) / \text{timespan}(h \text{ to } h+N+1)\). This formula accounts for the actual timespan covering N+1 blocks, providing a more precise calculation by avoiding the unnecessary correction factor \((N-1)/N\) that was previously applied.

This adjustment in methodology is particularly relevant when comparing competing blockchain tips. In scenarios where the last block has not yet been found but the ending time remains constant, both the hashrate and work calculations under this new method agree on the assessment of work effort between chains with varying difficulties. For example, a tip with easier difficulty is recognized as having performed 33% more work. This nuanced understanding underscores the importance of using the correct timespan in calculations to accurately reflect the amount of work done within a specific period.

Furthermore, the decision-making process for determining a leading tip benefits from this approach, as it emphasizes summing the difficulties based on current time rather than the last known timestamp. This ensures that the calculated work reflects all efforts up until the present moment, offering a more dynamic and accurate picture of a blockchain's state. Through these refinements, the evaluation of blockchain performance, especially in terms of hashrate and work done, becomes more reliable and reflective of true computational effort expended over time.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-01T19:53:03.275000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
