<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-03T02:53:02.441523+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.279000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-02T13:37:58.279000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T02:53:02.441557+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/83" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical specification of a script, `CAT DUP CSFS`, and its execution conditions concerning cryptographic operations. The primary focus is on the mechanism by which this script can be satisfied using specific stack configurations and mathematical operations.

The core of the process involves having a certain value on the stack, indicated as `` (an apparent placeholder for a specific but unstated value). The satisfaction condition for the script hinges on a mathematical relationship where `s*G = R + H(R,G,G)*G`. Here, `G` represents a generator point in elliptic curve cryptography (ECC), `R` is a point resulting from another operation, and `H` denotes a hash function applied to the components `R`, `G`, and `G`.

To compute the preimage of `R`, referred to as `r`, the equation provided simplifies the process by subtracting the hash of `R`, `G`, and `G` from `s`, yielding `r = s - H(R,G,G)`. This operation illustrates a method to reverse-engineer `R` without the necessity for private keys, relying solely on public information and the inherent properties of ECC mathematics.

This explanation underscores the innovative approach to cryptographic verification embedded in the `CAT DUP CSFS` script, emphasizing the efficiency and security facilitated by leveraging hash functions and elliptic curve math in concert. The technique outlined bypasses traditional key dependency, offering a streamlined pathway to satisfying script conditions through calculated preimages and ECC fundamentals.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-02T13:37:58.279000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
