<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-03T02:57:11.416279+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-07-02 17:18:14.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T02:57:11.416311+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain and digital ledger technologies, the integrity and synchronization of node operation are paramount. A crucial aspect of maintaining this integrity is the handling of timestamps within the transmitted blocks. Nodes presenting timestamps significantly ahead of their arrival time cannot be considered as operating correctly. Such discrepancies necessitate a stringent response, including the potential for permanent rejection unless it is proven that the receiving node's clock was inaccurately set. This measure ensures that only nodes adhering to the network's time constraints continue to participate actively in the ledger's maintenance.

Similarly, issues arise with timestamps that are far behind the current network time. While initial reactions might lean towards immediate dismissal of such data, considerations must be made for genuine delays in data propagation. In cases where delays can be substantiated, a timeout period may be instituted to accommodate verification before deciding on the appropriateness of the block's inclusion in the chain. This approach balances the need for timely data with the realities of network transmission times.

The process of Proof of Work (PoW) plays a vital role in resolving disputes over which blockchain partition accurately reflects the majority of computational effort, otherwise known as hashrate. When faced with conflicting data, especially concerning timestamps, PoW mechanisms can identify the chain segment supported by the most significant mining effort. However, the adoption of new blocks based on their timestamp's validity can introduce complexities in scenarios where network partitions or delays are genuine. The decision to switch to a new partition, despite having encountered blocks with problematic timestamps, requires careful consideration of whether the delay was an intentional manipulation tactic or a result of genuine network issues.

Furthermore, the strategy of withholding blocks—a technique known as selfish mining—exploits the timing of block release to gain an unfair advantage in mining efforts. This behavior underscores the need for robust mechanisms to discern and mitigate instances where miners may attempt to leverage future-dated timestamps for personal gain. Despite these challenges, the overarching goal remains to ensure the blockchain operates seamlessly across all nodes, maintaining both its integrity and the trust of its participants.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-02T17:18:14.414000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
