<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2025-07-04T02:51:17.801942+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.098000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-03T08:10:02.098000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2025-07-04T02:51:17.801980+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of the [simple-ctv-spacechain](https://github.com/nbd-wtf/simple-ctv-spacechain/blob/3c3c664c56aaf8069cd33bb3ba7b86b4d7e0e137/main.py) highlights a series of innovative blockchain transactions that leverage the CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) mechanism to create chains of transactions culminating in an OP_RETURN. This approach has been observed in various instances between November and December, with some chains being relatively short, starting with transactions such as those found at mempool.space's signet ([1](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/4436231f5003fe7943c4394d5c04a2b1d51fea76bb8f63f2b611bd834c0573ed), [2](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/f4e627b1d97264fad4905270f9c5b9962c0f9b1aebb818fb058043d49786caa6), [3](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/dff73d8afd0c9abdc6b7fd00e4e70371f16c295f9ca1ccd62d038d19fb9f2b1f)) and others extending slightly longer ([4](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/68f45bca9e52c76497060cbc33a8c9f33c74f578de4c40eb3eea8396e1efffb2), [5*](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/d541ccbce23f958cb475d1878a7333300cddb5d92da7b1103b0d9439da588b04), [6*](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/141d852317d3c45e34f9454dd343636f4e1b9a3ad7a6f1a1c8881d2d065b830e), through to [9](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/54e38782931bc7cf2539099b892313dae078ec64953ac2edc12146dc840a44b5)). A few of these transaction chains were not completed, suggesting potential for continuation by re-utilizing information from previous spends with the same scriptPubKey.

In December, there was a noticeable experimentation with a pattern described as `CHECKSIGVERIFY CTV DROP`, which also redundantly included the CTV hash within the witness stack as the concluding "true" value. April witnessed a unique transaction employing a pattern `IF 1 CSV DROP CTV ELSE CTV ENDIF`, marking another variation in the use of CTV mechanisms. Additionally, a range of plain `CTV` or `CTV DROP` transactions were recorded between November and April, lacking any complex logic, as exemplified by transactions listed from [[12]](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/17a4dfa811e0a44ab7370b0e4c10127816d4d65eae78b36b0102bc6d80895be0) through to [[16]](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/d508d1f6873abe6031a2ff620c7830d72e103a1593353b88ee15896f81eef827). These diverse applications of CTV reflect ongoing experimentation within the blockchain space, offering insights into how developers are leveraging and iterating on this technology to explore new kinds of transaction structures and capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-03T08:10:02.098000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
