<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-08T02:52:26.771148+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-07T10:51:28.392000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T02:52:26.771185+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse presents an intriguing analysis of network latency and its impact on block propagation within a specific computational context, focusing primarily on the phenomenon of stale blocks. The analysis begins by addressing the characterization of network delays, suggesting a novel perspective by proposing the substitution of "Fibre" with "Fibre-like" to describe the network's performance. This recharacterization supports the notion that the network can be perceived through a lens where it operates at 80% efficiency for speed and encounters a 20% slowdown, though it also acknowledges a more nuanced, continuous spectrum of performance.

Further examination reveals an attempt to understand the network's behavior in relation to stale blocks, which are blocks that were once valid but have been superseded by another block added to the blockchain. By leveraging external data from another website, the analysis uncovers that stale blocks occur at a rate of approximately one per 1277 blocks, or equivalently, one every nine days. This finding is pivotal as it translates to a hashrate-weighted propagation delay of 477 milliseconds. The critical insight here is the evaluation of whether such a delay is credible or if it suggests that larger pools might be intentionally holding back blocks to gain a competitive advantage.

This exploration is significant as it not only sheds light on the technical aspects of network performance and block propagation but also hints at broader implications for fairness and strategic behavior in the computational realm. The meticulous approach to dissecting the observed stale rate against estimated latencies offers a compelling narrative on the complexities and challenges inherent in optimizing network performance while ensuring equitable participation within the ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-07T10:51:28.392000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
