<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
  <updated>2025-07-11T02:58:16.057436+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-10T08:07:13.544000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-11T02:58:16.057472+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/understanding-and-mitigating-a-op-ctv-footgun-the-unsatisfiable-utxo/1809/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the complexities and limitations involved in committing to a single input in transaction systems, specifically highlighting the issues that arise when only the output side is considered. A significant point raised is the inability to add extra inputs once a commitment to a single input has been made, suggesting that this constraint could potentially be addressed by adopting a standardness policy. However, the efficacy of combining policy rules with replacement rules to universally solve for an arbitrary number of inputs remains an intriguing yet unresolved question.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon several problems associated with committing solely to the output side, such as the half-spend issue and malleation concerns. These issues are notably discussed within the context of BIP-119, where it's clarified that malleation primarily affects the TXID, placing it somewhat outside the current discussion scope. The half-spend problem receives acknowledgment as a valid concern, contrasting with the Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CCV) approach which avoids this issue through its cross-input amount logic.

The possibility of implementing a CTV-like opcode that limits its use to a single input is proposed as a potential solution to these challenges. This approach would necessitate some form of simple cross-input logic, aiming to mitigate the identified problems without introducing undue complexity. The conversation includes references to specific Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) to provide further insight and rationale behind these points, such as [rationale from BIP-119](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/c17a3dbcebafb6d48a8510438ab9dab58ece1add/bip-0119.mediawiki) and [CCV](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/c17a3dbcebafb6d48a8510438ab9dab58ece1add/bip-0443.mediawiki), enriching the discussion with technical details and proposals for addressing these issues within digital transaction systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-10T08:07:13.544000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
