<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-07-11T02:58:40.771094+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2025-07-10 21:18:02.242000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-11T02:58:40.771126+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse emphasizes the potential risks associated with locking cryptocurrency for an extended period, especially in light of the uncertain timeline for the development and deployment of quantum computing technology. The writer expresses skepticism towards the utility and safety of engaging in long-term coin lockup agreements, particularly those exceeding two years. This caution stems from the acknowledgment that quantum computing, while still in its nascent stages, poses a real threat to the security of currently encrypted assets. Given the unpredictability of technological advancements and the non-trivial probability that quantum computers will become operational within our lifetimes, the author advises against committing to extensive time locks on digital currencies.

Furthermore, the concern is not just theoretical; it reflects a broader apprehension regarding the fast-paced nature of technological evolution and its implications for digital asset security. The person writing does not claim expertise in quantum computing but underscores the importance of considering the potential for quantum attacks when making decisions about cryptocurrency investments. This perspective highlights a prudent approach to risk management in the context of emerging technologies, suggesting that conservatism and flexibility in investment strategies could safeguard investors from unforeseen vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-10T21:18:02.242000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
