<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-12T02:58:25.967596+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-12T00:55:02.853000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-12T02:58:25.967630+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The relationship between chain work and the lowest hash in blockchain technology is a nuanced topic that delves into statistical analysis and mathematical modeling to predict and understand how these two factors interact. The equation $\text{chain_work} = \frac{2^{256}}{2 \cdot \text{lowest_hash}}$ suggests a direct relationship wherein the chain work is inversely proportional to twice the value of the lowest hash observed in the network. This formula, while simplistic, offers an insight that the effective target for a blockchain's lifetime might be twice the lowest hash seen, thereby providing a rudimentary method for estimating chain work.

Further exploration into this topic reveals that the actual computation of chain work may significantly deviate from this simple model, with empirical evidence suggesting that the calculated chain work using this formula can be on average approximately 3.5 times higher than the actual figures, with variations ranging from twice to seven times the calculated amount. Such discrepancies highlight the challenges in accurately modeling blockchain dynamics, particularly when small numbers are involved in the calculations, leading to potentially large variances in the outcomes.

The investigation into the relationship between chain work and the lowest hash draws parallels with the principles of the exponential distribution. Through experimentation, it was found that both the expected solve time and the chain work could be modeled using exponential distribution formulas, where $D = \frac{2^{256}}{\text{lowest_hash}}$ represents the expected solve time (or the inverse of the rate parameter $\lambda$), and the probability density function (PDF) for chain work follows the form $\text{PDF}(W) = \frac{1}{D} e^{-\frac{W}{D}}$. This modeling approach yields histograms of chain work over $D$ that resemble the exponential PDF, with median values close to the natural logarithm of 2, and mean and standard deviation values approximating 1, as predicted by theory. 

In practical terms, this analytical framework implies that the true measure of a blockchain's lifetime effective hashrate and the corresponding chain work can be statistically inferred from the lowest hash, albeit with a recognition of inherent variability and unpredictability. The experiments conducted acknowledge the dynamic nature of blockchain difficulty adjustments in response to fluctuating hash rates, with solvetimes being modeled using the cumulative distribution function (CDF) of the exponential distribution to simulate real-world mining scenarios. The findings underscore the complexity of estimating chain work based solely on the lowest hash, highlighting a significant degree of variability with ratios of $D/W$ frequently observed in the range of 5 to 30 across multiple simulation runs, thus indicating the practical challenges in applying theoretical models to predict blockchain behavior accurately.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T00:55:02.853000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
