<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-07-13T03:08:04.608804+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-12T12:49:23.515000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T03:08:04.608838+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses an innovative approach to improving security and access management within a cryptographic system, specifically focusing on the use of master extended public keys (xpubs) for enhanced control over descriptors. The sender expresses dissatisfaction with the current requirement of maintaining a secret for accessing descriptors and proposes the utilization of a master xpub chain code as a potentially more effective solution. This method would enable access to all descriptors that incorporate keys derived from the specified master xpub, suggesting a streamlined approach to managing access rights.

Furthermore, the proposal questions the necessity of having a shared secret for multisig operations, instead recommending that each participant in a multisig arrangement independently create backups. These backups would be symmetrically encrypted using their own master xpub chaincode. This technique implies a move towards a more decentralized and secure method of backup encryption, which could offer each participant a higher degree of autonomy and security. By encrypting backups with the individual's master xpub chaincode, the need for a shared secret is eliminated, potentially reducing the risk of unauthorized access through compromise of a single shared secret.

Overall, the email outlines a proposition aimed at refining the security mechanisms for managing cryptographic descriptors and multisig participations. It highlights the potential benefits of leveraging master xpub chain codes for both access control and backup encryption, aiming to enhance privacy, security, and operational efficiency within these systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T12:49:23.515000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
