<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
  <updated>2025-07-13T03:05:23.767731+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-12T17:51:14.257000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T03:05:23.767769+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>This case study delves into the innovative use of Script opcodes for implementing amount locks in Bitcoin transactions, focusing on ensuring that the value of inputs and outputs adheres to specified conditions. The exploration is grounded in the development of features that facilitate the direct incorporation of amount restrictions within Script through two primary proposals. The first initiative aims to introduce 64-bit arithmetic capabilities into Script, as detailed in a [GitHub proposal](https://github.com/Christewart/bips/blob/79257ba5d7a632fa828208f266fd4f5540ffba7f/bip-XXXX.mediawiki), enhancing its computational power. The second proposal revolves around new opcodes, `OP_IN_AMOUNT` and `OP_OUT_AMOUNT`, which allow for the inspection of transaction amounts directly in the script, further elaborated in an online discussion ([delvingbitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549/3)). These innovations are pivotal in retrofitting existing opcode frameworks to support amount locks effectively.

A significant focus is placed on the [`AMOUNTVERIFY`](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/83ac8427e7f81cead035728b9c1d925aceddf0d0/bip-0119.mediawikiuser-content-OP_AMOUNTVERIFY) feature within the OP_CTV (CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) proposal, aiming to establish secure forwarding addresses. This mechanism prevents the creation of unsatisfiable UTXOs due to amount mismatches and addresses the risk of overfunded UTXOs necessitating large miner fees. The concept of a "safe" forwarding address emerges as a solution to mitigate user errors, such as sending insufficient funds to an OP_CTV-locked output. By leveraging `OP_IN_AMOUNT`, developers can design alternative script paths that facilitate fund recovery without the constraints of exact amount matches. This approach not only enables the correction of underfunding but also provides strategies to handle overfunding, ranging from simple recovery to complex multi-signature security for significant excesses.

The practical application of these concepts is illustrated through a Python test suite, offering a tangible example of how safe forwarding addresses can be implemented ([GitHub repository](https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/blob/91815443c06b64858c532821d72c4e3a2b33aa52/test/functional/feature_ctv_amount.pyL273)). The ongoing dialogue also acknowledges future challenges, such as addressing amount replay attacks, highlighting the dynamic nature of developing secure and functional enhancements in blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T17:51:14.257000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
