<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Building Secure and Watchtower-efficient Bitcoin Payment Channels with BitVMX</title>
  <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:43.170902+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>SergioDemianLerner.094000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-14T12:23:32.094000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Building Secure and Watchtower-efficient Bitcoin Payment Channels with BitVMX</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:43.170934+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/building-secure-and-watchtower-efficient-bitcoin-payment-channels-with-bitvmx/1830" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>This article explores the development of a sample Bitcoin payment channel that incorporates BitVMX to facilitate efficient state revocations and the integration of compact watchtower operations. The core feature of this payment channel is its use of BitVMX for off-chain verification of Schnorr-signed messages, which articulate state revocations. This mechanism significantly reduces the on-chain footprint by allowing for sophisticated dispute resolution processes without necessitating extensive blockchain space.

The payment channel's architecture is designed around a transaction directed acyclic graph (DAG), with transactions co-signed by the parties involved to advance states or resolve disputes. A notable innovation within this system is the introduction of one-time signatures (OTS) for state commitments, ensuring that each state update is securely anchored. The protocol includes mechanisms for unilateral channel closures and dispute initiation, wherein a party may close the channel by publishing the most recent state and triggering a dispute if necessary. This is complemented by a timer mechanism activated through preimage revelation, safeguarding against inactivity or uncooperative behavior during state transitions.

Watchtowers play a crucial role in monitoring the payment channel, receiving and storing only the latest revocation message per channel, identified by a unique monitoring ID. This represents a significant improvement over traditional Lightning Network watchtowers by eliminating the need to store a separate revocation key for every state update. Instead, the BitVMX platform verifies the logic of these revocations off-chain, enhancing both storage efficiency and security.

Furthermore, the article briefly mentions the potential addition of Hash-Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs) and points toward further enhancements like PTLCs and other new locking functions, indicating the protocol’s adaptability for more complex applications beyond simple payment channels. Through this simplified yet extensible design, the article showcases BitVMX's capabilities in creating secure, efficient, and scalable off-chain Bitcoin protocols.

For those interested in a deeper dive into the technical specifics, including the incorporation of HTLCs and an expanded discussion on the transaction DAG, the original article provides further details and can be accessed [here](https://bitvmx.org/knowledge/building-secure-and-watchtower-efficient-bitcoin-payment-channels-with-bitvmx).</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T12:23:32.094000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
