<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-15T03:06:41.114048+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-14T15:09:06.786000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T03:06:41.114078+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around BIP-360 (P2QRH), emphasizing its importance not just for its quantum resistance capabilities but also as a valuable addition to output types in the cryptocurrency space. The proposal suggests a shift in naming conventions to better communicate the security features of different outputs, particularly in the context of a post-quantum world where certain cryptographic methods may become vulnerable. The suggested name, P2QRH, stands out as it explicitly signals quantum resistance, making it distinct from other output types like P2TR, which could be susceptible to quantum attacks.

Further elaboration on naming strategies highlights the use of Segwit version 3, intentionally incorporating an 'r' to signify resistance (e.g., `bc1r..`). This mnemonic device is designed to aid users in easily remembering and identifying quantum-resistant addresses. The goal is to prevent users from mistakenly sending funds to potentially vulnerable addresses (denoted with `bc1p..`), thereby mitigating the risk of losses due to quantum computing advancements. This precaution underscores the need for clear, user-friendly labeling to help individuals navigate the complexities of address types and ensure the security of their digital assets against future threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T15:09:06.786000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
