<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Augur: Block’s Open Source Bitcoin Fee Estimation Library</title>
  <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:18.940677+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-17T21:30:12.150000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Augur: Block’s Open Source Bitcoin Fee Estimation Library</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:18.940710+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/augur-block-s-open-source-bitcoin-fee-estimation-library/1848/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process to determine Bitcoin Core versions responsible for the results from the Blockstream API involves an educated guess. The investigation into the version used by `curl https://blockstream.info/api/fee-estimates` leads to a deduction that version 27.2 might be in use, as suggested by a specific file within the [Blockstream's GitHub repository](https://github.com/Blockstream/esplora/blob/52de3ccf39c56ff839e26829ccd6d18f169832f7/contrib/Dockerfile.baseL37). This inference is based on the documentation and configuration files found within the repository. 

Further analysis indicates an expectation of improved accuracy in fee estimation in future releases, particularly from version 28.0 onwards. The anticipation of lower overestimation rates and a reduced average overestimation factor stems from enhancements introduced in newer versions, which include a switch to an "economical" default mode. This change is poised to refine the process of estimating transaction fees, making it more efficient and closer to the actual costs incurred during transactions. Such advancements are indicative of the ongoing efforts to optimize Bitcoin Core, ensuring that it remains responsive to the needs of its user base while adapting to the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T21:30:12.150000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
