<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
  <updated>2025-07-21T03:08:35.220515+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jesseposner 2025-07-20 18:33:40.534000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T03:08:35.220541+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-quantum-hd-wallets-silent-payments-key-aggregation-and-threshold-signatures/1854" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of lattice-based cryptographic structures unveils a promising foundation for the evolution of Hierarchical Deterministic (HD) wallets, stealth addresses, key aggregation, and threshold signatures. These components are essential for enhancing security and privacy in blockchain technologies, particularly in making them resilient against quantum computing threats. A significant piece of research titled "[A Secure Hierarchical Deterministic Wallet with Stealth Address from Lattices](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304397524002895?via%3Dihub)" introduces a deterministic tree that leverages basis-delegation and a static public identifier. This methodology enables any sender to generate a one-time address, ensuring transactions remain private and untraceable by third parties.

In the realm of key aggregation, the study "[Round-Optimal Secure Multisignature Schemes from Lattices with Public Key Aggregation and Signature Compression](https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-51938-4_14)" demonstrates how multiple lattice public keys can be consolidated into a single public key alongside a compressed signature. This innovation is further refined in the subsequent work, "[Efficient Multi-Signature Scheme Using Lattice](https://academic.oup.com/comjnl/article-abstract/65/9/2421/6289877?redirectedFrom=fulltext)," which proposes an even more efficient approach to multi-signature schemes utilizing lattice cryptography.

Moreover, the development of threshold signatures, akin to the FROST protocol but based on lattice foundations, is presented in "[Finally! A Compact Lattice-Based Threshold Signature](https://eprint.iacr.org/2025/872)." This research introduces a t-of-n protocol where the resulting signature maintains the same size as a single Dilithium signature, even for t ≤ 8. This feature is particularly noteworthy because it addresses one of the common challenges in threshold signature schemes: the bloating of the signature size with the number of signatories.

Collectively, these advancements indicate a substantial compatibility between lattice-based cryptographic mechanisms and the requirements set forth by current Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and other cryptographic protocols. There appears to be no fundamental obstacle preventing the integration of post-quantum primitives with existing standards such as BIP-32, BIP-352 silent payments, MuSig, or FROST. This alignment holds significant promise for the future of secure, quantum-resistant digital currency transactions and wallet technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-20T18:33:40.534000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
