<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-21T03:07:56.016745+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jesseposner.734000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-20T18:46:55.734000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T03:07:56.016783+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion raises concerns about the potential vulnerability of Bitcoin and similar cryptocurrencies to quantum computing attacks, specifically those that could exploit the cryptographic algorithms underpinning these currencies. The issue at hand is not merely whether individual holders can secure their assets through quantum-resistant measures, but rather if a substantial portion of the cryptocurrency supply remains exposed, the implications for the market could be severe. The argument suggests that in anticipation of such vulnerabilities, holders might find it prudent to convert their holdings into other assets less susceptible to these threats. This strategy hinges on the availability of alternatives that match or surpass the value proposition offered by current cryptocurrencies.

A significant point of debate is the possible introduction of a Bitcoin fork designed to mitigate these quantum vulnerabilities by disabling certain operations (DL opcodes), which could, however, be viewed unfavorably due to its implications for property rights within the digital asset ecosystem. Furthermore, the actual impact of a mass release of stolen coins into the market remains speculative. Historical resilience against various challenges might offer some reassurance that Bitcoin could weather such an event. Yet, the unpredictability of market responses and the strategic choices of potential quantum attackers add layers of uncertainty to the situation. This complexity underscores the broader challenges facing the evolution of cryptocurrencies as they navigate technological advancements and emerging threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-20T18:46:55.734000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
