<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-07-22T03:01:51.417551+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rafael</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-21T13:45:12.676000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T03:01:51.417586+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Implementing a soft fork involves changes that are backward compatible with older versions of the blockchain protocol. In this scenario, the proposed soft fork would introduce a flag that modifies the timelock parameter to be 8 times longer than its current setting. This alteration means that transactions incorporating this new flag would require a significantly extended period before they could be executed, compared to transactions under the existing rules.

A critical risk associated with not moving coins within the original 1x timelock period is highlighted. Since older nodes in the network, which have not updated to recognize the new flag, would continue to operate under the legacy rules, they might inadvertently accept and propagate transactions that attempt to spend the coins before the extended timelock expires. Consequently, there exists a possibility for miners who have not upgraded to the new protocol version to include these prematurely spent transactions in a block, thus undermining the security intended by the extended timelock.

This situation underscores the inherent challenges and potential vulnerabilities associated with implementing soft forks on blockchain networks. It serves as a reminder of the delicate balance between advancing technological improvements and ensuring network security and consensus among participants.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-21T13:45:12.676000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
