<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-22T03:01:24.031032+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman 2025-07-21 15:21:36.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T03:01:24.031071+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811/23" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence delves into the intricacies of enhancing security within Bitcoin transactions, particularly focusing on mitigating vulnerabilities against quantum attacks. The primary discussion revolves around the concept of protecting EC public keys embedded in wallet descriptors from being exploited by quantum attackers, even before an OTS (One-Time Signature) endorsement signature is publicly revealed. This approach is aimed at countering long exposure attacks on reused public keys, a prevalent concern within the cryptocurrency domain.

The proposal suggests an innovative yet straightforward mechanism to safeguard transactions without necessitating significant modifications to the existing P2QRH framework. By integrating a requirement that spending transactions must provide both a preimage and a signature that satisfy specific cryptographic conditions, it establishes an additional layer of security. This method effectively shields against long exposure attacks by ensuring that each transaction leaf possesses a unique preimage, thereby complicating unauthorized access through public key reuse.

Further expanding on potential enhancements, the conversation references a technique detailed in the document "Signing a Bitcoin Transaction with Lamport Signatures," accessible via a [Google Groups link](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/mR53go5gHIk). This approach offers a marginal improvement by employing Lamport Signatures within the P2SH (Pay to Script Hash) transactions, albeit with limitations due to operational constraints imposed by the current script execution environment, which restricts the feasible key space and thus remains susceptible to brute-force attacks.

Adam Borcany's critique underscores the necessity for a more robust OTS scheme tailored for script endorsements, suggesting the possibility of introducing this as a new script leaf version through a dedicated BIP (Bitcoin Improvement Proposal). This proposal signifies an acknowledgment of the need for a more concrete and elaborated framework to effectively counteract the specified security threats, indicating a direction for future research and development in enhancing Bitcoin's resilience against quantum computing threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-21T15:21:36.411000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
