<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
  <updated>2025-07-23T03:04:01.979660+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sanket1729.563000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-22T18:55:36.563000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T03:04:01.979689+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-quantum-hd-wallets-silent-payments-key-aggregation-and-threshold-signatures/1854/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the potential of post-quantum (PQ) cryptography technologies, it's crucial to evaluate their advantages and drawbacks in comparison to current standards such as ECDSA. One notable discovery is the efficiency improvement offered by schemes like Musig/Frost, which require only a single round of signing instead of the two rounds needed by their ECDSA counterparts. This significant reduction in the number of rounds represents a leap forward in making cryptographic protocols more efficient and potentially more attractive for implementation.

The evaluation process involves a detailed comparison between various PQ schemes and existing ECDSA options, focusing on practicality and performance enhancements. The goal is to identify whether these new technologies not only match but surpass the capabilities of current cryptographic solutions. By scrutinizing each scheme's unique characteristics, one can ascertain their suitability for broader adoption in securing communications against the looming threat of quantum computing.

This comprehensive analysis aims to unearth post-quantum cryptographic solutions that are not just theoretically secure but also practical for real-world applications. Identifying such technologies is vital for the future of cybersecurity, ensuring that our digital infrastructure remains impervious to both contemporary and forthcoming threats. Through meticulous research and comparison, the endeavor is to spotlight those post-quantum schemes that promise to offer a seamless transition from traditional to quantum-resistant cryptography, marking a milestone in the evolution of digital security protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-22T18:55:36.563000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
