<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disclosure: LND gossip_timestamp_filter DoS</title>
  <updated>2025-07-23T03:04:24.630436+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Crypt-iQ.805000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-22T20:39:23.805000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disclosure: LND gossip_timestamp_filter DoS</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T03:04:24.630464+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-lnd-gossip-timestamp-filter-dos/1859/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email highlights a recent development in the field of network security, specifically addressing an incident related to the Lightning Network. The core of the message is about an unsuccessful attempt to mitigate a stealth attack on this network. This attempt was documented in a commit on GitHub, which can be reviewed [here](https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lnd/pull/8030/commits/a242ad5acb6b46e82ef839be84b0695b2de089a7diff-5321d5dad7ab003eff5e595aef273619fd9c22586f28f1b141940932b93c6ec7). The crux of the matter lies in the method attempted for mitigation, which was found to be ineffective because it could easily be circumvented by attackers using multiple node IDs.

Further into the details, the sender of the email takes personal responsibility for the flaw in the mitigation strategy, despite what the commit attribution might suggest. This acknowledgment indicates a level of transparency and accountability often expected within the programming and open-source communities. Such interactions not only shed light on the ongoing challenges faced by developers in securing networks but also illustrate the collaborative and iterative process of developing and refining technology solutions. Through such candid sharing of experiences and setbacks, the community as a whole can learn and advance more effectively.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-22T20:39:23.805000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
