<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-27T03:12:18.415820+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-26T23:45:02.647000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-27T03:12:18.415854+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed fork of Bitcoin aims to address the issue of money centralization by ensuring that only one wallet can be created per physical entity, verified through a national identity number (NIN) like the US's SSN or Mexico's CURP. This approach seeks to verify the existence of the individual as a living, conscious being who has not been registered as deceased. It also suggests a method for institutional Bitcoins to be replicated into a personal wallet, but with a replication limit set at a socially acceptable level, perhaps 10 to 20 times the average wealth of a global citizen. Any Bitcoins not claimed within a specified replication period, suggested to be three months, would become nonexistent in the new blockchain, hence available for mining as new Bitcoins.

This initiative is driven by the goal of reducing the disproportionate power held by a few institutions over society, which undermines democratic principles and tilts the balance towards oligarchy. By restricting the new form of Bitcoin to individuals and excluding institutions, this proposal aims to decentralize financial power and further the democratization enabled by the internet and its native tools. Furthermore, by ensuring only humans or conscious living beings can participate in this platform, it could also serve as a global equity platform.

For countries lacking a reliable NIN system, alternatives such as biometric identification (facial recognition, fingerprints, etc.) or other solutions developed in collaboration with Bitcoin community members (miners, nodes, etc.) are suggested. These methods should verify the individual's status as a conscious living being. While genome or blood tests could complement NINs, they are considered more complex and recommended for later implementation. The proposal explicitly opposes any invasive technology.

Although implementing such a system would significantly reduce the anonymity traditionally associated with Bitcoin, it is seen as a positive step towards combating inequality and corruption within this new blockchain framework. This shift could allow for the broader use of these tools for the common good, aligning with the original spirit of democratization that the internet and digital currencies promise. The full discussion and proposal details were initially posted on GitHub but were redirected due to the forum's guidelines ([original post](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/32897?reload=1?reload=1)).</summary>
    <published>2025-07-26T23:45:02.647000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
