<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:11.378758+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary.024000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-28T13:48:08.024000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:11.378790+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of fungibility is crucial in understanding certain critiques surrounding digital currency and internet usage proposals. Fungibility refers to the interchangeability of a unit of asset with other units of the same asset. This characteristic is foundational in the valuation and utility of currencies like Bitcoin. The suggestion to restrict internet access exclusively to living individuals overlooks the significant and growing domain of machine-to-machine transactions, which form a substantial part of the digital economy. Bitcoin and its underlying technology offer a framework for these transactions, enabling a machine payable web. This ecosystem allows devices to transact autonomously, facilitating a more efficient and automated digital landscape.

Exploring the notion of limiting internet use raises questions about the practicality and justification behind such restrictions. The internet, by design, is a decentralized network that supports a wide range of applications, including those that operate independently of human intervention. The integration of blockchain technology and cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin has further expanded the internet's utility, establishing a secure and transparent mechanism for machines to interact financially. This development underscores the importance of considering the broader implications and benefits of digital currencies and their role in supporting an interconnected, automated world.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T13:48:08.024000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
