<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
  <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:58.942770+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-28T19:16:27.695000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:58.942800+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v29-1-release-candidate-available/1881" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release candidate for Bitcoin Core, version v29.1rc1, is now available for download. Interested parties can access the binaries from [Bitcoin Core's official website](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-29.1/test.rc1/) and the source code from the project's GitHub repository under the signed tag [v29.1rc1 on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v29.1rc1). This marks an important step towards a new minor version release of Bitcoin Core.

Detailed preliminary release notes for this version have been published, providing insights into what has been changed or improved. These notes can be found through a direct link to the [release notes document](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/565af03c37d8262632543a078b2d8d29459d0b91/doc/release-notes.md), which offers comprehensive information about the updates and enhancements included in this release candidate.

Release candidates serve as critical test versions prior to the final release. They play a pivotal role in identifying and rectifying any critical problems before the official version is tagged and released. The developers encourage users to actively test this release candidate and report any issues encountered via the [GitHub issue tracker](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues) to ensure stability and functionality. Further updates regarding this release candidate or any future candidates will be provided to keep interested parties informed on the development progress.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T19:16:27.695000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
