<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-30T03:09:20.256469+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann.737000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-29T02:41:47.737000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T03:09:20.256504+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/paralel-bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of fungibility and its application to different types of entities, such as living beings versus non-living entities like institutions, machines, robots, AI's, and devices. The core argument hinges on the notion that the value of money, which is intrinsically linked to scarcity and governed by supply and demand dynamics in the market, should not be uniformly affected by inflation across these fundamentally different categories of entities. The reasoning behind this perspective is that the growth rates of living-conscious-physical-beings and other types of entities vary significantly. Therefore, it raises a philosophical and economic question about why living entities should endure the inflationary impacts primarily generated by the proliferation of non-living entities.

Another layer of this discussion questions the ethical and existential roles between living and non-living entities. It challenges the premise that living beings should serve the needs or purposes of non-living entities, suggesting that such an arrangement contradicts the fundamental reason for the Universe's existence, which is posited as the expansion of life. This standpoint emphasizes a reevaluation of our current economic and social paradigms, urging a shift towards recognizing and prioritizing the unique value and role of living consciousness within the broader universal scheme. The underlying message advocates for a reconsideration of how we assign value and manage resources in a way that respects the distinct nature and growth trajectories of living beings relative to artificial or institutional constructs, thereby ensuring that economic systems are aligned with the overarching purpose of life's expansion.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-29T02:41:47.737000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
