<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>RGB yellow paper: the formal specification of Bitcoin &amp; Lightning smart contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-08-01T03:19:40.370490+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-07-31T04:40:31.684000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>RGB yellow paper: the formal specification of Bitcoin &amp; Lightning smart contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T03:19:40.370522+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/rgb-yellow-paper-the-formal-specification-of-bitcoin-lightning-smart-contracts/1885" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The completion of the formal specification for the RGB consensus layer marks a significant milestone for the community. This document is pivotal for developers and researchers interested in understanding and contributing to the RGB project. The comprehensive nature of this specification lays down the foundation for future developments and integrations within the RGB ecosystem.

The paper detailing this specification is now available for review and can be accessed through the provided [link](https://github.com/RGB-WG/yellowpaper/blob/4c18a6ac346a4dd379766f0bf2fcc02a3ca7e722/rgb-yellowpaper.pdf). This accessibility ensures that the community can engage with the material, offering feedback, suggestions, and potentially contributing to further refinements of the consensus layer. It's an invitation for collaboration, aiming to enhance the robustness and functionality of the RGB infrastructure.

Moreover, the publication of this specification underscores the project's commitment to transparency and open-source principles. By making such critical information readily available, it fosters an environment of shared knowledge and collective advancement. The document serves not only as a technical guide but also as a testament to the collaborative spirit that drives the RGB project forward.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-31T04:40:31.684000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
