<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-16T03:05:28.800243+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-07-15 15:35:18.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-15 15:09:55.489000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman 2025-07-15 14:48:49.506000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky 2025-07-15 11:19:21.847000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-15 01:13:12.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:05:51.271000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:03:39.361000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:55:06.554000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:30:49.131000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 19:35:52.115000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 18:26:10.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 15:09:06.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 09:31:50.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-07 16:01:15.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5485_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5484_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5482_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5479_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5471_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5467_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5466_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5465_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5464_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5460_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5459_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5458_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5450_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5412_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T03:05:28.800344+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion explores several facets of Bitcoin's technological advancements and proposals, focusing primarily on quantum resistance and the optimization of transaction structures within the cryptocurrency's ecosystem. A significant portion of the conversation delves into the potential modification of Bitcoin's Taproot upgrade to include features that simplify user transactions by reducing the need for change outputs, potentially lowering transaction costs but raising concerns about privacy implications. The critique against such modifications emphasizes that privacy should not be compromised for cost-saving measures, advocating for the maintenance of Taproot's original goal to enhance privacy without imposing additional costs on users.

Further discourse highlights a proposed simplification in the Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) through the introduction of pay-to-taproot (p2tr) primitives. This proposal has garnered attention for its potential to streamline Bitcoin's infrastructure, though it faces challenges related to comprehensive review and consensus within the community. The technical discussion extends to comparing P2TR and P2QRH for blockchain transactions, with an emphasis on optimizing transaction size and facilitating smart contract composition. The dialogue suggests a preference for P2QRH in scenarios prioritizing compact transaction sizes and straightforward smart contract compositions, leveraging CAT and SHA methods over the more complex EC tweaking required by taproot.

An update is shared regarding a recent change implemented in the GitHub repository, inviting Steven Roose's approval for further incorporation into the BIP discussion thread. This gesture underscores the collaborative nature of development and improvement processes within the Bitcoin ecosystem.

Humorously, a programmer proposes renaming a concept to "Pay to Tap Script Hash" or P2TSH, aiming for a rhyming similarity with an existing protocol to facilitate approval within the community. This reveals the interpersonal dynamics and creative persuasion involved in proposing technological improvements. Concerns are raised about the naming and conceptual framing of the "pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash" proposal, critiquing its potential to miscommunicate the intended mechanics and emphasizing the importance of clear, user-friendly labeling to navigate the complexities of address types.

The conversation also touches upon the implementation of post-quantum cryptography, suggesting a shift in naming conventions to reflect the broader applicability of proposed features beyond quantum resistance. This aims to capture the multi-faceted appeal and potential usage across different ecosystem segments.

Significant advancements in BIP-360 introduce a script-only version of Taproot (P2TR), removing the quantum-vulnerable key-spend pathway to enhance resilience against quantum computing threats. The modification focuses on committing P2QRH outputs directly to the tapleaf merkle root computed by taproot, leveraging existing infrastructure for seamless integration. By eliminating taptweak steps and emphasizing script and tapleaf support, this approach simplifies implementation while enhancing protection against long-exposure attacks. Furthermore, the proposal outlines a strategic plan for Post-Quantum (PQ) signatures, allowing for independent consideration of specific PQ signature algorithms, thus ensuring the robustness and future-proofing of the Bitcoin protocol against potential quantum computing advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-15T15:35:18.444000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
