<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-02T02:51:21.517410+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2025-07-01 22:03:02.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-30 17:09:09.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-06-30 00:57:12.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-02 14:22:43.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-22 21:20:03.071000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-12 17:47:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:20:40.305000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:17:55.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-04-15 15:55:25.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5387_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5379_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5371_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5192_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5092_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4993_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4878_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4877_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4790_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-02T02:51:21.517510+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse begins by addressing the intricacies of calculating the cost of capital for routers within payment networks, specifically focusing on Lightning Network's HTLCs (Hash Time-Locked Contracts). It underscores the fallacy in assuming a simple rate of return based on transaction fees without considering the myriad costs and risks involved, such as on-chain fees, risk of fund loss, computation, and communication costs. These factors necessitate the inclusion of both Upfront and Success Fees to adequately compensate for the router's services while highlighting the unrealistic expectation of doubling capital 26 times per year from routing alone. Instead, a more realistic cost of capital at a 19% compounded annual rate of return is posited, taking into account the Hold fee that compensates for the capital held up across all nodes involved in a transaction. This comprehensive approach ensures each node stakes an amount covering the maximum cost of capital, thereby increasing the financial stake at each downstream node by a factor of ten.

In exploring the mechanics of charging hold fees during transactions, the process unfolds in three phases to secure necessary funds, culminating in the adjustment of channel states upon the resolution of the HTLC. This detailed mechanism reflects a sophisticated attempt to encapsulate the entire cost of capital, suggesting potential modifications to address various transaction scenarios more accurately. Such adaptations include fixed charges post-grace periods or nonlinear fee calculations, aiming to fine-tune the protocol's response to evolving payment landscapes, like Taproot Assets payments. Moreover, the Fee-Based Spam Reduction Protocol introduces a structured fee system comprising Upfront, Hold, and Success Fees to mitigate risks and cover costs across a 10-hop payment scenario. This model delineates the fees into components aimed at offsetting immediate expenses, compensating for temporary allocation of channel funds, and rewarding successful transaction completions. The protocol emphasizes fair compensation and efficient processing, presenting a nuanced approach to handling delayed or failed payments.

A revision in the paper version to 1.1, hosted on [GitHub](https://github.com/JohnLaw2/ln-spam-prevention), offers an expanded specification for a low-latency bug fix, enhancing the solution's effectiveness and efficiency. This update signifies a commitment to refining strategies against spam within payment channels, emphasizing ongoing improvements in tackling identified challenges. Furthermore, the proposal to mitigate jamming attacks through a collateral lock-up strategy elucidates the necessity of balancing operational costs with security measures, highlighting the importance of strategic fund allocation to protect against potential exploitation while ensuring network resilience.

The correspondence also delves into advanced protocols for managing Hold Fees for HTLCs, proposing a two-step update process that addresses the complexities of fee handling and transaction security. This solution aims to streamline the process, mitigating vulnerabilities to exploitation by requiring precise coordination between transaction parties. Additionally, the discussion extends to theoretical vulnerabilities where nodes could be manipulated into incurring unwarranted fees, showcasing the nuanced risks within payment channel operations and the critical need for robust mitigation strategies.

In summary, the emails encompass a deep dive into the economic and operational frameworks governing cryptocurrency payment networks, particularly the Lightning Network. They reveal a layered approach to fee structuring, risk management, and spam prevention, aiming to enhance network efficiency, fairness, and security. Through continuous refinement and adaptation, these discussions contribute significantly to the development of more resilient and equitable blockchain-based payment systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-01T22:03:02.578000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
