<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-29T03:13:32.113685+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2025-07-28 16:29:21.158000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-07-28 15:55:10.451000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2025-07-28 12:27:54.293000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-07-28 10:56:09.658000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2025-07-28 10:43:29.539000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-05-23 17:25:01.983000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob  . 2025-05-23 16:20:44.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-05-23 15:45:07.582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob  . 2025-05-23 15:18:47.518000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-05-21 00:06:44.757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2025-05-17 21:36:35.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5582_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5581_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5579_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5578_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5577_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5106_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5102_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5101_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5100_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5064_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5025_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T03:13:32.113768+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion encompasses the nuanced debate surrounding the implementation of covenants in blockchain technology, particularly in contrast to multisignature (multisig) agreements and pre-signed transactions. Covenants are portrayed as offering specialized functionality for transaction protocols, yet many of their advantages could be mirrored through multisig arrangements paired with oracle systems. However, this emulation approach might lead to trade-offs, such as increased security risks for users seeking to utilize covenants for honest purposes. The conversation advocates for a thorough evaluation of covenants' unique benefits, highlighting their experimental nature within the blockchain community and the substantial interest they have garnered.

Furthermore, the origins and applications of CheckLockTimeVerify (CLTV) are explored, underscoring its pivotal role in Bitcoin's technical evolution and its significant contribution to the development of payment channels and the Lightning Network. The narrative emphasizes CLTV’s utility beyond its initial scope, supporting the broader functionalities of Bitcoin and indicating a forward-looking approach by the Bitcoin development community towards leveraging technological advancements like CLTV for expansive applications.

The dialogue shifts to address interpersonal communication dynamics within the community, particularly focusing on discussions around vaults. It suggests a negative impact on the individual's reputation due to a persistent focus on vaults, recommending a more constructive engagement with contentious or complex topics. This advice underlines the importance of fostering a positive discourse, which is essential when navigating intricate discussions within the community.

Moreover, there's an exploration of the critique against requiring innovations to first prove their necessity through emulation, using the Lightning Network's reliance on `CLTV`/`CSV` as a case study. The argument highlights how certain applications, like vaults, may not reach their full potential without direct changes to consensus mechanisms. This portion of the discussion points to the demand for consensus-driven solutions and the need for straightforward soft fork proposals that can meet market needs effectively.

Lastly, the conversation delves into the philosophical debates surrounding "evil covenants" and the potential introduction of "perpetual KYC contracts" within Bitcoin. It challenges the outright dismissal of soft fork proposals based on their capability to facilitate restrictive covenants, arguing instead for a balanced assessment that considers both the positive and negative implications of covenants. The narrative concludes by advocating for a reflective pursuit of technological advancement within Bitcoin, emphasizing the dual-use nature of technologies and the ethical responsibilities of individuals and organizations in utilizing these advancements for promoting financial freedom and integrity.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T16:29:21.158000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
