<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-07-13T03:08:23.238128+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky 2025-07-12 12:49:23.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jdlcdl  . 2025-06-22 10:33:44.879000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-06-02 09:44:03.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-06-01 09:54:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-06-01 07:08:14.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-31 22:24:07.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-31 18:45:36.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-25 23:34:10.338000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-25 11:41:49.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-24 18:41:51.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-21 09:45:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh  . 2025-05-21 06:34:14.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5445_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5326_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5186_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5185_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5183_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5182_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5180_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5118_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5117_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5113_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5072_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5070_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T03:08:23.238275+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exchange revolves around an innovative approach to enhance the security and accessibility of cryptographic keys and descriptors within digital wallets, particularly focusing on multisig setups in the Bitcoin network. The proposal advocates for using a master xpub chain code as a secret for symmetrically encrypting backups of wallet descriptors. This method aims to streamline access control by allowing all descriptors that keys derived from the master xpub are part of, to be accessed without necessitating a shared secret among multisig participants. Each participant is responsible for creating their own encrypted backups, enhancing privacy and security.

A deep dive into the cryptographic nuances explores the utilization of XOR operations among individual secrets (Ci) and a shared secret (S) in deciphering a ciphertext payload. The discourse elaborates on the theoretical and practical aspects of applying XOR in scenarios involving multiple public keys (xpubs), highlighting the complexities and limitations when attempting to isolate or manipulate Ci values to derive the shared secret S. It becomes evident that achieving a definitive result through simple XOR operations among individual secrets is not straightforward due to the structured constraints of cryptographic protocols designed for robust security measures.

The conversation also addresses optimal practices for managing account numbers within digital wallets, especially when devices are repurposed across different setups. A preference for a non-mandatory but predictable derivation method for account numbers is suggested to conceal the setup's participant count, thus bolstering privacy. This recommendation aligns with a balance between user convenience and security, suggesting fresh account numbers for each setup yet acknowledging the feasibility of reusing account numbers under certain conditions.

Key management intricacies are further examined, particularly concerning the T component's role alongside extended public keys (xpubs). The discussion suggests keeping derivation paths unencrypted within wallet backups could alleviate concerns over the predictability and recoverability of xpubs. This nuanced perspective underscores the ongoing debate on achieving a harmonious balance between security prerequisites and practical recovery processes.

Technical challenges associated with integrating the T component within Bitcoin operations are scrutinized. Issues arise from how Bitcoin Core processes descriptors, leading to potential complications in maintaining T's distinctiveness in key structures due to normalization processes and BIP32 limitations. A workaround involving timestamp division is proposed to circumvent these issues, aiming for compatibility and uniqueness within the system's operational framework.

Furthermore, the discourse introduces `descriptor-encrypt`, a Rust library offering a novel solution for encrypting descriptors, ensuring that only authorized spenders can decrypt them. This development marks a significant stride in cryptographic security, providing a robust encryption solution tailored to complex wallet setups. The library's compatibility with various descriptors and miniscript, coupled with its innovative encoding scheme, paves the way for advanced data security methodologies.

The importance of backing up wallet descriptors is emphasized, contrasting with traditional emphasis on seeds and private keys. This shift highlights the need for a comprehensive backup strategy encompassing public keys and wallet policies, addressing the challenges associated with their loss or compromise. The discussion sheds light on emerging perspectives regarding cryptographic information backup, suggesting methodologies for preserving the integrity and availability of public keys and wallet policies critical for digital asset systems' seamless operation.

In summary, the exchange encapsulates a forward-thinking dialogue on cryptographic security, key management, and data backup strategies within the context of Bitcoin and digital wallets. The discussions range from theoretical considerations to practical solutions, underscoring the dynamic interplay between enhancing security measures and maintaining practical usability across cryptographic frameworks.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T12:49:23.515000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
