<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-13T03:09:51.432090+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-07-12 10:32:27.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T03:09:51.432201+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The nuanced relationship between chain work and the lowest hash in blockchain technology is explored through statistical analysis and mathematical modeling, revealing a direct, albeit complex, interaction. The foundational equation suggests that chain work is inversely proportional to twice the lowest hash observed, hinting at a method for estimating chain work by considering the effective target for a blockchain's lifetime as twice the lowest hash seen. However, this model's simplicity belies the actual complexity involved in accurately computing chain work, with discrepancies often found between calculated and actual figures. This divergence underscores the challenges in modeling blockchain dynamics, especially given the significant variance possible due to small number calculations.

Further examination of chain work through the lens of exponential distribution illustrates both the expected solve time and the chain work can be statistically inferred from the lowest hash, despite inherent variability. This approach, employing principles like the probability density function for chain work, suggests that the median values of chain work over expected solve time closely align with theoretical predictions, providing a more nuanced understanding of blockchain operation and the impacts of difficulty adjustments on mining.

The conversation then shifts to a refined methodology for calculating hashrate and total work in blockchain networks. By focusing on the sum of difficulties for blocks within a specific timespan, this method offers a more accurate reflection of computational effort, especially when comparing competing blockchain tips. It highlights the importance of considering the actual timespan over which work is performed, rather than relying on outdated correction factors, thereby enhancing the accuracy of work and hashrate assessments.

An intriguing scenario involving a hypothetical Proof of Work protocol demonstrates how miners, divided by network partition into groups with varying difficulty levels, can achieve equal work output under different conditions. This example raises critical considerations about the efficiency and security implications of hashrate versus actual work completed, challenging assumptions about the correlation between higher hashrates and successful mining outcomes.

The methodology for estimating the number of hashes performed based on a constant hashrate assumption is discussed, emphasizing its limitations outside of hashrate estimation contexts. This conversation highlights the specificity required in applying theoretical models to practical situations in computational tasks, where variables significantly impact outcomes.

In exploring the calculation of total work in a system assuming a constant hashrate and static target, the discussion leverages the properties of the Erlang distribution to more accurately estimate total work done. This approach underscores the complexities of estimating network parameters and the importance of sophisticated statistical methods in analyzing decentralized systems.

The exploration delves into the mechanics of mining and work within blockchain technology, illustrating how the exact number of hashes required for mining a block is directly proportional to the difficulty level and inversely proportional to the target hash rate. This analysis aims to quantify the computational power expended in the mining process, offering insights into efficiency and evolution over time.

A revised formula for calculating the hashrate in scenarios of substantial changes in both mining difficulty and network hashrate is proposed, addressing inaccuracies found in traditional calculations. This new method, incorporating adjustments such as (N-1)/N, reduces error and ensures more accurate representation of work in Proof of Work consensus decisions, highlighting its relevance in distributed ledger technologies and the critical role of median hashrate in consensus mechanisms.

A correction regarding the use of Erlang distribution for calculating expected values clarifies the necessity of adjusting calculations to account for biases, leading to a more precise and reliable measurement of the hashrate. This distinction is crucial for accurate computations in fields requiring high precision, such as cryptographic applications.

An innovative approach to estimating the hashrate of a blockchain network focuses on using a fixed time window for more accurate real-time estimations. This method adjusts for minor discrepancies in timestamps and proposes an alternative for estimating total chain work without needing knowledge of difficulty or timestamps, emphasizing the inclusion of all orphans in the calculation for comprehensiveness.

A detailed analysis introduces a method for estimating the unknown but constant hashrate crucial for understanding blockchain dynamics, particularly in Bitcoin mining. This discussion extends to correcting a bias in the maximum-likelihood estimator for the hashrate, proposing an adjusted formula for an unbiased estimator, thereby enhancing the accuracy of blockchain analytics.

Finally, the discussion identifies a significant overestimation error in current network hash rate calculations, proposing a correction method to more accurately reflect the actual hash rate. This adjustment, along with a suggested shift in methodology from counting a fixed number of blocks to measuring blocks over a fixed period, aims to improve the accuracy of network performance assessments, underscoring the ongoing need for precise and adaptable techniques in blockchain technology analysis.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T10:32:27.275000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
