<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-30T03:09:36.608997+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann 2025-07-29 02:53:14.348000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann 2025-07-29 02:41:47.737000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5586_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5587_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T03:09:36.609036+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/paralel-bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the critical examination of institutions and their roles in serving human needs versus their evolution into entities that primarily fulfill egocentric goals such as resource concentration and power. It highlights a growing concern over institutions that, despite being designed to address human existential problems like hunger, quality of life, and inequality, have strayed from their foundational missions. This divergence is notably pronounced when these institutions become public entities, such as those listed on stock exchanges, where they may receive even greater rights and protections than individual humans. The narrative suggests a reevaluation of how machines and non-conscious entities are integrated into our societal framework, emphasizing that their existence should unequivocally aim to enhance or expand life for the common good, rather than contributing to existential threats.

The proposal introduces the concept of designated sub-wallets for machines and institutions, managed by conscious living beings, to ensure that the operations and objectives of these non-conscious entities align with the broader goal of life expansion and betterment. This idea stems from a philosophical standpoint concerning the primary purpose of the universe and the inherent value placed on life and consciousness. The argument extends to question the current financial structures and the notion of fungibility, speculating on why living beings should bear the inflationary consequences of economic activities controlled by non-living entities. The discourse challenges the accepted norms of market-driven scarcity and value determination, proposing a separation in how the economic growth or inflation of non-living entities impacts the financial stability and sustainability of living, conscious beings. In essence, it puts forth a model where the economic systems serve the interests of life and consciousness rather than subjugating them to inanimate institutions and machines.

Furthermore, the dialogue touches upon the philosophical implications of this issue, suggesting that it may be more aptly debated within the realm of philosophy. It underscores the need for a fundamental shift in perspective regarding the relationship between living beings and the institutional or mechanical constructs they create, advocating for a future where the development and application of technology and institutions are unequivocally aimed at supporting and enriching human life and the natural world. This philosophical inquiry invites a broader reflection on our collective priorities and the ethical frameworks guiding the advancement of civilization.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-29T02:53:14.348000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
