<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-08T02:52:58.216518+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-07-07 10:51:28.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-07-07 03:03:18.023000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-06 22:40:48.497000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-02 17:18:14.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-02 16:16:16.902000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 12:01:51.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-06-05 20:26:39.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5411_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5410_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5409_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5398_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5396_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5365_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5233_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T02:52:58.216583+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The examination of block propagation delays and their impact on mining efficiency and fairness within cryptocurrency networks reveals a nuanced landscape of competitive advantage and potential for manipulation. The analysis begins with the observation that stales, or blocks that are not included in the longest blockchain, occur with a notable frequency, suggesting an underlying issue with network latency. Specifically, a hashrate-weighted propagation delay of 477 milliseconds is identified as a significant factor contributing to this phenomenon. This delay notably affects the distribution of rewards among miners, particularly highlighting the differential impact on those utilizing Fibre, a technology that ostensibly ceased operation around 2020-2021. Fibre miners, by leveraging superior connectivity, inadvertently or otherwise, introduce a delay in block visibility for non-Fibre miners. This delay effectively allows Fibre miners a temporary exclusivity in mining efforts, leading to a calculable increase in their profits by approximately 0.03% at the expense of non-Fibre miners who see a reduction in rewards by about 0.1%.

Furthermore, the integrity of blockchain networks relies heavily on the synchronization and accuracy of node operations, especially concerning timestamp handling. Discrepancies in timestamps, whether significantly ahead or behind current network time, pose a threat to the consensus mechanism, necessitating rigorous validation processes to ensure the reliability of block inclusion in the chain. In addressing these challenges, a proposal suggests enforcing a narrow margin of error for block timestamps (+/- 5 seconds, with an additional 2 seconds for propagation delay) as a measure to mitigate selfish mining practices. This strategy emphasizes the importance of precise and honest timestamping to maintain equity among miners and uphold the blockchain's integrity.

In the broader context of achieving secure consensus in distributed systems, a shift towards requiring a supermajority (66.67%) for consensus rather than a simple majority is advocated to enhance system security. This approach underscores the necessity of strict adherence to conditions such as synchronized clocks and digitally signed messages, highlighting Bitcoin's limitations in meeting these ideal criteria due to its lenient timestamp regulations.

The concept of selfish mining is further explored through a detailed mathematical analysis based on the seminal 2013 research paper "Majority is not enough." This strategy, where miners withhold blocks to nullify competitors' efforts and skew the reward distribution in their favor, becomes increasingly viable as a miner's control over the network's hashrate grows. The discussion includes a Markov Chain model to illustrate the state transitions of a selfish miner and concludes that profitability thresholds for selfish mining strategies are contingent upon both hashrate dominance and block propagation speed. Specifically, the analysis indicates that a miner needs to control between 36% and 37% of the total network hashrate for selfish mining to be considered beneficial, thereby posing a significant concern for the security and fairness of blockchain protocols.

This comprehensive examination of block propagation, timestamp management, and mining strategies within blockchain networks provides critical insights into the complexities of maintaining fairness and integrity in digital ledger technologies. Highlighting specific technological and strategic vulnerabilities, it calls for ongoing scrutiny and adaptive measures to safeguard against manipulation and ensure equitable participation across the mining ecosystem. For those interested in a deeper dive into the mechanics and implications of selfish mining, further information can be found in the associated GitHub repository, which offers a simulation of the process ([GitHub Repository](https://github.com/darosior/miningsimulation)).</summary>
    <published>2025-07-07T10:51:28.392000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
