<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
  <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:02.420875+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jesseposner 2025-07-28 19:05:27.483000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-07-22 18:55:36.563000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jesseposner  . 2025-07-20 18:33:40.534000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5584_Post-Quantum-HD-Wallets-Silent-Payments-Key-Aggregation-and-Threshold-Signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5539_Post-Quantum-HD-Wallets-Silent-Payments-Key-Aggregation-and-Threshold-Signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5525_Post-Quantum-HD-Wallets-Silent-Payments-Key-Aggregation-and-Threshold-Signatures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Post-Quantum HD-Wallets, Silent Payments, Key Aggregation, and Threshold Signatures</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T03:15:02.420919+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-quantum-hd-wallets-silent-payments-key-aggregation-and-threshold-signatures/1854" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of post-quantum (PQ) cryptography is an essential endeavor in the face of potential threats posed by quantum computing. A significant area of focus within this field is the comparative analysis between PQ cryptographic schemes and established standards like ECDSA. Notably, advancements such as Musig/Frost have been highlighted for their efficiency, requiring only a single round of signing compared to the two rounds needed by ECDSA protocols. This reduction in complexity marks a substantial improvement, potentially making these protocols more appealing for practical implementation. The primary objective of such evaluations is to determine whether new PQ technologies can exceed the capabilities of current cryptographic solutions in terms of security and feasibility for real-world applications. Through detailed examination of each scheme's unique attributes, researchers aim to identify those that are not only theoretically secure but also viable for widespread adoption, thereby securing our digital communications against both current and future threats.

In addition to the general assessment of PQ schemes, recent research has shed light on the promising role of lattice-based cryptographic structures in enhancing blockchain technology. Specifically, the development of Hierarchical Deterministic (HD) wallets, stealth addresses, key aggregation, and threshold signatures stands out as a notable advancement. For instance, research outlined in "[A Secure Hierarchical Deterministic Wallet with Stealth Address from Lattices](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0304397524002895?via%3Dihub)" introduces a deterministic tree structure that facilitates private and untraceable transactions through the generation of one-time addresses. Moreover, studies such as "[Round-Optimal Secure Multisignature Schemes from Lattices with Public Key Aggregation and Signature Compression](https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-51938-4_14)" and its subsequent refinements demonstrate the consolidation of multiple public keys into a single entity alongside signature compression, enhancing the efficiency of multi-signature schemes. Additionally, the introduction of lattice-based threshold signatures as seen in "[Finally! A Compact Lattice-Based Threshold Signature](https://eprint.iacr.org/2025/872)" addresses critical challenges such as signature size bloating, indicating a move towards more compact and efficient cryptographic solutions.

These developments collectively underscore the compatibility of lattice-based cryptographic methods with existing Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and other cryptographic standards. There appears to be no significant barrier to integrating post-quantum primitives with current protocols, suggesting a bright future for secure, quantum-resistant digital currency transactions and wallet technologies. This alignment between new PQ schemes and established cryptographic frameworks promises to significantly enhance the security and privacy of blockchain technologies, especially in mitigating the risks associated with quantum computing advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T19:05:27.483000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
