<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:26.138511+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-14 09:29:43.875000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-07-10 21:18:02.242000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-10 04:50:02.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5449_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5434_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5425_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:26.138570+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse sheds light on the complexities and potential risks associated with implementing long-term timelocks in cryptocurrency, particularly against the backdrop of emerging quantum computing technologies. The concern is primarily rooted in the uncertainty surrounding the timeline for quantum computers becoming operational, which could pose a significant threat to the security of encrypted digital assets. This scenario reflects a broader apprehension about the rapid pace of technological advancements and their implications for the security of digital currencies. While the writer is not a quantum computing expert, they emphasize the importance of considering the potential for quantum attacks when making decisions related to cryptocurrency investments. This perspective advocates for a cautious approach to risk management, suggesting that conservatism and flexibility in investment strategies may protect investors from unforeseen vulnerabilities.

In response to the feedback from users desiring longer timelock durations potentially extending to ~10 years, an experimental proposal has been put forth without advocating for immediate changes to the Bitcoin protocol through a soft fork. The proposed method involves adjusting the `nSequence` field of a transaction by setting bit 21 and leaving bit 22 unset, thereby interpreting the timelock unit as 8 blocks instead of one. This adjustment aims to extend the duration of timelocks to approximately 10 years with minimal modifications required to the existing Bitcoin Core codebase. Despite the innovative approach, there's an acknowledgment of potential oversights due to limited familiarity with all intricacies of Bitcoin Core's architecture.

The discussion encompasses several key areas: identifying viable use cases for extended timelocks up to 10 years, evaluating the risks and potential edge cases that might arise from such implementations, exploring alternatives for achieving these longer timelocks without a soft fork, and assessing the proposed implementation strategy using the bit 21 flag with 8-block units. This exploration reflects a balanced effort to address user demands for longer timelock periods in Bitcoin transactions, weighing the technical feasibility against the broader implications for the network and its stakeholders.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T09:29:43.875000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
