<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-07T03:09:16.118758+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2025-08-06 16:47:35.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sceptic 2025-08-06 15:44:53.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-05 07:40:00.709000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-05 03:36:29.160000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-08-04 17:09:18.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-02 19:24:55.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-01 06:27:52.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-31 20:07:11.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5664_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5662_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5644_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5641_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5636_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5623_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5610_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5601_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:09:16.118828+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse initiates with a critical examination of the urgency to implement changes in Bitcoin's transaction fee policy within the upcoming release. It delves into the proposal to adjust the minimum relay fee rate, which is vital for the propagation of transactions across nodes. An innovative proposition within this dialogue is the introduction of a subpool designated for transactions with fees below 1 satoshi per byte (sat/vbyte). This subpool aims to segregate lower fee transactions under specific parameters, such as a maximum memory pool size and an expiry time, to avoid the devaluation of transaction fees through a free relay system. The discussion suggests that adjusting the `minrelaytxfee` to a nominal value above zero could be plausible if it doesn't encourage free relay, thereby potentially enhancing mining revenue and fee estimates amidst declining fee revenue trends since 2017.

Further explored is the integration of Proof of Work (PoW) with Bitcoin transactions, excluding TapScript, to bolster security for second-layer solutions like the Lightning Network. This approach allows conditional execution through script commands and has been exemplified by a faucet rewarding users for solving puzzles, thus promoting collaborative PoW efforts. This method not only combats spam but also enhances transaction integrity, offering an alternative to higher transaction fees through computational work. Such a mechanism underscores a shift towards prioritizing security over financial costs, aiming for inclusivity and resilience in the network.

The discussion extends to the implications of miners validating free transactions and the potential for future Segwit versions to facilitate random data pushes, raising concerns about the abandonment of standardness rules. This highlights a need for leniency in policy adjustments to prevent the unnecessary blocking of valid transactions while safeguarding against denial-of-service attacks. It invokes a broader contemplation on the adaptability of Bitcoin’s network rules and the dynamic nature of what constitutes a "standard" transaction, driven by miner practices and technological advancements.

Additionally, the conversation touches upon the scalability and economic models of transaction fees within the blockchain. It debates the feasibility of maintaining low on-chain transaction fees and the consequent implications for second-layer solutions. By proposing adjustments to the minimum relay feerate, from 1000 satoshi per kilobyte to 100 satoshi per virtual byte, the discourse reflects on recent trends where transactions with sub-1sat/vB fees have been successfully mined, highlighting the balance between avoiding block relay issues and mitigating DoS attacks. This discussion encapsulates the ongoing dialogue regarding the optimal management of transaction fees, network stability, and the decentralized ethos of cryptocurrency technologies. The inclusion of [GitHub pull requests](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106) and related discussions ([related PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32959)) provides tangible examples of these proposed adjustments, inviting further reflection on the ideal minimum feerate and its implications for the ecosystem at large.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T16:47:35.037000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
