<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Chain Code Delegation: Private Access Control for Bitcoin Keys</title>
  <updated>2025-10-16T02:27:47.718907+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jurvis  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-15 00:41:07.310000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>marathongary  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-16 20:15:30.976000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>jaonoctus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-29 08:08:38.123000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>pinheadmz  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-08-20 15:51:59.920000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>jurvis  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-08-24 00:01:41.912000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jurvis</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-15 03:40:34.123000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5469_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5506_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5593_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5755_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5766_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6086_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Chain Code Delegation: Private Access Control for Bitcoin Keys</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T02:27:47.719705+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/chain-code-delegation-private-access-control-for-bitcoin-keys/1837/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-07-15 00:41:07.310000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The development of Chain Code Delegation by Jesse Posner introduces a novel approach to collaborative custody, focusing on enhancing privacy and security in digital transactions. This technique is built around the concept of withholding BIP-32 chain codes while providing only scalar tweaks at the time of signing. It represents a departure from traditional methods by allowing custodians to enforce policies such as spending velocity controls without having access to an XPUB. The lack of access to the entire key tree limits the custodian's ability to view all transaction histories, addressing a significant privacy concern in typical multisig arrangements.
Chain Code Delegation offers a solution to the limitations encountered with existing methods such as multiparty computation (MPC) and disjoint spending paths with Tapscript, especially in the context of ECDSA. By enabling custodians to sign transactions without revealing the full extent of their capabilities, this method significantly mitigates security risks. Custodians are confined to knowing only the information necessary for signing specific transactions, thereby reducing the potential damage in the event of a system compromise.
This methodology incorporates several innovative techniques to ensure transaction privacy and security. For instance, applying BIP32 tweaks to blind Schnorr signatures helps maintain confidentiality about which transactions a custodian has signed. Predicate blind signatures further allow for policy enforcement during the signing process without compromising on privacy. Such measures are crucial in environments with large attack surfaces, like mobile phones, as they limit the scope of compromised keys to only those transactions for which scalar tweaks were shared.
The conceptual foundation for Chain Code Delegation aligns with ideas similar to blinded extended public keys, as discussed on GitHub. This approach minimizes security risks associated with the exposure of the blinded path for an xpub, marking a significant advancement in cryptographic operations' privacy and security.
Moreover, Schnorr signatures play a vital role in this ecosystem due to their clean algebraic structure and robust security features. The incorporation of tweak variables into the public key ensures the integrity of the signature, despite any alterations. This exemplifies the application of mathematical principles in securing digital communications effectively.
OpenBazaar's use of a unique protocol that leverages cryptocurrency technology for secure and private transactions between buyers and sellers showcases another aspect of innovative cryptographic applications. By employing static public keys and specialized scripts, OpenBazaar facilitates transactions with a high degree of privacy, involving moderators only in cases of disputes. This protocol underscores the potential of cryptographic techniques in creating secure, fair, and private digital marketplaces.
For readers interested in the technical details and further implications of Chain Code Delegation, references include discussions on Private Collaborative Custody with FROST and Concurrently Secure Blind Schnorr Signatures, available at [link](https://gist.github.com/nickfarrow/4be776782bce0c12cca523cbc203fb9d/) and [link](https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1676), respectively. Additionally, the concept is under consideration for a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal, with more information available at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/2004). These resources offer comprehensive insights into the mechanisms, benefits, and potential applications of Chain Code Delegation in enhancing the security and privacy of digital transactions.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>