<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-09T02:53:35.516176+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-08 19:49:40.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-08-08 02:23:35.114000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-08 00:32:21.279000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-07 21:56:29.740000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-07 00:45:21.764000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 10:32:27.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5676_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5675_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5674_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5673_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5668_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T02:53:35.516341+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens with an examination of the methodological approach to estimating computational work in blockchain mining, utilizing statistical models based on hash values. It emphasizes the use of the k'th lowest hash value as a means to estimate total work done, assuming each hash attempt is a uniformly random sample from a continuous uniform distribution. This methodology proposes that the k'th lowest hash follows a Beta distribution, facilitating the calculation of expected work and its variance, thereby highlighting the challenges in accurately estimating work due to the high level of estimation uncertainty, even with constant values of \(k\).

Further exploration into the quantification of work within proof-of-work (PoW) blockchains reveals an intricate relationship between the effort required to find a valid block and the difficulty level represented by the second-lowest hash encountered during the mining process. This analysis underlines the comparative difficulty measured against near-successes, offering a nuanced perspective on what constitutes "work" in blockchain mining. Additionally, the correction of a significant error related to the inversion of 'D' and 'W' in a document underscores the importance of accuracy in presenting mathematical formulas, highlighting how such inaccuracies can lead to widespread misconceptions.

The narrative then delves into the direct relationship between chain work and the lowest hash observed in a network, proposing a simplistic model for estimating chain work, albeit acknowledging the potential discrepancies and the inherent challenges in modeling blockchain dynamics accurately. The discussion transitions into detailing a refined approach to calculating hashrate and total work over a given timespan, advocating for a more accurate measurement that accounts for the actual timespan covering blocks, thus enabling a more precise assessment of work effort across competing blockchain tips.

A hypothetical scenario illustrating the difference between hashrate and work output in PoW protocols serves to question the efficiency and security implications of these metrics. This scenario posits that a higher hashrate does not necessarily equate to an increased amount of work completed, suggesting a nuanced balance between operational difficulty, hashrate, and resultant work. The follow-up contemplation on whether shifting focus from hashrate to work for a fixed output might yield more accurate insights into the required timespans for mining operations further explores this complexity.

Addressing the methodology for estimating the number of hashes performed under the assumption of a constant hashrate, the discussion acknowledges the limitations of this approach outside of hashrate estimation contexts. It highlights the necessity of this assumption for reliable hashrate estimations while recognizing the potential inaccuracies when applied to broader applications such as work estimation.

In dissecting the nuances of time-weighted target calculations for PoW consensus mechanisms, a significant discovery regarding the accuracy of hashrate calculations under varying conditions is shared. The introduction of a revised formula aims to reduce errors in scenarios where both difficulty and hashrate fluctuate significantly, emphasizing the importance of adjustments in accurately reflecting the work done and impacting consensus decisions, especially in distributed ledger technologies.

The conversation shifts to a crucial correction regarding the use of Erlang distribution for calculating expected values, underscoring the discrepancy between the mathematical expectation of the inverse of a variable and the inverse of its expected value. This distinction is critical for achieving an unbiased estimation of the hashrate, highlighting the sophisticated statistical methods required for analyzing decentralized systems effectively.

An innovative approach to calculating the hashrate of a blockchain network is detailed, focusing on using a fixed time window for more accurate estimations at specific moments, like daily estimates. This method adjusts for minor discrepancies in timestamps and suggests modifications to traditional formulas to account for real-time conditions, proposing alternative methods for estimating total chain work without needing knowledge of difficulty or timestamps.

Finally, the dialogue encapsulates the development of an accurate method for estimating the unknown but constant hashrate crucial for blockchain dynamics, specifically Bitcoin mining. It outlines the construction of a mathematical framework for hashrate estimation using block work and duration, leading to the derivation of a maximum-likelihood estimator (MLE) for the hashrate. The analysis critiques the current estimation methods, proposes corrections for inherent biases, and posits the unbiased estimator's efficiency and sufficiency, indicating its potential as the minimum-variance unbiased estimator (MVUE). This comprehensive overview not only enhances understanding of blockchain analytics but also underscores the dynamic nature of technical discussions within the cryptocurrency domain, where methodologies are continually refined for greater accuracy and insight.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-08T19:49:40.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
