<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:08.848205+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky 2025-07-17 18:29:51.913000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2025-07-16 17:53:01.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-16 16:45:26.989000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-15 15:35:18.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 15:09:55.489000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-15 14:48:49.506000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-15 11:19:21.847000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-15 01:13:12.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:05:51.271000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:03:39.361000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:55:06.554000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:30:49.131000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 19:35:52.115000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 18:26:10.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 15:09:06.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 09:31:50.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-07 16:01:15.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5512_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5505_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5497_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5485_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5484_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5482_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5479_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5471_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5467_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5466_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5465_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5464_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5460_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5459_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5458_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5450_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5412_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:08.848324+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the nuanced considerations of blockchain protocol versioning, particularly in relation to payload size and efficiency. The dialogue underscores the criticality of selecting a protocol version that efficiently aligns with the requirements of a 256-bit hash payload without incorporating unnecessary bytes, aiming to optimize space on the blockchain. This optimization is vital due to the permanent implications on blockchain real estate. Despite some confusion over protocol versions—specifically, the Segregated Witness (SegWit) versions associated with Taproot—the discussion clarifies that P2TR operates under version 1, and there's a pivotal choice between version 2 or 3 for future applications. Ethan’s decision against adopting the same version as P2TR for their purposes highlights the significance of choosing the most appropriate protocol version based on specific technical needs.

The exchange further explores the implementation of Taproot, spotlighting the SegWit versioning and the potential for accommodating different payload lengths in future versions of taproot. It addresses the numeration confusion due to the 0-based numbering system and refers to BIP-341 for detailed framework usage. The conversation identifies constraints tied to using a 256-bit payload, illustrating the complexity and forward-looking considerations crucial in evolving Bitcoin's infrastructure for advanced features. Additionally, privacy concerns related to MAST (Merkelized Abstract Syntax Trees) are discussed, emphasizing the balance between functionality and privacy in cryptographic protocols’ design and implementation.

A novel proposal for a 'taproot v2' mechanism is introduced, suggesting enhanced functionality without addressing quantum resistance concerns. This mechanism aims to maintain user anonymity and transaction obfuscation akin to the current taproot implementation for transactions not utilizing the key spend feature. The discussion also touches upon the unconventional use of SegWit versions as markers for different types of transaction outputs to simplify identification and enhance usability, inviting community feedback on the approach.

Security measures for tapscript outputs and the strategic choice of Segwit version 3 for its efficiency and compatibility with existing payload sizes are deliberated. Furthermore, the potential modification of Bitcoin's Taproot upgrade to incorporate Ethereum-like features for UTXO set management sparks a debate on privacy implications and the ethos behind Taproot’s design. The ongoing efforts to enhance Bitcoin's infrastructure through careful consideration and review of improvements, alongside discussions on naming conventions and quantum resistance proposals, reflect the collaborative nature and technical rigor within the Bitcoin development community.

Lastly, significant advancements in Bitcoin Improvement Proposal 360 (BIP-360) aim to bolster Bitcoin's defense against quantum computing threats by transitioning Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH) to a script-only version of Taproot (P2TR). This move enhances security by removing the quantum-vulnerable key-spend pathway and commits P2QRH outputs directly to the tapleaf merkle root. The proposal also outlines a plan for Post-Quantum (PQ) signature verification opcodes, allowing for flexible integration of new signature algorithms in the future, further contributing to the robustness and adaptability of the Bitcoin protocol against emerging threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T18:29:51.913000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
