<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where to post information about new protocol releases?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-12T02:57:47.730625+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dr-orlovsky</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5440_Where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5436_Where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5435_Where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3040_Where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3039_Where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where to post information about new protocol releases?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-12T02:57:47.730682+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-to-post-information-about-new-protocol-releases/1087" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Engagement within online forums, especially those dedicated to software and technology development, operates on a trust-based leveling system. Users who actively participate by reading posts, reacting to them, and contributing their own content can attain higher trust levels, granting them additional privileges such as the ability to create new tags. This system is designed to encourage active participation and reward users who contribute positively to the forum's ecosystem.

The concept of introducing a new tag titled "client-side-validation" has been proposed to encapsulate discussions around an array of technologies including OpenTimeStamps, RGB, shielded client-side validation, and TapAss, among others. This suggests a growing interest and need for categorizing content that revolves around these technologies, indicating the forum’s adaptability to emerging technological trends and discussions.

Furthermore, the method of disseminating information about software releases or protocol improvements has been reevaluated. Instead of using announcement tags conventionally, crafting detailed posts that mirror the depth and presentation of conference talks is recommended. This strategy is aimed at enhancing the impact and comprehension of the shared content, ensuring it resonates more effectively with the intended audience. Additionally, the guidance on posting flexibility highlights the importance of community involvement in content organization. Contributors are encouraged to initially post in the section they find most appropriate, with the caveat that their submissions can be flagged as "off-topic" by community members for relocation, rather than being flagged as "spam."

The discussion also touches upon significant contributions to Bitcoin’s ecosystem through the development of protocols like RGB smart contracts, a new Rust implementation of the Lightning Network Protocol (LNP), and tools for bitcoin-based self-sovereign identities (SSI). These advancements underscore a collective effort to enhance Bitcoin’s scalability, privacy, and versatility. The emphasis on sharing developments related to such projects in communities or forums focused on cryptocurrency technology advancements and blockchain development ensures that the information reaches an engaged and knowledgeable audience. This approach not only broadens awareness but also cultivates a space for collaboration, feedback, and support from stakeholders with shared interests in the innovation and application of Bitcoin and its technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-11T21:37:45.272000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
