<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-07-12T02:58:54.321429+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-12T02:58:54.321631+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The examination of chain work in relation to the lowest hash encountered in a blockchain network reveals a nuanced understanding of how computational effort is quantified over the lifespan of a blockchain. The initial hypothesis posits that the "effective target" for a blockchain's entire life equates to twice the lowest hash seen, leading to a formula that approximates chain work but tends to overestimate it significantly—by factors ranging from two to seven times the actual figure. This discrepancy draws parallels to challenges in estimating expected solvetime from a single instance, suggesting both phenomena may be governed by exponential distribution characteristics. The exploration delves into the mathematical representation of chain work and its probability density function (PDF), uncovering a relationship with the exponential PDF and providing insights into how lifetime effective hashrate and blockchain lifetime intertwine within this probabilistic framework. The findings indicate that while initial assumptions about the direct correlation between the lowest hash and effective target offer a rough estimation method, substantial variability exists, making accurate predictions challenging.

Further analysis introduces an advanced methodology for calculating hashrate at any given blockchain height, refining previous approaches by accounting for the actual timespan covering an additional block beyond those queried. This adjustment ensures a more precise calculation, particularly useful when comparing competing blockchain tips under varying difficulty levels. It emphasizes the significance of incorporating the correct timespan in computations to accurately gauge the amount of work done within a specified period, thereby enhancing the decision-making process for determining leading tips. By focusing on summing difficulties based on current time instead of relying solely on the last known timestamp, the methodology provides a dynamic and accurate reflection of a blockchain's state, highlighting the critical role of using the correct timespan in assessing blockchain performance in terms of hashrate and work done.

In scenarios involving network partitions and varying mining difficulties, the relationship between hashrate and work output comes into sharp focus. An observed equality in work output between groups operating at different difficulties raises questions about efficiency and security implications in Proof of Work protocols. The discussion suggests that a higher hashrate does not necessarily correlate with an increased number of successfully mined blocks, challenging conventional wisdom about the efficacy of raw computational power in blockchain mining operations. This scenario underscores the complexity of modeling blockchain dynamics and the importance of differentiating between operational difficulty, hashrate, and resultant work in evaluating network security and efficiency.

The discourse extends to the precision required in estimating the total number of hashes or total work performed by a blockchain network, shedding light on the limitations of assuming a constant hashrate and the specificity needed in applying theoretical models to practical situations. Through a detailed examination of calculating expected work using the Erlang distribution and adjusting for statistical variance inherent in block discovery times, the conversation enriches our understanding of blockchain mining dynamics. It highlights the necessity of sophisticated statistical methods in analyzing decentralized systems and the challenges in accurately measuring network parameters.

A comprehensive exploration of mining work, as defined by the exact number of hashes required per block, further elucidates the direct proportionality to mining difficulty and inversely to the target hash rate. This granular insight into the computational power expended in the mining process offers a pathway to better understand mining efficiency, energy consumption, and the evolution of mining practices over time. Through formalizing the mathematics behind these observations, the effort aims to quantify the intricacies of blockchain operations more clearly, providing valuable insights into cryptocurrency mining dynamics.

The calculation methodologies discussed offer significant advancements in understanding and estimating blockchain hashrate and chain work. By employing statistical properties of the lowest observed hashes and adapting formulas to account for real-time conditions, these methods propose more accurate and flexible ways of interpreting blockchain network performance and security. Such adaptive techniques are pivotal in the constantly evolving landscape of blockchain technology, underscoring the importance of accuracy and adaptability in analyses and methodologies related to blockchain analytics and optimization.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-12T00:55:02.853000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
