<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-07-16T03:06:25.532515+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-15 15:04:53.147000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth 2025-07-15 06:13:47.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth 2025-07-15 06:10:54.947000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth 2025-07-15 06:09:14.255000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth 2025-07-15 05:52:08.461000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 09:29:43.875000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-07-10 21:18:02.242000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-10 04:50:02.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5483_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5477_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5476_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5475_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5473_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5449_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5434_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5425_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T03:06:25.532586+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse initiates with a discussion on the feasibility and implications of expanding the relative timelock limits in Bitcoin, highlighting the potential use cases that could benefit from such an extension. It centers on the proposition to extend the current timelock limit to approximately 10 years, presenting this as a preferable alternative to a shorter extension, like 5 years. The conversation underscores the practicality of implementing longer timelocks for specific applications, despite recognizing that a decade-long period might seem excessive. Concerns are raised about the implications of locking funds for such extended durations, especially considering how future soft forks could impact users' access to their assets. However, apprehensions regarding quantum computing's effect on locked funds are dismissed, given that absolute locktimes already allow for long-term fund locking, thus countering arguments against extending relative timelocks.

The dialogue further explores the technical feasibility and necessity of a soft fork to accommodate the desired changes, critiquing the impracticality of pre-signing a series of relative timelock transactions as an alternative solution. It proposes a more efficient and effective implementation method through a soft fork, discussing the technical aspects of extending timelocks, including the suggestion to utilize a bit 21 flag with 8-block units. This method aims to maintain granularity while expanding the capacity for longer durations, possibly up to 20 years by using 16 block units, or adjusting the starting point for 8 block units to post the initial 65535 blocks to effectively extend the duration and simplify the representation of relative timelocks.

The enthusiasm for extended timelock capabilities is driven by their potential to enable new applications, such as inheritance constructions, which are not feasible under the current 1-year timelock limitation. This reflects a broader interest in developing more flexible and extended timelock functionalities to support a wider array of user needs and applications.

However, the conversation also brings to light concerns over the potential risks associated with long-term cryptocurrency locking agreements, especially given the uncertain timeline for quantum computing development. The writer advises caution, emphasizing the importance of considering the potential for quantum attacks in decision-making processes related to cryptocurrency investments. This cautious stance is informed by the unpredictability of technological advancements and their potential implications for digital asset security.

Further exploration into extending Bitcoin's relative timelocks reveals experimental approaches aimed at meeting user demands for longer timelock periods without necessitating immediate protocol changes through a soft fork. A proposed method involves utilizing bit 21 in the `nSequence` field of a transaction to signal a "long" timelock, potentially enabling durations of approximately 10 years with minimal modifications to the existing codebase. This proposal prompts discussions on the viability of such lengthy timelocks, the risks and edge cases associated with their implementation, and alternatives to achieve extended durations without significant protocol alterations. The comprehensive examination reflects a blend of innovation and caution, seeking to address user needs while considering the broader implications for Bitcoin's network and its stakeholders.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-15T15:04:53.147000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
