<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-25T03:01:27.459534+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-07-24 08:35:32.946000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-07 10:51:28.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-07 03:03:18.023000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-06 22:40:48.497000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-02 17:18:14.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-07-02 16:16:16.902000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 12:01:51.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-06-05 20:26:39.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5551_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5411_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5410_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5409_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5398_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5396_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5365_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5233_Where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Where does the 33.33% threshold for selfish mining come from?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T03:01:27.459606+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/where-does-the-33-33-threshold-for-selfish-mining-come-from/1757" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on blockchain technology and its inherent challenges, particularly focusing on network latency, block propagation, and the fairness of mining practices, offers a rich analysis of the delicate balance required to maintain both efficiency and equity within this digital ecosystem. A notable concern is how variations in network performance, referred to as "Fibre-like" efficiency, impact the occurrence of stale blocks—blocks that are valid at one point but become superseded by another block on the chain. By examining data on block propagation and analyzing the rate of stale blocks, which occurs approximately once every nine days or one per 1277 blocks, the discussion illuminates the nuanced relationship between network efficiency and the equitable distribution of mining rewards. This analysis raises critical questions about the potential for larger mining pools to leverage network inefficiencies for competitive advantage, subtly suggesting that the integrity of the blockchain may be compromised by strategic behaviors that exploit these inefficiencies.

Further exploration into the realm of blockchain reveals intricate strategies employed by miners to gain an upper hand, specifically through the manipulation of block timestamps. The concept of selfish mining, where miners withhold blocks to invalidate competitors' efforts and secure additional mining time, showcases the strategic depth within this technological sphere. This practice not only underscores the technical challenges associated with maintaining accurate and synchronized timestamps across the network but also highlights the broader implications for fairness and trust within the blockchain community. The analysis delves into the specifics of how miners could potentially exploit timestamp manipulation to their advantage, emphasizing the need for robust mechanisms to ensure that all participants adhere to agreed-upon temporal parameters for block validation.

Addressing these challenges, the discourse proposes innovative solutions aimed at enhancing the integrity and fairness of the blockchain. For instance, implementing stricter regulations on block timestamp validity could mitigate the issue of selfish mining by disqualifying blocks that fall outside a narrowly defined temporal window from immediate consideration. This approach entails a temporary "timeout" for blocks with questionable timestamps, allowing the network to rectify discrepancies caused by intentional manipulation or genuine network delays. Such measures not only aim to deter unfair mining practices but also contribute to a more secure and trustworthy blockchain environment. 

Moreover, the discussion extends beyond the technicalities of timestamp manipulation to consider the broader consensus mechanisms that underpin blockchain technology. It critiques the conventional wisdom that a simple majority hash rate constitutes sufficient security, advocating instead for a more stringent threshold to combat the vulnerabilities exposed by selfish mining and other strategic behaviors. This perspective underscores the complex interplay between technological infrastructure, strategic behavior, and the overarching principles of fairness and security that guide the evolution of blockchain technology.

In summary, the exploration of blockchain's technical and strategic challenges, coupled with proposed solutions for enhancing system integrity, provides valuable insights into the ongoing efforts to balance efficiency, fairness, and security within this rapidly evolving digital landscape. The meticulous analysis of network performance, block propagation, and mining practices underscores the importance of continued innovation and collaboration among stakeholders to safeguard the foundational principles of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-24T08:35:32.946000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
