<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-27T03:10:50.207828+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2025-07-26 19:36:06.826000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-07-14 13:26:38.093000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-07-13 00:20:28.380000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-07-02 13:03:14.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-07-01 22:03:02.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-30 17:09:09.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-06-30 00:57:12.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-02 14:22:43.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-22 21:20:03.071000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-12 17:47:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:20:40.305000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:17:55.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-04-15 15:55:25.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5565_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5454_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5448_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5392_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5387_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5379_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5371_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5192_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5092_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4993_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4878_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4877_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4790_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-27T03:10:50.207964+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a nuanced discussion about the economics of jamming attacks within payment channels, particularly the Lightning Network, an in-depth analysis reveals that an attacker can jam a channel for two weeks at relatively low costs. This is predicated upon the number of slots within a channel, with 120 slots being the focal point of this examination. For instance, to occupy all slots with 10k-sat payments would require approximately 8,000 sats, a figure that significantly drops when considering 1-sat payments due to the proportional decrease in required funds. The conversation further delves into the intricacies of fee structures beyond the Hold Fee, namely the Upfront Fee and Success Fee, which collectively aim to safeguard against such exploitative practices by ensuring the cost of jamming remains prohibitively high.

Adding complexity to the financial dynamics of routing payments, the dialogue shifts toward the operational costs and risks associated with running Lightning Network nodes. It dismantles the notion that routers can effortlessly double their funds through transaction facilitation, highlighting instead the reality of capital lock-up and the various fees incurred during payment processing. Specifically, it outlines how upfront collateral requirements scale with the position of a node in the payment chain, illustrating the compounded financial commitment necessary to secure transactions. Furthermore, an alternative cost model proposes a more realistic annual cost of capital, fundamentally recalibrating expectations around profitability and risk management in network participation.

The correspondence offers innovative solutions to mitigate the financial and operational challenges posed by jamming and spam attacks within the Lightning Network. One such proposal involves optimizing channel architecture by dedicating specific channels to small payments, thereby reducing the disproportionate impact of hold fees on low-value transactions. Additionally, the OPR protocol is presented as a promising avenue for eliminating delays and extra charges in payment resolution, enhancing the efficiency and security of the network.

The technical discourse extends into the realm of protocol improvement, specifically addressing latency issues introduced by recent bug fixes. A proposed solution aims to maintain low latency in payment forwarding by allowing downstream nodes to commit to increased burn funds without necessitating additional round-trip communications. This nuanced approach seeks to balance speed and security, ensuring that payments are processed swiftly without compromising on the integrity of the transaction process.

Furthermore, the conversation acknowledges the potential for exploitation through the manipulation of hold fees, illustrating complex scenarios where nodes could incur unwarranted charges due to strategic delays imposed by malicious actors. This underscores the critical need for refined protocols that prevent abuse while ensuring equitable compensation for all parties involved in the routing process.

In response to these challenges, an enriched protocol framework is outlined, incorporating upfront, hold, and success fees to comprehensively address the costs and risks inherent in payment routing. This framework introduces mechanisms like burn outputs to enforce fair fee distribution and incentivize cooperative behavior among nodes. Detailed calculations and operational strategies are discussed, providing a robust foundation for mitigating spam and enhancing the overall efficiency of the Lightning Network.

Lastly, advancements in the protocol are highlighted through a revision that includes detailed specifications for improved latency management and spam prevention. This reflects a continuous effort to refine the network's functionality, demonstrating an ongoing commitment to addressing both existing and emergent challenges within this dynamic ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-26T19:36:06.826000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
