<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-22T09:10:09.529418+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>setavenger</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>AdamISZ  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>AdamISZ  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T09:10:09.530896+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and potential solutions associated with implementing Silent Payments over the nostr platform, focusing on issues such as transaction notification losses due to the platform's statelessness, reliance on relay overlaps for message delivery, and risks of notification flooding by malicious actors. A proposed solution involves using confirmation messages to ensure transaction notifications are received, highlighting the necessity for sender and receiver to share a relay for effective communication. The conversation also delves into the technical specifics of generating new keys for bitcoin payments on nostr, leveraging `npub` keys and the concept of stealth addresses to enhance privacy and security. This approach suggests an adaptive use of cryptographic practices to maintain user anonymity.
Further, the communication outlines the process of secure key exchange between parties, emphasizing the importance of shared secrets in confidential communications. It introduces the mathematical foundation for generating stealth keys, which enable private transactions without exposing actual public or private keys. The proposal suggests a method where Alice can securely notify Bob of a payment using an encrypted message, thereby circumventing the need for Bob to scan for transactions actively. This system aims to streamline transactions while ensuring high levels of security and privacy.
Additionally, the email touches upon the compatibility of nostr with Bitcoin's cryptographic techniques and its advancements over existing protocols like BIP 47 version 1. It proposes a new protocol development for stealth payment notifications that could significantly improve user experience by reducing the need for scanning silent payments. A proof of concept is provided through Python code examples, demonstrating the generation and use of stealth keys within the Nostr framework. These examples offer a practical guide to developers for implementing secure, anonymous transactions, suggesting Nostr's potential to bolster Bitcoin's privacy features.
The overall correspondence reflects a deep interest in exploring the cryptographic intricacies of secure, anonymous transactions on the nostr platform. It emphasizes the need for innovative solutions to overcome the limitations of current systems and enhance the privacy and security of digital payments. Through a detailed examination of cryptographic principles and a practical implementation guide, the discussion provides valuable insights into the development of more secure and efficient payment systems in the cryptocurrency space.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>