<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-07-28T03:09:57.846778+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>PakoVM 2025-07-27 13:18:07.445000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>chris 2025-07-27 13:15:22.273000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann  . 2025-07-26 23:45:02.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5571_Bitcoin-Version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5570_Bitcoin-Version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5567_Bitcoin-Version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Version 2 only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T03:09:57.846822+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-version-2-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed fork of Bitcoin is an innovative approach aimed at addressing the challenges of money centralization by introducing a system where each physical entity can only create one wallet, verified through national identity numbers (NIN) such as the US's Social Security Number (SSN) or Mexico's Clave Única de Registro de Población (CURP). This method ensures that the individual behind each wallet is a living, conscious being who has not been registered as deceased. The initiative seeks to democratize financial power by limiting the ability of institutions to hold disproportionate influence over society, thereby supporting democratic principles and reducing oligarchic tendencies.

This proposal introduces a novel concept where institutional Bitcoins could be replicated into personal wallets, with a replication limit set at a socially acceptable level—potentially 10 to 20 times the average wealth of a global citizen. Unclaimed Bitcoins within a three-month period in this new blockchain system would vanish, thus becoming available for mining as new Bitcoins. This mechanism aims to distribute wealth more equitably and ensure that digital currency contributes positively to societal balance.

To accommodate countries without a reliable NIN system, the proposal suggests alternative methods such as biometric identification or other solutions developed cooperatively with the Bitcoin community, including miners and nodes. These alternatives are aimed at verifying the individual’s status as a conscious living being, with genome or blood tests considered as complementary options for future implementation. Despite the potential reduction in anonymity, which is a hallmark of Bitcoin, the proposal is viewed as a beneficial move towards mitigating inequality and corruption within the digital currency space.

By restricting the new form of Bitcoin to individuals and excluding institutions, the proposal aligns with the internet’s foundational spirit of democratization, offering a platform for global equity. This shift could enable broader utilization of digital currencies for the common good, echoing the original democratizing intentions of the internet and digital currencies. The detailed discussion and initial proposal were made available on GitHub but had to be relocated due to forum guidelines, with the full content accessible via the provided [original post](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/32897?reload=1?reload=1).</summary>
    <published>2025-07-27T13:18:07.445000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
