<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-21T03:08:18.106162+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jesseposner 2025-07-20 18:46:55.734000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-19 22:10:01.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-19 19:24:15.695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2025-07-18 23:11:43.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-17 18:29:51.913000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2025-07-16 17:53:01.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-16 16:45:26.989000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-15 15:35:18.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 15:09:55.489000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-15 14:48:49.506000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-15 11:19:21.847000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-07-15 01:13:12.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:05:51.271000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 00:03:39.361000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:55:06.554000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-07-14 20:30:49.131000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 19:35:52.115000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 18:26:10.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-14 15:09:06.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 09:31:50.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-07 16:01:15.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5526_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5524_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5522_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5519_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5512_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5505_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5497_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5485_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5484_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5482_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5479_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5471_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5467_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5466_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5465_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5464_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5460_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5459_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5458_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5450_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5412_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-21T03:08:18.106302+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing Bitcoin's security in anticipation of quantum computing threats has yielded several pivotal considerations and proposals. At the heart of these discussions is the recognition of the potential vulnerability of a significant portion of Bitcoin's supply to quantum-enabled attacks, particularly those coins held in outputs susceptible to discrete logarithm (DL) based exploits. The conversations acknowledge that individual efforts to secure assets in quantum-safe outputs might prove insufficient if a large volume of insecure coins remains, posing a risk of market flooding by stolen coins. This scenario underscores the importance of a collective migration towards more secure asset holdings, potentially through assets or forks of Bitcoin that offer enhanced security without compromising on principles such as property rights.

Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) play a critical role in strategizing against quantum vulnerabilities, with debates focusing on the introduction of measures to secure transactions. One approach suggests disabling checksig opcodes for existing scripts, urging a transition to quantum-safe output types. However, concerns about the high fee costs associated with quantum-resistant signatures have led to the proposal of P2QRH, which aims to provide a quantum-secure transaction method without imposing significant financial burdens on users. This dual-capability model encourages adoption by reducing costs and facilitating a smoother transition to quantum-resistant practices.

Critiques of current proposals highlight their potential inadequacy in fully mitigating quantum threats, especially without a direct prohibition of DL-based spending. These critiques call for more radical consensus changes to effectively protect the network. Moreover, there's a continuous exploration of innovative solutions like borrowing concepts from SPHINCS to create dynamic script endorsements, aiming for a gradual move towards quantum-resistant addresses. Additionally, discussions extend to the technical aspects of implementing Taproot and other upgrades, emphasizing the need for compatibility with future payload sizes and addressing privacy concerns inherent in MAST outputs.

Privacy concerns are also paramount, with suggestions for 'taproot v2' aimed at concealing certain transaction details to maintain user anonymity. Yet, this does not address quantum resistance directly, leaving room for further enhancement. An unconventional proposal suggests using SegWit versions as markers for specific transaction output types, aiming for clearer identification and usability, though this raises questions about its technical and community acceptance.

Further discussions revolve around optimizing blockchain transactions regarding protocol versions and smart contract compositions. The choice between P2TR and P2QRH reflects a balancing act between transaction efficiency and quantum security. The collaborative nature of these discussions is evident in exchanges over proposed changes and naming conventions, reflecting a broader commitment to improving Bitcoin's infrastructure in the face of quantum computing advancements.

Ultimately, the evolution of BIP-360 signifies a strategic pivot towards leveraging taproot structures for quantum resistance, proposing a script-only version of P2TR and planning for the integration of post-quantum signature verification opcodes. This forward-looking stance prioritizes flexibility and security, preparing the Bitcoin protocol for a future where quantum computing capabilities may pose a tangible threat to cryptographic foundations.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-20T18:46:55.734000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
