<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-22T02:43:21.734830+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger 2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-22T02:43:21.734907+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion explores the intricacies and potential challenges of implementing silent payments within the Nostr protocol, specifically focusing on transaction notification and privacy issues. One key challenge identified is ensuring that transactions are not lost due to Nostr's lack of a global state, raising concerns about the possibility of missed notifications if Alice and Bob do not share a common relay or if a relay deletes a note before it can be seen. A proposed solution involves Alice rebroadcasting the notification note until Bob confirms receipt, although this requires an overlap in their relay sets. This problem might be mitigated by wallets ensuring they check for transactions within a range around the last received index, but this does not address scenarios where Bob receives transactions from Alice infrequently. The discussion also highlights the risk of malicious actors flooding receivers with fake notifications, a concern given the minimal scanning effort required by the proposed system compared to traditional Silent Payments, which offer protections such as Proof of Work (PoW) against transaction flooding.

Another aspect covered is the use of `npub` keys on the Nostr platform for creating stealth addresses, emphasizing the importance of key exchange for secure communications and transactions. It delves into the mechanics of generating new keys from `npub` for receiving bitcoin payments, illustrating the cryptographic processes that enable Alice and Bob to establish a shared secret and generate stealth keys for private exchanges. This process underscores the nuanced approach to maintaining confidentiality and user anonymity on the platform through cryptographic practices.

Furthermore, the proposal introduces a cryptographic method where Alice generates a new key for Bob and notifies him via an encrypted message using NIP-17, detailing the equations and mechanisms involved. This method aims to streamline the monitoring of transactions by Bob, potentially reducing the computational overhead associated with address monitoring in cryptographic systems. The email signifies a deep interest in dissecting the mathematical and cryptographic framework of the proposed solution, seeking clarity on its operational specifics and structural intricacies.

Nostr's adoption of cryptographic techniques similar to Bitcoin's, combined with improvements on limitations found in BIP 47 version 1, proposes an innovative approach to stealth payment notifications. By allowing Alice to generate a new key for Bob and notify him through encrypted messages, Nostr aims to enhance user experience without compromising privacy. This is further illustrated through a Python code example demonstrating the generation of stealth keys and showcasing Nostr's potential to improve upon Bitcoin's privacy features. The code serves as a guide for developers to integrate stealth payment capabilities into their applications, encouraging further innovation in cryptocurrency payments and privacy enhancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-21T17:50:10.995000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
