<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
  <updated>2025-07-05T02:46:30.794503+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-07-04 18:22:21.558000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-07-04 18:07:40.193000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-07-04 14:07:13.432000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-07-04 13:24:37.788000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2025-07-03 20:09:21.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5406_Understanding-and-Mitigating-a-OP-CTV-Footgun-The-Unsatisfiable-UTXO.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5405_Understanding-and-Mitigating-a-OP-CTV-Footgun-The-Unsatisfiable-UTXO.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5404_Understanding-and-Mitigating-a-OP-CTV-Footgun-The-Unsatisfiable-UTXO.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5403_Understanding-and-Mitigating-a-OP-CTV-Footgun-The-Unsatisfiable-UTXO.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5402_Understanding-and-Mitigating-a-OP-CTV-Footgun-The-Unsatisfiable-UTXO.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Understanding and Mitigating a OP_CTV Footgun: The Unsatisfiable UTXO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-05T02:46:30.794560+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/understanding-and-mitigating-a-op-ctv-footgun-the-unsatisfiable-utxo/1809" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and potential solutions involved in managing `OP_CTV` (CheckTemplateVerify) templates within Bitcoin scripting, specifically addressing the issue of underfunded transactions. The primary concern lies with `OP_CTV` templates that commit to exactly one input, which can lead to the creation of permanently unspendable Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) if the incoming amount does not precisely match the committed amount. This situation necessitates a design where at least two inputs are committed within the `OP_CTV` template, providing a mechanism for correcting discrepancies post-creation of the UTXO. This approach mitigates the risk of locking funds indefinitely by allowing the addition of a secondary input to adjust the total amount to the intended target.

The usefulness of incorporating multiple inputs into `OP_CTV` templates extends beyond error correction, offering a pathway for applications like vault constructions. Vaults, which secure large amounts of funds in `OP_CTV` outputs, benefit from the flexibility of adjusting or recovering underfunded amounts. Despite the drawbacks of increased transaction size and slightly higher fees due to the additional input, the security and fund management benefits are considered to outweigh these concerns. A Python test showcases the practical implementation of this recovery process, demonstrating how a secondary input can effectively rectify an underfunded `OP_CTV` UTXO.

Further exploration into integrating `OP_CTV` with other proposals such as `[OP_{IN,OUT}_AMOUNT](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549)` is ongoing, aiming to enhance the safety and efficiency of forwarding address contracts. These efforts align with the goals of the `[AMOUNTVERIFY](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/fd1955694b95440bde70890475548dfb59e2e759/bip-0119.mediawikiop_amountverify)` concept proposed in BIP119, striving to refine the `OP_CTV` functionality within the Bitcoin protocol. The collective advancements in this area underline the commitment to ensuring transactional security while accommodating the need for flexibility in fund management.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-04T18:22:21.558000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
