<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T03:08:39.073691+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-08-04 16:05:38.162000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-08-04 11:24:34.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>chris  . 2025-08-03 11:57:18.875000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-23 11:53:33.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rafael  . 2025-07-21 13:45:12.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>scgbckbone  . 2025-07-21 12:55:15.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-07-21 09:28:45.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-07-21 09:22:39.376000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-19 00:58:18.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-16 11:27:15.836000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-16 10:28:56.706000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-16 09:27:16.850000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>scgbckbone  . 2025-07-16 09:08:20.167000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>scgbckbone  . 2025-07-16 08:34:31.869000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-16 02:02:26.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-15 15:04:53.147000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-15 06:13:47.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-15 06:10:54.947000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-15 06:09:14.255000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-15 05:52:08.461000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-07-14 09:29:43.875000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2025-07-10 21:18:02.242000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-10 04:50:02.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5635_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5631_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5624_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5544_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5532_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5530_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5529_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5528_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5520_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5494_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5493_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5492_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5491_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5490_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5489_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5483_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5477_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5476_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5475_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5473_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5449_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5434_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5425_Exploring-Extended-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T03:08:39.073845+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse encompasses various aspects of implementing and extending timelocks within the Bitcoin protocol, revealing a multifaceted exploration into enhancing the functionality and user experience of cryptocurrency transactions. At the heart of these discussions is an interest in leveraging the Taproot annex to extend relative timelocks and introduce per-input absolute timelocks under a unified proposal aimed at improving timelock features. The conversation acknowledges the complexity and potential risks associated with activating new consensus rules, emphasizing the need for widespread miner support to ensure the integrity and stability of the network. This process underscores the importance of backward compatibility and careful planning to facilitate smooth transitions across different versions of network software.

A significant portion of the discussion delves into the technicalities and implications of implementing a soft fork to modify the timelock parameter, proposing an eightfold extension to the current setting. This suggestion brings to light concerns about network security and the challenges of aligning older nodes with new protocol versions, highlighting the delicate balance required to advance technological improvements while maintaining system robustness.

The conversation also critiques the use of absolute timelocks and the stacking of multiple wallets as inadequate for certain applications, like dead-man-switch scenarios, due to the inability to "disable" old wallets effectively. This limitation is seen as a catalyst for security vulnerabilities and operational inefficiencies, driving the need for protocol enhancements to address these issues. Furthermore, it emphasizes the simplification of policy/miniscript to improve readability and validation on signing devices by average users, aiming to bridge the gap between complex policy creation and end-user interaction.

Exploring the concept of refreshing the relative lock through techniques like transferring funds to reset the nLockTime value, the discussion reflects on the challenges of maintaining comprehensive backups and validating updated policies on all signing devices. This aspect highlights the intricacies of managing Bitcoin transactions and the importance of thorough procedures to safeguard transaction integrity.

Moreover, the dialogue touches upon the proposal to extend the duration of relative timelocks to accommodate uses like long-term custody and inheritance planning, recognizing the practicality of longer timelocks for specific applications. This consideration leads to a broader reflection on the future-proofing of the Bitcoin protocol to support more flexible and extended timelock capabilities, addressing the evolving needs of the user base.

The debate around the potential expansion of relative timelock limits to ~10 years underscores the desire for a more straightforward and inherently flexible system, despite acknowledging the risks associated with locking funds for extended durations. The discussion explores technical considerations for implementing extended timelocks, including the use of a bit 21 flag with 8-block units to maintain granularity while expanding capacity. This approach signifies a strategic move towards system simplification, prioritizing ease of use and robustness over maintaining legacy features that may no longer serve the majority of user requirements effectively.

In conclusion, the discourse encapsulates a comprehensive examination of extending timelock functionalities in the Bitcoin protocol, balancing technical feasibility with the broader implications for network stability, user experience, and security. Through careful consideration of various perspectives and potential solutions, the conversation illuminates the ongoing efforts to adapt and enhance the Bitcoin ecosystem to meet the complex and dynamic needs of its users.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:05:38.162000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
