<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
  <updated>2025-09-27T02:20:23.388597+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-09-26 14:34:32.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger  . 2025-09-21 17:50:10.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-18 07:56:53.710000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-17 20:21:08.582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-09-17 10:58:14.858000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-09-15 18:38:45.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-07-09 17:13:25.556000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5976_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5943_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5912_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5909_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5891_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5878_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5419_Stealth-addresses-using-nostr.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stealth addresses using nostr</title>
    <updated>2025-09-27T02:20:23.388665+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stealth-addresses-using-nostr/1816" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on integrating nostr notifications with Silent Payments delves into the complexities and potential solutions to ensuring that transaction notifications are reliably communicated within a decentralized, stateless environment. The concerns revolve around the possibility of missed or lost notifications due to the nature of nostr's architecture, which lacks a global state, potentially leading to scenarios where transaction notifications fail to reach their intended recipients. This situation is further complicated by various factors, including the reliance on relays for the dissemination of notifications, the risk posed by malicious actors flooding the system with fake notifications, and challenges related to metadata leakage. Despite these challenges, the integration of nostr notifications with Silent Payments is seen as a promising avenue for streamlining transactional communication while preserving privacy and reducing the need for intensive scanning efforts typically associated with Silent Payments. The approach suggests leveraging recent advancements in nostr for private messaging and minimizing metadata leakage, thereby enhancing security and efficiency in transaction notifications.

The exchange between parties utilizing nostr involves a sophisticated interplay of cryptographic techniques, including the generation of new keys and the secure transmission of payment information. The proposal under consideration explores the utilization of `npub` keys for creating stealth addresses, indicating a tailored approach to maintaining privacy and anonymity within transactions. The technical aspects of this approach involve generating new keys for receiving bitcoin payments and ensuring secure communication through the encryption of messages using specific protocols like NIP-17. The methodology suggested includes mathematical equations and operational strategies aimed at avoiding the need for extensive scanning, thus streamlining the process of monitoring transactions. This approach underscores a deep interest in the cryptographic foundations of secure and efficient key exchanges within the context of nostr and Bitcoin.

Furthermore, the application of nostr's cryptographic methodologies extends to the generation of stealth keys, facilitating private transactions while leveraging shared secrets between parties. This includes detailed procedures for creating and using stealth public and private keys, illustrating the capacity of nostr to enhance privacy features within Bitcoin payments. The provision of Python code examples demonstrates the practical implementation of these concepts, offering developers a concrete foundation upon which to build and innovate. By addressing the limitations of existing protocols and introducing mechanisms for stealth payment notifications, the exploration provides insights into the potential for nostr to significantly improve the user experience and security of cryptocurrency transactions. Through this engagement with cryptographic principles and the development of practical solutions, the discussion contributes to the broader discourse on privacy, security, and efficiency in digital financial interactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-26T14:34:32.020000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
