<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Augur: Block’s Open Source Bitcoin Fee Estimation Library</title>
  <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:50.919997+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2025-07-17 21:30:12.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>lauren 2025-07-17 20:51:59.595000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2025-07-17 09:26:05.142000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>lauren  . 2025-07-16 22:04:13.944000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5514_Augur-Block-s-Open-Source-Bitcoin-Fee-Estimation-Library.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5513_Augur-Block-s-Open-Source-Bitcoin-Fee-Estimation-Library.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5511_Augur-Block-s-Open-Source-Bitcoin-Fee-Estimation-Library.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5510_Augur-Block-s-Open-Source-Bitcoin-Fee-Estimation-Library.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Augur: Block’s Open Source Bitcoin Fee Estimation Library</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T03:02:50.920049+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/augur-block-s-open-source-bitcoin-fee-estimation-library/1848" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The examination of Bitcoin Core's version used for generating results from the Blockstream API reveals an assumption pointing towards version 27.2, based on a specific Dockerfile from Blockstream's GitHub repository. This analysis suggests that versions 28.0 and above are expected to feature lower overestimations and a reduced average overestimation factor due to significant improvements, specifically the switch to an economical default mode. There is anticipation around the release of version 1 of a benchmarking tool which promises to incorporate additional metrics like the average overestimation factor, aimed at evaluating the severity of overpayments in transaction fees. This development is part of a broader effort to refine fee estimation methodologies.

Block has contributed to these efforts by making its Bitcoin fee estimation library, Augur, available to the public. Augur distinguishes itself by utilizing live mempool data for fee recommendations, departing from the traditional approach of relying on historical block data. This real-time model is designed to offer more accurate fee suggestions, enhancing the user experience in executing Bitcoin transactions. The library is accessible with a reference implementation in Kotlin and a public API endpoint, facilitating easy integration and experimentation for developers.

Augur's methodology emphasizes a mempool-first strategy, prioritizing current transaction volumes and the inherent unpredictability of Bitcoin mining. This approach allows Augur to accurately predict confirmation times by analyzing the mempool's fee rate categories and transaction inflow rates. Such a methodology presents a dynamic alternative to conventional models, enabling adjustments to fee recommendations based on real-time network conditions.

In evaluating Augur's performance, Block developed a custom benchmarking tool that assesses accuracy and cost-effectiveness through various metrics, including miss rate, average overestimate, and a composite score reflecting under and overestimation. Preliminary findings indicate that Augur offers a reliable yet cost-efficient solution compared to other major fee estimators, particularly during periods of normal-to-moderate mempool volatility. Block plans to release this benchmarking tool as open source, encouraging community involvement in validating Augur's performance and contributing to the ongoing improvement of Bitcoin fee estimation methods. Developers and Bitcoin enthusiasts are invited to explore Augur and its reference implementation to better understand how it can enhance application and transaction efficiency on the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T21:30:12.150000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
