<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
  <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:00.922927+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-07-15 01:13:12.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-15 00:05:51.271000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-15 00:03:39.361000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2025-07-14 20:55:06.554000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2025-07-14 20:30:49.131000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman 2025-07-14 19:35:52.115000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-14 18:26:10.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman 2025-07-14 15:09:06.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-07-14 09:31:50.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthanHeilman  . 2025-07-07 16:01:15.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5471_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5467_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5466_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5465_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5464_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5460_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5459_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5458_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5450_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5412_Changes-to-BIP-360-Pay-to-Quantum-Resistant-Hash-P2QRH-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changes to BIP-360 - Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T03:07:00.923006+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changes-to-bip-360-pay-to-quantum-resistant-hash-p2qrh/1811" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions and proposals surrounding Bitcoin Improvement Proposal 360 (BIP-360) have highlighted significant considerations for enhancing Bitcoin's security in the face of potential quantum computing threats. The modification to transition Pay to Quantum Resistant Hash (P2QRH) towards a script-only version of Taproot, removing the key-spend pathway vulnerable to quantum attacks, marks a pivotal shift. This change ensures that P2QRH outputs are directly committed to the tapleaf merkle root, leveraging the taproot structure to bolster security against these futuristic computational threats. The specific scriptPubKey definition for P2QRH outputs aligns with this goal by simplifying the implementation process and magnifying its defense mechanism against long-exposure quantum attacks, which pose a more immediate risk than their short-exposure counterparts.

The proactive approach taken avoids the drastic measure of disabling key-spends in Taproot upon the advent of quantum-capable attacks, offering the community time to adapt without resorting to emergency consensus changes. This foresight allows for a more measured response to the quantum threat, providing a buffer against the urgency that such advancements might precipitate. Additionally, BIP-360 articulates a plan for Post-Quantum (PQ) signatures that decouples the commitment to specific PQ signature algorithms from the proposal, thereby permitting independent progress on PQ signature standards. This separation is crucial for avoiding premature decisions on PQ signatures while still moving forward with enhancements to quantum resistance.

The proposal also envisages the future inclusion of tapscript PQ signature verification opcodes for ML-DSA and SLH-DSA through OP_SUCCESSx opcodes, laying a groundwork for adopting PQ signature algorithms separately as needed. This flexible strategy ensures that new signature algorithms can be integrated into the Bitcoin protocol without necessitating new versions of tapleaf, thus maintaining compatibility and ease of adoption. An upcoming BIP is expected to detail the specifications for these PQ signatures, contributing to the ongoing efforts to safeguard Bitcoin against quantum computing threats. This comprehensive approach underscores the Bitcoin community's commitment to future-proofing the network, ensuring its resilience in the face of evolving technological landscapes.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-15T01:13:12.060000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
