<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-07-16T02:07:32.717597+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-11-02T21:44:47.087000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T02:07:32.717630+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/segwit-ephemeral-anchors/160/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency addresses, specific modifications to a two-digit code can result in different types of bech32m addresses. For instance, changing the code to `0x4e73` generates the address `bc1pfeessrawgf`, which interestingly breaks down into a predictable structure: the prefix "bc1p", followed by a segment that can vary ("fees" in this case), and concluded with a checksum. This pattern is applicable across various codes; for example, `0xffff` leads to `bc1plllsqd8ech`, while setting the code at `0x0100` (which represents the number 1) results in `bc1pqyqqgs7ult`. Similarly, using `0x0001` (or 256 in decimal) produces `bc1pqqqs4em24r`. 

The versatility in generating these addresses is further highlighted through different network prefixes. For Testnet or Signet networks, modifying the code to `0x4e73` yields an address like `tb1pfees9rn5nz`, whereas for Regtest, it results in `bcrt1pfeesnyr2tx`. Such variations underscore the adaptability of bech32m addresses to different blockchain environments.

For enthusiasts interested in exploring various combinations and their corresponding addresses, the Bitcoin command-line interface (CLI) tool provides a means to decode scripts through the command `bitcoin-cli decodescript 51024e73`. This functionality allows users to engage with the technology hands-on, offering a bridge between theoretical knowledge and practical application in the creation and analysis of cryptocurrency addresses.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-02T21:44:47.087000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
