<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-07-16T02:07:12.685531+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-08 17:25:23.577000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T02:07:12.685564+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/segwit-ephemeral-anchors/160/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency transactions, particularly those involving Bitcoin scripting, there's an emerging discussion on the preference between supporting `OP_TRUE` and `OP_TRUE 0x4e73`. The consideration for choosing one over the other hinges on a nuanced difference that might not significantly impact all users. However, it opens up an option for users who prioritize transaction flexibility over the technical benefits of Segregated Witness (SegWit).

SegWit was introduced to improve the scalability of cryptocurrency networks by separating the witness from the transaction block. This separation enhances the efficiency of block size usage and mitigates certain types of transaction malleability. Despite these benefits, there remains a subset of users who may opt for non-SegWit transactions due to their indifference towards the stability of child transactions' transaction identifier (txid). For such users, the choice between using `OP_TRUE` and `OP_TRUE 0x4e73` is presented as a way to accommodate preferences related to txid stability without mandating a shift to SegWit.

This ongoing dialogue reflects the broader ethos of cryptocurrency development, where user autonomy and technical optimization are often balanced through flexible protocol design. By allowing users to select between `OP_TRUE` and `OP_TRUE 0x4e73`, developers acknowledge the diversity in user priorities and the importance of facilitating a range of transactional behaviors within the ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-08T17:25:23.577000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
