<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
  <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:30.529417+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-11-08T22:44:10.093000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:30.529456+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/defunct-post-clustermempool-package-rbf/173/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the process of integrating `minrelay` into the transaction handling paradigm, several key steps are outlined to ensure the efficiency and security of transactions before they are added to the mempool. Initially, a pre-eviction step is crucial where any part of a transaction, referred to as a chunk, that does not meet the minimum fee rate specified by either `mempoolminfee` or `incremental_relay_feerate` is removed. This step acts as a form of Denial-of-Service (DoS) protection by ensuring that only transactions contributing sufficient fees are considered for addition to the mempool. An example provided illustrates this mechanism: comparing two transactions of the same size, one with no fee and the other with a minimal fee, the latter would be accepted into the mempool if submitted independently. However, when these transactions are submitted as a package, the entire package could be rejected if the combined score falls below the `minrelay` threshold. This ensures that the system prioritizes transactions that collectively cover their processing costs.

Following the pre-eviction step, the verification process involves a thorough check of all transactions within the `PKG` against several criteria including policy compliance, standardness rules, and available Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) from various sources like the blockchain itself, the mempool, and the `PKG`. This verification likely includes script execution to validate transaction authenticity and integrity.

The final addition step detailed involves adding transactions from the `PKG` to the mempool one at a time, subject to consensus validation. This raises questions about potential failures during this phase, suggesting the complexity of ensuring transactions are both valid and in agreement with network consensus rules. The mention of a `TimeToSize` step, although briefly touched upon, indicates an additional layer of validation that correlates the temporal aspect with transaction size, further emphasizing the multifaceted nature of transaction handling within this framework.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-08T22:44:10.093000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
