<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
  <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:16.371663+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-09 00:30:37.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:16.371696+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/defunct-post-clustermempool-package-rbf/173/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of handling transactions within a package (`PKG`) involves several critical steps aimed at ensuring both efficiency and security in the management of mempool transactions. Initially, any part of the `PKG` that does not meet the minimum fee rate requirements, either set by `mempoolminfee` or `incremental_relay_feerate`, is eliminated. This step, termed as pre-eviction, is crucial for optimizing the process rather than serving as a direct measure against Denial of Service (DoS) attacks. 

Following the initial filtration, the verification stage commences, where transactions within the `PKG` are scrutinized based on policy and standardness rules, utilizing Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) from various sources including the blockchain, the mempool itself, and the `PKG`. This ensures that the transactions are not only valid but also desirable, considering they adhere to expected fee rates without yet undergoing consensus checks, which could reveal them as incompatible or undesirable.

A significant point of discussion revolves around the operational sequence for handling connected components within the `PKG`. Given the potential for targeted transaction eviction through package relay strategies, there's contemplation over restricting peer-to-peer (p2p) package relay to singular transactions and their ancestors. This limitation could mitigate risks associated with accepting broader transaction packages over p2p networks.

The debate extends to the overall adequacy of the current approach, illustrated through diagrams showcasing transaction interactions within the mempool. An example provided demonstrates the benefits of an ancestor-first package acceptance method. By prioritizing transactions with ancestors in the mempool, it's possible to maintain a streamlined and efficient processing order. This method suggests a more dynamic handling of transactions by sequentially adding new transactions from `PKG` after linear analysis and updates to the relevant datasets (`OLD`, `NEW`, and `CON`). Should a chunk within the `PKG` prove non-beneficial or fail validation, the procedure is halted entirely, emphasizing a cautious yet systematic approach to mempool management.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-09T00:30:37.503000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
