<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
  <updated>2024-11-20T03:22:50.257504+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-11-14T20:10:10.012000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T03:22:50.257537+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/defunct-post-clustermempool-package-rbf/173/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a proposal aimed at refining the process of handling transactions within a Bitcoin system, specifically focusing on the Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanism and how it processes transactions in chunks. The initial suggestion was to modify an existing proposal with added justification and an example that highlights the current method's limitations. However, it was decided to introduce these ideas through a new topic instead of updating the existing description. This decision was made to ensure clarity and to provide a dedicated space for discussing the nuances of the proposed changes.

The new proposal, as introduced, suggests a shift towards processing transactions in chunks, a method previously recommended by another contributor named AJ. This approach is believed to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the RBF mechanism. The proposal's details, including its justification and an illustrative example showing its advantages over the current system, are now accessible through a newly created topic on the forum [Delving into Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-clustermempool-package-rbf-per-chunk-processing/190). This move facilitates a focused discussion on the subject, allowing contributors to delve deeper into the specifics of the proposal and its potential impact on transaction processing within the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-14T20:10:10.012000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
