<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Post-clustermempool package RBF: per-chunk processing</title>
  <updated>2024-05-24T02:01:25.788431+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-15 03:05:41.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Post-clustermempool package RBF: per-chunk processing</title>
    <updated>2024-05-24T02:01:25.788463+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-clustermempool-package-rbf-per-chunk-processing/190/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussion regarding transaction processing and mempool management within a blockchain network, the focus is on whether it is practical to pass on information about transactions that have been accepted into the mempool, especially in scenarios where certain transactions are prioritized due to higher fees or are dependent on other transactions. A suggestion was made to potentially recognize transactions that pay Denial-of-Service (DoS) fees for higher priority or to keep track of transactions orphaned specifically for DoS reasons. This would allow for such transactions to be retried when their high-fee child transactions are announced. 

However, there's an inclination towards initially omitting this feature, with the possibility of introducing it later as an improvement. The rationale behind this approach includes considerations of simplicity and the likelihood that the scenario may not occur frequently enough to justify immediate implementation. This decision aligns with the Keep It Simple, Stupid (KISS) principle, emphasizing the importance of maintaining straightforward and uncomplicated systems.

Despite reservations, there's acknowledgment of the potential usefulness of reliably implementing such a feature. It is recognized that accurately tracking and managing these interdependent transactions could enhance the efficiency and reliability of the network's transaction handling capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-15T03:05:41.951000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
