<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
  <updated>2024-05-31T02:02:45.530320+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-26 16:24:32.871000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
    <updated>2024-05-31T02:02:45.530356+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of setting up algorithms, particularly focusing on how prefix intersection algorithms play a crucial role. By elaborating on the concept where $c_{j+1}$ represents a chunk within $\gamma_j + c_{j+1}$, due to the structure $\gamma_j = c_1 + c_2 + ... + c_j$, and how these chunks are correctly assembled, it's clear that this setup facilitates a systematic approach to generating chunking by merging transaction sets in any sequence. This methodology inherently avoids the need to split chunks once they're formed, allowing for a more streamlined process.

Further exploration into formalizing these concepts using lean4 is mentioned, albeit with an admission of slow progress. The ability to convert a list of transactions into a chunking and to compare fee rate graphs demonstrates a significant step towards understanding and applying these principles practically. These fee rate graphs are evaluated at each integer byte/weight with a total fee in $\mathbb{Q}$, indicating a meticulous approach to analyzing transaction efficiency and cost-effectiveness.

However, challenges in defining diagrams for these processes are acknowledged, particularly when attempting to represent them as functions from $\mathbb{N} \to \mathbb{Q}$. The initial strategy of plotting line segments from $(s_1,f_1)$ to $(s_2,f_2)$ was found to be overly complex, suggesting that simplification or alternative methods might be necessary to enhance understanding and applicability of these concepts.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-26T16:24:32.871000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
