<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Linearization post-processing (O(n^2) fancy chunking)</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:25:57.928540+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2023-11-29 22:52:59.338000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Linearization post-processing (O(n^2) fancy chunking)</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:25:57.928540+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/linearization-post-processing-o-n-2-fancy-chunking/201/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post begins by discussing a significant observation within the realm of Bitcoin transaction processing. Specifically, it refers to an insight made by a user named @sdaftuar concerning the application of the gathering theorem to a particular problem in transaction sequence organization.

The gathering theorem, a concept derived from the field of prefix-intersection merging, provides a framework for understanding how reordering transactions can lead to optimized outcomes in terms of fee rates. This theorem is instrumental in explaining why certain alterations to transaction sequences can be beneficial. It particularly highlights that when dealing with two disconnected sequences of transactions—each grouped in linearization—the action of swapping these sequences so that the one with a higher fee rate follows the other invariably results in an improvement. The rationale behind this is that it aligns the transactions according to their fee rates, thereby potentially leading to more efficient block space utilization and increased miner revenue.

The referenced theorem is detailed in a discussion on DelvingBitcoin.org, where users explore complex topics related to Bitcoin's underlying technology. For those interested in delving deeper into the specifics of the gathering theorem and prefix-intersection merging, the provided links lead to an in-depth conversation about merging incomparable linearizations (https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209/28) and the general topic (https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209).

In essence, this observation underscores the value of careful transaction ordering within the Bitcoin network and its impact on the efficiency and profitability of mining operations. As such, it presents a potential area of interest for developers and researchers looking to refine transaction processing protocols.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-29T22:52:59.338000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
