<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:15:04.435592+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-11-30T19:30:00.473000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:15:04.435592+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209/31" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion delves into the construction of a feerate diagram for the combined lists $L_G + L_B$, focusing on the comparison between different subsets and their corresponding diagrams. The core idea presented is to evaluate the feerate efficiency of a combined list by comparing it to the original list $L$. To do this, the sender suggests an approach where the initial segments, characterized by having a feerate of $f$ or lower, are collectively considered, followed by the remaining portion of $L_G$ not included in these segments, which has a higher feerate.

A key concept introduced is the 'kinking' up of the diagram when including the suffix of $L_G$. This kinking indicates that the subset being considered is more efficient than the former chunks, including up to $c_j$. A visual aid is mentioned as being added to better illustrate this point.

Furthermore, the discussion evolves towards an alternative representation method using a ray plot. Here, the suggestion is to plot points $P(\gamma_i)$, representing different segments for specific ranges along the x-axis, with their corresponding $R(\gamma_i)$ values plotted on the y-axis. The goal is to compare two diagrams by checking if one lies entirely below the other, implying a more optimal chunking reflected by a monotonically decreasing line.

Finally, there appears to be a bit of confusion regarding whether to plot the feerate $R(\gamma_i)$ or the fee $F(\gamma_i)$. It's clarified that plotting the fee would result in a monotonically increasing line since fees cannot be negative, contrasting with the earlier implication of plotting the feerate.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-30T19:30:00.473000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
