<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-07-16T02:08:19.891929+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-07-15 20:00:25.016000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-22 13:48:35.594000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-22 12:27:47.317000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2023-11-22 10:25:57.154000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-13 15:57:43.826000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2023-11-13 15:38:31.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-13 14:25:54.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2023-11-13 05:25:40.472000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-08 17:25:23.577000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-02 21:45:36.219000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-11-02 21:44:47.087000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-02 19:51:15.616000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders 2023-11-02 17:50:55.522000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2880_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/461_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/460_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/459_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/397_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/396_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/395_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/393_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/347_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/330_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/328_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/329_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/327_Segwit-Ephemeral-Anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Segwit Ephemeral Anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T02:08:19.892024+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/segwit-ephemeral-anchors/160" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discussion revolves around the technical aspects and proposed enhancements to Bitcoin's scripting and transaction mechanisms. A specific feature, Pay To Anchor (P2A), has been introduced, with its concept and implementation details available for review and feedback at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30352). This initiative seeks to address certain limitations within the Bitcoin network, particularly focusing on script and transaction malleability by leveraging Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) 141's softfork for witness programs.

The conversation highlights a debate over the optimal size of push operations in witness programs, referencing BIP141's requirement for a push of between 2 and 40 bytes, and questioning the prohibition against 1-byte pushes. The discussion points out that a 1-byte push might introduce ambiguity and potential for malleability, hence the preference for a range that ensures clarity and security. Further examination of these technical nuances is encouraged through engagement with the Bitcoin Stack Exchange community, as seen in a question about 2-byte witness programs which suggests that the motivation behind this requirement is to avoid ambiguity in how data is pushed onto the stack ([Bitcoin Stack Exchange](https://bitcoin.stackexchange.com/questions/110660/how-could-a-2-byte-witness-program-make-sense)).

The discourse also touches upon the concept of Ephemeral Anchors, an innovative approach aimed at creating key-less output types that can hold minimal values ("dusty values"), provided they are spent within the mempool in a manner that is atomic. This concept is detailed further in a GitHub repository ([GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/26403)), highlighting its potential benefits and drawbacks, particularly its reliance on Bitcoin's legacy script system. This reliance introduces the issue of transaction ID (txid) malleability by miners due to the absence of CLEANSTACK consensus rules in legacy scripts, complicating interactions with other protocols such as splicing.

An alternative solution proposed involves utilizing BIP141's framework for witness programs to mitigate these shortcomings. By replacing certain scripts with undefined witness programs, such as changing "OP_TRUE" to "OP_TRUE 0xffff", it's possible to leverage the scriptSig rule in BIP141 while keeping the witness undefined, thereby allowing an empty witness to spend. This method offers a more efficient use of space and adheres to standard creation processes, albeit requiring additional adjustments for spending. The proposal underscores a nuanced understanding of Bitcoin's scripting capabilities and reflects an ongoing effort to refine and enhance the network's operational efficiency and security.</summary>
    <published>2024-07-15T20:00:25.016000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
