<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - [DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
  <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:54.109476+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Greg Sanders</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/352_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/413_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/407_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/405_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/404_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/368_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/366_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/360_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/359_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/357_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/353_-DEFUNCT-Post-clustermempool-Package-RBF.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - [DEFUNCT] Post-clustermempool Package RBF</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T03:24:54.109612+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/defunct-post-clustermempool-package-rbf/173/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post discusses the process and considerations involved in handling transaction packages within a Bitcoin-like network's mempool, specifically focusing on the Replace-By-Fee (RBF) rules for these packages. The initial steps of processing an incoming package include deduplication, which removes any transactions already present in the receiver's mempool, and pre-linearization, where transactions are ordered without considering dependencies in the mempool. A critical step is the pre-eviction, aimed at discarding parts of the package with a fee rate below certain thresholds, serving as DoS protection. Conflict identification between the mempool and the incoming package is crucial, leading to the creation of clusters `OLD` (existing related clusters in the mempool) and `NEW` (derived by adjusting `OLD` with the incoming package minus conflicts).

Further checks ensure the new package's fees justify its inclusion over the existing ones, including verifying that the package meets specific fee rate criteria if applicable. All transactions must comply with policy and standardness rules, validated against available UTXOs. Conflicting transactions are evicted from the mempool to make way for the incoming package, which is added after validating each transaction against consensus rules. During this process, considerations about cluster count and size limits are significant to avoid exceeding mempool constraints.

The discussion also touches on operational questions, such as whether to treat connected components within a package individually and the robustness of the proposed process. Potential complications could arise from subpackages affecting clusters differently, raising questions about the optimal strategy for merging or validating subpackages to achieve the best outcome. Two discussions elaborate on these RBF rules: an initial proposal and a more evolved design, suggesting further examination and refinement ([initial proposal](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-package-rbf-sketch/171), [evolved design](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-clustermempool-package-rbf-per-chunk-processing/190)).

Another aspect explored is the use of the peer-to-peer network for distributed computation to optimize transaction sorting within the mempool, acknowledging the challenges in finding the best subset of a proposed package due to the complex state of all affected clusters. A suggested approach involves adding packages atomically to one's mempool and relaying newly added transactions to peers, potentially minimizing unnecessary evictions and simplifying the propagation of optimal transaction sets across the network. The concept of "good enough" solutions is discussed, indicating that moderate improvements that change only edge cases might be sufficient, emphasizing the necessity of anti-pinning guarantees under certain conditions for package propagation and inclusion in block templates.

The conversation highlights various technical aspects, including the importance of pre-eviction steps for DoS protection, the verification of transactions against policy and standardness rules, and the incremental adjustments needed when adding transactions to the mempool. Questions around the need for running operations separately for each connected component in a package and the adequacy of current approaches point to the complexity of achieving optimal transaction handling within the mempool.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-29T18:50:53.731000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
