<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Project categories?</title>
  <updated>2024-05-29T02:02:28.247628+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josibake</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2554_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2551_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2546_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2545_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2440_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2438_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/522_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/440_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/402_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/401_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/332_Project-categories-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Project categories?</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T02:02:28.247713+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/project-categories/162" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies and functionalities of `wg-` tags utilized within a community framework to designate discussions that have restricted participation, with these restrictions varying across different groups. The Silent Payments Working Group, for instance, while allowing public reading, limits posting and commenting privileges to approved members only. This model is designed to keep discussions focused and ensure contributions are made by those with relevant interest or expertise. Joining such groups has been streamlined to encourage active participation without the need for cumbersome procedures. For more detailed involvement guidelines, individuals are directed to the Silent Payments Working Group's [about page](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/about-the-wg-silent-payments-category/876) and can join through the specified [wg page](https://delvingbitcoin.org/g/wg-silent-payments).

There's an expressed confusion over the use of `wg-` tags which signal that only pre-approved members can reply to proposals tagged accordingly. This system has led to frustrations among users who, after investing time in understanding specific proposals, realize they cannot participate in the discussion due to not being in the allowlisted group. A suggestion was made to introduce clear labeling for closed working groups to help distinguish them from open discussions, addressing concerns over the potential misinterpretation of consensus among experts when critics are unable to respond.

The creation of the 'wg-silent-payments' protocol emerged from offline collaborative efforts aiming at improving payment processes. This initiative seeks to address various aspects crucial to the development of silent payments, like standardizing indexes for light clients and PSBT support, by gathering related discussions under one umbrella to facilitate efficient progression towards drafting Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) or initiating mailing list posts.

Moreover, the 'wg-cluster-mempool' project, originally kept private and restricted to group members, has now transitioned to a public domain, marking a significant move towards openness while maintaining regulated contribution rights. This approach may serve as a model for other groups seeking a balance between inclusivity and controlled access.

The formation of the implementation:wg-blockrelay working group within the Bitcoin Core community, discussed in [Issue 28462 on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/28462), emphasizes specialized technical discussions aimed at optimizing network connections for block relay purposes. The innovative management of discussion platforms allows for private categories limited to group members, read-only categories accessible to a wider audience, and moderated public categories, enhancing both engagement and content quality.

Bitcoin-inquisition stands out as a specialized tool for analyzing the impact of proposed consensus changes on the Bitcoin network, facilitating informed decision-making regarding the adoption of such changes. 

Lastly, the proposal to introduce a 'tools and libraries' category aims to centralize programming resources, making it easier for programmers to locate necessary tools and libraries. This initiative promises to be a valuable asset for the programming community by consolidating resources in a structured manner, reflecting the latest technological advancements and trends. Additionally, the idea of providing dedicated categories for bitcoin-related projects on platforms like GitHub, exemplified by [bitcoin-inquisition](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/wiki), suggests a streamlined approach for managing and accessing project-specific discussions and information.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-28T12:25:42.955000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
