<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
  <updated>2024-06-19T02:03:20.900013+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2737_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2724_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2229_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/786_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/541_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/516_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/448_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T02:03:20.900077+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/differential-fuzzing-of-bitcoin-implementations/208" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The programming community has been actively engaging with recent updates in the realm of cryptocurrency, notably within Bitcoin's development libraries and tools. A significant enhancement has been the addition of `btcd` support, though it introduces a challenge with an API mismatch in transaction decoding when compared to Bitcoin Core's behavior. This discrepancy could influence interoperability between different Bitcoin implementations. Additionally, the `rust-bitcoin` library has encountered a bug where it neglects to check for the witness flag in transactions that possess empty witnesses, potentially complicating the witness verification process. An issue has also been identified in the `rust-miniscript` library regarding the rejection of certain miniscripts and inconsistencies in validating miniscripts from strings, particularly with the handling of the `+` sign in specific expressions. This difference from Bitcoin Core's parsing logic points to a need for alignment in script compatibility and functionality.

Furthermore, the parser function within `rust-miniscript` continues to use recursion, contrasting with Bitcoin Core's updated approach and leading to some miniscripts being valid for Core but rejected by `rust-miniscript` due to maximum recursion depth limitations. These developments underscore the dynamic nature of cryptocurrency programming, where community feedback and contributions are essential for ongoing improvements.

A new vulnerability in the Rust Bitcoin library, documented under issue 2681, emphasizes the community's role in identifying and addressing software weaknesses. This effort is critical for maintaining the library's robustness as a tool within the Bitcoin ecosystem ([GitHub Issue](https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-bitcoin/issues/2681)). Another technical concern involves a crash in the rust-miniscript repository, attracting attention from the development community, including notable contributors. The issue, tracked under identifier 633, highlights the importance of prompt resolutions to maintain the integrity of applications dependent on rust-miniscript ([GitHub Issue Comment](https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-miniscript/issues/633issuecomment-1856401701)).

This collaborative environment is further exemplified by the focus on differential fuzzing projects like bitcoinfuzz, which targets Bitcoin implementations and libraries. The project seeks community input to refine its fuzzing strategies, demonstrating an open invitation for contributions that could bolster the security and reliability of Bitcoin technologies ([bitcoinfuzz GitHub](https://github.com/brunoerg/bitcoinfuzz)). These instances reflect the vital role of active participation and dialogue among developers to navigate the complexities of blockchain programming and enhance the ecosystem's overall health and security.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-18T12:37:11.465000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
