<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Emulating curve point scalar multiplication with OP_CAT</title>
  <updated>2024-01-09T09:26:42.478953+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-08T04:58:48.145000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Emulating curve point scalar multiplication with OP_CAT</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T09:26:42.478953+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-op-cat/370/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The essence of the email revolves around an analogy that questions the practicality of imposing limitations on the use of tools, especially in a field as expansive and versatile as programming. The sender compares the scenario to a hypothetical situation in which a handyman is asked to choose only one tool from an array of essential items such as a knife, hammer, screwdriver, or handsaw. This comparison highlights the absurdity of restricting oneself to a single tool when the nature of work often requires a multifaceted approach.

The underlying message suggests that the conversation, while intriguing as an intellectual exercise or a casual debate over drinks, does not translate well into the real-world application of programming. It emphasizes that just as a handyman needs a variety of tools to address different tasks effectively, a programmer benefits from the flexibility of using various programming constructs and technologies (CAT in this context) to solve complex problems. The dialogue serves as a reminder that artificial constraints can hinder creativity and efficiency, especially in a domain characterized by its need for adaptability and innovation.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-08T04:58:48.145000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
