<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
  <updated>2024-01-09T09:19:05.175808+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-08T08:20:24.624000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T09:19:05.175808+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bug-spammers-get-bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-lets-fix-it/327/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue among programmers often reveals varying perspectives on transaction cost models within blockchain systems. One such conversation explores the pricing of native asset transactions in relation to alternative assets, particularly in the context of block space utilization and transaction complexity.

Central to this discussion is the contention that native asset transactions should not be made more expensive arbitrarily. Instead, there's an argument advocating for a cost model where simpler transactions—quantified here by sheer volume, such as 6000 simple transactions—are economically favored over complex ones, assuming both types occupy the same block size, exemplified by a 2 MB block. The point being made is that a larger number of straightforward transactions should not incur higher costs in terms of satoshis compared to a single transaction of equal data size but greater complexity.

This viewpoint challenges certain proposed changes, like those that might emerge from the implementation of techniques such as taptweak and client-side validation, which could potentially make alternative asset transactions more financially viable than their native counterparts. By suggesting that the cost structure should inherently benefit simpler native asset transactions, the conversation highlights a desire for a fee system that reflects transactional efficiency and encourages optimal use of block space without penalizing the base currency operations on the network.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-08T08:20:24.624000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
