<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
  <updated>2024-01-09T09:18:00.905895+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-08T19:49:36.541000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T09:18:00.905895+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bug-spammers-get-bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-lets-fix-it/327/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the prioritization of certain types of Bitcoin transactions, specifically those labeled as "simple transactions" which are characterized by having N-inputs and 2-outputs, all signed with a single signature. There is some uncertainty expressed regarding the rationale behind giving these transactions precedence. The argument against this prioritization stems from the fact that witness data, which is part of Segregated Witness (SegWit) transactions, is given a discount because it can be pruned during synchronization without affecting the transaction graph – an operation that cannot be performed on other types of transaction data.

The perspective offered suggests that the costing of chain resources should reflect the real expenses incurred by nodes during verification processes rather than showing favor to any specific use case. This view challenges the concept of "spam" transactions in a decentralized system, pointing out that the term itself may not be relevant since every transaction has associated costs. If those costs exceed what users pay, then it is considered a systemic issue that needs addressing. Moreover, it is suggested that if "simple transactions" are deemed inefficient in terms of network resource utilization, they ought to be de-prioritized or 'thrown under the bus' to ensure the optimal functioning of the network.

This stance emphasizes the principle that the pricing mechanism within the blockchain should correlate directly with the actual costs borne by the network, thereby ensuring fairness and efficiency in resource allocation across various types of transactions. This would imply a more dynamically balanced system where no particular kind of transaction is inherently preferred, fostering a more sustainable and rational economic model for the network's operations.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-08T19:49:36.541000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
