<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
  <updated>2024-01-10T02:08:29.607545+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-09T14:57:31.676000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
    <updated>2024-01-10T02:08:29.607571+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/v3-transaction-policy-for-anti-pinning/340/28" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the intricacies of determining an appropriate pin size in relation to mempool conditions, referencing a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) which suggests a maximum "5x theoretical pin." This maximum is a significant reduction from the previously stated 500x, although it acknowledges that practical limits will vary based on factors often beyond the control of both attackers and defenders in the network. The proposal implies that the only direct method for further reducing this pin size would be to decrease the Child-Pays-For-Parent (CPFP) maximum size, with the caveat of not affecting legitimate CPFP transactions.

Previously, the child transaction size was around 4kvB, but adjustments have already been made once after discussions. To aid in understanding and potentially to contribute to more informed decisions regarding these sizes, @0xB10C has created visual representations in the form of charts. These charts illustrate relevant data and can be found shared on social media, specifically Twitter, providing a resource for those interested in the technical details of the BIP's considerations. The information shared in the provided GitHub link to the BIP text gives a more detailed explanation of the motivation behind these proposals and the implications for Bitcoin's transaction processes.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T14:57:31.676000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
