<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
  <updated>2024-01-10T02:01:35.804293+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-09T18:03:47.512000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
    <updated>2024-01-10T02:01:35.804322+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bug-spammers-get-bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-lets-fix-it/327/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current discussion revolves around the concept of network data and its interpretation. It is essential to recognize that a network perceives each byte of data without discrimination, treating all bytes equally regardless of their content or the complexity of the transaction they represent. This equality in data treatment by the network has implications when considering the pricing of block space. The question at hand delves into the argument surrounding whether a simple transaction should incur a higher cost for block space.

When assessing this notion, the fundamental assertion remains that one byte equals one byte within the network's purview. The debate continues as to whether this metric should directly influence the pricing models adopted for block space utilization, especially when juxtaposing simple transactions against more complex ones. The underlying query seeks to challenge the justification for potentially higher blockspace prices for transactions that are deemed simpler, possibly suggesting an alternative perspective on how these costs should be structured relative to the transaction's nature and complexity.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T18:03:47.512000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
