<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-01-11T02:05:32.635739+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.130000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-10T19:56:47.130000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-01-11T02:05:32.635768+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence in question revolves around the technical implementation details of using CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) to streamline transaction processes. Specifically, it seeks to understand the method employed to eliminate unnecessary round-trips during transactions by utilizing CTV.

The referenced explanation and definition of `CovSig` can be found within the documentation of a proposed method aimed at reducing round-trips without applying CTV or annex usage. This method is outlined in detail in a GitHub repository, which hosts the rationale for this approach. The document can be accessed through a direct link to a particular commit on GitHub: [XX-eltoo-transactions.mdrationale-1](https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/blob/a17b60f42077a785c625430e8f6e8e2828d4d898/XX-eltoo-transactions.mdrationale-1). Additionally, discussions and issues related to this topic are being tracked in a separate issue thread on the same repository, which provides further insights into the application and implications of the technique: [GitHub Issue #5](https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/issues/5).

These resources collectively provide the necessary background and technical information required to understand the use of CTV in optimizing transaction efficiency by mitigating the need for additional communication steps, commonly referred to as "round-trips," within the transaction process. The materials are intended for programmers and other individuals with an interest in the technical aspects of transaction optimization through innovative coding practices.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-10T19:56:47.130000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
