<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-01-12T02:14:16.227351+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-11T14:07:42.305000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-01-12T02:14:16.227382+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of introducing covenant opcodes into programming, particularly those that would benefit from arithmetic operations on satoshi values, has been acknowledged favorably. The idea is to enhance the functionality and flexibility of these opcodes, which play a significant role in certain programming applications. By enabling arithmetic on satoshi values—satoshi being the smallest unit of Bitcoin—it opens up new possibilities for developers working with cryptocurrency-related projects.

This proposal suggests that incorporating such capabilities could significantly improve how covenants function. Covenants are conditions placed on transactions that restrict how the outputs can be spent, and by allowing arithmetic operations on their associated values, it provides a more dynamic and powerful toolset for developers. This change could lead to more efficient and sophisticated smart contracts, expanding the use cases and overall efficiency of cryptocurrency transactions.

By improving covenant opcodes with arithmetic functionalities, programmers could script more complex conditions and controls over transaction outputs. This advancement would potentially make blockchain and cryptocurrency platforms more secure, versatile, and scalable. It reflects a thoughtful progression towards enhancing the technical underpinnings of digital currencies and leveraging the full potential of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-11T14:07:42.305000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
