<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-01-13T02:02:11.637194+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-12T13:20:15.414000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-01-13T02:02:11.637226+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers on the implementation and potential extension of `CScriptNum` for 64-bit arithmetic in scripting. The existing `CScriptNum` is presented as a tried-and-tested solution that is already in use, suggesting it would be advantageous to build upon it rather than introduce an entirely new number format. The compactness of the current minimal-length big-endian representation within scripts is highlighted as a benefit, especially when compared to a hypothetical fixed-size little-endian alternative which might compel developers to frequently convert between formats, potentially hindering a smooth transition to a larger bit-sized number format.

Further discussion acknowledges that while there may be edge cases concerning the use of `CScriptNum` with 8-byte values, a proposed solution by @sipa appears straightforward, as demonstrated in the provided commit link: https://github.com/halseth/bitcoin/pull/1/commits/13c1848edf66410517b3cb6d47d80874438abb1f, which extends 64-bit support across various numeric opcodes. Additionally, the availability of `leaf_version` from the interpreter is noted, indicating that defining a new version should be relatively simple.

The conversation also touches on potential issues related to overflow detection and handling if multiplication opcodes like `OP_MUL` are reintroduced. Ensuring that these opcodes are backward compatible with the existing number format (alongside a `leaf_version` update) is emphasized as an ideal approach for re-enabling them. The overall tone suggests a preference for enhancing the existing infrastructure rather than overhauling it, balancing the needs of current developers with the system's growth and evolution.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-12T13:20:15.414000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
