<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Deploying new taproot leaf versions</title>
  <updated>2024-01-13T02:03:39.339814+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2024-01-12 16:14:14.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Deploying new taproot leaf versions</title>
    <updated>2024-01-13T02:03:39.339846+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deploying-new-taproot-leaf-versions/406" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the implementation of new leaf versions in the Bitcoin interpreter, specifically focusing on how they can modify the interpretation of opcodes. A particular example is provided where a new leaf version, identified as `0x66`, has been created with the effect of disabling the OP_CHECKSIGADD opcode. Although this change serves merely as an illustrative example and is not a proposal for actual modification of functionality, it raises questions about the intended use of new leaf versions within the system. The example is substantiated by a link to a GitHub repository branch where the changes have been made, providing a concrete reference for reviewing the practical application of this concept.

It's important to note that the inquiry is not promoting the deactivation of the OP_CHECKSIGADD feature, but rather using it to understand the potential applications and scope of new leaf versions in the codebase. Further elaboration or examples related to deploying new leaf versions would enhance the understanding of their purpose and capabilities within the interpreter. The provided link to the GitHub repository offers additional context for those interested in examining the technical details: https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/tree/2024-01-12-new-tapleaf-ver-example. This exploration into the adaptability of the interpreter through leaf versions is indicative of ongoing efforts to evolve the interpretive mechanisms of Bitcoin script execution.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-12T16:14:14.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
