<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-01-14T02:08:14.418354+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-13T14:53:41.807000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-01-14T02:08:14.418387+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of adding extra encoding for numbers within a programming project has been considered with an analysis of its potential impact on the complexity of the system. The introduction of additional encoding could indeed present some challenges, but it may concurrently simplify other aspects of the development process. Notably, for newcomers to the project, particularly those who intend to perform numerical computations using Script, the current necessity to understand specific policies like `SCRIPT_VERIFY_MINIMALDATA` poses a hurdle. Simplification could be achieved by implementing changes that might allow for these policies to be disregarded, reducing the overall complexity of the system.

Moreover, the conversation extends to the possibility of affecting the `SCRIPT_VERIFY_MINIMALIF` policy. While the term 'removing' might overstate the intended effect, the proposed adjustments aim to mitigate the need to consider these policy flags in the context of future soft forks. By doing so, developers would benefit from a streamlined process, easing their tasks and potentially making the system more approachable and easier to manage. This consideration reflects a broader goal of enhancing the developer experience and simplifying the coding environment without compromising functionality or introducing undue burdens elsewhere.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-13T14:53:41.807000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
