<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:14:49.841503+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-17T13:54:52.395000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:14:49.841535+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors/418/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The communication clarifies a previously misunderstood point regarding the support for the CPFP (Child Parent Family Plan) carve-out. The correct interpretation, as now explained, aligns with the initial understanding that users who are part of the CPFP carve-out will be automatically enrolled in the new version 3 policy, which includes an expanded coverage scheme allowing one parent and two children.

This revised policy indicates a commitment to not only maintain support for the existing users under the CPFP carve-out but also to enhance their benefits by adopting a more inclusive framework. By integrating the additional child into the plan, the policy evolves to accommodate the dynamics of family structures, reflecting an understanding of the diverse needs of users.

The update serves as a reassurance that the transition to the new policy will be seamless for CPFP carve-out users, ensuring that they continue to receive uninterrupted and improved service without any additional actions required on their part. This proactive measure demonstrates an effort to streamline processes and provide extended coverage, thereby reinforcing the value placed on user satisfaction and policy inclusivity.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T13:54:52.395000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
