<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:14:39.179027+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-17T14:11:04.951000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:14:39.179061+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors/418/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions among programmers have highlighted a proposed change in how eclair implements anchor outputs. This change introduces new restrictions that would affect the current flexibility in handling anchor outputs. Specifically, under the updated usage, it would no longer be possible to batch multiple anchor outputs for spending simultaneously. Additionally, there would be limitations on using the change output from an unconfirmed anchor transaction to fund another transaction. Furthermore, the proposal would prevent the use of unconfirmed inputs for anchor transactions. 

These alterations aim to ensure compatibility across different implementations, but they require careful consideration from all parties involved. The feedback from various implementations is crucial to assess the viability and impact of these restrictions. It is implied that there may be other considerations or constraints not yet identified, suggesting an open invitation for further analysis and discussion within the programming community. 

Ensuring alignment and agreement on these changes is essential for maintaining a cohesive approach to the development and use of anchor outputs. This ongoing dialogue underscores the collaborative nature of the field, where modifications are scrutinized collectively to achieve optimal outcomes for all implementations.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T14:11:04.951000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
