<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:08:51.300455+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:08:51.300491+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The importance of achieving consensus before initiating a soft fork in the Bitcoin network cannot be overstated. Initiating signaling for a soft fork without prior consensus can lead to divisiveness and potential chain splits, which historically have proven to be detrimental to productivity and focus within the community. The message emphasizes that caution should be exercised to prevent another disruptive event akin to the "block size war," an episode that caused significant turmoil within the Bitcoin ecosystem. For those unfamiliar with this period, a resource is provided to offer insight into the challenges faced during that time. It is suggested that only after a unanimous agreement on the activation of a soft fork should any signaling commence, with the objective of maintaining unity and avoiding conflict that could lead to a repeat of past adversities.

For further reading on the contentious period referred to as the block size war and its impact on Bitcoin's development, one may consult the book available [here](https://www.amazon.com/Blocksize-War-Control-Bitcoins-Protocol/dp/B096CLR1SS/). This historical account serves as a cautionary tale, highlighting the consequences of proceeding without consensus and the extensive headaches it causes for developers, overshadowing the pleasure it might bring to observers and media.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T20:20:44.934000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
