<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:10:42.311231+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-17T22:31:06.270000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:10:42.311264+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/28" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The reintroduction of 256-bit arithmetic into Bitcoin's script capabilities is contemplated in the context of recent advancements brought by the implementation of Taproot. With Taproot, the possibility for more complex cryptographic operations within Bitcoin scripts becomes a reality, albeit these operations are generally not intended to be used onchain given Taproot's design for optimizing the typical, non-dispute path. However, the notion of using intricate sigma protocols as an onchain mechanism specifically in dispute scenarios is proposed.

This would enable a more robust set of conditions and proofs to be available within the network, though such implementations would be rarely seen due to their activation only during disagreements. To prevent potential misuse of this increased complexity, it is suggested that additional costs in the form of sigops (signature operations) could be imposed. These costs would act as a deterrent against frivolous or malicious deployment of these advanced scripts, ensuring they are reserved solely for their intended purpose of resolving disputes. 

While the idea presents an interesting expansion of Bitcoin's scripting abilities, it also raises considerations about the trade-offs between script flexibility and blockchain efficiency. The proposal implicitly acknowledges the importance of maintaining a balance between empowering users with advanced cryptographic tools and preserving the streamlined operation of the blockchain for everyday transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T22:31:06.270000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
