<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-01-21T02:05:22.041994+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-20 03:46:40.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T02:05:22.042028+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the process of analyzing blockchain transactions, recent simulations have been conducted to understand the behavior of systems at different transaction creation and confirmation rates. The tests were carried out with a confirmation rate set at 3.75 transactions per second (tx/s) and a creation rate set at 7 tx/s. These rates were applied within a single system environment.

The performance of the system under these conditions has raised some concerns. Specifically, when the creation rate reaches 7 tx/s, it is expected that there should not be any issues with mempool synchronization before implementing a particular proposed change (referred to as "this PR"). This expectation aligns with the observations made in the simulation results. Yet, stability issues have been encountered despite the anticipated outcomes. 

The nature of these stability problems is being questioned. There are several potential factors that could be contributing to the instability during the high transaction rate simulations. Firstly, the resources expended on CPU-intensive operations such as signing and verifying transactions may be overwhelming the system. Secondly, the size and management of wallets might be affecting performance, especially if the tracking and spending of unspent transaction outputs (utxos) become slow due to their increasing size. Lastly, another possibility is that the performance remains adequate but yields inconsistent results across different simulation runs.

It is clear from this inquiry that understanding the root cause of the simulation's instability is crucial for developing robust blockchain systems capable of handling high transaction rates effectively. Identifying whether the bottleneck is due to CPU limitations, wallet management issues, or simply inconsistencies in simulation outcomes will guide further improvements and optimizations in the system.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-20T03:46:40.964000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
