<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disclosure: Btcd consensus bugs due to usage of signed transaction version</title>
  <updated>2024-01-23T02:10:07.902126+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-22T22:26:32.151000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disclosure: Btcd consensus bugs due to usage of signed transaction version</title>
    <updated>2024-01-23T02:10:07.902159+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-btcd-consensus-bugs-due-to-usage-of-signed-transaction-version/455/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discovery in the realm of cryptocurrency security has been met with acclaim and recognition, underscored by the receipt of a bug bounty reward from the btcd project. The awarded sum of 0.023 BTC serves not only as a testament to the significance of the finding but also as an embodiment of the collaborative spirit inherent within the programming community. This particular success story owes its genesis to the innovative application of differential fuzzing, as recommended by Guido Vranken, a technique employed on the script interpreters of both btcd and Bitcoin Core.

Differential fuzzing, a method that systematically stresses software by generating a multitude of random inputs to find bugs, was pivotal in uncovering the anomaly. By comparing the outputs of different implementations under varying input conditions, it enables the identification of inconsistencies and potential vulnerabilities. This approach has proven especially fruitful in environments where precision and reliability are paramount, such as those dealing with cryptographic currencies and their underlying technologies.

The notion of open-source software (OSS) stands at the forefront of this discussion, given its role in promoting transparency and collective progress through shared knowledge and resources. The query regarding the open-source status of the fuzzing utilized in this instance highlights a broader conversation about the accessibility of tools and methods that can be leveraged for the betterment of technology and security practices at large.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-22T22:26:32.151000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
