<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Disclosure: Btcd consensus bugs due to usage of signed transaction version</title>
  <updated>2024-01-23T02:09:43.668604+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dergoegge.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-22T23:04:10.980000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Disclosure: Btcd consensus bugs due to usage of signed transaction version</title>
    <updated>2024-01-23T02:09:43.668638+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/disclosure-btcd-consensus-bugs-due-to-usage-of-signed-transaction-version/455/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post would discuss the discovery of a bug in an open-source software (OSS) through the technique of differential fuzzing. Although the specific details of the harness used for identifying the bug have not yet been made public, there is an intention to release a comprehensive write-up on the subject. This publication will include both an explanation of how the bug was found and the actual code involved in the process.

The post would emphasize the practical applications of fuzzing techniques in uncovering software vulnerabilities. It could provide insights into the importance of such methods in improving software reliability and security, especially in OSS where community contributions play a crucial role in development and maintenance.

Furthermore, the post could anticipate the forthcoming publication as a valuable resource for programmers and security researchers interested in understanding and applying differential fuzzing methodologies. The sharing of the harness code would likely encourage further research and collaboration within the community, potentially leading to enhanced debugging processes and more secure software systems.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-22T23:04:10.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
