<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-01-25T02:07:08.011279+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-24T15:46:48.103000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T02:07:08.011311+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors/418/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin transaction management, particularly concerning version 3 (v3) transactions, the discussion revolves around the concept of sibling eviction and its potential implications. The implementation of sibling eviction is notable for its ability to allow certain "imbued" commitment transactions—those created before specification updates—to replace other anchor spends using Replace-By-Fee (RBF) instead of relying on a carveout. This approach can lead to a more efficient use of blockchain space and transaction fees.

A practical application of this concept is the utilization of a 330 satoshi keyed anchor, which could also pave the way for the removal of a `1 CSV` delay from all other scripts associated with the transaction. Moreover, there's the possibility of employing multiple anchors, reflecting a flexibility in managing transaction costs and the segregation of funds and fees. These ephemeral or temporary anchors can make anchoring less expensive while offering the added advantage of separating different types of transactional information.

Additionally, it's feasible to omit these ephemeral/keyed anchors in certain commitment transactions under specific conditions, such as when only a remote balance output remains. This adjustment could further optimize transaction structures and potentially bring about other unexplored benefits. For a detailed exploration of this topic, interested individuals can refer to the [discussion on Delving Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sibling-eviction-for-v3-transactions/472).</summary>
    <published>2024-01-24T15:46:48.103000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
