<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
  <updated>2024-01-26T02:09:45.198530+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse.268000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-25T16:05:57.268000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T02:09:45.198563+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sibling-eviction-for-v3-transactions/472/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Understanding the nuances of package replacements in Bitcoin transactions can be quite complex, but the correspondence provides some clarity on this topic. The discussion involves the Replace-by-Fee (RBF) feature, which allows unconfirmed transactions to be replaced by another transaction paying a higher fee. It's highlighted that with only 1 parent 1 child (1p1c) package relay and RBF, certain package replacements are possible under specific conditions.

The first scenario presented is a situation where two transactions, `A-B` and `A'-B'`, both start with zero satoshis per virtual byte (sat/vB) and `B'` offers a higher fee rate than `B`. This replacement is deemed workable within the v3 package replacement framework. The same goes for a direct swap where `A` remains constant, and `B` is replaced by `B'` with a higher fee rate. These examples are illustrated using mermaid flowchart syntax which helps visualize the transaction relationships.

However, there's a query about a case where `A-B` is attempted to be replaced by `A-C` where `C` offers a higher fee rate than `B`. The consensus is that sibling eviction should be enabled to allow such a replacement, as it represents the most intuitive behavior for users. With Package RBF, the entire package, including transactions in the mempool, should be considered when assessing potential replacements. By implication, if `A-C` has better fees, it should logically replace `A-B`, enhancing the fee market dynamics and user experience of the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T16:05:57.268000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
