<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PoC: Fix fee bypass bug using OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY</title>
  <updated>2024-01-26T02:11:02.137808+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.058000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-25T23:04:19.058000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PoC: Fix fee bypass bug using OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T02:11:02.137837+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/poc-fix-fee-bypass-bug-using-op-checktemplateverify/478/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussed email, the sender proposes a security protocol for keyspend transactions using FROST (Flexible Round-Optimized Schnorr Threshold). A 3-of-4 multisignature scheme is suggested, where "HH" controls two of the four necessary keys. This configuration is designed to provide flexibility and security in transaction settlements.

To facilitate various settlement conditions, four alternative script spends are outlined, each consisting of a combination of cryptographic checks such as `CHECKSIGVERIFY` and `CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY`, alongside conditional checks including `CLTV` (Check Lock Time Verify). These scripts ensure that transactions can only be completed under specific conditions, enhancing the control mechanisms over the settlement process.

The proposed system allows for a unilateral settlement by one party with a single signature after a predefined period – specifically, two weeks. This feature is designed to minimize deadlock situations and enable resolution without complete mutual agreement initially. In scenarios where disputes arise, the protocol accommodates cooperative dispute resolution between the buyer and seller after the initial two-week period has passed.

If cooperation fails to yield a resolution after two months, there is a competitive mechanism introduced where both parties can vie for the funds. The structured timeframe and tiered approach to conflict resolution highlight an emphasis on flexibility and an escalated response to disagreements, potentially leading to a more dynamic and responsive settlement process.

The sender's email illustrates a detailed and strategic approach to managing multisig transactions within decentralized systems, aiming to strike a balance between security, autonomy, and dispute resolution efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T23:04:19.058000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
