<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Untraceable Taprootized Atomic Swaps</title>
  <updated>2024-01-28T01:57:59.089334+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding.205000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-27T17:22:35.205000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Untraceable Taprootized Atomic Swaps</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T01:57:59.089367+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/untraceable-taprootized-atomic-swaps/458/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A PTLC, or Point Time-Locked Contract, is a type of smart contract used within the blockchain realm, particularly in Bitcoin operations. It serves as an alternative to the more commonly known HTLC, or Hashed Time-Locked Contract. The email inquires about the distinctions between the conventional HTLC and the innovative PTLC, suggesting a comparison of their functionalities, benefits, or implementations. 

PTLCs are instrumental in enhancing privacy and efficiency in blockchain transactions. Unlike HTLCs that rely on hash functions for conditional execution, PTLCs use cryptographic points which provide advantages such as better privacy by not leaving identifiable hashes on-chain post-transaction. This characteristic is particularly important for preserving the privacy of participants in multi-hop payment channels, such as those used in the Lightning Network. Furthermore, PTLCs can leverage adaptor signatures, enabling more flexible and interoperable designs within the scope of smart contracts.

For a deeper understanding of how PTLCs operate and their potential impact on blockchain technology, one can refer to the comprehensive guide provided at [Bitcoin Optech](https://bitcoinops.org/en/topics/ptlc/). This resource offers valuable insights into the technical workings, applications, and implications of PTLCs in the context of Bitcoin's evolving infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-27T17:22:35.205000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
