<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-01-30T08:14:57.889440+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>m3dwards 2024-01-29 13:01:26.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-01-30T08:14:57.889467+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In recent correspondence, a programmer detailed their observation of instability within a network, noting that nodes were losing connections with peers but not attributing the issue to CPU constraints. Instead, the programmer hypothesized that the instability stemmed from handling a large number of network connections. Efforts are underway to enhance the scalability and stability of simulations in Warnet, a platform presumably used for these tests, with intent to increase transaction rates once improvements have been made.

The programmer also sought clarity on specific technical aspects of the network's operation. They posed questions regarding the dynamics between relay rate and transaction requests, pondering if an increased relay rate might lead to greater variability within the mempool due to differential transaction fees. The expectation set forth was that the mempool would optimally retain the most lucrative transactions, leading to a consistent state across all nodes despite the differing fees.

Furthermore, the programmer expressed uncertainty about how certain Bitcoin transaction policies and mechanisms—specifically Replace-By-Fee (RBF), Child Pays For Parent (CPFP), and chains of unconfirmed transactions—would influence the outcomes of their tests. These elements are crucial in understanding how transactions are managed and propagated across the network, particularly under conditions where transactions remain unconfirmed and strategies such as RBF and CPFP are employed to adjust fee priorities.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-29T13:01:26.898000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
