<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:36:31.750941+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2024-01-02 09:36:47.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:36:31.750941+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/v3-transaction-policy-for-anti-pinning/340" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Gloria Zhao has proposed a new transaction relay policy known as "V3" to address the issue of pinning in Bitcoin network transactions. This proposal is often considered alongside Greg Sanders' concept of ephemeral anchors, which presents a complementary approach to the same problem. The discussion of V3 has been prompted by the impending discontinuation of a mailing list traditionally used for such technical deliberations.

The original thread on the mailing list provides insight into the initial discussions surrounding V3. Additionally, a gist containing preliminary conversations that led to the formal post on the mailing list offers background on the evolution of this policy. A significant step towards implementing the V3 policy is evident in a pull request submitted to the Bitcoin Core repository. The pull request includes comprehensive design specifications that detail the workings of the version 3 policy.

Moreover, the relevance and integration of V3 within the broader context of package relay enhancements for the Bitcoin network are outlined in a dedicated issue tracker on the Bitcoin Core GitHub repository. These resources collectively form the foundation for understanding the technical aspects and implications of the proposed V3 policy and its potential role in improving transaction relay in the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-02T09:36:47.462000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
