<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:39:16.498661+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-04T00:21:38.864000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:39:16.498661+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current state of Bitcoin development and consensus processes reveals a complexity in the proposal and activation of soft forks. The traditional model where the `bitcoind` organization played a pivotal role in proposing changes with a unified stance has been altered, leading to a lack of clarity surrounding what constitutes a ready proposal. This shift away from a single authoritative voice has introduced more uncertainty into the system, particularly for economic actors reliant on a clear definition of "rough consensus," which is typically signified by a merge into `bitcoind`.

Despite this, Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIP) 9 and 8 still open the possibility for multiple soft forks to be proposed simultaneously. However, the socio-economic landscape hasn't fully adapted to this due to high coordination costs and extensive review requirements. Current alternative implementations to `bitcoind` are not yet a viable solution, as they lag significantly in development progress and support, representing a high risk for conservative market participants.

Furthermore, the notion of miner-activated upgrades is controversial within the community, with divergent opinions stemming from past events like the segwit and block size debate. There appears to be a growing sentiment among certain community members, especially those vocal on social media platforms like Twitter, who favor hard forks despite the inherent challenges of achieving global coordination. They view optional soft forks, originally engineered as a means to facilitate updates without unanimous agreement, with skepticism, suggesting that the era of soft forks may be coming to an end sooner than anticipated.

In summary, the dynamic between developers, miners, and users in the Bitcoin ecosystem is undergoing a transformation, where the previous mechanisms of introducing and activating changes are being reevaluated. This evolution underlines the need for new approaches to achieving consensus and implementing upgrades in a decentralized environment.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:21:38.864000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
