<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:42:20.522573+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:42:20.522573+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current protocol for passing nonces during rounds has an inherent limitation when paired with the "simplified update" protocol initially suggested by Rusty. Presently, a single nonce is used per round, which works under normal circumstances. However, this design does not account for scenarios where "optimistic" updates are transmitted. Optimistic updates allow for sending updates out of sequence, aiming to reduce latency but require additional logic to be implemented correctly. Specifically, to facilitate these optimistic updates, an additional nonce is necessary, along with a mechanism for its safe handling.

Although the implementation of optimistic sending of updates was not completed, the possibility of such updates was not completely prohibited and remains part of the specification. The referenced specification can be found at [GitHub](https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/blob/a17b60f42077a785c625430e8f6e8e2828d4d898/XX-eltoo-peer-protocol.md#eltoo-simplified-operation). To address the issue of out-of-turn updates effectively, it is essential to consider integrating another nonce and the corresponding logic into the system. This adaptation would ensure that the protocol can support the intended reduced-latency benefits of optimistic updates without compromising on safety or performance.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T19:18:51.887000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
