<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:33:43.404601+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>nettimel 2024-01-05 21:20:21.432000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:33:43.404601+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/v3-transaction-policy-for-anti-pinning/340/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of modifying blockchain consensus rules is addressed to ensure a fair and decentralized transaction validation process. The proposition entails that a block may only contain a parent ephemeral anchor if it also includes the corresponding child spend. To further align with decentralized payment practices, an additional soft fork rule is suggested which requires the child spend to have at least two inputs. This measure aims to equate the block space utilized by those who pay miners outside the blockchain network with those who engage in standard decentralized transactions, thereby neutralizing incentives for off-chain payments.

Despite these proposed changes, there are efficiencies identified by Peter Todd suggesting that miners could still consolidate multiple anchor channel outputs into a single block more effectively than through the typical Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) method. The efficiency of paying out-of-band remains intact due to the necessity of creating and spending UTXOs for ephemeral transactions. Looking ahead, it is anticipated that the majority of channels will resemble systems like Phoenix, which prefer maintaining one UTXO per user, a structure that currently does not support anchoring. Todd's insights on this topic can be further explored through his [Twitter post](https://twitter.com/peterktodd/status/1743376014154121374).</summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T21:20:21.432000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
