<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:32:39.892322+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-01-05T22:00:07.209000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>V3 transaction policy for anti-pinning</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:32:39.892322+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/v3-transaction-policy-for-anti-pinning/340/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a recent discussion, the implications of SIGHASH_ANYONECANPAY and its potential risks to decentralization were addressed. It was noted that despite acknowledging this issue, the argument seemingly downplays it by suggesting future mitigations such as the implementation of SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT. The conversation raises an important question regarding the necessity for smart contracts to include endogenous fees in order to preserve decentralization. The debate touches upon whether the requirement for these fees is a sustainable rationale to halt proposals, especially considering the minimal cost, estimated at around 50 virtual bytes (vb), that ephemeral anchors would incur.

The exchange reveals a broader concern about the balance between advancing technological features within cryptocurrency frameworks and maintaining the core principle of decentralization. This balance is crucial as the industry explores new upgrades and enhancements that could potentially compromise the distributed nature of blockchain networks. The dialogue reflects a tension between innovation and the preservation of foundational values, prompting a deeper evaluation of how emerging technologies like SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT can be integrated without undermining the system's decentralized structure.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T22:00:07.209000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
