<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Building Intuition for the Cashu Blind Signature Scheme</title>
  <updated>2024-02-14T01:59:29.495087+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-02-13 02:34:17.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-02-12 16:47:19.070000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>thunderbiscuit  . 2024-01-31 15:07:20.658000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1527_Building-Intuition-for-the-Cashu-Blind-Signature-Scheme.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1522_Building-Intuition-for-the-Cashu-Blind-Signature-Scheme.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1397_Building-Intuition-for-the-Cashu-Blind-Signature-Scheme.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Building Intuition for the Cashu Blind Signature Scheme</title>
    <updated>2024-02-14T01:59:29.495147+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/building-intuition-for-the-cashu-blind-signature-scheme/506/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on ecash tokens introduces a privacy-centric approach to digital transactions, employing a unique system where only the issuer (mint) can authenticate the token's validity and its spending history. This methodology allows for transactions where the final recipient is unaware of the transaction's origin, thereby ensuring anonymity and privacy uncommon in traditional payment systems. Despite the advantages, this system faces challenges, particularly regarding fraud prevention and transaction verification. The reliance on the mint for these verifications introduces a potential point of vulnerability or fraudulent activity, as there's a possibility for the mint to falsely claim that a token has been previously spent. To mitigate these risks, suggestions include implementing fraud proofs through arbitration or a public challenge-response mechanism, which would complicate the token issuing and redemption process. Additionally, the Cashu mint's use of DLEQ proof to validate tokens introduces privacy concerns by requiring the revelation of the blinding factor, undermining unlinkability—a critical privacy feature. Furthermore, the prospect of offline token transfers adds complexity and could affect the fungibility of tokens due to additional spending and redemption conditions.

In addressing the cryptographic foundation of ecash tokens, the blind signature scheme utilized in [Cashu](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts) is highlighted. This scheme ensures privacy in token creation and redemption processes using elliptic curve Diffie-Hellman points for secure exchanges between parties, without revealing private keys. Unique to this system is the method of blinding and unblinding tokens, where a user sends a mint a blinded message containing a modified public key. The mint signs this message blindly, allowing the user to later unblind it, keeping the issuance and redemption of the token private. This process enables users to prove token possession to the mint without revealing their identity, maintaining transaction anonymity. Moreover, the system aims to prevent double-spending and unauthorized redemptions while ensuring that the mint cannot trace transactions back to individuals, thereby preserving the essence of private payments within the ecash framework.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-13T02:34:17.911000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
