<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Emulating curve point scalar multiplication with OP_CAT</title>
  <updated>2024-01-09T09:28:22.622217+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus.475000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus.052000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.942000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.971000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  ..228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1010_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1009_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1007_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1008_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1006_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/957_Emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-OP-CAT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Emulating curve point scalar multiplication with OP_CAT</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T09:28:22.622217+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/emulating-curve-point-scalar-multiplication-with-op-cat/370" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discussion among programmers revolves around the potential applications and limitations of OP_CAT in Bitcoin scripting, specifically as it pertains to simulating cryptographic operations. The conversation begins with an analogy, comparing the restrictive use of a single tool for multiple jobs to the limited functionality available within Bitcoin's scripting language. This sets the stage for a debate on whether such constraints are practical or necessary.

The technical exchange progresses to the introduction of `OP_CAT`, a proposed operation that could extend the scripting capabilities by allowing concatenation of data elements. The main point under scrutiny is the ability of `OP_CAT` to facilitate scalar multiplication for curve points through a single subtraction of field elements. This concept is considered an interesting result because it would enable recursive covenants, which are advanced transaction constructs in Bitcoin. Recursive covenants have the potential to significantly enhance Bitcoin's programmability by allowing more intricate spending conditions.

However, concerns are raised regarding the enforceability of message authenticity within this framework. A hypothetical attack is described where a false claim about a public key point's relationship to a signature can be made without a reliable way to verify the truthfulness of the associated values. The discourse suggests that while the method might be sufficient in some scenarios, it could be vulnerable without additional mechanisms like CSFS (CHECKSIGFROMSTACK) to ensure the integrity of the message hash used in the verification process.

The summary concludes that, although the idea of using `OP_CAT` to emulate curve point scalar multiplication presents an intriguing technical challenge, it also reflects the complexity of implementing advanced features within Bitcoin's intentionally minimalistic scripting environment. The writeup serves as both a guide and a conceptual exploration for developers seeking to push the boundaries of what is possible with Bitcoin smart contracts. This development could contribute to expanding the platform's future functionalities, provided these complex techniques can be effectively and securely integrated into the current system.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-08T04:58:48.145000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
