<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:17:48.219657+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-17 23:13:02.376000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2024-01-17 22:45:18.634000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-01-17 14:34:16.713000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-01-17 14:11:04.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2024-01-17 13:54:52.395000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-01-17 13:33:00.486000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-17 12:44:11.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2024-01-17 11:23:16.215000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2024-01-17 11:20:38.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-01-17 09:58:32.274000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 22:55:57.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-16 18:06:54.151000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-01-16 17:28:44.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1175_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1174_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1163_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1161_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1160_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1159_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1158_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1156_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1155_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1154_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1149_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1147_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1145_Lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Lightning transactions with v3 and ephemeral anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:17:48.219752+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-transactions-with-v3-and-ephemeral-anchors/418/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The programming community is actively discussing enhancements in Bitcoin's Lightning Network, specifically focusing on the implementation and optimization of v3 HTLC (Hashed Time-Locked Contracts) transactions to combat pinning attacks. The proposed upgrade aims to include these transactions within commitment packages, improving security for both HTLC-Success and HTLC-Timeout paths through pre-signing according to v3 protocols.

The vulnerability of current HTLC transactions to pinning attacks due to the ANYONECANPAY nature has raised concerns. A transition to presigned v3 transactions is suggested as a remedy, although it may increase virtual bytes in non-adversarial scenarios. An option under consideration is `option_anchors_zero_fee_htlc_tx`, which could maintain existing behaviors while enhancing security by relaying as part of the commitment package.

Coin selection algorithms that utilize a `max_weight` parameter are acknowledged for their ability to prevent exceeding weight limits. Innovations such as CoinGrinder (CG) require further examination due to their novelty. Feedback is requested on potential policy changes affecting batching, use of unconfirmed inputs, and the enrollment of users to CPFP carve-out under v3 policy.

Technical discussions also involve determining the ideal size for V3 child transactions to facilitate practical CPFP transactions without introducing pin vectors. This involves considering the variability in maximum sizes of commitment transactions across different implementations and ensuring efficient UTXO pool management.

Additionally, proposed improvements to lightning transactions include integrating V3 capabilities and ephemeral anchors to refine commitment transaction structures. This would simplify output structures, decouple on-chain fees from off-chain funds, and necessitate broadcasting transactions as packages with simple one-parent-one-child structures initially. The ephemeral anchor output would be claimable by anyone, incentivizing miners to prioritize transactions with higher fees and requiring node operators to assess their maximum dust exposure.

HTLC transactions employing zero-fee options with broadcaster signatures allowing additional inputs are expected to remain unaffected by the restructuring. Discussions about non-disruptive upgrade paths are in progress, weighing the urgency against development timelines. Input from wallet projects is sought to help determine optimal sizes for V3 child transactions within the new framework.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T23:13:02.376000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
