<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-19T02:14:54.388031+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-18 22:46:22.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-18 20:39:44.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-17 01:30:45.419000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1213_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1211_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1171_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1152_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T02:14:54.388128+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin's evolution and the mechanisms of consensus are currently under intense discussion among programmers. These debates, informed by the lessons from the block size war, focus on how to implement protocol changes without reigniting internal conflicts. Programmers are considering various aspects of implementing soft forks, including activation clients and settings like LockinOnTimeout (LOT). Consensus is crucial to avoid network splits due to premature signaling by miners.

Post-taproot activation, technical consensus has led to enhancements in Bitcoin Core and related projects. Nonetheless, there is a concern about chain splits resulting from changes that lack unanimous support. Some community members advocate for halting further changes to preserve stability, suggesting an ossification of the Bitcoin protocol. The role of miners is contentious; while some oppose miner-activated soft forks (MASFs) for potentially coercing older nodes out of consensus, others see strategic value in MASFs for facilitating upgrades and warding off harmful changes. This highlights the need for pragmatic governance focusing on network integrity and secure management of capital.

The sender of the email differentiates between technical consensus on software changes and consensus on rule alterations, noting the financial risks of chain splits. They suggest publishing activation clients to measure user influence over miners' soft fork decisions. A target year for soft fork activation is proposed to promote proactive developer and reviewer engagement, emphasizing the importance of adapting to technological advancements.

The transition away from the `bitcoind` organization's centralized approach to proposing changes has complicated the concept of "rough consensus," which used to be indicated by code merges into `bitcoind`. Despite this, Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIP) 9 and 8 still allow for multiple soft forks to be proposed concurrently. However, the community faces challenges with coordination costs and rigorous review processes. Alternative implementations to `bitcoind` struggle due to underdevelopment and lack of support, raising concerns for cautious market participants.

The discourse also reflects past incidents, such as segwit and block size discussions, shaping current views on miner-activated upgrades. There's a noted shift in community preference from soft forks to hard forks, possibly occurring sooner than anticipated.

Rusty Russell's blog post presents a model for Bitcoin soft fork activation: "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override." This model outlines the roles developers, miners, and users play in network upgrades, ensuring no single group can unilaterally enforce changes. The email sender values Russell's framework and invites the recipient to share thoughts on achieving broader consensus in cryptocurrency governance, considering the balance between proposal initiation, miner activation, and user-driven oversight in Bitcoin soft fork activations.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-18T22:46:22.075000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
