<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
  <updated>2024-01-22T02:05:47.835415+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-21 23:17:19.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hampus  . 2024-01-19 21:44:31.109000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 06:22:10.878000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>alex  . 2024-01-17 14:51:04.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RubenSomsen  . 2024-01-10 15:30:30.263000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-09 20:34:43.479000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-08 10:21:44.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-08 06:31:45.340000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-07 20:48:53.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-07 20:31:47.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:55:48.846000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 19:30:43.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:17:58.402000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 18:41:08.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1278_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1233_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1182_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1165_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1056_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1050_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1014_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1011_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1000_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/999_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/996_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/995_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/993_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/989_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
    <updated>2024-01-22T02:05:47.835522+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lnhance-bips-and-implementation/376/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Blockchain technology is advancing, with significant developments in the realm of cryptocurrency systems. The 'immortal' statecoin concept, which draws on LN-symmetry constructs, suggests a new method for transferring channel ends, allowing a single channel funding to benefit multiple users. This technique aims to increase channel reusability, where one channel's closure leads to the opening of another, each assigned its own timeout.

Developer Rearden's recent Twitter hint about a tool reminiscent of APO spacechains has stirred interest in the developer community, focusing on how it might affect the architecture of blockchain systems. Concurrently, developers are contributing to enhancements in the Bitcoin 'binana' repository, generating numbers for CSFS and INTERNALKEY features, with pull requests also submitted against the Bitcoin Core repository.

Jeremy Rubin's website, utxos.org, provides comprehensive resources regarding CheckTemplateVerify (CTV), including documentation and examples, facilitating developer education in CTV applications. Moreover, covenant proposals suggest potential advancements in spacechains through pre-committed transactions, while a new proposal explores signature flexibilities within Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) using Covenants via Transaction Outputs (CTV).

LN-symmetry represents a targeted development offering specific functions without the full suite of APO features but focuses on efficiently achieving key tasks. Questions have been raised about whether current blockchain constructs can support capabilities such as those provided by channel factories and Spacechains, crucial for scalability and interoperability.

A non-interactive channel (NIC) framework resistant to TXID malleability has been highlighted, featuring collaboration between entities like Alice and Lightning Service Providers managing virtual UTXOs. Additionally, there is an inquiry into the maturity of Probabilistic Timelock Contracts (PTLCs) and APO-like structures, with a request for a list detailing their developmental stages.

The bitcoin-inquisition repository serves as a preliminary stage for Bitcoin Core development, concentrating on essential consensus changes. It aids in discussions about LN-Symmetry implementation and the constraints of APO development. A new design for sighash flags has been proposed to address upgrade limitations, contrasting with the more defined design space of CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (CTV) detailed in BIP119.

To optimize Bitcoin development, the bitcoin-inquisition repository segregates consensus change discussions from general work, fostering focused development efforts. There is also interest in alternative methods for implementing LN-Symmetry without APO reliance. Proposals like BIP119, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK(VERIFY), and OP_INTERNALKEY—collectively termed "LNHANCE"—aim to enhance the Lightning Network and facilitate innovations such as ln-symmetry and Point Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs). These proposals lay the groundwork for output-restricting covenants in the Bitcoin protocol, promising greater control, privacy, and efficiency, marking progress in Bitcoin's scalability and utility.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-21T23:17:19.660000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
