<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - 64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-01-11T02:07:30.070139+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-10 23:10:38.930000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2024-01-10 16:11:01.778000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1061_64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1057_64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - 64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-01-11T02:07:30.070191+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The importance of 64-bit arithmetic in enhancing blockchain capabilities is gaining attention among protocol developers. It has been recognized that implementing 64-bit operations can facilitate the development of features like TLUV, which stands for Transaction Level Unspent Value, and would benefit other areas requiring detailed introspection, such as TXHASH (Transaction Hash), CAT (Concatenate command for script), and various elements opcodes within the Bitcoin scripting language.

A proposal for integrating 64-bit arithmetic into the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) framework has been made and is available for review. The BIP represents a formalized plan to improve the Bitcoin protocol, and the specifics of this proposal are documented on GitHub. Interested parties can access the BIP draft through the provided link: https://github.com/Christewart/bips/pull/1. Additionally, an implementation that corresponds to this proposal is also open for examination at: https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/pull/2. This preliminary sharing of information seeks early feedback from the community and serves to gauge interest before formally presenting it to the wider developer mailing list. Although there was some uncertainty regarding the appropriateness of the format for this discussion venue, the decision to post indicates a desire for collaborative input at this stage.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-10T23:10:38.930000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
