<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-02-01T02:03:44.145264+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>m3dwards 2024-01-31 12:43:52.567000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2024-01-29 22:41:00.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-29 13:01:26.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 03:46:40.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:56:02.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:48:45.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-22 03:04:11.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-21 18:03:33.954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2023-12-21 11:23:16.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-20 21:54:22.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-18 02:43:32.230000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-14 21:14:15.928000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1394_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1374_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1365_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1238_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1235_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1237_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/849_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/848_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/845_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/843_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/783_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/732_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T02:03:44.145355+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent discussions among programmers have focused on the optimization of blockchain network performance, specifically addressing transaction relay rates and fee calculations. Modifications to the `estimatesmartfee 5` command introduce a variability margin of ±10% to avoid random fees while allowing for fluctuations.

Efficient transaction propagation is essential, balanced with measures to prevent network abuse, such as setting a minimum fee rate measured in satoshis to deter "free relay" attacks. The transaction relay rate is crucial for maintaining node synchronization, particularly for high-fee transactions in the top 1MB of the mempool. Transactions are prioritized by fee rate, and determining the optimal relay rate involves monitoring compact block logging to assess mempool synchronization.

The current transaction relay rate may be too low, as suggested by increased mempool activity during peak times. Natural fee rate increases should be considered, rather than random distributions, to enhance mempool synchronization. Replace-by-Fee (RBF) strategies should only be employed for specific issues related to UTXOs.

Instabilities in network performance have been reported, which do not appear to be CPU-related but could be due to numerous connections. Efforts to improve scalability and stability include simulation enhancements on Warnet to handle higher transaction rates. The impact of RBF, CPFP (Child Pays For Parent), and unconfirmed transaction chains on simulation outcomes remains uncertain, as does the relationship between relay rate and transaction requests.

During simulations involving 100 nodes on a virtual machine, focusing on Bitcoin transaction relays and confirmations, no significant evidence was found to support the effectiveness of updates under moderate transaction rates. It is speculated that implementing RBF, CPFP, and unconfirmed transaction chains may require a shift to Kubernetes for improved stability. Adjusting block production rates could potentially skew results, and 'mocktime' is proposed as a solution to address these discrepancies.

For testing purposes, faster block production provides quicker feedback, but real-world conditions must be maintained for relevance. A deterministic methodology for UTXO generation has been agreed upon, which will involve incrementally increasing transaction creation rates to evaluate system performance thresholds.

To simulate larger network conditions accurately, a protocol has been outlined that includes mining blocks every ten minutes and generating transactions in Taproot or P2WSH formats with dynamically calculated fees. Performance will focus on compact block relay efficiency, with anticipated discrepancies in mempools and an increase in 'txn requested' messages when exceeding certain transaction rates.

Realistic replication of mainnet conditions involves understanding transaction dynamics and network configuration. Different nodes should be used for transaction and block generation to grasp network impacts, including RBF transactions reflecting current mainnet practices. Testing suggests that running 250 nodes using Docker is feasible, and Kubernetes may allow more extensive node management. Discussions continue on optimizing node arrangements to emulate mainnet conditions effectively. Monitoring metrics post-implementation, the correlation between increased bandwidth and CPU usage with relay rate changes, and the effects on mempool turnover during congestion and high fee periods are areas requiring further research. Community input is sought to refine simulation strategies to ensure they accurately represent and inform on mainnet behavior.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T12:43:52.567000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
