<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
  <updated>2024-01-24T02:21:49.211993+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-23 17:15:37.327000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 04:52:15.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-19 16:56:04.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1315_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1240_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1224_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
    <updated>2024-01-24T02:21:49.212037+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ephemeral-anchors-and-mevil/383/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the analysis of blockchain transaction strategies, a dialogue unfolds involving the interaction of multiple transactions, with particular emphasis on their fee structures and how these play into miner incentives. The discussion begins by scrutinizing a diagram where all transactions are depicted as having non-zero fees, raising questions about the approach taken for ephemeral anchor outputs. A revised understanding is introduced through additional diagrams, illustrating scenarios where ephemeral anchor spends are assessed against various transaction types to simulate Replace-by-Fee (RBF) scenarios.

One example showcases an ephemeral anchor spend from `TxA` being compared to a 65-byte OP_RETURN transaction labeled `TxC`, which serves as a pure burn with a fee of 1000 satoshis. Despite `TxB` offering a higher total fee, it does not prevail over the pure burn due to its lack of dominance in the fee structure, leading to its rejection. Conversely, when the proposed spend from `TxA` to `TxB` carries a fee of 1400 satoshis, this transaction is accepted given that it satisfies both the higher total fee and fee rate criteria.

The correspondence progresses to dissect the economic considerations underlying miner preferences and the strategic maneuvering of transaction participants like Alice and Bob. It delves into the conditions for Bob's `TxC` to steer clear of direct competition with `TxA`, emphasizing the value limit of the ephemeral anchor. This is relevant because miners might opt to directly claim the anchor through a simpler, smaller transaction if it were profitable enough. To avoid reliance on `TxA`, Bob's `TxC` must offer substantial fees from other sources, proposing a figure of 101 units. This would enable Bob to initiate a conflict with `TxD`, presenting an appealing proposition to miners based on total fee and fee rate without engaging with `TxA`.

Additionally, the email touches upon an anomaly within the "anti-MEVil" mechanism, meant to prevent unfavorable transaction ordering. The conversation uncovers a loophole whereby increasing the ephemeral anchor value can be exploited, especially under the bip125 rule3 pin. An entity could leverage trimmed funds from 'Alice' to provoke a conflict with 'TxD'. This aberration is a consequence of anti-DoS rules; without them, adversaries would have no extra incentive to inflate the ephemeral anchor value. However, these rules inadvertently create a motive to do so when it leads to a child transaction conflicting with another, thus potentially distorting the standard transaction validation process.

The discourse encapsulates the nuanced dynamics of transaction fee economics within blockchain systems and underscores the multifaceted strategies employed by participants to optimize their outcomes in a competitive mining landscape. It reflects a deep comprehension of how transactions are engineered to appeal to miners and how certain mechanisms may give rise to unintended strategic behaviors.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-23T17:15:37.327000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
