<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mailing list mode</title>
  <updated>2024-01-31T02:01:12.846440+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida.498000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef.192000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..962000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  ..334000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  ..360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1382_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1377_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1376_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1375_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1373_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/572_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mailing list mode</title>
    <updated>2024-01-31T02:01:12.846526+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mailing-list-mode/245" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email exchange sheds light on the current state of email interaction within the DelvingBitcoin forum. A user inquires about the ability to respond directly to forum threads through an email client without having to log into the website. The response clarifies that this feature is not enabled and must be activated by an administrator before users can reply to forum posts via email. This functionality, when available, will allow users to maintain a traditional mailing list experience within the Bitcoin development community, catering to those who prefer this method of communication.

To streamline the management of incoming information from various sources, the email suggests employing email filters and mailing list mode. Filters can automatically organize emails into specific labels based on their content. Mailing list mode consolidates updates from the forum into a single stream, which is beneficial for following multiple threads. Although a screenshot was provided to demonstrate the interface where configurations can be made, it cannot be displayed in text form.

Furthermore, there is an ongoing discussion about the utility of the "disable mailing list mode" option, which has recently been turned off. Debaters are considering whether subscribing to specific tags or categories might be more advantageous than using the comprehensive mailing list mode. For users interested in adjusting their settings, instructions are provided: click on the favicon at the top right corner, select the head-and-shoulders icon, navigate to the preferences option, and then the email tab. Additionally, a Discourse community link ([Completely disable mailing list mode](https://meta.discourse.org/t/completely-disable-mailing-list-mode/37334)) hosts further discussion on this topic. Changes to these features aim to refine notification management and influence user interaction with both content and other members within the platform.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-30T15:39:51.498000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
