<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
  <updated>2024-01-21T02:10:30.578176+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-20 04:52:15.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-19 16:56:04.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1240_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1224_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T02:10:30.578229+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ephemeral-anchors-and-mevil/383/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain transactions, a detailed analysis was presented regarding a potential anomaly concerning transaction fees and the creation of conflicts between transactions. The discussion centers on a scenario where an entity, possibly motivated by external payments, manipulates the ephemeral anchor value to create a conflict with another transaction. This situation becomes particularly relevant when considering transactions that are subject to the bip125 rule3 pin.

The example provided describes 'Bob' using 'Alice's trimmed funds to create a conflict with 'TxD'. A flowchart included in this analysis shows four different transactions: 'TxA', which has a fee of 1 unit and a size of 1 unit; 'TxB', which has a fee of 5 units, a size of 1 unit, and is in conflict with 'TxC'; 'TxC', which has a fee of 106 units and a size of 1 unit; and 'TxD', which has a fee of 100 units, a size of 100 units, and also conflicts with 'TxC'.

The critical point of contention involves the anti-DoS rules currently implemented, which inadvertently create a loophole. In absence of these rules, there would be no additional incentive for malicious actors to engage in such behavior since it would lead to an increase in the fee rate required for their subsequent child transactions. However, due to the existence of these rules, there is a perverse incentive to artificially raise the ephemeral anchor value. This can result in a child transaction that conflicts with another, causing unforeseen effects within the system for validating transactions. It raises concerns about the effectiveness of the "anti-MEVil" mechanism intended to prevent malicious transaction ordering, suggesting that the current rules might encourage precisely the kind of behavior they were designed to deter.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-20T04:52:15.672000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
