<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
  <updated>2024-02-01T02:06:46.640471+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-31 19:13:07.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-24 22:44:23.190000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-01-24 22:04:54.478000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-24 12:19:55.474000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-24 05:20:08.136000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-23 17:15:37.327000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 04:52:15.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-19 16:56:04.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1398_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1331_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1329_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1320_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1319_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1315_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1240_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1224_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T02:06:46.640548+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ephemeral-anchors-and-mevil/383/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email conversation involves a detailed technical discussion about the fee rate dynamics in blockchain transactions, particularly concerning the use of ephemeral anchors and their potential manipulation by third parties. This concept is important in networks such as the Lightning Network, where transaction fees play a critical role in maintaining efficient and equitable payment channels.

A hypothetical situation is presented where a counterparty might inflate transaction fees by manipulating ephemeral anchor values. This could force other channel participants to resort to Replace-by-Fee (RBF) mechanisms, inadvertently increasing their costs due to higher block feerates needed for prompt inclusion on the blockchain. The concern is that while an initial transaction passes the pure burn diagram check and has attached fees, it may not confirm quickly enough, leading to additional fees for RBF.

The discussion further delves into optimizing transaction fees within the Bitcoin network by considering the strategic behavior of miners and peers in response to protocol-enforced checks. A specific comparison is made between two combined transactions (TxA+TxB) with a certain fee rate against a single transaction (TxA) including a pure burn of the ephemeral anchor, which increases the fee rate. The sender suggests adjusting the byte count for the burn from 65 bytes to 41 bytes if the ephemeral anchor is added as an input to an existing transaction. This adjustment reflects efficiency gains from combining inputs rather than creating separate transactions.

Moreover, there is a focus on a conditional check within a code snippet related to transaction fees. The sender calculates the fee rate of combining TxA and TxB compared to TxA with an additional ephemeral anchor burn. The provided C++ code offers a condition that must be met for a transaction to succeed regarding fee sufficiency when spending by the ephemeral anchor. The importance of calculating the correct byte size to maintain an adequate fee rate is emphasized.

The discussion also illustrates various scenarios using diagrams to verify transactions according to fee structure and size, determining their validity within the system. For example, a diagram shows that a transaction with higher total fees but not dominating a pure burn would be rejected. It is implied that "pure burn" cases do not require incremental relay checks and would inherently be accepted without further verification.

Lastly, the email describes how transaction fee economics and strategic considerations can influence the crafting of transactions attractive to miners. It outlines the strategies of two parties, Alice and Bob, in a competitive blockchain environment, highlighting the complexities of navigating around the actions of others to maximize benefits.

In summary, the conversation examines the challenges of ensuring fair and efficient transaction fee rates in the presence of potential manipulations by third parties, the importance of correctly calculating transaction sizes for fee optimization, and the strategic behavior of network participants in a complex transaction fee market.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T19:13:07.936000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
