<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-02-19T01:56:05.652968+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rgrant 2024-02-18 01:33:26.363000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>arshbot  . 2024-02-16 21:12:50.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>arshbot  . 2024-02-14 22:52:05.913000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-02-14 02:56:12.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-19 21:45:17.997000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 21:13:36.520000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-19 20:40:21.562000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 20:32:01.313000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 20:07:13.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 19:38:31.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 22:46:22.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-18 20:39:44.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-17 01:30:45.419000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1595_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1591_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1574_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1556_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1234_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1232_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1231_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1230_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1229_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1227_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1213_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1211_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1171_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1152_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T01:56:05.653123+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse delves into Bitcoin's development process, focusing on the nuanced roles of developers, miners, and users in the soft fork activation process. It challenges the conventional belief that miners primarily influence soft fork activations, revealing a complex interaction where developers play a significant role in initiating changes. This underscores the importance of developer consensus before proposing activation to miners, highlighting the lack of trusted figures to guide decisions and the need for leadership to address indecision on significant issues.

Two governance models, direct democracy and representative democracy, are discussed as potential solutions to the leadership void within the Bitcoin community, with a preference for representative democracy to align with Bitcoin's foundational ideals. The stagnation of technical proposals due to minimal direct impact on everyday users is explored, indicating a broader issue where significant updates struggle to gain traction. This points to an inherent resistance within the system against shifts that could democratize influence or substantially alter the user experience.

Environmental concerns related to Bitcoin are acknowledged, along with the challenges of managing consensus changes without succumbing to external coercion. The discussion differentiates between weak and strong technical consensus, using OP_EVAL as a case study to illustrate the complexities of reaching agreement within the community. A significant concern regarding the adaptability of perspectives on Bitcoin's development suggests a dichotomy between flexible and rigid viewpoints, emphasizing the need for adaptation to avoid obsolescence.

The narrative also addresses the broader vision for Bitcoin's development, emphasizing the creation of a sustainable system that can adapt to a growing user base and evolving use cases. Achieving consensus before initiating a soft fork is crucial to prevent divisiveness and potential chain splits, with historical incidents like the "block size war" illustrating the disruptive effects of proceeding without unanimous agreement. The discussion underscores the need for caution and suggests consulting historical accounts to understand the implications of proceeding without consensus, as indicated by a book on the block size war available [here](https://www.amazon.com/Blocksize-War-Control-Bitcoins-Protocol/dp/B096CLR1SS/).

The conversation includes recent discussions advocating for an activation client with the LockinOnTimeout (LOT) parameter set to false, expressing concerns over the drawbacks of LOT=true. The distinction between achieving technical consensus on software changes and reaching agreement on consensus rule alterations is emphasized, reflecting a pragmatic approach to governance in decentralized systems.

Rusty Russell's blog post models the Bitcoin soft fork activation process as "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override," delineating the roles of different stakeholders. This model emphasizes the collaborative and structured approach required for successful soft fork activation, portraying a system where checks and balances are integral to the democratic evolution of the network. The sender expresses admiration for Russell's insights and encourages further exploration of the nuances of proposal, activation, and user sovereignty in these processes.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-18T01:33:26.363000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
