<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-01-30T02:22:07.074035+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>amiti 2024-01-29 22:41:00.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 03:46:40.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:56:02.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:48:45.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-22 03:04:11.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-21 18:03:33.954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2023-12-21 11:23:16.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-20 21:54:22.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-18 02:43:32.230000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-14 21:14:15.928000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1374_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1238_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1235_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1237_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/849_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/848_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/845_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/843_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/783_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/732_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-01-30T02:22:07.074124+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Blockchain network optimization requires a delicate balance between transaction relay efficiency and system security. Setting a minimum fee rate is critical to prevent abuse and manage bandwidth costs. The target is to synchronize the top 1MB of the mempool, allowing miners to access high-fee transactions, using topological fee rate sorting for prioritization.

Testing revealed that excessively high relay rates can be problematic, but low rates can cause synchronization issues. Using compact block logging as a heuristic has been suggested to measure synchronization. Simulation studies have shown mempool synchronization challenges during high transaction rates, with possible causes including resource-intensive operations and inconsistent simulation results. Identifying these causes is essential for system optimization.

In a Warnet scenario with 100 nodes, simulations focused on Bitcoin transaction relay did not show significant performance changes with pending updates. Future tests will consider the effects of different transaction features and higher node counts. A Kubernetes-based environment is proposed for enhanced stability and handling increased transaction volumes.

The limitations in presenting simulated pull request (PR) outcomes are noted due to the absence of visual data. The discussion is thus steered toward collaborative development practices without detailed simulation results. Mocktime implementation needs careful consideration, with a preference for real-time testing to ensure practicality and precision.

Adjusting block production frequency directly influences transaction clearance. Researchers advocate for cautious adjustments during simulations to maintain relevance to real-world conditions. Testing under accelerated block production aims to emulate high-load scenarios but may not accurately represent standard operations.

The proposal includes experimenting with various node counts and establishing deterministic UTXO generation to determine performance thresholds. Aligning individual node metrics with network standards is crucial. A study on transaction rates and network performance will use a 100-node network running Bitcoin Core version 26.0 to observe system behavior, potentially adjusting connection parameters for accurate emulation of larger networks. Blocks will be mined every ten minutes, underscoring the significance of transaction distribution patterns.

A project is underway to assess compact block relay efficiency by generating Taproot or P2WSH transactions at specific rates. Dynamic fee calculation through `estimatesmartfee 5` and observing network handling of block relays via debug mode logs are key components. Concerns include potential mempool discrepancies and transaction requests exceeding 18 transactions per second, especially during RBF operations or CPFP scenarios.

Replicating mainnet conditions is challenging due to its complexity and warnet resource limitations. However, tests show the feasibility of running 250 nodes using Docker, with scalability options like Kubernetes. The ideal node count and network topology to best reflect mainnet are still under discussion.

Post-implementation analysis will focus on identifying critical metrics such as bandwidth and CPU usage changes, mempool turnover, and fee rates during congestion. Different relay rates' impact on transaction propagation and the memory footprint from internal send queues are also under consideration. Community feedback is invited to refine these concepts and prioritize key elements, aiming to simulate an environment that offers insights into the behaviors of the mainnet.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-29T22:41:00.411000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
