<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:47:42.789090+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-07 20:48:53.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-07 20:31:47.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-07 19:55:48.846000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-07 19:30:43.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-07 19:17:58.402000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-07 18:41:08.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1000_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/999_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/996_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/995_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/993_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/989_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:47:42.789090+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lnhance-bips-and-implementation/376/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discourse among developers reveals that there is a consideration of different constructs that can be built on the Bitcoin network to enhance its capabilities, particularly concerning non-interactive channels (NIC), Payment Point/Hash Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs), and Lightning Network symmetrical channels (LN-Symmetry). PTLCs are acknowledged as currently feasible, while more advanced constructions like APO-like ones represent more ambitious developments.

Discussion has also highlighted the importance of having a dedicated space for testing significant changes prior to proposing them for activation in Bitcoin Core. This optional step is seen as beneficial for refining changes, although there is concern about the proliferation of differing proposals which could clutter the review process. The role of repositories such as bitcoin-inquisition is emphasized for handling proposed consensus changes to maintain focus within the main Bitcoin Core repository on non-consensus work.

A particular focus point is the criticism of the APO construct, which centers on the introduction of new key types along with a fixed set of sighash flags, limiting future upgrade paths. An open pull request suggests an alternative design to address this issue, indicating that the design space for sighash flags is large and lacks direct upgradeability. The conversation includes the sharing of a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) related to this matter ([BIP PR #1472](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1472)).

The debate further extends to the concept of LN-Symmetry and whether it should be implemented using APO or an alternative method. It's suggested that CTV (CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) combined with CHECKSIGFROMSTACK (CSFS) can provide a narrow design space with well-understood operations, potentially offering a foundational framework for future enhancements.

Finally, recent activity indicates the opening of new pull requests ([#29198](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29198), [#1534](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1534), and [#1535](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1535)) aimed at implementing a combination of BIP119, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK(VERIFY), and OP_INTERNALKEY, collectively termed "LNHANCE." These features are proposed as a starting point for introducing output-restricting covenants to Bitcoin and supporting the next iteration of Lightning development, including LN-Symmetry and PTLCs.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-07T20:48:53.197000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
