<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-01-15T02:07:17.762135+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-14 12:44:16.551000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-14 06:13:17.355000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-14 05:52:08.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-10 19:56:47.130000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-01-10 17:01:16.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:41:17.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-05 18:09:14.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1109_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1108_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1107_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1060_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1059_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/934_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/932_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/931_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/929_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-01-15T02:07:17.762217+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Technical challenges were encountered during the testing of eltoo, an update mechanism for the Lightning Network. Issues included feature bit overlap, broken non-eltoo channels, and difficulties in payment processing and shutdown processes. Node restarts were problematic due to invalid data retention.

Attempts to use ephemeral anchors for broadcasting transactions faced problems in key recovery for fund reclamation. CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) emerged as a solution to reduce round-trip confirmations by spending update transactions via settlement transactions without additional signatures, despite potential trade-offs in storage and complexity.

Documentation on GitHub details CTV's role in reducing communication steps and tracking discussions on its implications. A limitation was noted with the current protocol's single nonce usage, which could be addressed by incorporating optimistic updates to improve security.

Eltoo channels involve a complex process with multiple phases that can extend timelock durations. The LN-Symmetry Project advanced eltoo by developing software and functional tests, bypassing softforks or consensus requirements. The project also contributed to efforts like the Package Relay Project and developed a CLN implementation supporting eltoo available on GitHub.

Development and testing resources for CLN are accessible on GitHub, including a branch by instagibbs for anyprevout feature testing at https://github.com/instagibbs/bitcoin/tree/202207-anyprevout and an alternative Bitcoin protocol version at https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/releases/tag/v25.1-inq.

Progress has been made on BOLT specifications for segwit ephemeral anchors, with drafts shared for review at https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/tree/eltoo_draft. Libwally library updates support taproot changes, relevant for wallet functionality compatibility, and are available at https://github.com/instagibbs/libwally-core/tree/taproot.

Research into Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs) integration with eltoo channels is documented at https://gist.github.com/instagibbs/1d02d0251640c250ceea1c66665ec163single-sig-adaptor-ln-symmetry, offering insights into enhancing Lightning Network symmetry and functionality. Discussion on anti-pin technology and proposed policy changes within Bitcoin Core are tracked through commit history at https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/commits/zero_fee_commitment.

Although currently on hiatus, the LN-Symmetry Project's findings are expected to influence future softfork discussions and channel design, contributing to the Bitcoin network's robustness and functionality.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-14T12:44:16.551000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
