<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
  <updated>2024-01-25T02:11:40.251281+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-24 22:44:23.190000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Crypt-iQ 2024-01-24 22:04:54.478000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-24 12:19:55.474000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-24 05:20:08.136000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-23 17:15:37.327000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 04:52:15.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-19 16:56:04.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1331_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1329_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1320_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1319_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1315_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1240_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1224_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T02:11:40.251380+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ephemeral-anchors-and-mevil/383/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The intricacies of blockchain transaction fee structures and the strategies employed by participants in a competitive mining environment are highlighted in an in-depth discussion. A transaction diagram check is introduced as a means to validate transactions based on their fee structure and size, ensuring they conform to a proposed system that includes ephemeral anchor outputs. The concept is explained through hypothetical scenarios involving multiple transactions with varying fees and sizes, illustrating how transactions might be accepted or rejected according to the guidelines of the diagram check.

A situation is presented where two parties, Alice and Bob, engage in complex maneuvers across several transactions. Bob aims to avoid competition with Alice's transaction by ensuring that his transaction provides sufficient fees from other sources to create a direct conflict with another transaction, thereby bypassing Alice's interest in the combination of transactions. The dialogue suggests that a miner's economic incentives play a crucial role in deciding which transactions to confirm, considering both total fees and fee rates. The example underscores the strategic considerations involved in crafting transactions attractive to miners, emphasizing the fee market dynamics within a blockchain system.

Further exploration reveals concerns about the potential manipulation of the ephemeral anchor value by third parties, particularly in relation to the bip125 rule3 pin. An illustrative flowchart outlines a scenario where one party could exploit trimmed funds from another's transaction to instigate a conflict with a different transaction. The current anti-DoS rules introduce an unintended incentive for adversaries to artificially inflate the ephemeral anchor value, especially when this can lead to conflicts between child transactions and others in the mempool. This anomaly in the "anti-MEVil" mechanism, designed to mitigate malicious transaction ordering, points to the complexities of the transaction validation process and highlights the need for careful consideration of the rules governing blockchain transaction fees and conflicts.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-24T22:44:23.190000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
