<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-18T02:09:35.206641+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-01-17 01:30:45.419000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1171_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1152_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T02:09:35.206726+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent exchanges among programmers regarding Bitcoin's activation process and consensus rule changes have been robust and multifaceted, encompassing technical nuances, historical precedents, and future strategies for network upgrades. At the forefront of these discussions is the emphasis on achieving readiness before signaling support for soft fork activation to avoid chain splits and maintain a unified network. The experience from the block size war serves as a cautionary tale against hasty actions that could lead to unproductive periods and unnecessary division within the community.

The dialogue has also underscored the potential risks associated with not publishing LOT=FALSE clients and instead observing the outcomes, especially under a 95% threshold which determines the success or failure of the activation. This binary approach highlights a strategic choice that draws upon past insights, suggesting that clear goals are essential to prevent fragmentation of the network and loss of hash power. The importance of users adopting new consensus logic well in advance and the limitations of miner signaling as the sole measure of readiness are recognized as pivotal factors for ensuring stability.

Further complicating the landscape are differing opinions on the nature of Bitcoin mining and its evolution, particularly in light of historical instances like the July 2015 chain forks. Concerns about miners engaging in false signaling, which could lead to financial losses or even theft, illustrate the complexity of managing trust within the system. Debates continue over whether Bitcoin's consensus rules should be altered in response to external regulatory pressures, such as OFAC compliance—a move that would significantly alter the decentralized ethos of Bitcoin.

Despite the challenges, there is a consensus within the developer community on various enhancements post-taproot activation, with many proposals being integrated or widely accepted, such as encrypted peer connections and miniscript support in hardware wallets. However, the resistance to certain other ideas indicates a discerning approach to upgrades, with an overarching concern about chain splits and their detrimental impact on Bitcoin's economy.

The conversation has also touched upon the distinct processes of technical consensus versus agreement on consensus rule changes, the latter posing greater risks. There is a recognition of the importance of users influencing miners through the publication of activation clients, highlighting a pragmatic approach to governance in decentralized systems.

The role of miner-activated soft forks (MASFs) in consensus changes has been discussed, with an acknowledgment of miners' historical involvement in protocol amendments. Yet, the contentiousness of MASFs post-block size debate remains a point of concern. The discourse suggests that while some oppose MASFs, they are still considered a viable means for enacting soft forks under the right circumstances.

In terms of the process for achieving consensus on soft forks, a proactive strategy that sets a target year for activation has been suggested. This brinksmanship approach may encourage more active engagement and development cooperation within the community, emphasizing the urgency for Bitcoin's continued relevance and evolution.

Finally, the transition from a traditional model where a singular authoritative voice led proposal changes to a more decentralized and uncertain landscape has introduced complexities into the consensus process. With the socio-economic environment still adjusting to high coordination costs and review requirements, alternative implementations to `bitcoind` remain a less favored solution. The growing sentiment towards hard forks among community members on social media, despite their inherent coordination challenges, signals a transformation in the way developers, miners, and users interact to bring about changes in the Bitcoin ecosystem.

Rusty Russell's blog post, which outlines the roles of developers proposing changes, miners activating them, and users ultimately having the power to override, encapsulates the intricate balance of power within Bitcoin's soft fork activation model. This model highlights a system wherein each stakeholder group plays a crucial role in the governance of the network, ensuring a balanced and consensual approach to implementing changes.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T20:20:44.934000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
