<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Deploying new taproot leaf versions</title>
  <updated>2024-01-19T02:18:15.552921+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1183_Deploying-new-taproot-leaf-versions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1092_Deploying-new-taproot-leaf-versions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Deploying new taproot leaf versions</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T02:18:15.552958+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deploying-new-taproot-leaf-versions/406" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussion on the implementation of new leaf versions in Bitcoin's interpreter has introduced a proposal to define a new `SigVersion`. This addition has the potential to alter how certain opcodes are interpreted, depending on the version. A specific instance of this is the creation of leaf version `0x66`, which demonstrates the possibility of disabling the OP_CHECKSIGADD opcode. It should be emphasized that this particular change is simply an illustrative example, not a suggestion to modify the actual functionality, but rather to spark dialogue about the role of new leaf versions.

The GitHub link provided in the discussion serves as a concrete example, showcasing where these modifications have been applied. The branch reflects changes in the codebase and offers a basis for the technical evaluation of this concept. The initiative is not advocating for the deactivation of OP_CHECKSIGADD, however, it brings to light the broader implications and potential uses of new leaf versions within Bitcoin's interpreter system.

The discussion points towards an interest in expanding the interpreter's flexibility and highlights the ongoing efforts to refine script execution within the Bitcoin network. Further details and examples of how new leaf versions could operate would provide greater clarity on their intended function and the extent of their influence on the system's interpretive processes. For those interested in delving deeper into the technical aspects, the link to the GitHub repository is a valuable resource: https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/tree/2024-01-12-new-tapleaf-ver-example. As such, this exploration into the interpreter's adaptability through new leaf versions is an integral part of the continuous development of Bitcoin scripting capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-18T07:56:00.171000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
