<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
  <updated>2024-02-22T01:53:02.880131+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar 2024-02-21 13:59:55.418000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto 2024-02-21 12:31:28.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-18 15:43:27.168000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto  . 2024-02-18 15:28:06.571000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-08 15:23:54.319000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-08 15:00:36.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-08 14:15:36.144000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-05 15:08:32.829000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-03 11:29:09.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 15:36:24.905000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 15:00:33.098000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 14:46:32.086000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 14:30:38.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 19:27:17.249000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 18:21:48.769000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 18:04:39.566000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 15:31:36.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 15:04:58.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 01:26:13.557000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-09 22:52:52.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1654_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1652_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1599_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1598_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1490_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1489_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1485_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1461_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1450_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1447_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1442_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1441_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1429_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1097_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1096_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1095_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1090_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1089_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1087_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1046_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
    <updated>2024-02-22T01:53:02.880273+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Replace-by-Fee (RBF) transactions and their implementation within the Bitcoin network present significant challenges due to the need for detailed information about mempool ordering and feerates. Introduced in Bitcoin Core in 2015, and documented in BIP 125, RBF rules necessitate an understanding of conflicting transactions' feerates and total fees, including their descendants within the mempool. This complexity often leads wallet developers to iteratively increase transaction fees until acceptance into a mempool or confirmation, diverging from the specific requirements outlined in BIP 125.

The discussion further delves into transaction management on the blockchain, highlighting proposals aimed at enhancing scalability and addressing limitations in CoinJoin transactions through proposed limits on ancestor and descendant cluster sizes. These modifications intend to allow for more outputs from a single transaction to be spent before confirmation, potentially expanding blockchain transaction capabilities.

An algorithm suggesting prioritization of transactions based on fee rates is proposed to optimize mempool efficiency, introducing a process for managing large clusters within the mempool through strategic eviction based on a Cumulative Fee Rate (CFR). However, this approach does not fully address challenges such as incremental relay pin issues, indicating a need for further refinement in transaction selection strategies.

Considerations for reinserting previously evicted transactions emphasize a conservative strategy, aiming to minimize eviction impacts by identifying a minimal subset of transactions for removal. This consideration raises questions about the computational feasibility of such strategies.

The inefficiencies and security concerns associated with re-validating transactions that may be evicted and then re-accepted are noted, with suggestions for direct state transitions to mitigate these issues. Moreover, the potential for "top block" methodologies to optimize transaction selection processes is acknowledged, pointing towards evolving blockchain technology and the search for effective solutions to accommodate growing transaction volumes.

The blog post critiques current methods used to improve mempool quality and suggests delegating the computational task of deciding which transactions to evict to peers. It explores challenges in implementing an optimal transaction eviction policy and discusses alternative strategies, including sibling eviction as an alternative to the Child-Pays-For-Parent (CPFP) carveout rule within Bitcoin's mempool management. The refinement of 'carveout' rules utilized by the Lightning Network (LN) and the concept of applying incentive-compatibility to transaction fee rates are also covered.

Bitcoin Core's mempool policy revisions propose a new design focusing on cluster size limitations and a 'strictly better feerate diagram' for transaction replacement. This redesign aims to replace the current ancestor and descendant limits with a cluster-based organization, addressing challenges in transaction eviction and RBF calculations. Concerns over RBF pinning and the discontinuation of the CPFP carve-out rule are discussed, alongside anticipated advantages such as enhanced mining efficiency and streamlined transaction processing. Further details and initial draft implementations have been shared for community feedback, with additional analysis and benchmarking expected.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T13:59:55.418000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
