<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2026-01-23T03:03:47.249526+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>ProofOfKeags</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-05 18:09:14.568000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-05 18:41:17.125000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-10 17:01:16.260000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-10 19:56:47.130000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-14 05:52:08.172000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-14 06:13:17.355000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-14 12:44:16.551000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-15 06:56:27.495000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>cguida</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-16 16:35:24.004000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>cguida</author>
      <timestamp>2024-01-24 17:05:16.348000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-24 04:13:31.288000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-26 14:57:10.543000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="14">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-27 06:21:18.196000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="15">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-27 06:27:47.378000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="16">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2026-01-22 19:09:37.255000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/929_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/931_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/932_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/934_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1059_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1060_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1107_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1108_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1109_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1113_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1144_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1326_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1683_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1697_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1710_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1712_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2026/6671_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:03:47.251338+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The LN-Symmetry Project has taken significant strides in advancing the eltoo proposal, transforming it into research-quality software aimed at enhancing the Lightning Network's efficiency and reliability. Through meticulous development, the project has introduced basic functional tests for various channel operations, including openings, payments, and unilateral closes, among others. Despite achieving these milestones, some features like cooperative closes and genuine persistence mechanisms for new key types/fields remain undeveloped due to ongoing enhancements in current specifications and technical challenges. Notably, the project has focused on simplifying BOLT specifications and addressing eltoo's technical hurdles to assess its viability comprehensively.
A pivotal aspect of the project's success is attributed to the innovative use of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) emulation, which has significantly improved fee management and reduced the necessity for a utxo pool for fees. This advancement facilitates more streamlined payment processes by eliminating the need for round-trips in the payment protocol, potentially leading to faster transaction times. However, the project has also uncovered challenges, such as the difficulty of avoiding pinning and the realization that eltoo-style channels require longer htlc expiry deltas for enhanced security. These insights have contributed to a growing skepticism regarding the effectiveness of penalties in deterring competent adversaries, advocating instead for systems that inherently function correctly.
The LN-Symmetry Project has produced several key work artifacts, including comprehensive anti-pinning research that has been instrumental in the Package Relay Project, and the creation of Ephemeral Anchors. Additionally, the development of a CLN implementation and necessary changes to Bitcoin Core for CLN blackbox tests underline the project's extensive efforts in pushing forward the capabilities of the Lightning Network. Drafts for the BOLT specification incorporating segwit ephemeral anchors and libwally updates to support taproot changes further exemplify the project’s commitment to innovation. Insights into PTLCs and their compatibility with eltoo-style channels, alongside discussions on backporting anti-pin technology to current BOLTs, highlight the project's forward-thinking approach to channel design advancements.
As the project transitions its focus towards mempool-related work, it leaves behind a legacy of significant contributions aimed at de-risking future softfork discussions and channel design improvements. The exploration of efficient transaction protocols and fee structures within the blockchain framework has sparked conversations about optimizing update mechanisms for better performance and scalability. The comparison between adapter signatures and CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) mechanisms has opened up avenues for more collaborative and interconnected transaction networks. Furthermore, the potential for generalization to multi-party channels using a CTV-like approach underscores its versatility beyond single-user cases.
In summary, the LN-Symmetry Project's endeavors in advancing eltoo and its associated technologies reflect a concerted effort to address the inherent challenges of scalability and efficiency in blockchain systems. By exploring novel commitment schemes and optimizing transaction processes, the project contributes valuable insights and tools to the ongoing evolution of the Lightning Network and blockchain technology at large.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>