<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-17T02:10:58.487782+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T02:10:58.487860+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discourse among Bitcoin developers emphasizes the importance of carefully considered consensus mechanisms, particularly in relation to the activation of upgrades within the blockchain protocol. A recent discussion has centered on the proposed use of an activation client that prefers the LockinOnTimeout (LOT) parameter to be set to false. This approach aligns with a broader philosophy that prioritizes organic consensus and informed decision-making over enforced network changes. There is an understanding that while miner actions such as false signaling may not be ideal, they are deemed acceptable within the ecosystem's operation. The dialogue underscores the significance of ensuring that users have upgraded their software before any activation takes place and highlights the limitations of relying solely on miner signaling.

In detailing technical versus consensus rule changes, there is recognition of the delicate nature of the latter due to the high stakes involved. A soft fork without unanimous support might lead to a chain split, creating financial risks for miners and potential losses for uninformed users. Despite the risks, the sender expresses a preference for the LOT=false approach, which minimizes the likelihood of a chain split. The conversation also touches upon Bitcoin's history of mining and the precedent set by past events, including the July 2015 chain forks, where false signaling by miners led to unintended splits—a situation that could, hypothetically, lead to significant deviations from established practices.

Post-taproot activation, the Bitcoin community appears to have reached a technical consensus on several enhancements that were previously contentious. These include encrypted peer connections, full Replace-by-Fee (RBF), and advancements in the Lightning Network. However, certain proposals have been rejected due to a lack of widespread acceptance. The email notes the potential economic harm caused by chain splits and advocates for cautious approaches to modifying consensus rules, suggesting that if these risks cannot be mitigated, it would be better to halt further changes and ossify the protocol.

The debate over miner-activated soft forks reveals divergent views on the role of miners in consensus changes. Some community members perceive MASFs negatively due to their ability to coerce updates, while others recognize their utility in enacting non-coercive upgrades. The discussion has evolved from focusing on implementation methods to defining what constitutes consensus for activating upgrades. The legitimacy of opposing a soft fork is tied to whether it alters existing coin functions contrary to user expectations. Safety is paramount, and utility is indicated by review interest. A proposal is made for a brinksmanship approach to encourage timely engagement in the development process, emphasizing the urgency to maintain Bitcoin's relevance.

There has been a shift in the Bitcoin development landscape, moving away from a centralized authoritative voice for proposing changes to a more distributed model. This change has brought increased uncertainty, especially for economic actors who rely on the definition of "rough consensus." While BIPs 9 and 8 allow multiple simultaneous soft fork proposals, the broader socio-economic context is still adjusting to this new paradigm. Alternative implementations to `bitcoind` remain underdeveloped and risky for conservative participants. Controversy persists around miner-activated upgrades, and some community members increasingly lean towards hard forks. This reflects a reevaluation of update and activation mechanisms within the decentralized Bitcoin ecosystem.

Lastly, the email references Rusty Russell's blog post, which articulates a clear model for Bitcoin soft fork activation: "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override." This model embodies the balance of power between developers, miners, and users, ensuring a collaborative yet independent approach to network evolution. The sender appreciates Russell's perspective and seeks further insight into achieving broader consensus, indicative of the complex dynamics that govern cryptocurrency governance.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T23:10:55.866000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
