<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:40:12.827301+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:40:12.828299+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the activation of soft forks within the Bitcoin network highlights a critical examination of the roles played by miners, developers, and users. The debate is rooted in the nuances of how changes should be implemented, particularly focusing on the asymmetry between soft and hard forks. It is argued that miners hold the administrative responsibility to execute consensus updates, which includes the capability to enforce progressive soft forks by selectively censoring non-compliant transactions. This ability, however, should not be mistaken for an absolute power to override the collective will of the user base. Instead, mechanisms like BIP8/9 suggest a collaborative effort where miners signal their willingness to activate new features, while still being subject to user-initiated action if they reject widely supported upgrades.

When considering the readiness for activating a soft fork, it's essential to differentiate between the types of changes proposed. Non-invasive soft forks offer opt-in capabilities without altering existing users' interactions with Bitcoin, while more significant changes — such as those affecting Bitcoin's block reward or social contract — warrant stronger opposition if attempted covertly. The key is determining whether a proposal would alter the behavior of existing coins in ways that users did not anticipate when acquiring them. While proving the utility of a change can help garner interest and review, ensuring the safety of current system usage is paramount.

In terms of process, there's an emerging suggestion to approach consensus changes from the endpoint, working backward from activation rather than forward from the proposal. The concept aims to foster development speed and cooperation among stakeholders by setting a timeline for a future soft fork, with its contents yet to be determined but agreed upon as necessary. This brinksmanship could potentially drive the community to actively participate in finding a suitable agreement for Bitcoin's evolution, recognizing that its success isn't guaranteed without active engagement.

Reflecting on the structure of proposing changes, the absence of a unified voice within the `bitcoind` organization has led to ambiguity around what constitutes a ready proposal. Historically effective mechanisms may not assure future success, and the community continues to explore how best to navigate this emergent process. There's mention of the potential for alternative implementations to gain traction as viable platforms for proposals, despite currently lagging behind in development resources compared to `bitcoind`. 

The notion of "miners activate" remains contentious within the community, with divergent interpretations arising from past events such as the segwit and block size debates. Some community sentiments appear to favor hard forks, desiring updates that necessitate universal adoption, contrary to the original design of soft forks intended to bypass the challenges of global coordination by allowing optional upgrades.

A referenced blog post by Rusty Russell provides further insight into soft fork activation, reinforcing the model where developers propose, miners activate, and users have the final say. This framework underpins the ongoing discourse on achieving consensus and the practicalities of implementing changes within Bitcoin's decentralized ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:48:53.288000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
