<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2024-10-04T02:19:36.982128+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewkozlik 2024-10-03 15:18:51.917000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-10-02 15:40:06.265000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2024-01-16 15:02:53.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-01-16 14:34:11.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2024-01-16 14:20:19.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-01-16 11:03:51.006000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-28 16:38:10.719000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>wydengyre  . 2023-12-28 02:34:27.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 20:05:49.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 18:56:24.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 16:59:33.416000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:22.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:16.610000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:33:53.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:30:02.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:26:33.367000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:23:41.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:21:22.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:12:37.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:09:50.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:00:06.516000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 14:55:19.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 14:52:51.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 14:49:37.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 13:35:30.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 13:29:37.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3317_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3308_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1143_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1142_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1141_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1139_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/880_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/877_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/836_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/835_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/808_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/804_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/803_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/802_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/800_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/801_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/799_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/798_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/797_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/796_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/791_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/795_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/794_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/793_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/790_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/789_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T02:19:36.982294+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on improving the management of extended public keys (XPUBs) in wallet programming highlights the need for a method that is independent of their order to mitigate issues arising from the current handling of `sortedmulti_a` descriptors. Proposed solutions include sorting and hashing XPUBs, using XOR or modular addition of hashed XPUBs, with considerations for simplifying the process by focusing on parts of the XPUB such as the compressed public key or the chain code. The latter methods could simplify implementation and address potential security concerns posed by malicious participants manipulating the chain code to achieve a desired outcome.

The dialogue further delves into the integration of wallet policy features and their impact on hardware signers. It underscores the necessity of accommodating wallet policies efficiently, considering the complexities introduced by descriptor templates and the redundancy potential with taproot technology. A flexible approach compatible with any wallet-policy descriptor is favored for its broad applicability and ease of use, highlighting the importance of adaptability in programming practices. This flexibility is contrasted with the limitations posed by approaches requiring specific wallet policies, emphasizing the need for solutions that can cater to a wide range of scenarios without imposing unnecessary constraints.

A technical issue concerning the natural order of xpubs in wallet policies versus their sequence in descriptor templates is identified, suggesting a preference for an approach that aligns with wallet_policy's inherent structure. This aims to rectify inconsistencies and improve coherence in key arrangement. Additionally, the ongoing effort to integrate Taproot support into Liana focuses on enhancing user experience through the use of unspendable internal keys, following a methodology that leverages existing entropy to generate these keys according to specified standards. This approach facilitates seamless integration with future wallet policies and signing devices while ensuring security and consistency.

Comparing methods for making xpubs unspendable reveals a preference for simplicity and verifiability, with discussions around incorporating deterministic computation of chain codes into wallet policies. The straightforwardness of certain approaches, despite increasing descriptor complexity, is deemed an acceptable trade-off for their simplicity. Moreover, the enhancement of privacy and security through XOR operations on xpubs is explored, highlighting the balance between user-friendliness and cryptographic robustness. 

Conversations also touch on the non-disclosure of unspendable key paths to protect privacy, emphasizing the importance of voluntary information sharing. This extends to the management of wallet registrations, suggesting a shift towards backing up wallet policies for a more comprehensive account representation. The distinction between output descriptors and wallet policies is clarified, advocating for tailored properties to suit their respective applications, and the discussion on script complexity within cryptographic protocols raises points on privacy preservation and the identification potential of scripts.

In summary, these discussions reflect a concerted effort within the programming community to address challenges related to key management, wallet policy integration, and the implementation of new cryptographic standards like Taproot. The emphasis is on developing adaptable, secure, and user-friendly solutions that can accommodate the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency transactions and wallet management.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-03T15:18:51.917000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
