<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-12T02:10:31.604242+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-12T02:10:31.604313+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion explores the complexities surrounding Bitcoin's soft fork activation process and the varying opinions on how consensus should be achieved. The conversation begins by addressing the risks associated with miner-activated soft forks (MASFs), emphasizing that not all parties may agree on the activation of a soft fork, which can lead to chain splits and economic repercussions for miners and users alike. There is an acknowledgment that while some may not be concerned about these potential losses, others advocate for activation clients that use `LOT=false` as a way to minimize the risk of such splits.

Contrasting viewpoints are presented regarding the similarity between reaching technical consensus on Bitcoin Core software changes and consensus on Bitcoin's consensus rules. Some believe that the processes and people involved are largely the same, with the stakes being the only significant difference. Others argue that there is a distinct difference between the two, citing past incidents where false signaling by miners led to chain splits, such as the July 2015 event. This is highlighted as a dangerous precedent where miners could exploit false signaling for financial gain.

Further discussion reflects on the successful technical consensus achieved on various features since Taproot's activation, suggesting that Bitcoin's development community can indeed reach agreement on proposals. Examples include encryption in peer connections, full Replace-By-Fee (RBF) options, support for onion messages, Miniscript, and solutions to channel jamming attacks. However, it is also acknowledged that not all ideas gain traction and that if a soft fork proposal has not yet reached consensus, it may be due to a lack of compelling arguments rather than an inability to form consensus.

The dialogue then shifts to the broader discourse around readiness for soft-fork deployment. It outlines that the legitimacy of opposing a soft fork stems from any change that contradicts the expectations of existing coin holders. Review interest often signals utility but does not necessarily equate to influence. A proposed methodology for achieving consensus involves setting a target year for a soft fork without specific details, encouraging proactive engagement among developers and reviewers.

Lastly, the email addresses the changing role of the `bitcoind` organization in proposing changes and the uncertainty this creates for economic actors who depend on a clear definition of "rough consensus." Despite BIPs 9 and 8 allowing for multiple simultaneous soft fork proposals, alternative implementations to `bitcoind` do not offer a reliable solution at present. The community's sentiments toward miner-activated upgrades vary, especially in light of historical debates such as segwit and block size, with some community members expressing a preference for hard forks over soft forks.

The referenced blog post by Rusty Russell introduces a model for Bitcoin soft fork activation encapsulated by "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override," highlighting the roles of developers, miners, and users in the process. This model suggests a system of checks and balances where each group's influence is counterbalanced by the others, ensuring no single entity dominates the decision-making process. The sender of the email appears to appreciate Russell's perspective and invites further discussion on achieving broader consensus within cryptocurrency governance.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-11T09:46:02.345000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
