<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-01-30T08:16:57.308778+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2024-01-29 22:41:00.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>m3dwards 2024-01-29 13:01:26.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 03:46:40.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:56:02.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:48:45.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-22 03:04:11.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-21 18:03:33.954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2023-12-21 11:23:16.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-20 21:54:22.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-18 02:43:32.230000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-14 21:14:15.928000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1374_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1365_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1238_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1235_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1237_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/849_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/848_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/845_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/843_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/783_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/732_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-01-30T08:16:57.308865+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Blockchain networks require a balance between security and efficiency when setting transaction relay rates to prevent "free relay" attacks while ensuring quick transaction propagation and synchronization of the mempool. The relay rate's role is pivotal in network bandwidth management, and recent activity suggests that an increase may be necessary.

Network instability issues were linked not to CPU usage but to the number of network connections. Upgrades to Warnet's scalability and stability are in progress to support higher transaction rates. There is a need to understand how the relay rate correlates with transactions, and how strategies like Replace-by-Fee and Child Pays for Parent affect simulations.

Stability concerns have been raised in single system environments despite simulation predictions, indicating potential issues with CPU-intensive operations or wallet management. A 100-node Bitcoin transaction simulation on Warnet yielded no significant performance changes due to a pending update, leading to questions on relay rate impacts and the suggestion of transitioning to Kubernetes for better handling of high transaction rates.

Access to visual data is required for accurate summaries of simulation outcomes. Discussions about using Pull Requests highlight version control, code review processes, and team communication.

Real-time baselines might offer more practical comparison points than 'mocktime' for time tracking in programming. Applying mocktime correctly is complex but beneficial for validation. Block production rate's influence on transaction clearance and its consideration in peer-to-peer network testing is crucial, with adjustments needed to reflect real-world scenarios.

The proposal to vary node numbers in experiments has been well received, aiming to evaluate network robustness and reconcile individual node performance with overall network standards. The study will analyze different transaction rates and RBF patterns on a 100-node network, focusing on compact block relay efficiency and the expectation of inconsistent mempool synchronization at high transaction rates.

For realistic blockchain simulations, replicating mainnet dynamics and configurations is essential, although challenging due to its unknown structure and resource limitations. Experiments indicate the feasibility of running multiple nodes using Docker and Kubernetes, with discussions ongoing about optimal node numbers and network topology to emulate mainnet conditions.

In preparing simulations, it's critical to assess the impact of increased relay rates on bandwidth, CPU usage, mempool turnover, and fee rates during peak times. Observing effects on transaction propagation and memory impact of internal send queues is also important. Community feedback is sought to refine the approach, fill gaps, and set priorities, ultimately aiming to create simulations that closely mirror mainnet behavior for future optimization.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-29T22:41:00.411000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
