<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-01-17T02:12:50.096254+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-01-16 16:35:24.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-15 06:56:27.495000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-14 12:44:16.551000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 06:13:17.355000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 05:52:08.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-10 19:56:47.130000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-01-10 17:01:16.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:41:17.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-05 18:09:14.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1144_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1113_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1109_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1108_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1107_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1060_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1059_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/934_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/932_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/931_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/929_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T02:12:50.096344+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent advancements in Bitcoin's transaction optimization have focused on integrating protocols such as eltoo within the Lightning Network, to improve efficiency and reduce complexities. The use of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) or similar alternatives aims to minimize round-trip requirements for transactions by allowing a settlement transaction to spend an update transaction without signatures for each update. To address storage issues for historical transactions, solutions like utilizing the annex field or partial adaptor signatures have been proposed.

Implementing the eltoo update mechanism has presented technical challenges, including channel creation, payment processing difficulties, and software bugs that result in critical failures. Despite these obstacles, progress has been made with successful manual transactions using ephemeral anchors. The LN-Symmetry Project has developed research-quality software based on eltoo, though not all aspects are implemented due to ongoing improvements and dependencies. Testing has simplified BOLT specifications, highlighted the need for flexible fee management, and emphasized extended HTLC expiry deltas for security.

The project also identified the complexity of channel operations, which can double timelock durations and introduce risks, pointing to the necessity of an extra nonce for optimistic updates to ensure safety. Further investigation into alternative covenant schemes like OP_CTV remains of interest to provide similar properties for state-graph cut-through in Bitcoin transactions.

GitHub repositories and issue threads have been shared for those interested in the technical details of these advancements. The LN-Symmetry Project has made substantial progress, with segwit ephemeral anchors implementation being a notable development found in the BIP repository's 'ephemeralanchors' branch. Progress on the CLN front includes an eltoo-supportive version on GitHub, inviting community engagement.

Modifications to Bitcoin Core for CLN blackbox tests are available, demonstrating integration efforts with Lightning Network specifications. An alternative Bitcoin repository provides additional technical resources. Updates to the BOLT specification include segwit ephemeral anchors, and libwally now supports taproot changes for wallet interface compatibility.

PTLCs' examination shows their potential in enhancing lightning network channels alongside eltoo-style modifications. Discussions on backporting anti-pin technology and policy changes for Bitcoin Core are part of the project's comprehensive approach to transaction privacy and security.

While mempool-related work has currently shifted the project's focus, the contributions of the LN-Symmetry Project are anticipated to influence future softfork discussions and improve channel design within the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T16:35:24.004000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
