<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
  <updated>2024-01-26T02:10:37.899245+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2024-01-25 18:02:11.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-25 17:03:34.088000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-01-25 16:47:34.033000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-01-25 16:18:52.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2024-01-25 16:05:57.268000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2024-01-25 09:45:32.410000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-25 09:14:54.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2024-01-24 17:07:42.460000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2024-01-24 14:31:36.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1341_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1339_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1338_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1337_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1336_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1334_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1333_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1327_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1321_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T02:10:37.899338+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sibling-eviction-for-v3-transactions/472/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email conversation delves into the technical intricacies of transaction management within Bitcoin's Lightning Network (LN), discussing how certain proposed features could simplify and enhance the efficiency of commitment transactions. The topic of using a single shared key for anchor outputs at 330 satoshis is introduced as a means to streamline LN transactions. This approach, coupled with package relay and Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms, as well as the concept of sibling eviction, is considered beneficial in reducing the complexity of LN commitment transactions. Ephemeral anchors, which are outputs that must be spent when used, are deemed important not just for the Lightning Network but also for several other use cases outside of it.

The sender clarifies that ephemeral anchors remain relevant due to their ability to facilitate general sibling eviction — a process where a transaction can replace another by spending an unencumbered output from a common parent transaction, even in the absence of direct conflict between them. The utility of sibling eviction is emphasized particularly for its intuitive nature and the way it implicitly occurs through the requirement to spend ephemeral anchors. With this mechanism, it's possible to bump transactions in various scenarios involving package RBF and sibling eviction without the need for complex mempool topologies.

Furthermore, the messages explore the potential integration of v3 transaction rules into the existing Lightning Network framework, highlighting the simplicity of evaluating and executing sibling eviction under these rules. This is considered especially desirable for v3 transactions due to their inherent signaling for replaceability, which simplifies the decision-making process around descendant eviction. A GitHub pull request is cited as an example of implementing v3 logic ([GitHub pull request](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29306)).

In regards to package RBF and sibling eviction, the notion of evicting less economically viable descendants to make room for more profitable ones is discussed. The dialogue sheds light on the balance between anti-DoS measures and optimizing for high fee rate transactions within a mempool, suggesting that while sibling eviction provides some benefits, it should be accompanied by package RBF and package relay to address broader challenges, such as pinning and enabling zero-fee commitments within the LN. The integration of v3 transaction logic with current LN transactions is proposed as an interim solution until LN fully adopts v3 transactions. Lastly, the application of sibling eviction to multi-party arrangements, such as coinjoins, is mentioned, allowing any party to perform Child-Pays-For-Parent (CPFP) actions efficiently.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T18:02:11.893000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
