<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - B'SST: Bitcoin-like Script Symbolic Tracer v0.1.2 released</title>
  <updated>2024-05-13T02:00:17.002125+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2406_B-SST-Bitcoin-like-Script-Symbolic-Tracer-v0-1-2-released.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1284_B-SST-Bitcoin-like-Script-Symbolic-Tracer-v0-1-2-released.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - B'SST: Bitcoin-like Script Symbolic Tracer v0.1.2 released</title>
    <updated>2024-05-13T02:00:17.002166+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bsst-bitcoin-like-script-symbolic-tracer-v0-1-2-released/456/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A programmer has proposed a new format for displaying execution paths in the B'SST report, aiming to improve readability and comprehension. The suggested change involves a more descriptive presentation of conditions and outcomes for script execution paths. Previously, the format was more code-like and less intuitive, listing conditions and their evaluations in a compact manner. The proposed format replaces this with a clearer, more readable structure that specifies conditions, their values, and the corresponding script commands in a structured manner. This change is meant to make it easier for users to understand the logic and outcomes of Bitcoin and Elements scripts' execution paths. Feedback is sought on this proposed modification through comments either directly on the GitHub pull request or by experimenting with the change on user scripts. For a detailed overview and to try out the changes, interested parties are directed to the GitHub page hosting the pull request.

The latest release of a sophisticated analysis tool for Bitcoin and Elements scripts introduces several key enhancements designed to streamline user experience and broaden analytical capabilities. Central to this update is an overhauled plugin system, which now permits plugins to engage with different stages of the analysis, enabling both observation and modification actions. This release debuts new plugins that extend the tool's functionality, particularly around asserting stack values and making assumptions about data placeholders, thereby allowing for more accurate analyses. Instructions for these new features are detailed in the README under "Assertions" and "Assumptions."

This version also introduces support for dynamic analysis of specific opcodes such as `PICK`, `ROLL`, and `CHECKMULTISIG`, addressing scenarios where opcode arguments are dynamically determined. Enhancements include the ability to assign aliases to witnesses for enhanced clarity in reports and a new setting (`--produce-model-values-for`) that allows users to define patterns for generating model values, aiding in deeper analysis. Additionally, the tool now offers the option to report the byte sizes of model value samples, a valuable feature for those conducting malleability analysis. This analysis is further supported by two new plugins focused on tracking signature verification and model value usage across scripts. Other improvements encompass a range of less visible refinements and bug fixes aimed at enhancing the overall utility and reliability of the tool. Comprehensive details on all updates can be found in the release notes, accessible via the GitHub repository.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T19:16:01.454000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
