<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-01-20T02:03:34.114184+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-19 21:45:17.997000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-19 21:13:36.520000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-01-19 20:40:21.562000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-19 20:32:01.313000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-19 20:07:13.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson 2024-01-19 19:38:31.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 22:46:22.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-18 20:39:44.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-17 01:30:45.419000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1234_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1232_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1231_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1230_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1229_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1227_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1213_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1211_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1171_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1152_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-20T02:03:34.114318+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Discussions among programmers on Bitcoin's future emphasize the need for adaptability in its protocol to ensure long-term viability and avoid premature ossification. The debate draws on historical examples like xfree86 to xorg and vim to neovim to highlight the importance of evolution in software projects.

The community is concerned with maintaining Bitcoin's growth while preserving network integrity through cautious, consensus-driven changes. There's a strong emphasis on user consensus for soft fork implementations, aiming to prevent divisive actions and chain splits, as seen in past events such as the block size war.

Scalability and technical enhancements are priorities for Bitcoin's continuous improvement. The community seeks unity in decision-making, especially regarding consensus logic, and stresses the readiness to maintain stability despite potential regulatory pressures on miners, like those from OFAC.

Discourse around activation mechanisms reveals a preference for voluntary adoption over enforced changes, with skepticism towards the LockinOnTimeout parameter set to true. Financial risks associated with contentious soft forks are acknowledged, with some advocating for LOT=false to mitigate the threat of chain splits and economic repercussions.

Bitcoin mining's evolving nature affects consensus rules, evidenced by incidents like the July 2015 chain forks. Despite earlier disagreements, there is technical consensus on many subjects post-taproot activation, including developments like Miniscript for smart contracts and solutions for Lightning Network vulnerabilities.

Soft forks lacking unanimous support risk chain splits and economic harm. Some argue this inherent risk warrants halting further changes and supporting the protocol's immediate ossification. The role of miner-activated soft forks (MASFs) is debated, with opposition citing their coercive potential and resource costs. Instead, BIP8/9 and coordinated rejections of harmful changes are suggested for smoother upgrades, prioritizing safety before utility.

The process for proposing and activating soft forks has grown more complex with `bitcoind` taking a less central role, creating ambiguity in readiness indicators for proposals. While BIP 9 and 8 allow multiple proposals, socio-economic challenges persist due to coordination demands. Conservative views deem alternative implementations risky, highlighting a shift in sentiment towards potentially using hard forks instead of soft forks.

Rusty Russell's governance model "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override." reflects a balanced approach that involves all stakeholders in the consensus process. The email's sender values this perspective and encourages discussion on consensus achievement within the decentralized Bitcoin community, recognizing the need for novel methods of agreement and update execution.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T21:45:17.997000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
