<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
  <updated>2024-01-20T02:05:06.773246+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>hampus 2024-01-19 21:44:31.109000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 06:22:10.878000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>alex  . 2024-01-17 14:51:04.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RubenSomsen  . 2024-01-10 15:30:30.263000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-09 20:34:43.479000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-08 10:21:44.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-08 06:31:45.340000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-07 20:48:53.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-07 20:31:47.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:55:48.846000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 19:30:43.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:17:58.402000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 18:41:08.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1233_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1182_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1165_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1056_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1050_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1014_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1011_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1000_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/999_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/996_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/995_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/993_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/989_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
    <updated>2024-01-20T02:05:06.773346+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lnhance-bips-and-implementation/376/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>A developer known as @ajtowns has submitted a Pull Request (PR) to the 'binana' repository aiming to generate numbers for features CSFS and INTERNALKEY. Draft PRs related to these features have been proposed against the Bitcoin Core repository to facilitate easier review. This approach may be used for future features like CTV, where one PR will exclude functional tests and deployment parameters while another will include them.

Jeremy Rubin's utxos.org is recognized as a comprehensive resource for CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) technology, offering tools and educational material for developers. The site emphasizes the potential of Spacechains, which can support advanced blockchain structures without relying on covenants.

The conversation includes discussions about Oracle slashing, its implications for simplified Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) using Covenants via Transaction Outputs (CTV), and the utilization of specific signatures and CheckSequenceVerifyFromStack (CSFS) for delegation purposes. LN-symmetry is also mentioned, with existing contracts that suggest groundwork for its implementation.

A complex system involving a unidirectional non-interactive channel (NIC) immune to transaction ID malleability, operated by a Lightning Service Provider managing virtual Unspent Transaction Outputs (vUTXOs), is described. Additionally, Probabilistic Timelock Contracts (PTLCs) are considered ready for use, whereas APO-like constructions need further development.

Concerns are raised over cluttering the Bitcoin Core repository with multiple PRs for preferred opcodes and sighash flags, potentially limiting future development. An alternative design for sighash flags is suggested in an open PR, discussing upgrade paths and commitment requirements during certain modes.

The bitcoin-inquisition repository has been introduced to separate proposed consensus changes from the main Core repository for initial review. The use of APO versus CTV and CSFS is debated, with the latter providing a more confined design space. The organization within the Bitcoin Core repository aims to segregate tasks not directly related to core consensus rules, enhancing focus and efficiency.

Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and new operational codes (opcodes) such as BIP119, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK(VERIFY), and OP_INTERNALKEY, collectively referred to as "LNHANCE," have been proposed to improve the Lightning Network and introduce innovations like ln-symmetry and Point Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs). Contributors and reviewers can access these proposals through provided links to the relevant repositories. These enhancements intend to integrate output restricting covenants into the protocol, allowing for greater user control and advancing Lightning Network development with increased privacy and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T21:44:31.109000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
