<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY ECDSA useful?</title>
  <updated>2024-01-26T02:08:55.818993+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode.439000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding.294000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..423000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..659000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..207000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1345_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1343_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1225_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1222_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1220_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1216_OP-CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY-ECDSA-useful-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY ECDSA useful?</title>
    <updated>2024-01-26T02:08:55.819054+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checksigfromstackverify-ecdsa-useful/438" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The programming and cryptocurrency communities are currently engaged in a nuanced discourse regarding the use of cryptographic signatures, with a particular focus on the ECDSA (Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm) within different scripts and its potential replacement by newer methods like Schnorr signatures. A recent conversation highlights the concept of reactivating CAT for proof-of-work proofs using plain hashes as a better alternative to ECDSA, citing that there are more efficient ways to achieve this. It's suggested that while ECDSA could be used for proof of work via DER encoding, it presents several challenges that would require thorough examination by an expert before being adopted in any significant financial agreements.

Additionally, the importance of ECDSA signature length and the push for its standardization across all script types was underscored in a tweet by Super Testnet. Their argument is rooted in the belief that uniform proof of work verification through ECDSA signing will enhance security and reliability in the transaction validation process. For further technical insights on this integration, one can refer to the Super Testnet's Twitter [discussion](https://twitter.com/super_testnet/status/1748370856814715015).

In legacy systems where ECDSA is deeply ingrained, there's a hesitance to transition to new protocols and signatures due to trust in established procedures and the resource intensity involved in migrating to alternatives like Tapscript. The industry appears to favor BIP340 Schnorr signatures for CheckSigFromStack (CSFSV), though remains receptive to future changes if warranted by practical reasons. This inclination suggests a trend toward simplifying cryptographic operations while keeping options open based on feedback and development.

Large custodians, exemplified by Coinbase, demonstrate a reluctance to shift from ECDSA to Schnorr because of substantial investments in their current systems. The cautious approach of these organizations reflects an industry-wide resistance to change, preferring to wait until new cryptographic solutions have been thoroughly vetted.

A technical debate among Bitcoin developers has emerged over whether OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACKVERIFY should support both ECDSA and BIP340 Schnorr signatures or solely the latter. This discussion, which took place on the Optech review platform, reveals differing opinions on the inclusion of ECDSA and its scope. While some developers advocate for the exclusion of ECDSA, others remain open to its integration without strong arguments for its necessity. The outcome of this debate is crucial for determining the direction of Bitcoin scripting and has far-reaching consequences for script flexibility, security, and compatibility with existing infrastructures.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T23:40:42.439000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
