<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
  <updated>2024-01-25T02:12:52.532095+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2024-01-24 17:07:42.460000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2024-01-24 14:31:36.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1327_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1321_Sibling-Eviction-for-v3-transactions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sibling Eviction for v3 transactions</title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T02:12:52.532146+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sibling-eviction-for-v3-transactions/472/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the intricacies of Bitcoin transaction management, particularly in relation to Lightning Network (LN) and Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) strategies. The concept of sibling eviction is presented as a method for optimizing mempool space by replacing one unconfirmed transaction with another that has a higher fee rate, thus addressing issues of pinning and DoS attacks without compromising on descendant limits.

Sibling eviction offers an alternative to CPFP carve-out by evicting less incentive-compatible descendants to prioritize new, high-fee-rate transactions. This avoids DoS vulnerabilities while maintaining efficiency. Ephemeral Anchors is a proposed solution that emulates sibling eviction; however, it raises concerns about replace-by-fee (RBF) signaling, wallet compatibility, and the complexity of choosing which descendant to evict.

Version 3 (v3) transactions address these concerns as they inherently signal replaceability, simplifying the decision process since there's only one possible descendant which cannot have multiple ancestors. Sibling eviction under v3 would follow RBF rules to maintain incentive compatibility and limit resource costs. The implementation of this concept can be found in a proposed code update at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29306).

Moreover, the benefits of sibling eviction extend to LN commitment transactions. A suggestion was made to pattern-match LN transactions to v3 policy rules until a full transition to v3 is possible. The current issue is that LN commitments usually feature two anchors, whereas v3 supports a one parent, one child topology. Sibling eviction could resolve conflicts between local and remote CPFPs without necessitating a change to the transaction topology.

Additionally, sibling eviction facilitates v3 application in multi-party transactions like coinjoins, where participants may wish to use CPFP to expedite their transactions without needing a dedicated anchor. If a participant lowballs their fee bump, another participant's output could potentially evict the lowballed transaction's child, allowing for more flexible and efficient fee management.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-24T17:07:42.460000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
