<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - [BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
  <updated>2024-01-08T11:29:26.845863+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-07 22:15:10.341000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>DoctorBuzz1 2024-01-07 20:55:01.816000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski 2024-01-07 20:24:49.077000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-01-07 18:13:04.680000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski 2024-01-06 21:15:19.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski 2024-01-06 21:12:21.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski 2024-01-06 19:49:07.494000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-30 17:47:32.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2023-12-28 13:55:39.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski  . 2023-12-27 20:54:30.891000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1004_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1002_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/997_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/987_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/961_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/960_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/959_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/882_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/879_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/873_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - [BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T11:29:26.845863+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bug-spammers-get-bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-lets-fix-it/327/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email in question delves into the intricacies of Bitcoin transaction pricing, particularly focusing on the discrepancies between simple and complex transactions within the blockchain network. The correspondence highlights that native economic transactions, despite involving potentially complex scripts like multisig, are at risk of being economically disadvantaged compared to alternative asset transactions. It is pointed out that even if the cost for native asset transactions is only marginally increased, the relative fee rate would still need to be higher to maintain demand, which is deemed a negative outcome.

The writer questions the current state of affairs regarding blockspace pricing and suggests that revising the IsDust or GetDustThreshold parameter to better reflect transactional intent could alleviate some issues, specifically those related to BRC-20 style transactions. They express skepticism about the effectiveness of altering the witness discount, saying it won't bring any positive change for native economic users who will end up worse off due to competitive bidding for block space from protocols like BRC-20 during their hype cycles.

Furthermore, the email brings to light the fact that despite the intentions behind SegWit's introduction, such as deterring the misuse of witness space and incentivizing consolidation, these goals have not been met. The sender points to the high transaction fees and the growing UTXO set despite fewer simple transactions, indicating that the promised benefits of a 50% discount in transaction fees for using cheaper witness space have not materialized.

An alternative equation is proposed to discourage the excessive use of witness space without impacting regular users negatively. However, there is an acknowledgment that emerging digital asset protocols, likely to be more space-efficient, may render this solution less effective in the long term. The sender underscores the importance of understanding the foundational reasons behind the system's current configuration before suggesting changes.

Finally, the email criticizes the current pricing model based on examples of two specific transactions, arguing against the price discrimination of simple transactions. To combat the inefficiencies and skewed incentives in the system, they propose uniform pricing for blockspace in future versions of Segwit transactions. This approach would treat every byte of data equally in terms of weight, potentially normalizing costs across all transactions and fostering a more equitable environment for both simple and complex transactions within the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-07T22:15:10.341000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
