<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - 0conf LN channels and v3 anchors</title>
  <updated>2024-02-01T02:07:29.507085+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-01-31 07:30:44.084000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-30 21:13:29.571000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2024-01-30 20:48:10.596000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-30 20:10:14.070000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-01-30 10:24:58.122000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-29 22:29:37.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1393_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1389_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1387_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1386_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1379_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1370_0conf-LN-channels-and-v3-anchors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - 0conf LN channels and v3 anchors</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T02:07:29.507153+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/0conf-ln-channels-and-v3-anchors/494/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions on version 3 (v3) indicate that its initial design did not account for the potential integration of a cluster mempool, which is expected to significantly enhance v3's capabilities. The integration of a cluster mempool is believed to offer opportunities for optimization beyond what was originally anticipated with v3. As such, future development should consider the positive impacts of a cluster mempool and aim to maximize these benefits in the enhancement of v3.

In addressing transaction handling within v3, the focus has been on simplifying the funding transactions by excluding unconfirmed inputs, leading to a designated transaction topology. This simplification involves 0-confirmation funding transactions and adding a shared anchor for emergency CPFP transactions. The suggested approach aims to maintain the simplicity of the current v3 proposal while paving the way for improved reliability, providing parties with the necessary tools to manage emergencies effectively.

The challenges of designing unconfirmed splices are acknowledged, particularly regarding the analysis of transaction chains. The conversation reflects a preference for using RBF over CPFP for splice bumps despite the necessity of CPFP to prevent trivial attacks where one peer could steal funds from another. There is an emphasis on rethinking mempool policies to avoid the need for a subsequent version upgrade and to align closely with the intended framework.

An intricate issue revolves around limiting the funding transaction to exclude unconfirmed inputs, creating a more straightforward transaction structure. However, this raises concerns about inhibiting the chaining of unconfirmed splices. While the system can function adequately if the funding transaction confirms independently or through CPFP, the requirement for a change output on B's side to employ CPFP is not ideal. Despite this, the current workaround does not present new challenges specifically introduced by v3.

Lastly, the LN spec call brought attention to an issue with v3 transactions that support 0-conf channels. The dilemma arises when one party goes offline after a transaction, leaving the other wanting their funds back. The proposed v3 model faces a problem as it requires transactions not to have unconfirmed ancestors. The challenge is to create a solution that allows for a chain of transactions following a confirmed funding transaction, thereby enabling direct payments and subsequent CPFP fee bumps without invalidating the v3 transaction due to unconfirmed ancestors.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T07:30:44.084000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
