<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-02-03T01:52:44.819924+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-02-02T05:25:46.309000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-02-03T01:52:44.819953+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/37" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Understanding the implications of stack operations in programming is crucial, particularly when it comes to managing overflows. A proposed change involves pushing both the result and the overflow amount onto the stack to address issues in calculations that exceed 64 bits. This alteration would require that the overflow amount be represented in LE64 format. However, adopting this approach introduces complexity when checking for the absence of overflow. The standard practice of applying a `NOT VERIFY` operation becomes inadequate since `NOT` operates on a scriptnum, which doesn't align with the zero representation needed for 'no overflow' in LE64 format.

The proposed solution aims to streamline the handling of more-than-64-bit calculations without resorting to branching, which can often complicate code execution paths and impact performance. Yet, the simplicity of current practices must also be considered, as they offer straightforward methods for detecting non-overflow conditions. Finding a balance between enhancing capabilities to support extended calculations and preserving ease of use in common scenarios is an essential consideration for programmers working on this aspect of stack operation design.

In achieving this balance, developers must weigh the trade-offs of implementing new conventions against the potential increase in operational complexity. The goal is to evolve the programming model to accommodate advanced requirements while maintaining a high level of code clarity and maintainability. Such discussions are vital in evolving programming standards, ensuring that enhancements serve to improve overall functionality without introducing unnecessary complications.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T05:25:46.309000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
