<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-02-03T01:52:28.261785+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2024-02-02 16:50:27.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-02-03T01:52:28.261817+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/38" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of extended-bit arithmetic, a notable proposition stands out for handling more-than-64bit calculations. This concept revolves around the utilization of exclusively positive, variable-length integers that permit larger sizes. This approach is deemed more sophisticated compared to other potential methodologies.

The implementation of this idea would be complemented by the introduction of specific opcodes designed to facilitate the transition between variable and fixed encodings. The proposed `FIXNUM` opcode, possibly accompanied by variants such as `TOFIXNUM` and `FROMFIXNUM`, would serve as the cornerstone for these conversions, ensuring seamless interoperability within the system.

Moreover, to accommodate different endian formats, the `BYTEREV` opcode is recommended. This opcode would enable conversion between low-endian and big-endian representations, effectively broadening the utility of the system to cater to various practical computing requirements. This flexibility in handling endian conversions is critical, given that endian compatibility often poses significant challenges in multi-platform environments.

Overall, these enhancements would significantly enrich the computational capabilities of systems requiring arithmetic operations beyond the standard 64-bit limit, offering a robust and elegant solution to developers.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T16:50:27.200000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
