<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>ASMap creation process</title>
  <updated>2024-02-13T02:01:45.329599+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2024-02-12 13:21:31.730000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>ASMap creation process</title>
    <updated>2024-02-13T02:01:45.329631+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/asmap-creation-process/548" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The progress on developing a reliable ASMap file for inclusion in future releases has been significant, leveraging tools like Kartograf and sipa’s asmap-tool. These tools facilitate the collection and processing of data critical for creating an ASMap file trustworthy enough for official release use. The current repository for this data is hosted on GitHub, with discussions indicating a potential move to an official organization repository to formalize and streamline the process.

The initial step in this methodology involves a coordinated effort among contributors to initiate the Kartograf mapping process simultaneously, ensuring synchronization through the tool's `-wait` feature. This coordination is aimed at achieving a consistent result across multiple participants, with a proposed threshold of agreement set at over 50% among five or more contributors. This approach allows for iterative attempts to reach consensus, with room for adjustments based on practical experience gained over time. Should discrepancies arise in the results, participants are encouraged to share raw data for further investigation, maintaining transparency and collaborative problem-solving.

Following successful data collection, the next phase involves compressing the resultant data into an `asmap.dat` file, which then undergoes a review process similar to standard pull requests (PRs). This ensures that the compressed file is verified by multiple reviewers before being merged into the repository, adhering to rigorous quality control standards akin to those applied in core development practices.

Finally, the availability of `asmap.dat` files for users aims to enhance node operation with regular updates sourced from the repository. The selection of a default `asmap.dat` file for inclusion in official releases will be determined based on the most recent and reliable files available, underscoring the ongoing commitment to improving network functionality and security. Feedback on both the process and the tools involved is actively sought to refine and optimize this initiative further, with announcements regarding future creation dates to be shared for broader community engagement.

Relevant resources and tools mentioned include Kartograf ([Kartograf](https://github.com/fjahr/kartograf)), sipa’s asmap-tool ([asmap-tool](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/28793)), and the current data repository ([asmap-data](https://github.com/fjahr/asmap-data)). These links provide access to detailed information, demonstrations, and discussions pertinent to the ASMap file development process.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-12T13:21:31.730000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
