<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
  <updated>2024-02-17T01:58:36.929034+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv.944000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-02-16T13:27:33.944000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T01:58:36.929070+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/basic-vault-prototype-using-op-cat/576/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of the `vault_trigger_withdrawal` script within a demo showcased through an annotated script reveals insightful details about its operation and potential optimizations. The analysis conducted utilized B'SST, named after Bastet, the ancient Egyptian cat-goddess. This tool's application on the script underscores the importance of understanding script behaviors and identifying areas for efficiency improvements. The annotated version of the script is accessible for further review at [this link](https://gist.github.com/dgpv/f875e021905eb113070a23eb7fa981f6), requiring the use of `bsst-cli` with the parameter `--explicitly-enabled-opcodes=cat` to fully engage with the content.

The report generated from this examination delineates the enforced constraints per path, demonstrating that all valid paths must satisfy specific conditions related to signature verification and stack contents operation. For instance, a crucial part of the script ensures that the computed signature matches a precomputed signature sans its last byte, followed by a checksig operation against a designated public key. These operations are pivotal in ensuring the integrity and authenticity of transactions processed by the script.

Witness usage and stack contents form another critical aspect of the analysis. The report indicates that seventeen witnesses are used across all valid paths. Moreover, it elaborates on the intricacies of data handling within the script, such as how various hashes are calculated concerning outputs, spent scripts, and amounts, alongside signature hashing processes. Such detailed insights into witness and data management are vital for optimizing script performance and security.

One significant optimization highlighted pertains to witness size reduction. By consolidating ten witness values related to transaction epoch control, transaction version, lock time, and other elements into just two witness values, the script can achieve a notable decrease in bytes used for encoding witness sizes. This optimization not only enhances the script's efficiency but also reduces the overall transaction size, potentially lowering transaction fees and improving blockchain throughput.

In summary, the analysis of the `vault_trigger_withdrawal` script through B'SST offers a comprehensive understanding of its operational mechanisms and identifies a critical area for optimization. Reduction in witness size presents a tangible improvement that could benefit the script's performance and effectiveness within the blockchain ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T13:27:33.944000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
