<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-02-17T01:56:52.983518+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T01:56:52.983554+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussions surrounding the design suggestions for OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and the gradual loss of censorship resistance within Bitcoin's development community have been highlighted through various channels, including detailed analysis in Optech Newsletters. A significant aspect of this dialogue took place through two main threads on the Linux Foundation's mailing list, with each thread offering distinct insights into the challenges and considerations involved in evolving Bitcoin's protocol.

The first thread, from July 2021, sought design suggestions for OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK, a proposed opcode that aims to enhance Bitcoin's scripting capabilities. This discussion was thoroughly covered in the [Optech Newsletter 157](https://bitcoinops.org/en/newsletters/2021/07/14/request-for-op-checksigfromstack-design-suggestions), indicating the community's interest in expanding Bitcoin's utility while maintaining its security and decentralization principles. The conversation underscored the technical intricacies and potential impacts of introducing new opcodes, reflecting the cautious and collaborative approach taken by developers in proposing changes to Bitcoin's core functionalities.

In February 2022, another thread emerged, tackling the broader issue of Bitcoin's resilience against censorship, specifically focusing on the risks associated with recursive covenants. This topic was explored in depth in the [Optech Newsletter 190](https://bitcoinops.org/en/newsletters/2022/03/09/gradual-loss-of-censorship-resistance), along with a compilation of other arguments against recursive covenants. The discourse illuminated concerns about how certain technical implementations might inadvertently undermine Bitcoin's foundational goal of providing a censorship-resistant form of money. By delving into the potential consequences of recursive covenants, contributors to the discussion aimed to safeguard the network's integrity against mechanisms that could facilitate undue control or restrictions over transactions.

These conversations represent critical points of engagement for the Bitcoin developer community, showcasing a commitment to carefully considering the implications of proposed changes. Through open forums like the Linux Foundation's mailing list and resources such as the Optech Newsletters, developers and enthusiasts alike can stay informed and participate in shaping the future of Bitcoin. These platforms not only facilitate the exchange of ideas but also ensure that proposals are scrutinized from multiple perspectives, contributing to the robust and forward-thinking development culture that defines the Bitcoin project.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T16:27:39.486000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
