<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-02-25T01:56:11.634251+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-02-24T03:47:35.020000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-02-25T01:56:11.634283+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a specific scenario in the realm of Bitcoin development, where a proposed approach focuses on cautious progression rather than ambitious overhauls. The caution stems from a case known as "stratum2-gives-100%," which serves as a prime example of why it's prudent to avoid overly complex modifications to the system. This particular stance advocates for concentrating efforts and attention solely on the immediate next block within the Bitcoin blockchain, rather than entertaining elaborate changes or enhancements.

The underlying sentiment is one of prudence, suggesting that if there arises a necessity or desire for more intricate systems or modifications, such endeavors should be undertaken by other implementations outside the core development focus. This approach allows the core team to maintain a focused and manageable scope of work, ensuring stability and reliability. The suggestion implies a strategy where potential risks or complications introduced by new, complex systems can be evaluated and addressed after they have been implemented by these external parties, thereby safeguarding the core system from untested changes.

This perspective aligns with a broader philosophy within software development, particularly in critical infrastructure like Bitcoin, where stability, security, and predictability are paramount. By limiting the scope of changes to the most immediate and necessary improvements, the development team aims to mitigate unforeseen consequences and ensure the long-term integrity of the system.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T03:47:35.020000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
