<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
  <updated>2024-02-03T01:50:51.903552+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-02-02 15:36:24.905000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar 2024-02-02 15:00:33.098000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-02-02 14:46:32.086000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar 2024-02-02 14:30:38.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 19:27:17.249000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 18:21:48.769000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 18:04:39.566000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 15:31:36.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 15:04:58.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 01:26:13.557000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-09 22:52:52.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1447_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1442_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1441_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1429_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1097_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1096_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1095_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1090_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1089_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1087_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1046_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
    <updated>2024-02-03T01:50:51.903642+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence provides an in-depth analysis of cryptocurrency transaction mempool management, specifically addressing sibling eviction and its implications for networks utilizing "top block" solutions. It underscores the limitations of relying on peers to decide which transactions to evict due to visibility constraints and topology restrictions. The email suggests simpler yet effective methods may be preferable over complex strategies to improve mempool quality. Furthermore, it rejects the idea that the re-entrance of evicted transactions is a principled objection, advocating for functional improvements over none.

The discussion continues by considering whether sibling eviction could replace the carveout rule for Lightning Network (LN) transactions, suggesting a policy allowing transaction replacement under certain conditions. However, there are challenges with ensuring evicted transactions do not immediately re-enter the mempool. Implementing a sibling eviction policy without enabling trivial pinning is recognized as complex.

Technical aspects of 'carveout' rules crucial for LN transactions are analyzed, outlining four criteria for a valid carveout and noting the discrepancy between these and current LN anchor outputs. The necessity of maintaining predictable system efficiency through structured transaction graph topology is emphasized. Despite stringent individual carveout rules, the challenge of aligning them with the cluster mempool model remains unresolved.

The email calls for further research into incentive-compatibility for transaction fee rates, particularly at the top of the mempool. It discusses the potential of adapting "mempoolfullrbf" style Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms to temporarily exceed cluster limits before pruning back to fit. These theoretical approaches underscore efforts to improve blockchain network management of transaction fees and mempool dynamics.

In Bitcoin Core community discussions, optimizing mempool management focuses on fee rates and transaction volumes. Comparing two different-sized mempools, OLD and NEW, poses a challenge; one proposed method involves extending the smaller mempool artificially, while another extrapolates the smaller mempool's fee rate diagram based on an assumed tail feerate. Due to the complexity of these methods, a zero tail feerate is generally preferred.

Challenges with a carve-out rule exempting certain transactions from cluster size limits and evictions are highlighted, where adherence to cluster sizes is recommended over policies allowing exceptions. Concerns about RBF validation lead to suggestions for a flagging system to bypass cluster size restrictions for qualifying transactions.

Finally, a proposed redesign of the Bitcoin Core mempool introduces policy changes to supersede ancestor and descendant limits and refine RBF rules, aiming for a 'strictly better feerate diagram' for transaction replacement. This would establish total ordering of all transactions, facilitate efficient mining selections and evictions, and reduce CPU overhead. The community is directed to @sipa's original write-up for more details and invited to provide feedback on the draft implementation.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T15:36:24.905000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
