<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-16T01:54:40.360514+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell 2024-03-16 00:27:19.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-12 18:28:58.122000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-03-07 02:53:25.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-03-07 00:58:22.648000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 09:43:17.844000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 06:48:42.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 06:32:35.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 05:39:39.452000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-26 20:04:01.039000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-26 15:09:35.021000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-26 05:19:43.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-25 03:56:28.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-24 11:18:37.781000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 06:33:02.619000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 06:25:07.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 04:29:01.677000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:47:35.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:42:41.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-23 12:13:17.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-23 06:06:54.686000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-22 19:14:14.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-22 14:57:46.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-22 02:45:53.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-14 15:13:07.637000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-14 01:25:53.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-13 19:19:39.167000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1911_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1859_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1808_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1807_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1715_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1713_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1711_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1704_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1702_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1698_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1695_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1689_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1688_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1686_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1685_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1684_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1682_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1681_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1678_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1677_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1674_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1673_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1659_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1567_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1553_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1526_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-16T01:54:40.360719+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion provides an in-depth analysis of Bitcoin's transaction fee mechanism and mempool management, focusing on the replace-by-fee (RBF) policy, economic incentives for miners, and strategies to prevent denial-of-service (DoS) attacks. It emphasizes the need for policies that require increased total fees for transaction replacements to defend against low-fee transaction floods that strain network resources. The vulnerability of relying solely on fee rates for transaction prioritization is highlighted, along with the importance of striking a balance between fee maximization and avoiding network congestion.

Incremental fee adjustments following transaction eviction from the mempool are explored as a nuanced approach to managing network load and prioritizing transactions based on their economic contribution. The discourse also covers version 3 (v3) transactions and alternative strategies like transaction aggregation and introspection for enhancing scalability and cost-effectiveness within Bitcoin's ecosystem. The dynamic nature of Bitcoin's fee market is discussed, referencing the minfee adjustment protocol documented in the [Bitcoin GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/4d7d7fd123113342f09871b1a383cda1bb53d0ea/src/txmempool.cppL1091-L1121), which adjusts the minimum required fee based on mempool congestion levels.

Pinning transactions and the complexities of transaction conflicts are examined, alongside speculative solutions for overcoming pinning through new operational codes facilitating transaction deconstruction and reconfiguration. The conversation extends to blockchain transaction protocols, notably the mechanisms of First-Seen-Safe (FSS) and Replace-by-Fee (RBF), and their implications for miners' incentives under different scenarios. The Fee Density Priority (FDP) and Next Block Policy (NBP) are critiqued for their complexity in assessing the impact of replacing transactions based on fee rates.

Version 3 (V3) transactions are introduced as an advancement in managing high transaction fees, aiming to mitigate effects through adaptive fee requirements. A strategy targeting transaction fees within the mempool outlines potential outcomes of fee manipulation over time, raising concerns about DoS attack vulnerabilities. Further discourse addresses Fee Distribution Policy (FDP) challenges in maintaining incentive compatibility and DoS resistance, alongside critiques of V3 transactions in supporting Child-Pays-For-Parent (CPFP) amid rising fees.

Refining RBF policies leads to suggestions like the "Feerate Diagram Policy" and the "Next Block Policy," aiming to optimize mempool efficiency and security. The exploration of virtual block (vb) management emphasizes terminological precision and procedural nuances. The overarching narrative includes the alignment of miner incentives with blockchain network health, highlighting the importance of comprehensive research on game-theoretic impacts of transaction prioritization mechanisms.

In optimizing block mining processes within Bitcoin technology, the balance between theoretical ideals and practical constraints is explored. An approach for estimating system optimality involves examining block fullness upon encountering a transaction chunk exceeding capacity, acknowledging limitations in ancestor package sizes. The optimization of transaction ordering in Bitcoin's mempool introduces feerate diagrams and cluster strategies for approximating optimal transaction selection. Concerns about DoS attacks facilitated by lenient RBF policies are addressed, underscoring the importance of ensuring transaction replacements lead to net increases in fees. This research contributes to understanding how to maintain network integrity and efficiency while exploring incentive-compatible behaviors resistant to DoS attacks.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-16T00:27:19.754000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
