<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
  <updated>2024-02-19T02:01:14.164208+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar 2024-02-18 15:43:27.168000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto 2024-02-18 15:28:06.571000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-08 15:23:54.319000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-08 15:00:36.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-08 14:15:36.144000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-05 15:08:32.829000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-03 11:29:09.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 15:36:24.905000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 15:00:33.098000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 14:46:32.086000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 14:30:38.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 19:27:17.249000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 18:21:48.769000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 18:04:39.566000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 15:31:36.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 15:04:58.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 01:26:13.557000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-09 22:52:52.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1599_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1598_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1490_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1489_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1485_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1461_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1450_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1447_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1442_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1441_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1429_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1097_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1096_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1095_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1090_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1089_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1087_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1046_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T02:01:14.164333+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion examines the challenges and strategies for managing transactions within a mempool, with a specific focus on cluster size limits and the eviction of transactions to accommodate new ones. The concept of a cluster size limit is highlighted as a means to manage the output spendable from a single transaction before the parent transaction's confirmation, particularly in scenarios involving CoinJoin transactions. It is noted that there is an existing descendant count limit that restricts unconfirmed spends from a single transaction, with aspirations to support larger numbers than the default limit, potentially up to 100.

Further discussed are the mechanisms for prioritizing or evicting transactions in the mempool, including an algorithm employing a minheap prioritized by Cumulative Fee Rate (CFR) for managing large transaction clusters exceeding the mempool's capacity. This process aims to balance efficiency with the minimal impact on the transaction pool. The implications of these management strategies for practical use cases such as zero-confirmation funding transactions in the Lightning Network and Ark/Timeout trees are also considered, acknowledging the challenges of adding anchors and balancing efficiency against potential overhead.

Critiques are presented regarding the current approach to improving mempool quality, pinpointing inefficiencies related to rebroadcasting and revalidating unnecessarily evicted transactions. An alternative solution involving peers in the eviction decision process is proposed, albeit with questions about its feasibility and effectiveness. Additionally, the concept of sibling eviction is explored as an alternative to the CPFP carveout rule for optimizing transaction selection in the mempool, recognizing the complexity of eviction decisions while stressing the importance of considering all alternatives.

The correspondence delves into the implementation and refinement of 'carveout' rules within the Bitcoin blockchain for Lightning Network transactions. The detailed criteria for carveouts face challenges, especially concerning LN anchor channels and the enforcement of rules on the transaction graph's structure. A potential update ('v3') is mentioned, aiming to enforce stricter limitations on spending anchor outputs to simplify the transaction graph topology. The conversation further suggests an incentive compatibility model based on transaction fee rates to address mempool management challenges, including adapting "mempoolfullrbf" style Replace-By-Fee mechanisms and the concept of a "tail feerate" for evaluating mining profitability from different mempool configurations.

Lastly, two primary strategies for adhering to cluster size limitations are discussed: evicting existing transactions or expanding the cluster beyond its limits. A recommendation is made for strict adherence to predefined cluster sizes, emphasizing sound engineering principles. A new design proposition for the Bitcoin Core mempool introduces policy changes focused on cluster size limitations and updated RBF rules, aiming to replace the current system's shortcomings with a design that enforces total ordering of all transactions in the mempool, potentially streamlining the transaction processing framework.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-18T15:43:27.168000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
