<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
  <updated>2024-03-16T01:57:32.734875+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2024-03-15 17:03:20.291000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2024-03-15 09:54:03.446000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2024-03-15 08:07:32.947000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2024-03-14 20:00:11.530000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2024-03-14 19:55:23.909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-03-06 14:36:26.070000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2024-02-29 16:29:34.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1907_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1905_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1904_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1895_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1894_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1802_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1739_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
    <updated>2024-03-16T01:57:32.734942+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gitlab-backups-for-bitcoin-core-repository/624/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation initiates with the suggestion of adding a section on existing backups to the GitHub alternatives page for Bitcoin Core, pointing towards an interest in enhancing the documentation and accessibility of information regarding backups. This idea emphasizes the importance of having reliable backups and mirrors for significant repositories like Bitcoin Core, ensuring their availability and continuity. A personal practice mentioned involves using a mirror, specifically the [bitcoin-bitcoin mirror](https://mirror.b10c.me/bitcoin-bitcoin), as a convenient way to stay updated with new pull requests and issues, highlighting the practicality and utility of such mirrors in day-to-day operations.

An insightful episode from the Optech podcast is referenced, available at [Optech podcast](https://bitcoinops.org/en/podcast/2024/03/07/), which delves into the future directions of projects through audience questions. This discussion underscores the value of community engagement in guiding the development and focus of initiatives within the field. The podcast serves as a resourceful platform for gaining a broad understanding of diverse perspectives and the complexities involved in advancing technological innovations.

The technical feasibility of running two instances for importing and displaying data is explored, suggesting a more efficient way to manage backups without disrupting access to current data. This method involves one instance dedicated to cloning from GitHub and another for a GitLab to GitLab clone, optimizing the process by reducing reliance on APIs and offering a singular access point through a URL. However, the necessity of pre-accessing this data is questioned, bringing attention to the essential need for maintaining clean and functional backups. The proposal includes regular checks and possibly automating these verifications to ensure the reliability of the backup system.

A detailed discussion follows on the strategy for syncing between GitLab and GitHub, acknowledging the challenge of continuous import due to the lengthy process. An alternative approach suggests alternating between two instances over a 48-hour cycle to facilitate both display and import functions effectively. Additionally, the conversation shifts towards the efforts in backing up and mirroring GitHub repositories related to Bitcoin, outlining a comprehensive setup that includes a read-only mirror for the bitcoin/bitcoin repository and other critical components. The initiative also extends to rewriting links to enhance user experience and providing a Tor hidden service for anonymous access. Repositories involving backup and mirroring processes are made public, fostering transparency and community participation. Links to these resources and further discussions on the project can be found at [GitHub metadata backup](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-backup), [GitHub metadata mirror](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-mirror), and an extended write-up at [b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/](https://b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/). This elaborate effort highlights the significance of redundancy and accessibility in managing open-source projects, especially those with a considerable impact like Bitcoin.

The narrative concludes with the exploration of a self-hosted GitLab instance for Bitcoin Core GitHub repository backups, marking a crucial step towards ensuring data preservation and uninterrupted development. Despite initial challenges and extensive troubleshooting, a successful full backup was achieved, demonstrating the project's progress. The latest backup, available at [GitLab](https://gitlab.sighash.org/bitcoin/bitcoin) as of February 26, 2024, signifies a milestone in this venture. While focused on Bitcoin Core, the methodologies developed offer potential applications for other repositories, though smaller projects may not require the intricate configurations used here. This initiative showcases the advantages and possibilities of utilizing GitLab for repository backups, emphasizing proactive and flexible planning in software development.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-15T17:03:20.291000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
