<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-02-15T01:57:37.964977+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QcMrHyde  . 2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>juangalt  . 2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T01:57:37.965076+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discourse on the implementation and implications of covenants within cryptocurrency systems, particularly Bitcoin, sheds light on both potential benefits and risks. The discussion emphasizes the differentiation between custodial and non-custodial wallet providers concerning new regulations, with non-custodial wallets being exempt from certain regulatory scopes as outlined in a document provided by the European Union ([EU Regulations](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32023R1114)). This distinction is crucial for understanding the ecosystem's complexity and recognizing the varied roles and tools within it.

The debate over "evil covenants" explores the theoretical and practical aspects of integrating such functionalities into Bitcoin, highlighting the ecosystem's resilience given existing scripting capabilities and precedents set by alternative cryptocurrencies. Furthermore, the technical discussion about creating recursive covenants without the OP_CAT operation illustrates the need for innovative approaches to navigate Bitcoin's scripting limitations.

The conversation also covers how financial institutions might adopt blockchain technology, weighing the merits of on-chain mechanisms like covenants and multisig against traditional checks for regulatory compliance. This includes an analysis of KYC processes within Bitcoin transactions, pointing out the transparency and structural integrity advantages of covenant-based KYC pools over multisig arrangements.

Privacy and security strategies for digital financial transactions, such as generating new addresses for each transaction through extended public keys and using a Merkle root for transaction verification, are discussed. These methods demonstrate a balance between compliance, operational efficiency, and user experience.

The comparison between the covenant model and the cosigner model for enforcing KYC regulations reveals the former's practicality and efficiency. The covenant model, requiring fewer signatures and facilitating more straightforward processes, contrasts with the broader challenges of integrating blockchain technology into regulatory frameworks.

Moreover, the European Union's efforts to regulate Bitcoin through strict KYC laws are prominent, with [CoinDesk's examination](https://www.coindesk.com/learn/mica-eus-comprehensive-new-crypto-regulation-explained/) highlighting the proposal to incorporate perpetual KYC contracts within Bitcoin’s protocol. This would utilize script opcodes like `OP_CTV`, `OP_CSFS`, `OP_CAT`, and `OP_EXPIRE` for enforcing KYC compliance, offering benefits such as government authentication of whitelists, enhanced security, and spending limit adjustments based on KYC status.

The potential for governmental control over Bitcoin transactions through policy regulation is critically examined, raising questions about the implications of terming these policies as "perpetual." This includes whether such policies imply indefinite government control over Bitcoin, affecting its liquidity and autonomy, and the possibility for governments to reverse these policies.

In essence, the discourse provides a comprehensive examination of the technological, regulatory, and operational dimensions of employing covenants and related mechanisms within the Bitcoin ecosystem, highlighting the importance of innovation, security, and practical considerations in shaping the future of cryptocurrency applications and regulation.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-14T07:28:22.722000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
