<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
  <updated>2024-03-15T01:56:37.205246+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2024-03-14 20:00:11.530000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr 2024-03-14 19:55:23.909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-03-06 14:36:26.070000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2024-02-29 16:29:34.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1895_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1894_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1802_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1739_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T01:56:37.205298+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gitlab-backups-for-bitcoin-core-repository/624/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation initiates with a solution to the challenge of maintaining continuous import between GitLab and GitHub by proposing an alternative method. This method involves running two instances in an alternating manner to manage displays and imports within a 48-hour timeframe, given that the import process takes roughly 36 hours. The strategy includes one instance cloning from GitHub and upon completion, enabling the second instance to perform a GitLab to GitLab clone, which is expedited due to the utilization of database dumps rather than API calls. This setup aims to streamline the process for viewers by providing a single go-to URL, although there's skepticism regarding its necessity given potential low interest in accessing the data preemptively. The proposal also mentions the importance of verifying backups for integrity and the absence of erroneous data, suggesting the possibility of automating this verification through scripting.

Further into the discussion, there's an in-depth look at the backup and mirroring efforts for Bitcoin-related repositories on GitHub. A notable achievement is the establishment of a read-only mirror for the bitcoin/bitcoin repository, hosted at [https://mirror.b10c.me/bitcoin-bitcoin](https://mirror.b10c.me/bitcoin-bitcoin), designed to enhance accessibility and user experience by rewriting issue and pull request links to prevent redirection back to GitHub. For users requiring anonymity, a Tor hidden service is available for accessing the mirror. Additionally, systematic backups of the repositories have been conducted across GitHub and GitLab, covering various components such as the bitcoin core GUI, secp256k1, and Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs). These efforts are documented and made accessible through specific repositories and a detailed write-up, found at [https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-backup](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-backup) for backup code, [https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-mirror](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-mirror) for mirroring code, and [https://b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/](https://b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/) for a comprehensive overview of the project. This project illustrates the critical role of redundancy and availability in managing open-source repositories, especially those as impactful as Bitcoin.

The initiative to create backups for the Bitcoin Core GitHub repository using a self-hosted GitLab instance has evolved into a significant project aimed at ensuring data preservation and uninterrupted development. Despite initial optimism, the endeavor faced numerous hurdles, including extensive research, dialogues with GitLab support, and trial and error, before successfully executing a full backup. The results, reflecting the most current data as of February 26, 2024, are hosted on [GitLab](https://gitlab.sighash.org/bitcoin/bitcoin). While the focus remains on the Bitcoin Core repository, the methodologies and tools developed through this project offer potential applications for backing up other repositories. However, it's noted that repositories of smaller scale or activity may not necessitate the elaborate configurations employed in this project. This undertaking emphasizes the practicality and advantages of utilizing GitLab for repository backups, highlighting the significance of adaptability and proactive measures in software development projects.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-14T20:00:11.530000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
