<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Lightning Hardware Wallet</title>
  <updated>2024-02-15T01:56:17.290746+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-02-14 14:57:01.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pgrange 2024-02-14 09:23:43.182000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-02-13 12:49:23.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pgrange  . 2024-02-13 10:50:39.817000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1566_Lightning-Hardware-Wallet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1561_Lightning-Hardware-Wallet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1530_Lightning-Hardware-Wallet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1529_Lightning-Hardware-Wallet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Lightning Hardware Wallet</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T01:56:17.290797+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-hardware-wallet/555/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The integration of hardware wallets with the Lightning network presents a nuanced challenge aimed at enhancing the security of Bitcoin transactions. This initiative seeks to address the limitations of current Lightning wallets, which are optimized for smaller payments, by focusing on securing larger transactions through hardware wallet integration for key management. The project leverages the Phoenix project by ACINQ for its Lightning wallet component and plans to use a Ledger device for the hardware aspect, recognizing its popularity and proven track record in previous integrations. This experimental phase aims to assess both the technical feasibility and the user experience of this novel combination, with a prototype application that facilitates Lightning network payments with transaction signing delegated to the hardware wallet.

One significant hurdle identified is maintaining user convenience while integrating hardware security features. Currently, Lightning wallets automate the search for payment paths, a process that could become cumbersome if each attempt necessitates hardware validation. Moreover, receiving payments might face delays, as user validation is required before completion, potentially impacting the overall user experience. This endeavor seeks to find optimal solutions that seamlessly integrate hardware security mechanisms into the Lightning protocol without compromising user convenience.

Additionally, the proposal introduces several technical complexities, such as the need for the hardware device to be stateful and capable of implementing complex policies. After a user authorizes a payment, multiple signing operations may be necessary, requiring the hardware device to prevent malicious applications from exfiltrating funds. The device must also handle various background operations requiring signatures, such as splicing and commitment fee updates, autonomously. This suggests incorporating a substantial portion of the lightning channel state machine logic directly into the hardware device, a task equating to developing an entire lightning network implementation within the hardware wallet. This represents a considerable undertaking, underscoring the scale and complexity of the project.

This open-source project differentiates itself by targeting secure, large-amount transactions on the Lightning network, catering to end-users who prioritize securing their assets with hardware wallets. It contrasts with existing solutions like Bitbox and Electrum's approach, focusing solely on the security aspects of Lightning transactions. Despite recognizing other challenges like network liquidity, the project’s strategic focus remains on enhancing transaction security to bolster user confidence and control over their funds on the Lightning network. Feedback from individuals who self-custody Bitcoin and emphasize asset security is particularly valued as the project progresses.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-14T14:57:01.333000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
