<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-13T01:57:12.281708+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-03-12 18:28:58.122000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-03-07 02:53:25.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-03-07 00:58:22.648000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 09:43:17.844000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 06:48:42.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 06:32:35.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 05:39:39.452000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-26 20:04:01.039000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-26 15:09:35.021000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-26 05:19:43.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-25 03:56:28.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-24 11:18:37.781000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 06:33:02.619000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 06:25:07.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 04:29:01.677000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:47:35.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:42:41.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-23 12:13:17.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-23 06:06:54.686000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-22 19:14:14.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-22 14:57:46.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-22 02:45:53.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-14 15:13:07.637000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-14 01:25:53.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-13 19:19:39.167000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1859_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1808_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1807_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1715_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1713_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1711_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1704_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1702_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1698_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1695_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1689_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1688_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1686_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1685_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1684_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1682_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1681_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1678_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1677_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1674_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1673_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1659_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1567_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1553_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1526_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-13T01:57:12.281880+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/25" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse initiates with an examination of the replace-by-feerate scheme in conjunction with Bitcoin's existing Replace-By-Fee (RBF) rules, highlighting potential Denial-of-Service (DoS) vulnerabilities through low-cost, high-impact transaction resubmissions. This underscores the importance of ensuring transactions increment mempool fees to mitigate bandwidth exploitation, as detailed on [Bitcoin Stack Exchange](https://bitcoin.stackexchange.com/q/121541/5406).

Further analysis uncovers discrepancies between miners' financial incentives under RBF policies and network security principles, exposing a susceptibility to pinning attacks that can hinder transaction confirmations. This reveals a misalignment between economic motivations and transaction replacement mechanisms.

Proposed adjustments focus on managing mempool evictions by incrementing fees for subsequent transactions from identical senders, aiming for a more equitable resource distribution. The implementation challenges of such systems are acknowledged, especially in terms of complexity and transaction prioritization post-eviction.

The dialogue critiques the Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) method within Bitcoin transactions, advocating for designs that facilitate inline fees and shared costs more efficiently. Future covenant technology is suggested as a solution to override CPFP limitations, promoting protocol resilience in high-fee contexts.

Technical discussions extend to Bitcoin's fee adjustment strategy based on mempool congestion, employing a decay mechanism documented in the [Bitcoin GitHub repository](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/4d7d7fd123113342f09871b1a383cda1bb53d0ea/src/txmempool.cppL1091-L1121) to refine the fee market. Considerations around pinning transactions introduce potential operational codes for dismantling excessive fees and enhancing blockchain efficiency.

The conversation scrutinizes transaction replacement policies, emphasizing the need for comprehensive understanding of their effects on network security and economic dynamics. It also tackles the intricacies of v3 transactions and their impact on network fee management, suggesting limitations in addressing mempool eviction and calling for alternative strategies.

Concerns about the Fee Distribution Policy (FDP) and its influence on mining decisions highlight the critical nature of precision in policy discussions. Two policy proposals—Feerate Diagram Policy and Next Block Policy—are evaluated for their potential to improve economic efficiency and address DoS vulnerabilities, with a preference for the former due to its alignment with incentive compatibility.

Virtual block management and the clarification of technical terminologies are underscored, stressing accuracy in technical communications to uphold network efficiency and integrity.

Miner incentives, particularly in the context of declining total fees, prompt a call for further research into miner behavior and the practical implications of non-standard transaction sizes. The discourse advocates for simpler mining practices over complex optimization strategies, considering real-world inefficiencies.

A novel approach to Replace-By-Fee (RBF) evaluation proposes exponential discounting to accommodate mempool unpredictability, although it faces challenges regarding DoS protection and subjective assessments.

Finally, the exploration into optimizing Bitcoin's mempool highlights advanced strategies for maximizing fee collection while adhering to block size limits. Feerate diagrams and cluster linearizations emerge as vital tools for efficient transaction selection, despite complexities introduced by RBF policies. Concerns regarding lenient RBF rules and DoS attack vulnerabilities are addressed, emphasizing a balanced approach to network security and transaction fee dynamics.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-12T18:28:58.122000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
