<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
  <updated>2024-02-20T01:53:52.481477+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-02-19 10:06:34.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-02-19 09:40:13.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-19 00:34:09.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-18 19:42:28.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-18 18:08:44.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-12 11:15:33.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1605_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1604_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1603_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1602_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1601_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1518_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
    <updated>2024-02-20T01:53:52.481555+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-onchain-implementation-of-mining-feerate-futures/547/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the nuanced strategies employed by blockchain miners, particularly focusing on how large miners with a significant share of the network's total hashrate might adopt different tactics compared to their smaller counterparts. A pivotal point in the analysis is the strategic decision that large miners can make: opting not to mine a certain transaction in a given block if they believe they have a high probability of mining it in subsequent blocks. This approach allows them to potentially favor settling contracts to their advantage while foregoing higher fee transactions in the immediate block. Such a strategy, however, poses a disadvantage to smaller miners who have a negligible chance of mining the passed transactions later, thus compelling them to prioritize high-fee transactions immediately. The discussion suggests employing average fee rates over a specified number of blocks and settling discreet log contracts via multiple oracles as a remedy to level the playing field for all miners.

Onchain contracts are highlighted for their role in minimizing reliance on trusted third parties and counterparty risk, akin to placing bets without influencing the outcome directly. These contracts are less susceptible to manipulation by miners since they rely on fee data from confirmed transactions. However, the autonomy given to miners in choosing which transactions to include in blocks introduces a theoretical vulnerability where miners could ignore higher fee transactions for strategic gains. This behavior could make large miners more profitable, potentially increasing mining centralization, a concern that necessitates further exploration within the community.

The introduction of mining fee futures is proposed as a solution to the volatility of onchain fees, which fluctuates with demand for block space. This system would allow users to pay miners a flat rate above the median low-fee rate for guaranteed confirmation during periods of high fees, offering stability for both parties. Detailed within this scheme is a binary mining fee futures contract between a user and a miner, specifying payouts based on whether onchain fees surpass a predefined feerate boundary by a certain block height. The contract structure includes conditional execution paths designed to minimize block space wastage and ensure fair outcomes regardless of fee fluctuations, aiming to mitigate the risks tied to unpredictable fee changes and promote a stable blockchain environment.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-19T10:06:34.360000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
