<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-03-29T03:09:46.476852+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ganava 2024-03-28 22:32:29.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-14 13:00:12.989000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-13 13:55:05.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-12 23:45:54.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-12 20:09:36.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-03-03 02:22:15.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-02-29 19:29:30.553000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-21 04:47:51.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic  . 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2080_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1887_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1871_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1866_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1863_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1770_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1740_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1649_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T03:09:46.476945+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the introduction of `OP_EXPIRE` to Bitcoin's protocol, aiming to enhance block space management. This opcode is considered for its potential to allow transactions to expire if not confirmed by a certain time, which contrasts with previous concerns that it might lead to inefficient block space use due to high transaction fees. The feature offers increased operational flexibility in blockchain systems, enabling more strategic handling of transactions concerning timing and space.

Concerns are raised about the possibility that expiring transactions could incentivize blockchain reorganizations (reorgs) and impact network bandwidth. High transaction fees tied to these expiring transactions might encourage miners to include them in blocks just before expiration, potentially leading to collaboration between miners and senders to undo transactions through reorgs. This situation presents a risk where the incentive extends beyond fees to the payment amount itself.

The implementation of reverse timelocks by Chia, as detailed in CHIP 14, represents a notable development aimed at enhancing decentralized finance (DeFi) platforms. It signifies a strategic move to support DeFi functionalities, suggesting a pragmatic approach to managing risks related to blockchain reorganizations and mempool management. 

The economic implications of transaction expiration are discussed, touching on stale blocks and miner incentives. Peter Todd proposes higher minimum relay fees for near-expiration transactions as a mitigation strategy for bandwidth waste, aligning with atomic asset swaps' economic logic. Additionally, strategies are suggested to counter the uncertainty introduced by transaction expiration, including creating conflicting transactions with higher fees to ensure network efficiency.

Further examination addresses the impacts of transaction expiration on Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) censorship, asset value, and Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) design. The conversation explores how expired UTXOs might unintentionally benefit the community by increasing currency value and discusses safeguards in PSBT design against asset loss due to expiration.

A shift in PSBTs from off-chain to on-chain contexts raises considerations around Miner Extractable Value (MEV) and verification mechanisms, with a nuanced debate on using block height versus block time for transaction expiration.

The email introduces a new opcode intended to improve peer-to-peer asset swaps efficiency and promote decentralization by reducing reliance on centralized marketplaces. An early draft Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) outlines this initiative, available [here](https://github.com/EvanWinget/bips/blob/7d70761da8fe43ae5d4fdd0c18b14765652ccfec/bip-checkmaxtimeverify.mediawiki), focusing on economic inefficiencies caused by unconfirmed transactions. By allowing these transactions to become invalid after a specific block height or time, the proposal aims to streamline asset swap markets and foster a more decentralized ecosystem.

The importance of the [OP_EXPIRE](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022042.html) post is highlighted, presented as a critical resource for understanding the benefits and considerations of implementing such a feature within the Bitcoin protocol. The call for feedback from the Bitcoin community seeks to identify potential issues and ensure the proposal's viability and effectiveness in achieving its goals.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-28T22:32:29.012000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
