<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
  <updated>2024-02-15T01:54:00.087797+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>arshbot 2024-02-14 22:52:05.913000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-02-14 02:56:12.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-19 21:45:17.997000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 21:13:36.520000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-19 20:40:21.562000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 20:32:01.313000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 20:07:13.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-19 19:38:31.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 22:46:22.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-18 20:39:44.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-17 20:20:44.934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-17 01:30:45.419000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-16 23:10:55.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-01-16 23:05:10.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-11 09:46:02.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-11 03:07:06.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 03:04:16.191000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-11 02:28:17.246000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-04 00:48:53.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-01-04 00:21:38.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-03 09:18:27.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1574_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1556_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1234_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1232_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1231_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1230_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1229_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1227_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1213_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1211_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1171_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1152_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1151_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1150_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1067_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1064_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1065_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1063_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/918_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/917_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/903_On-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On consensus changes in bitcoin 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T01:54:00.087950+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-consensus-changes-in-bitcoin-2024/334/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent discussions among programmers and Bitcoin community members have highlighted a variety of concerns and perspectives on the evolution of Bitcoin, focusing on the complexity of consensus changes and the importance of community involvement. The discourse underscores the delicate balance between leadership facilitation and the risk of coercion, referencing initiatives like the Bitcoin Contracting Primitives Working Group to illustrate efforts towards technical consensus despite challenges in maintaining momentum and broad agreement.

There's an acknowledgment of personal disagreements within the community, pointing out the potential for echo chambers and stubbornness that could obfuscate issues, making it difficult to differentiate between incompetence and ill-intent. This reflects the broader challenge of evolving Bitcoin in a way that ensures its long-term functionality and integrity amidst technological and regulatory changes.

Strategic considerations for proposing and activating changes to the Bitcoin network are discussed, emphasizing caution against altering consensus rules hastily and advocating for scaling Bitcoin responsibly for future generations. The correspondence revisits the block size war as a historical example of the difficulties in achieving consensus and the consequences of divisive actions, promoting consensus prior to initiating any soft forks to avoid past conflicts.

The risks associated with soft forks, particularly those lacking unanimous support, are highlighted, including the potential for chain splits and their financial implications. A pragmatic approach is suggested, involving an activation client using LOT=false to mitigate these risks. Historical instances, like the July 2015 chain forks, are cited to demonstrate miners' capacity for false signaling and the dynamic nature of Bitcoin mining practices, raising concerns over trust in the system and the dangers of regulatory compliance changes.

Post-taproot activation, there's been technical consensus on enhancements such as encrypted peer connections and support for onion messages, indicating a shift towards developer consensus on certain upgrades. The discussion also touches on the contentious nature of non-unanimous soft forks and debates the role of miner-activated soft forks (MASFs) in consensus changes, reflecting on the block size controversy and the dynamics of hard versus soft forks.

The conversation further explores the transition from a unified proposal process towards a more fragmented approach, highlighting the challenges in defining "rough consensus" and the viability of alternative implementations. The growing preference for hard forks signals a potential shift in update and activation mechanisms, necessitating new methods for building consensus in a decentralized environment. Rusty Russell's model, "Devs propose. Miners activate. Users override," is referenced to encapsulate the nuanced dynamics of soft fork activation and the ongoing debate on achieving broader consensus within cryptocurrency governance.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-14T22:52:05.913000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
