<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-02-23T02:01:05.222851+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-02-22 19:14:14.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar 2024-02-22 14:57:46.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell 2024-02-22 02:45:53.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-14 15:13:07.637000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-14 01:25:53.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-13 19:19:39.167000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1674_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1673_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1659_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1567_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1553_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1526_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-02-23T02:01:05.222914+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion explores enhancing the efficiency of Bitcoin block mining through optimizing transaction selection. A proposed shift from the current ancestor-feerate transaction selection method to a cluster mempool strategy is examined. This new approach aims to improve the process by using a different algorithm, potentially outperforming the existing system. However, sorting transactions within large clusters optimally poses significant challenges due to the time complexity and the NP-hard nature of finding the highest value-weight ratio in a dependency graph, as highlighted on [cs.stackexchange.com](https://cs.stackexchange.com/questions/163467/finding-highest-value-weight-ratio-in-dependency-graph-np-hard).

The complexity of achieving ideal block composition is further compounded by the knapsack problem, with theoretical optimality capped at around 90% due to maximum size constraints of ancestor packages. Despite these limitations, there is speculation that actual efficiency might be higher given the small size of most transactions.

The paper introduces innovative tools such as feerate diagrams for visualizing different transaction ordering strategies and constructing convex hulls to compare these orderings. The concept of clusters allows for a more detailed approach to transaction selection, promising closer approximation to optimal selection across the entire mempool. It also addresses the intricacies of Replace-By-Fee (RBF) policies and the challenges of ensuring beneficial replacements for miners without unintended consequences. The [cluster mempool proposal](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/1) provides theoretical and practical insights into effective transaction management within the Bitcoin network.

Further investigation into RBF policies reveals the limitations of simple fee and feerate comparisons, proposing mining scores to guide RBF rules. Concerns over DoS attacks facilitated by lenient RBF policies are discussed, underscoring the need for a critical balance between maintaining an open network and preventing abuse. Transaction fees' role in network relay dynamics and the introduction of mempool eviction to manage size by adjusting required feerates for new transactions offer insights into incentive-compatible behaviors and resistance to DoS attacks. This comprehensive exploration suggests that while theoretical ideals face practical constraints, ongoing research and development could yield significant improvements in blockchain domain efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-22T19:14:14.434000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
