<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
  <updated>2024-02-19T02:04:29.090956+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-02-19 00:34:09.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-02-18 19:42:28.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-02-18 18:08:44.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-12 11:15:33.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1603_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1602_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1601_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1518_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T02:04:29.091008+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-onchain-implementation-of-mining-feerate-futures/547/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The [contemporary post](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553a-simple-analysis-of-a-toy-problem-14) highlights a potential flaw in the theoretical model of blockchain transactions, particularly focusing on how miners with a significant portion of the total network hash rate might manipulate transaction mining to their advantage. This manipulation involves delaying the mining of specific transactions to later blocks, where they can still benefit from them, thus potentially settling contracts in their favor despite not mining higher fee rate transactions in the current block. Such a strategy is not available to miners with a smaller share of the network hash rate, putting them at a disadvantage since they have a minimal chance of mining the transactions again in subsequent blocks. The discussed scenario assumes a congested blockchain environment where the number of high-fee-paying transactions exceeds the capacity of a single block, forcing miners to choose between executing a low-paying contract now or opting for higher-paying transactions in the immediate future.

Moreover, the discussion introduces the concept of mining fee futures as a solution to the unpredictability of on-chain fees, which can fluctuate due to various factors such as novel uses of the blockchain or innovations. The unpredictability poses challenges for both miners, who rely on these fees for income, and users, who may be subjected to sudden fee spikes. Mining fee futures contracts propose a mechanism where users pay a flat rate above the median low-fee rate to secure confirmed transactions during periods of high fees, benefiting from stable transaction costs while providing miners with predictable income. These futures contracts are structured around a Taproot address and incorporate different execution branches to accommodate varying fee scenarios, ensuring fair outcomes for both parties involved.

This structure aims to provide a balance between maximizing fee revenue for miners and securing predictable transaction costs for users, potentially reducing the incentive for miners to manipulate transaction selections for short-term gains. However, the initial analysis also acknowledges that this approach could inadvertently favor larger miners, possibly exacerbating the centralization of mining operations. Despite these concerns, the proposed mining fee futures concept presents an innovative way to mitigate risks associated with fee volatility, thereby promoting a more stable and efficient use of blockchain technology for all parties involved.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-19T00:34:09.933000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
