<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-02-25T01:54:33.826112+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell 2024-02-24 04:13:31.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-01-24 17:05:16.348000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-01-16 16:35:24.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-15 06:56:27.495000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-14 12:44:16.551000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 06:13:17.355000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 05:52:08.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-10 19:56:47.130000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-01-10 17:01:16.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:41:17.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-05 18:09:14.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1683_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1326_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1144_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1113_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1109_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1108_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1107_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1060_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1059_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/934_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/932_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/931_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/929_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-02-25T01:54:33.826213+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The innovative approach in financial transactions focuses on eliminating additional rounds of signature exchanges by leveraging CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) or similar protocols. This method facilitates update transactions to be spent via a corresponding settlement transaction without individual signatures for each update, streamlining the transaction process and reducing delays associated with waiting for parties to exchange signatures. To address potential issues with tracking historical transactions, the proposal suggests using the annex field of update transactions for information recovery, or employing partial adaptor signatures despite the complexity of dual signatures.

A practical example of these concepts is demonstrated by Core Lightning's force-closing of channels on the inquisition signet, detailed in a [Gist](https://gist.github.com/chrisguida/43e482e684727daa618423e52a14d09a). This experiment contributes to the development of cryptocurrency networks and Lightning Network protocols through community engagement and feedback. Additionally, an ongoing project involving a significant code rebase with 283 commits in a CLN implementation highlights the collaborative efforts in software development for compatibility with systems like APO, LNHANCE, and TXHASH.

Technical challenges in implementing the eltoo update mechanism within the Lightning Network include conflicting feature bits, data integrity post-node restarts, and difficulties in channel shutdowns, emphasizing the complex nature of network protocol development. These experiences provide insights into blockchain technology's continuous evolution. Discussions on enhancing transaction processes with CTV, exploring eltoo-style channels, and considering alternative covenant schemes indicate active efforts to improve financial transactions on the blockchain.

The LN-Symmetry Project explores the eltoo proposal ([eltoo proposal](https://blockstream.com/eltoo.pdf)) by developing research-grade software, achieving milestones such as channel openings and payments, while facing limitations like incomplete persistence for new keytypes. The project aims to streamline BOLT specifications, enhance fee management, and apply CTV emulation to improve payment protocol efficiency. Anti-pinning research and creations such as Ephemeral Anchors and a CLN implementation ([GitHub](https://github.com/instagibbs/lightning/tree/eltoo_support)) contribute to the discussion on future softforks and channel design. Despite pausing the project for mempool-related endeavors, its outcomes are expected to influence future developments in the field.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T04:13:31.288000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
