<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
  <updated>2024-02-22T01:55:43.800167+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>quantobasta 2024-02-21 22:19:02.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 10:06:34.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 09:40:13.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-19 00:34:09.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-18 19:42:28.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-18 18:08:44.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-12 11:15:33.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1658_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1605_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1604_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1603_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1602_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1601_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1518_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
    <updated>2024-02-22T01:55:43.800234+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-onchain-implementation-of-mining-feerate-futures/547/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The innovative implementation discussed seeks to align with Bitcoin's ethos by promoting incentivized yet voluntary participation, minimal intermediary involvement, and on-chain operations. It addresses the need for Bitcoin-native projects to have predictable costs and offers a mechanism for miners to hedge against periods of low fee rates. The example of Block Green seeding a miner with capital in exchange for future block revenue highlights a growing interest among miners for upfront capital. This opens up the possibility for services that provide collateral to miners with certain stipulations for default situations, suggesting an evolving landscape in cryptocurrency mining financial strategies.

A detailed analysis of mining strategies within cryptocurrency networks reveals the complex economic incentives driving both large and small miners. Strategic mining adjustments, where miners can opt for different fee extraction tactics, illustrate how strategic choices can yield varying benefits irrespective of the miner's size. A mathematical model demonstrates that while strategic miners seem to benefit from a higher total fee extraction, normal miners, when considering their hash power investment, might find themselves benefiting more on a proportional basis. This nuanced understanding of mining strategies underscores the critical role of strategic decision-making and hash rate distribution in maximizing mining returns.

An exploration into transaction mining strategies highlights the nuanced dynamics between larger miners with significant hashrate shares and smaller miners. Larger miners might delay mining specific transactions betting on securing them in later blocks they mine, potentially centralizing mining advantages. However, this strategy inadvertently benefits smaller miners by leaving behind high-fee-rate transactions, suggesting a more balanced field of opportunities for future block rewards. This insight challenges the notion that larger miners inherently gain at the expense of smaller ones across all scenarios.

The vulnerability in theoretical models assuming miners always prioritize highest-fee transactions is scrutinized, especially under network congestion and strategic considerations by dominant miners. This analysis proposes using average fee rates over multiple blocks and settling contracts through multiple oracles to ensure fairness regardless of a miner's hashrate share, aiming to mitigate biases in contract settlements and transaction selection.

Onchain contracts are lauded for reducing reliance on trusted third parties and mitigating counterparty risk, akin to sports betting mechanisms devoid of athlete influence. Despite their advantages, the potential for miners to manipulate outcomes by selectively including transactions raises concerns about trust and corruption. A suggested solution involves mining fee futures to stabilize onchain fees, crucial for miner income and blockchain security amidst fluctuating demand and future halvenings.

Mining fee futures are introduced as a means to address onchain fee unpredictability, offering a symbiotic arrangement for users and miners against fee volatility. Detailed binary mining fee futures contracts propose a structured approach allowing for minimal space wastage and ensuring equitable outcomes for both parties based on actual onchain fees versus predetermined boundaries. This scheme not only aims to mitigate risks associated with fee fluctuations but also promotes a stable blockchain operation environment.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T22:19:02.511000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
