<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-02-22T01:56:18.107090+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget 2024-02-21 04:47:51.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic  . 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1649_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-02-22T01:56:18.107146+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse addresses the intricate considerations surrounding the implementation of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) and their potential migration from an off-chain to an on-chain system, elucidating the complexities this shift might introduce, especially regarding Miner Extractable Value (MEV). The conversation notably highlights the need for a nuanced examination of how such a transition could impact transaction dynamics within the blockchain ecosystem, stressing the importance of analyzing the use of CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) against CheckMultiTimeVerify (CMTV) scripts. The flexibility provided by certain scripts, allowing assets to be spent at any given time, contrasts with the introduction of scripts that could eventually render transactions unspendable, raising concerns about miner incentives towards censoring such transactions. This dialogue underscores the pressing necessity to delve into these matters, considering their profound implications for security, user autonomy, and potential unintended consequences that may arise, including increased censorship activities by miners.

Further, the conversation pivots to the discussion of incorporating an operation code (op code) to enable transaction expiration within the Bitcoin protocol. This proposal, notably favored over the initial suggestion and rooted in Peter's insights, emphasizes choosing block height as a more dependable metric over block time due to concerns over possible manipulation by miners for personal gain. The dialogue also contemplates the coexistence of high fee rate transactions with expiration times and those with lock times within the mempool, suggesting that this could lead miners to adjust the nTime value both forwards and backwards. Such adjustments would aim to include transactions beneficial to them, thus introducing a complex strategic layer to mining activities that could potentially equalize economic incentives across the network.

The significance of the [OP_EXPIRE](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022042.html) post is highlighted as a crucial resource for understanding the benefits and considerations of implementing an expiratory mechanism within Bitcoin transactions. Although the draft Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) had not been reviewed by the sender, the recommendation to explore the OP_EXPIRE post suggests its utility in shedding light on the intricacies of adding expiration features to enhance the cryptocurrency's functionality.

Moreover, the email delves into a proposed opcode aimed at improving the efficiency of peer-to-peer asset swaps and fostering decentralization by reducing reliance on centralized exchanges. This proposal is outlined in an early draft BIP found [here](https://github.com/EvanWinget/bips/blob/7d70761da8fe43ae5d4fdd0c18b14765652ccfec/bip-checkmaxtimeverify.mediawiki), with its motivation tied to addressing economic inefficiencies associated with unconfirmed transactions. By enabling such transactions to become invalid after a specific block height or time, the proposed opcode seeks to make asset swap markets more efficient, reduce their on-chain footprint, and ultimately support a more decentralized ecosystem. The author calls for feedback from the broader Bitcoin community to refine the concept and ensure its effectiveness in achieving its intended goals.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T04:47:51.660000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
