<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Subscript rendering in graph broken in Safari</title>
  <updated>2024-04-16T01:55:35.150483+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2232_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1727_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1723_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1717_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1705_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1700_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Subscript rendering in graph broken in Safari</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T01:55:35.150542+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-safari/608" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The resolution of an issue within the mermaid-js project, specifically documented under issue number 5339 on GitHub, has been confirmed. This particular fix was integrated upstream and verified against the development branch to ensure that there was no duplication or pending implementation, highlighting efforts to maintain code integrity and address issues promptly to enhance the reliability of the mermaid-js project. The discussion also touches upon the utility of diagrams created with Mermaid, a tool for generating diagrams from text, and contrasts it with Graphviz. Users experiencing issues, especially those related to rendering in Safari, are advised to report these directly to the developers through Mermaid's GitHub page, emphasizing the importance of demonstrating the malfunction to facilitate troubleshooting. This advice signals a proactive approach to resolving browser-specific rendering issues by engaging directly with Mermaid's development team.

Further details reveal an encounter with an unexpected output or error within a live editor, indicating a technical issue depicted through an image. The sender's uncertainty about the role of Graphviz and their unfamiliarity with the Delving forum and possibly Mermaid itself highlights a need for assistance or guidance. This situation underscores the technical nature of the problem and the barriers faced due to a lack of familiarity with certain tools, necessitating expert intervention. Additionally, the behavior of a specific code snippet is explored, suggesting testing in various environments, including a gist and the live editor platform provided by Mermaid. In case of inconsistencies or bugs, reporting directly to the Mermaid developers is advised, underscoring the importance of community feedback for the improvement of open-source tools. This process allows users to manually update components in their projects with fixes before official integration, maintaining functionality and reliability.

Moreover, an anomaly was observed in the rendering of subscript numbers within a transaction graph when viewed through Safari on macOS versions 13.6.4 and 14.3.1, where subscripts appeared clustered at the top-left corner instead of their intended positions. This glitch, specific to Safari, does not affect other browsers like Chrome, which correctly displays the graph. This issue, initially discussed in a meta topic to keep the primary discussion focused, highlights a compatibility or rendering problem exclusive to Safari on the mentioned macOS versions, affecting the visual representation and understanding of data within the transaction graph.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-15T15:20:13.331000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
