<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-02-14T02:04:59.371861+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sanket1729 2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QcMrHyde 2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent798 2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>juangalt 2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent798 2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent798 2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light 2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-02-14T02:04:59.371954+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the potential for implementing "evil covenants" in Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies to enforce perpetual Know Your Customer (KYC) regulations. This involves using a combination of Bitcoin scripting capabilities, such as `OP_CTV`, `OP_CSFS`, `OP_CAT`, and `OP_EXPIRE`, to create a system where financial transactions are perpetually subject to governmental oversight and control. The primary argument in favor of such mechanisms is that they could offer governments and financial institutions a way to ensure compliance with stringent KYC laws, like those being developed in the European Union, while still benefiting from the advantages of cryptocurrencies, like quick international settlement times and a fixed supply.

One proposed method involves the government signing a Merkle root of a whitelist of approved addresses every two weeks, along with the current date. Transactions would be validated by checking this signature and ensuring the recipient's address is on the whitelist, using the mentioned opcodes to enforce these checks and the covenant itself. This method has several notable features, including the ability to update the whitelist without altering existing contracts, eliminating the need for a cosigning server, allowing the government to sign offline with air-gapped devices, and giving the government the flexibility to add or remove addresses and adjust spending limits as needed.

Furthermore, the discussion explores the practicality and ethics of employing such covenants. It suggests that while these measures could streamline regulatory compliance and enhance security for self-custodied coins by preventing unauthorized transfers, they also raise significant concerns. The permanence of these restrictions, the potential for governmental abuse, and the impact on user autonomy and privacy are critical considerations. The possibility of the government relinquishing control over coins under this policy, by whitelisting non-covenant addresses, offers a theoretical means to mitigate some concerns but does not fully address the broader implications for freedom and decentralization inherent in cryptocurrency.

Additionally, the discourse touches upon alternative approaches for enforcing KYC policies, like utilizing multisig setups or backend server code for transaction verification, which might offer similar benefits without the need for on-chain covenants. These alternatives could potentially reduce the complexity and user experience drawbacks associated with the proposed covenant system, such as the waiting period for new addresses to be registered.

In summary, the conversation reflects a deep dive into the technical, ethical, and practical dimensions of integrating regulatory compliance mechanisms directly into cryptocurrency protocols. While such innovations could provide solutions to regulatory challenges, they also prompt a reevaluation of the balance between security, compliance, and the foundational principles of freedom and privacy that underpin the cryptocurrency movement.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-13T23:50:36.188000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
