<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
  <updated>2024-02-06T02:00:05.196420+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-02-05 15:08:32.829000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-03 11:29:09.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 15:36:24.905000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 15:00:33.098000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-02 14:46:32.086000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-02 14:30:38.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 19:27:17.249000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 18:21:48.769000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 18:04:39.566000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-12 15:31:36.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-12 15:04:58.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-01-12 01:26:13.557000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-01-09 22:52:52.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1461_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1450_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1447_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1442_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1441_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1429_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1097_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1096_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1095_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1090_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1089_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1087_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1046_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
    <updated>2024-02-06T02:00:05.196519+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post addresses the complexities of managing the mempool in blockchain systems and the impact on transaction fees, security, and network efficiency. It presents a method to improve mempool quality by re-adding previously evicted transactions, which could lower fees for those initiating the eviction but add computational complexity.

Transaction management challenges are discussed, highlighting the impracticality of relying on peers or wallets to make informed eviction decisions due to their limited view of network-wide transactions. The potential role of sibling eviction policies is recognized, considering their impact on fees and vulnerability to attacks, such as pinning, despite the complexity involved in selecting which transactions to evict.

The concept of carveouts is detailed, proposing four criteria inspired by the Lightning Network to increase predictability and efficiency. Discrepancies with current LN anchor outputs call for updates to prevent misuse. A Mermaid syntax diagram is used to show how multiple carveouts can coexist within a cluster while adhering to strict rules, though harmonizing these with the cluster mempool remains a challenge necessitating further discussion.

Incentive compatibility in transaction fee rates is explored, suggesting prioritization of higher fee rates at the top of the mempool over those at the bottom to reflect the risk of lower-end transactions being replaced or timing out. Theoretical ideas about anti-pin strategies and temporary cluster limit exceedances are mentioned as areas needing more research.

The debate on cryptocurrency mining and transaction fee analysis includes evaluating profitability in different mempool states, focusing on a fair comparison between two mempools (OLD and NEW) based on their terminal vbytes and fee rates. The consensus favors a zero tail feerate for simplicity in comparison, acknowledging the complexities of a non-zero tail feerate and its influence on transaction replacement dynamics.

Discussion on implementing a carve-out rule that exempts certain transactions from cluster size limitations faces enforcement challenges. Strategies like evicting existing transactions or expanding the cluster size have drawbacks, including disrupting contracts and increasing validation complexity. The v3 transaction model offers an alternative, seeking to support specific transaction topologies while respecting cluster sizes.

A new design for the Bitcoin Core mempool proposes policy changes to enforce stricter cluster size limitations and require incoming transactions to provide better feerate diagrams for acceptance. The draft implementation aims for a fully sorted mempool to facilitate organization, efficient mining selection, and eviction, with anticipation for enhancements following community reviews and benchmarking. Technical details of this new approach are available in the original write-up by Pieter Wuille, known as @sipa.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T15:08:32.829000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
