<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Subscript rendering in graph broken in Safari</title>
  <updated>2024-02-28T02:08:15.383194+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-02-27 19:05:03.918000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2024-02-27 12:02:48.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-02-27 05:56:12.977000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2024-02-26 17:48:55.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1723_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1717_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1705_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1700_Subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-Safari.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Subscript rendering in graph broken in Safari</title>
    <updated>2024-02-28T02:08:15.383245+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/subscript-rendering-in-graph-broken-in-safari/608/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion revolves around a specific rendering issue encountered with diagrams based on Mermaid.js, a visualization tool distinct from Graphviz. The problem arises when these diagrams are viewed on Safari browsers, particularly on macOS versions 13.6.4 and 14.3.1. It was noted that subscript numbers within transaction graphs do not appear in their intended positions but are instead clustered in the top-left corner of the graph. This misplacement disrupts the proper visual interpretation of the data, affecting the usability of these diagrams for conveying complex information accurately. Interestingly, this rendering issue seems to be exclusive to Safari, as Chrome displays the same graphs correctly without any such problems, indicating a potential compatibility or rendering bug specific to Safari.

Further communication suggests that encountering this glitch in the live editor or while using the diagrams elsewhere necessitates reporting the issue to the developers of Mermaid.js. Contributors are encouraged to file an issue on [Mermaid's GitHub page](https://github.com/mermaid-js/mermaid/issues) with a demonstration of the problematic behavior to facilitate its resolution. This approach aims at addressing the bug directly at its source by the development team behind Mermaid.js, potentially leading to a broader fix that benefits all users encountering similar issues across different platforms or discussion forums, such as Delving forum. The importance of resolving such discrepancies is emphasized to ensure consistent user experiences across browsers and to maintain the integrity and effectiveness of data representation through Mermaid.js diagrams.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-27T19:05:03.918000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
