<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-03-01T01:56:51.476898+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-02-29 19:29:30.553000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-21 04:47:51.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic  . 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1740_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1649_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-03-01T01:56:51.476985+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the complexities of implementing an expiration mechanism for transactions within a blockchain framework. It highlights the potential for such a mechanism to introduce confusion regarding the finality of transactions and incentivize certain behaviors that could undermine the integrity of the blockchain, like reorganizing blocks to exclude transactions that were meant to expire. The concept of creating a conflicting transaction that is timelocked but offers a higher fee as a way to make the original transaction invalid introduces an incentive-compatible approach to transaction expiration.

There's a concern regarding the unintended consequences of expiring Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), which could lead to them becoming unspendable and inadvertently increasing the value of the remaining currency due to the reduction in total coins. This scenario is considered more of an accidental benefit rather than a targeted outcome. The introduction of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) for asset swaps is discussed as a mitigation strategy against the risk of expiring transactions, ensuring outputs remain spendable by their creators even if the transaction expires before confirmation.

The dialogue also explores the implications of moving PSBTs from an off-chain to an on-chain framework, especially concerning how Miner Extractable Value (MEV) issues are managed. The shift introduces new dynamics in addressing MEV, necessitating a comparison between using CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) versus CheckMultiTimeVerify (CMTV) scripts. There's an acknowledgment of the nuanced considerations involved, including the potential for increased censorship activities by miners, highlighting the need for careful analysis of these changes' impact on transaction dynamics and the broader blockchain ecosystem.

Further discussion is centered around the addition of an op code for transaction expiration, based on a proposal viewed more favorably than the original idea suggested by the author. The debate focuses on using block height versus block time for determining transaction expiration, with a consensus leaning towards block height due to concerns over miners manipulating block time. The complexity introduced by having transactions with different expiration incentives coexist in the mempool is noted as a potential counterbalance to miner manipulation, adding strategic depth to economic incentives across the network.

The significance of the [OP_EXPIRE](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022042.html) post is mentioned, suggesting it as a foundational resource for understanding the merits and considerations of implementing an expiration feature in the Bitcoin protocol. This recommendation underscores the post's relevance and utility in the context of Bitcoin development.

Lastly, the proposal for introducing a new opcode aimed at making peer-to-peer asset swaps more efficient and reducing reliance on centralized marketplaces is discussed. The early draft BIP linked [here](https://github.com/EvanWinget/bips/blob/7d70761da8fe43ae5d4fdd0c18b14765652ccfec/bip-checkmaxtimeverify.mediawiki) outlines the motivation behind this idea, focusing on economic inefficiencies associated with unconfirmed transactions. By enabling these transactions to be invalidated beyond a specific block height or time, the proposal aims to encourage decentralization and improve the efficiency of asset swap markets, thus mitigating the push towards centralized solutions. Feedback from the Delving Bitcoin community is sought to identify any potential issues with the concept, ensuring its viability and effectiveness.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-29T19:29:30.553000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
