<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
  <updated>2024-02-27T01:53:14.075327+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-02-26 14:57:10.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 04:13:31.288000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-01-24 17:05:16.348000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-01-16 16:35:24.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-15 06:56:27.495000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-14 12:44:16.551000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 06:13:17.355000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-14 05:52:08.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-10 19:56:47.130000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-01-10 17:01:16.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 19:18:51.887000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:41:17.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-01-05 18:09:14.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-05 18:03:45.164000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1697_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1683_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1326_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1144_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1113_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1109_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1108_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1107_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1060_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1059_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/934_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/932_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/931_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/929_LN-Symmetry-Project-Recap.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LN-Symmetry Project Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-02-27T01:53:14.075432+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ln-symmetry-project-recap/359/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on optimizing blockchain transaction protocols to improve efficiency and security, specifically within layered network solutions like the Lightning Network. A proposed method involves segregating transactions into update and settlement categories to streamline operations and reduce trust exploitation risks. This approach suggests a dynamic system where potentially only two transactions are needed if awaiting a response before sending another update, which could fast-forward to the most recent transaction state. Technical solutions such as adapter signatures and CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) were analyzed, with CTV being more optimal in certain scenarios. Despite their benefits, an ideal solution would involve a commitment scheme that allows spenders to directly handle fees from their outputs or incorporate their own fee inputs, simplifying the transaction process further.

The blog post also highlights practical implementations and ongoing projects within the Core Lightning (CLN) framework, including the successful force-closing of channels documented through a shared [Gist](https://gist.github.com/chrisguida/43e482e684727daa618423e52a14d09a). It discusses a significant code rebase involving 283 commits in preparation for integration with various systems, indicating a collaborative effort open to community participation. Furthermore, it addresses transaction challenges, especially with large amounts and across private channels, emphasizing the importance of route hints and the uncertainties of untested functionalities.

The exploration includes an examination of the eltoo update mechanism and its implementation challenges, such as conflicts with other channel features and data integrity concerns post-restarts. Progress is noted in manually broadcasting transactions using ephemeral anchors. The blog delves into optimizing transaction processes using CTV to eliminate extra signature round-trips, proposing alternative solutions like leveraging the annex field or partial adaptor signatures to streamline updates and settlements.

Additionally, the blog touches upon the complexities of implementing the eltoo protocol within the Lightning Network, highlighting the multi-step process and potential extension of timelock durations. It underscores the potential for innovation in blockchain transaction protocols and the challenges developers face in enhancing efficiency, security, and usability in real-world applications. The discussion extends to state-graph cut-through in Bitcoin transactions, examining the use of OP_CTV and alternative covenant schemes for achieving simpler transaction processes. Although OP_CTV is favored, emulation using APO suggests other methods might achieve similar results, indicating a broader scope for innovation in transaction efficiency within the Bitcoin network.

The LN-Symmetry Project made strides in developing research-quality software based on the eltoo proposal, focusing on proving the concept's viability. Despite successfully implementing basic functional tests for various operations within channel management, some aspects remained unimplemented. The project aimed to simplify BOLT specifications and address technical challenges associated with eltoo, including flexible fee management and reduced dependency on utxo pools for fees. The use of CTV emulation emerged as a benefit, potentially reducing payment times by streamlining the payment protocol.

Key outcomes from the LN-Symmetry Project include identifying challenges like avoiding pinning and recognizing that eltoo-style channels require longer htlc expiry deltas for secure operation. The project contributed to skepticism regarding the effectiveness of penalties in future implementations, suggesting that correctly functioning systems offer better deterrence against adversaries. Contributions to the [Package Relay Project](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/27463), the creation of [Ephemeral Anchors](https://github.com/instagibbs/bips/blob/d33cdbd0777700f4fc488d54b90a8795d2c33639/bip-ephemeralanchors.mediawiki), and several repositories and drafts related to BOLT specification, Bitcoin Core changes, and PTLC compatibility with eltoo-style channels were among the project's outputs. Currently, the project is paused as attention shifts towards mempool-related work, aiming to inform future discussions on softforks and channel design advancements.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-26T14:57:10.543000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
