<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-02-21T01:54:37.617794+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-02-21T01:54:37.617867+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the intricacies of introducing a new opcode, OP_EXPIRE, to the Bitcoin protocol, highlighting its potential to enhance transaction efficiency and encourage decentralization. The sender begins by expressing uncertainty about the implications of moving Pay-to-ScriptHash (PSBTs) transactions from off-chain to on-chain with respect to Miner Extractable Value (MEV). They ponder the effects of Conditional Multisig TimeLock Verification (CMTV) versus CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) mechanisms, suggesting that the timing of script spendability could influence miner behavior, including possible censorship based on economic incentives.

Further, the email references a discussion on the merits of implementing an expiration feature for Bitcoin transactions. This concept is substantiated by a proposal made by another developer, Peter, which appears to be more compelling than the sender's initial idea. Peter's insights, particularly on the risks associated with time-based transaction parameters, underscore the preference for block height over block time to prevent miners from misrepresenting time data. This conversation sheds light on the broader dialogue concerning the utility and design considerations of adding such a feature, noting the existing reliance on timestamp-based locks and how an expiration opcode might balance economic incentives for miners.

The sender points out the relevance of the [OP_EXPIRE post](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022042.html), suggesting it as a foundational resource for understanding the proposal's implications and benefits. Although they haven't reviewed the detailed Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) linked within, they believe this document can offer valuable insights into the proposed opcode's role in improving peer-to-peer asset swaps and reducing dependency on centralized marketplaces.

Central to the email is the exploration of a draft BIP aimed at making unconfirmed transactions invalid after a certain point, either through block height or time. This initiative seeks to address inefficiencies in asset swap markets and mitigate competition for block space, potentially fostering a more decentralized ecosystem. The sender is soliciting feedback from the community to refine the proposal and ensure its effectiveness in promoting decentralization while enhancing transactional efficiency within the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-20T12:12:48.309000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
