<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-02-17T01:58:15.608545+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QcMrHyde  . 2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>juangalt  . 2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T01:58:15.608649+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recently detailed regulation at [EUR-Lex](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32023R1114) distinguishes between custodial and non-custodial wallet providers in the cryptocurrency sector, indicating a move towards more regulated custody services to enforce Know Your Customer (KYC) regulations more effectively. This shift is likely to influence the digital finance landscape by promoting custodian services for better compliance.

Discussions around the implementation of "evil covenants" in cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin acknowledge that while these features could pose risks, existing capabilities in altcoins and Bitcoin's scripting have not led to significant issues. Various technical solutions are explored to mitigate the risks associated with covenants, including scripts controlled by internal keys or using a designated freeze key to comply with covenant conditions. These debates highlight the balance between innovation and security in integrating new functionalities into Bitcoin.

There is an analysis of methods to enhance transaction introspection within Bitcoin, mentioning six different approaches for detailed transaction analysis. The discourse also proposes strategies for creating recursive covenants without the OP_CAT operation, suggesting ways to work within Bitcoin's scripting limitations for innovative solutions.

The text discusses the challenges of incorporating new financial institutions into regulatory frameworks, especially regarding the use of covenants or multisig mechanisms. It suggests that backend server code updates might provide a simpler and more efficient method for ensuring compliance and security, contributing to the debate on the utility of on-chain solutions versus traditional server-based checks in financial technologies.

A comparative analysis between covenant KYC pools and multisig KYC pools shows a governmental preference for covenants due to their rule-bound nature, transparency, and verifiability, contrasted with the flexibility but less public accountability of multisig arrangements. Additionally, the strategy of generating new addresses for each transaction is discussed as a means to balance privacy with regulatory oversight.

Operational and user experience implications of employing a Merkle root in transactions for enforcing KYC regulations are explored. The covenant model, requiring only a single signature every two weeks, is emphasized for its practicality over the cosigner model, which demands co-signatures for each transaction, highlighting the efficiency and reduced operational burden of the covenant model in a regulated framework.

The European Union's efforts to regulate Bitcoin through stringent KYC laws are gaining momentum, with details provided on [CoinDesk](https://www.coindesk.com/learn/mica-eus-comprehensive-new-crypto-regulation-explained/). The potential integration of perpetual KYC contracts within Bitcoin’s protocol could ensure regulatory compliance while offering benefits like fast international settlements. A unique approach involves government signing of a Merkle root of an approved whitelist bi-weekly, enhancing security and allowing for dynamic updates to the whitelist and spending limits based on KYC status.

The text also examines operational challenges and solutions for governments managing secure cryptocurrency transactions, suggesting offline, air-gapped devices for signing transactions as a secure method. It contrasts infrastructure requirements between maintaining a cosigning server for multisig operations and managing a whitelist server, without favoring one over the other from logistical or security perspectives.

Furthermore, the capacity of regulatory authorities to control Bitcoin transactions through whitelisting addresses indicates ongoing developments in policies or technologies to meet regulatory needs. Lastly, questions about the permanence of government policies on Bitcoin ponder the potential for policy evolution or revocation, highlighting the dynamic nature of regulatory approaches and the government's ability to relinquish control over Bitcoin transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T16:27:39.486000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
