<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
  <updated>2024-02-05T01:58:54.245027+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-02-04 12:27:13.569000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-21 23:17:19.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hampus  . 2024-01-19 21:44:31.109000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-18 06:22:10.878000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>alex  . 2024-01-17 14:51:04.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RubenSomsen  . 2024-01-10 15:30:30.263000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-09 20:34:43.479000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-08 10:21:44.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>urza  . 2024-01-08 06:31:45.340000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-01-07 20:48:53.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-07 20:31:47.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:55:48.846000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 19:30:43.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>michaelfolkson  . 2024-01-07 19:17:58.402000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-01-07 18:41:08.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1459_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1278_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1233_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1182_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1165_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1056_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1050_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1014_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1011_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1000_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/999_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/996_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/995_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/993_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/989_LNHANCE-bips-and-implementation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - LNHANCE bips and implementation</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T01:58:54.245136+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lnhance-bips-and-implementation/376/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The integration of internal fees within onchain mechanisms to handle unilateral exits has been proposed, aiming to reduce blockspace usage by eliminating the need for anchor outputs and Child Pays For Parent (CPFP) transactions. An extension for `OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY` has been developed to support this and can be further studied at [this link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sighash-outputdeltabounds/504/2?u=zmnscpxj).

A new proposal suggests using a contract similar to LN-symmetry for statecoins, which could significantly improve the efficiency and scalability of digital assets by allowing a single channel funding to benefit many users in a continuous cycle with a timeout mechanism.

Developers have shown considerable interest in a speculated tool with functionalities like APO, anticipating it to widen architectural possibilities, particularly for channel factories and statechains. This speculation is fueled by Rearden's Twitter post available at [Rearden's Tweet](https://twitter.com/reardencode/status/1748452392046334366).

Progress in Bitcoin coding includes a Pull Request in the 'binana' repository for CSFS and INTERNALKEY features, accessible at [this GitHub link](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/binana/pull/1). The proposals for these features are also drafted against the main Bitcoin Core repository, found at [internalkey PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29269) and [csfs PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29270). Modularization of CTV is being considered for better integration and testing.

Jeremy Rubin’s website, utxos.org, offers resources for CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) applications and is updated regularly to assist developers working with CTV technology.

Spacechains, enabling pre-commitment of future transactions without covenants, facilitate the creation of structures like channel factories that typically require covenant mechanisms.

There's an emphasis on Oracle slashing for simplified Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) using Covenants via Transaction Outputs (CTV), using signatures such as `SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUTANYSCRIPT|SIGHASH_ALL`. Additionally, CheckSequenceVerifyFromStack (CSFS) can be used for delegation, allowing more complex script constructs.

LN-symmetry focuses on executing crucial tasks effectively, and its strategic development emphasizes key processes over broad functionality.

The discussion touches upon the implementation of channel factories and Spacechains, indicating a high level of interest in advanced blockchain mechanisms and seeking expertise from Ruben Somsen for further clarification.

A unidirectional non-interactive channel (NIC) immune to TXID malleability is mentioned, utilized within a virtual UTXO pool managed by an entity known as a Lightning Service Provider (LSP), aiming for secure and efficient user operations.

The conversation also examines Probabilistic Timelock Contracts (PTLCs) and APO-like constructions, noting PTLCs as currently achievable technologies. A unified approach is deemed necessary to avoid clutter and noise from various pull requests, addressing concerns about APO's limitations on future development due to new key types and sighash flags that might be difficult to upgrade. An open PR against APO suggests alternative designs for sighash flags.

Meanwhile, a cautious strategy is recommended for deploying CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (CTV) alongside CHECKSIGFROMSTACK (CSFS) as per BIP119 to analyze its efficacy before proposing additional sighash modes for future Tapscript key versions. Organizational strategies, such as the bitcoin-inquisition repository, are highlighted for managing Bitcoin's software development by segregating consensus changes from other updates.

Newly proposed Bitcoin Improvement Proposals and operational codes under "LNHANCE," including BIP119, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK(VERIFY), and OP_INTERNALKEY, aim to enhance the Lightning Network's capabilities and aid in the development of ln-symmetry and Point Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs). These initiatives show promise for granting users more control over their Bitcoin outputs, potentially leading to significant advancements for the Lightning Network by improving privacy and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-04T12:27:13.569000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
