<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-21T18:38:58.435354+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-26 05:12:52.072000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-25 00:16:13.204000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 21:49:58.786000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 20:50:31.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>harding  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>sanket  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>roasbeef  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>QcMrHyde  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>juangalt  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_18" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_19" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5171_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5120_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5114_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5026_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5024_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T18:38:58.436773+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the complexities of securing large transactions against attackers, highlighting the contrast between TLS certificates and co-signing keys. While TLS certificates offer an easily revocable security measure for lost or compromised keys, co-signing keys lack this flexibility once integrated into UTXOs. However, technologies like CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS suggest a move toward replicating TLS-like infrastructure within different contexts, hinting at a future where dynamic security management can adapt to emerging threats.
When examining the effectiveness of Know Your Customer (KYC) protocols in digital currency systems, it's clear that KYC alone cannot prevent account misuse or stop the movement of stolen funds. The ability to quickly blacklist compromised accounts is crucial, as demonstrated by stablecoin issuers' responses to hacking incidents. Despite the traceability offered by KYC-compliant accounts, the absence of transaction volume restrictions does little to hinder the immediate liquidation of stolen assets. This points to the inherent challenges in key management and the nuanced differences between managing PKI systems for secure communication on government websites and the uncharted territory of Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs).
The potential abuse within KYC covenant mechanisms raises concerns about their security, as sophisticated fraud schemes found in traditional banking could be replicated. Alternatives like Railgun and Privacy Pools, facilitated by `OP_CAT`, offer a glimpse into trustless privacy solutions that bypass conventional KYC measures. These discussions underscore the importance of ongoing evaluation and development of digital currency management practices to mitigate risks of misuse.
The discourse around Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, specifically OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK, and the gradual loss of censorship resistance highlights the developer community's engagement with enhancing Bitcoin's utility while preserving its foundational principles. The exploration of recursive covenants and their potential implications on censorship resistance emphasizes the careful consideration developers must give to any proposed changes within Bitcoin's protocol.
Recent EU regulations delineate a clear distinction between custodial and non-custodial wallet providers, aiming for a regulated custody service landscape. Skepticism around the utility of covenants for nefarious purposes suggests a preference for existing multisig setups over new covenant applications, indicating a strategic shift towards simplifying regulatory compliance across the digital finance ecosystem.
The conversations surrounding evil covenants in cryptocurrency systems reveal that the perceived risks may already be accounted for within the ecosystem. Proposed solutions highlight the balance between innovation and security, suggesting the use of internal keys or designated freeze keys to enforce policy compliance, illustrating the technical and practical considerations in deploying such features within Bitcoin.
The analysis of transaction introspection methods reveals a focus on extracting detailed information from transactions, acknowledging the challenge of achieving similar outcomes without OP_CAT. This engenders a deeper understanding of Bitcoin's scripting language and encourages innovative approaches within its limitations.
The complexity of integrating new financial institutions into the regulatory framework using covenants or multisig mechanisms sparks debate on the balance between ease of implementation and security efficacy. This reflects the evolving nature of financial technologies and the continuous search for solutions that satisfy both regulatory requirements and operational efficiency.
Comparing covenant KYC pools to multisig KYC pools illuminates the structured, transparent, and accountable framework of covenants, favoring them over the flexible but less publicly verifiable multisig arrangements. This preference underscores the importance of transparency and verifiability in managing KYC protocols within Bitcoin transactions.
The discussion on employing Merkle roots and covenant models for transaction processes contrasts their impact on user experience and operational efficiency. The covenant model's single signature requirement every two weeks, compared to the cosigner model's demand for millions of signatures annually, highlights the operational burden differences. Additionally, the debate between whitelist and multisig mechanisms for government-related transactions sheds light on the logistical and security considerations without asserting a definitive preference for either approach.
Finally, the European Union's efforts to regulate Bitcoin through KYC laws suggest a move towards introducing perpetual KYC contracts, potentially enhancing regulatory compliance while maintaining Bitcoin's benefits. This approach underscores the ongoing development and adaptation of policies governing Bitcoin transactions to meet regulatory needs, questioning the permanence of such policies and the government's ability to relinquish control over BTC under specific frameworks.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>