<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
  <updated>2024-02-24T01:45:57.682858+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-02-23 03:58:00.041000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-22 23:25:13.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-22 10:47:04.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>quantobasta  . 2024-02-21 22:19:02.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 10:06:34.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 09:40:13.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-19 00:34:09.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-18 19:42:28.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-18 18:08:44.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-12 11:15:33.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1676_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1675_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1669_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1658_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1605_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1604_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1603_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1602_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1601_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1518_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
    <updated>2024-02-24T01:45:57.682942+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-onchain-implementation-of-mining-feerate-futures/547/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent discussions within the cryptocurrency mining community have highlighted several key areas of interest, including the dynamics of mining efficiency and profitability, innovative transaction fee mechanisms, strategic mining adaptations, implications of transaction selection strategies, and the utility of onchain contracts. 

Firstly, it has been revealed through mathematical analysis that smaller miners could achieve a higher proportional payoff compared to larger miners when rewards are adjusted for hash power contributed. This insight is supported by a verified mathematical model available in a [Gist](https://gist.github.com/harding/3af02613d233554837f7921d7fd44e68), which clarifies misunderstandings and highlights opportunities for individual miners.

An innovative concept aimed at revolutionizing transaction fee mechanisms has been introduced, focusing on creating a proof-of-low-fees system. This system allows miners to include artificially-enlarged transactions in their blocks to recover bonded funds, incentivizing lower transaction fees and providing financial stability through more predictable cash flows. The model emphasizes the importance of integrating legal frameworks to ensure compliance and safeguard interests.

Discussions have also explored how different mining strategies can yield varied benefits regardless of miner size. A detailed examination revealed that normal miners might benefit more on a proportional basis from strategic versus normal mining, challenging the notion that strategic mining exclusively favors larger miners.

The discourse touched upon the implications of transaction selection strategies by miners, especially during network congestion and high transaction fees. A critical analysis pointed out a vulnerability where miners with substantial control over the network's hashrate may bypass certain transactions in anticipation of mining them in subsequent blocks. This strategy does not exclusively benefit large miners, as it inadvertently increases fees available for the next block, offering opportunities for all miners.

Onchain contracts were explored for their ability to mitigate risks associated with reliance on trusted third parties by removing counterparty risk. Despite their advantages, there remains a challenge that miners can influence the selection of transactions included in blocks, potentially impacting the reliability of Decentralized Ledger Contracts (DLCs).

A recent exploration discussed a vulnerability in the blockchain mining process where miners might strategically omit high-fee transactions, benefiting from settling contracts more favorably at the expense of ignoring higher-fee transactions in the immediate block. This behavior underscores the potential for mining centralization and necessitates further investigation. Insights from this discussion are anchored by a [contemporary analysis](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553a-simple-analysis-of-a-toy-problem-14).

Furthermore, mining fee futures emerge as a novel solution to the unpredictability of onchain fees, aiming to stabilize miners' income amid demand fluctuations for block space. A detailed description outlines a binary mining fee futures contract leveraging a Taproot address and incorporating distinct branches for executing transactions based on prevailing fee conditions, thus promoting a more stable and predictable framework for blockchain transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-23T03:58:00.041000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
