<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
  <updated>2024-02-23T01:58:39.377591+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-02-22 23:25:13.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-02-22 10:47:04.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>quantobasta  . 2024-02-21 22:19:02.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 10:06:34.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-19 09:40:13.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-19 00:34:09.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-18 19:42:28.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-18 18:08:44.754000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-02-12 11:15:33.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1675_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1669_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1658_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1605_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1604_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1603_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1602_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1601_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1518_An-Onchain-Implementation-Of-Mining-Feerate-Futures.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An Onchain Implementation Of Mining Feerate Futures</title>
    <updated>2024-02-23T01:58:39.377668+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-onchain-implementation-of-mining-feerate-futures/547/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of innovative cryptocurrency mining strategies introduces the concept of a proof-of-low-fees mechanism. This mechanism aims to provide miners with a more predictable income by offering high-fee insurance to users, which is particularly beneficial during periods of low transaction fees. It reduces operational uncertainties, such as grid balancing issues, by requiring miners to include an artificially-enlarged transaction in their blocks to recover bonded funds. This approach strikes a balance between voluntary participation and minimizing intermediary roles while addressing needs like cost predictability.

Further analysis distinguishes between normal and strategic mining, highlighting how these different strategies affect miners based on their size. Strategic mining, which involves optimizing total returns despite potentially lower immediate block returns, suggests that normal miners might achieve higher proportional payoffs when adjusting for their hash power. This insight emphasizes the need to consider the broader context of hash rate distribution and strategic choices among miners, illustrating the complex economic and strategic considerations within cryptocurrency mining.

The discussion also challenges the assumption that larger miners inherently benefit at the expense of smaller ones by analyzing transaction selection strategies. It suggests that bypassing certain transactions could inadvertently benefit miners with lower hashrates, indicating a more balanced opportunity landscape for future block rewards across miners of various sizes.

A critical examination of blockchain transaction prioritization during network congestion questions theoretical models that assume miners will always include the highest fee transactions. Reality proves more complex, with strategies involving strategic omissions by miners with substantial network control to favor future contract settlements. Proposed mitigation strategies include using average fee rates over multiple blocks and incorporating multiple oracles to ensure fair play among miners.

Onchain contracts are discussed as a method to reduce counterparty risk and prevent manipulation outcomes, yet they reveal a vulnerability where miners with significant network control could exclude transactions, potentially reinforcing mining centralization concerns. This highlights the dual role of onchain contracts in addressing traditional system issues while affecting mining dynamics.

The introduction of mining fee futures presents a novel solution to the unpredictability of onchain fees, benefiting both miners and users through stabilized income and protection against fee spikes. This scheme offers structured pathways for handling transactions expected to incur low or high fees, optimizing block space usage and ensuring fairness. For low-fee conditions, it enables efficient cooperation between users and miners to minimize block space wastage. In high-fee scenarios, it provides users with mechanisms to manage financial risks posed by high transaction fees. This approach aims to promote a stable and predictable blockchain environment, improving transactional efficiency and reducing risk for all participants.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-22T23:25:13.184000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
