<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2014-January-004257</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP70 message delivery reliability</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:23:19.886344+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Jan_2014/004257_BIP70-message-delivery-reliability.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2014/004255_BIP70-message-delivery-reliability.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2014-January-004257</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP70 message delivery reliability</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:23:19.886344+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2014-January/004257.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email conversation between Mike Hearn, Chuck and Pieter discusses the implementation of the PaymentRequest/Payment/PaymentACK protocol in Bitcoin. Mike Hearn suggests that the transaction is only committed to the wallet if the server accepts the Payment message and ACKs it, which would mean that if there's a failure submitting or some kind of internal server error, the tx would not be retried if there's a failure submitting or some kind of internal server error. Pieter states that this is one right way to do it but not what is suggested or required by the specification and not what bitcoin core master currently implements. Chuck raises the issue of failure situations and how to address them with minor changes. Pieter agrees that the current implementation has a hole in the delivery of the payment message, which could cause a merchant to argue that the transactions seen on the network were insufficient. Pieter suggests that the specification should prevent transactions confirming without the payment message ever being delivered by storing them in the sender's client, retrying when necessary, or using exponential backoff.</summary>
    <published>2014-01-30T12:02:02+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
