<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core 27.1rc1 is now available</title>
  <updated>2024-06-01T02:06:33.650252+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake.655000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-01T01:11:11.655000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core 27.1rc1 is now available</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T02:06:33.650286+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-27-1rc1-is-now-available/930" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The availability of binaries for the Bitcoin Core version v27.1rc1 has been announced, with downloads accessible via [bitcoincore.org](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-27.1/test.rc1/). Additionally, the source code for this release candidate is available on GitHub under a signed tag, which interested parties can view at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v27.1rc1). This version marks a new minor version release, aiming to introduce improvements and possibly new features to the Bitcoin Core software. 

For those looking to delve deeper into the specifics of this release, preliminary release notes have been made available at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/fccd32efe6e2950b2c74fdec2ade54040ca32a2c/doc/release-notes.md), providing insights into the changes and enhancements included in this update. As a standard practice with release candidates, the community is encouraged to participate in testing. This process is crucial for identifying and resolving any potential issues before the final release. Feedback and issue reporting are highly valued, with a dedicated platform for such communications provided at [GitHub Issues](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues).

The significance of this testing phase cannot be overstated, as it directly influences the stability and functionality of the forthcoming official release. Should this release candidate meet the necessary standards without surfacing critical problems, it will be officially tagged as version 27.1. The announcement also hints at the possibility of future release candidates, depending on the outcomes of the ongoing testing efforts.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-01T01:11:11.655000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
