<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Proposed risk framework for Bitcoin L2s and Sidechains</title>
  <updated>2024-06-02T02:04:23.192507+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>janusz</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-01T14:27:22.756000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Proposed risk framework for Bitcoin L2s and Sidechains</title>
    <updated>2024-06-02T02:04:23.192546+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposed-risk-framework-for-bitcoin-l2s-and-sidechains/933" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Janusz is spearheading the [Bitcoin Layers](https://www.bitcoinlayers.org/) project, which evaluates different implementations of L2s and sidechains in the cryptocurrency domain. The inception of this initiative was motivated by the burgeoning array of sidechain protocols, aiming to provide a comprehensive analysis of these technologies based on a set of common criteria. To facilitate this, Janusz has developed a [risk framework](https://hackmd.io/@januszgrze/bitcoin-layers-risk-proposal), with input from research advisors and an advisory board, designed to elucidate the risks each implementation poses to users. This framework is structured around several key areas: unilateral exit capabilities, data availability, block production, and state validation (settlement), offering users a clear understanding of potential vulnerabilities.

The project is currently facing challenges due to the inherent differences and trade-offs among protocols, such as those between rollups and payment channel protocols. In response, a proposal has been made to refine the assessment methodology by introducing a more nuanced approach that includes assigning weighted scores to specific risk factors. Instead of assigning overall scores, this model would adjust a protocol's risk category based on how it fares against specific criteria, supplemented by binary questions to further dissect the risks associated with each protocol. This information is condensed into a risk summary that highlights key trade-offs and potential impacts on the Bitcoin network.

The initial assessment categorizes protocols based on four main criteria: data availability, network operators, settlement assurance, and bridge custody, with risk levels designated as high, medium, or low based on specific conditions. For instance, protocols utilizing offchain data availability solutions like single servers are considered extremely high risk due to the potential for collusion leading to fund theft. Conversely, protocols that enable user self-hosting of data or leverage Bitcoin for data availability are deemed low risk.

Furthermore, the framework extends its analysis to other areas such as the role of alternative tokens in network security, potential risks for Miner Extractable Value (MEV) at both the protocol and base layer levels, and whether fees are paid to Bitcoin miners. The aim is to customize the framework to capture the nuances of various scaling solutions present in Bitcoin today, acknowledging that Bitcoin lacks a unified scaling roadmap and each protocol has its own set of trade-offs.

This dynamic document invites community feedback and continuous refinement to accurately reflect the evolving landscape of Bitcoin scaling efforts. Janusz encourages participation in the discussion through their [community chat](https://t.me/+8rv-1I2gkmQ4ZmJh) to ensure the framework remains relevant and comprehensive, emphasizing that the goal is not only to assess but also to improve the understanding of these complex systems within the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-01T14:27:22.756000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
