<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-06-03T02:02:00.010355+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.093000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-02T23:30:11.093000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>64 bit arithmetic soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-06-03T02:02:00.010391+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64-bit-arithmetic-soft-fork/397/50" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of programming, particularly within the context of script writing for financial transactions or similar applications, the issue of handling overflows presents a significant challenge. A common practice among programmers is to overlook the potential for overflow in their scripts. This oversight can lead to vulnerabilities, where malicious individuals may exploit these oversights to orchestrate theft. The utilization of an `OP_DROP` operation following an arithmetic operation is highlighted as a simplistic approach that assumes overflow will not occur. However, this approach is fraught with risk, as it leaves the door open for exploitation through carefully crafted attacks that induce overflow.

To mitigate such risks, a more cautious strategy involves employing the `OP_VERIFY` operation immediately after arithmetic operations to ensure no overflow has occurred. This method serves as a safeguard, making scripts more robust against overflow exploitation. An example provided from a script in the [review club](https://bitcoincore.reviews/29221l-86) showcases how the lack of verification following an addition operation (`OP_ADD64`) could potentially introduce security vulnerabilities. The proposed solution to this problem involves refining the handling of arithmetic operations in scripting languages used for blockchain and similar technologies. 

A suggestion made in the discourse proposes the creation of two distinct opcodes: `OP_ADD64` and `OP_ADD64VERIFY`. The latter would inherently include a verification step to confirm that no overflow took place during the operation, failing the script if an overflow is detected. This approach directly addresses the vulnerability by integrating an automatic check that prevents scripts from proceeding when an overflow error occurs. Another angle put forth involves not altering the fundamental behavior of existing opcodes but rather adjusting the acceptable range of inputs for these operations. This would require changing how the `ADD` operation is processed to accommodate 64-bit numbers efficiently and introducing new operations like `ADD_OF` and `MUL_OF`, which would explicitly manage overflow flags on the stack, enhancing the security and reliability of scripts without drastically altering their semantics. 

This dialogue underscores the critical need for programmers to adopt more rigorous practices in script development, especially in applications where security and accuracy are paramount. By incorporating verification steps or redefining the operational parameters of arithmetic functions, developers can significantly reduce the risk of exploitation through overflow vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-02T23:30:11.093000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
