<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:07:39.704082+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-03T08:56:16.868000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:07:39.704108+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet/937" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent activation of `OP_CAT` on signet, made possible via the [bitcoin inquisition client](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-inquisition-25-2/838), introduces a new avenue for executing complex scripting capabilities on the blockchain. This functionality, previously theoretical, now allows for the validation of proof-of-work (PoW) in an innovative manner. By manipulating hash bytes through concatenation and validation processes, it becomes feasible to create scripts that validate PoW directly on the blockchain. This development is particularly significant for signet, a permissioned blockchain where acquiring coins typically relies on allocations from signet block producers. The introduction of a mechanism for coin distribution based on PoW contributions adds a dynamic layer to the acquisition of sBTC, as demonstrated by a [proof-of-concept transaction](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/25deff74b7775918aa6824cfeab9121a519fb419d31ea74f6cb6a53f98cc863a) and further explicated through a [Python script for claiming funds](https://github.com/ajtowns/bitcoin/blob/634e72cbfc0aa3f657a35c7b597f688bb2bb29a6/contrib/signet/powcoins).

Addressing concerns around the reuse of PoW by others or multiple claims by the same entity involves cryptographic techniques that tie the proof conclusively to the claimant's identity and ensure each PoW is uniquely applicable to a single claim. This process involves a combination of signature verification and length commitments, making unauthorized claim attempts or duplicate uses of the same work impractical. The choice of work compatible with Bitcoin ASICs underscores a design tailored towards leveraging existing mining infrastructure, thereby aligning with Bitcoin's broader ecosystem.

The technical implementation of this concept is detailed through script components that manage difficulty specification, concatenate necessary data elements, and verify the validity of the constructed preimage against expected cryptographic standards. This intricate scripting ensures that only valid PoW submissions meeting predetermined criteria can successfully claim coins. Programmatically, the initiative encompasses setting up a specialized wallet and executing claims against available coins with a focus on maximizing value relative to the effort expended, as highlighted in operational commands for initiating wallet setup and claiming processes.

Collaborative efforts, such as those between contributors to the bitcoin inquisition project, highlight the communal approach to innovation within the cryptocurrency domain, addressing potential challenges and expanding the functional landscape of Bitcoin scripting and its applications on signet.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T08:56:16.868000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
