<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:09:19.116751+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>myles.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-03T17:21:52.526000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:09:19.116782+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around Bitcoin's scalability and its true purpose raises several critical points. One of the main concerns is the practicality of using Bitcoin for everyday transactions, especially given the necessity of conducting at least two on-chain transactions to set up Lightning channels. With transaction fees predicted to rise due to increased demand for block space, the affordability of participating in the Bitcoin network becomes a significant issue for lower-income individuals worldwide. For instance, families living on $5 per week in Ethiopia would find it challenging to self-custody Bitcoin under the current fee structure, which contradicts the decentralized ethos of Bitcoin.

There is also a debate regarding the intended users of Bitcoin's base layer. The argument that it should be reserved for governments, banks, and major companies while ordinary people interact with Bitcoin through these entities undermines the foundational principle of Bitcoin - the autonomy of managing one's assets without intermediaries. This perspective raises concerns about the loss of control over one's funds, encapsulated in the phrase "not your keys, not your coins."

Furthermore, the necessity and feasibility of running one's full node have been questioned, considering the advancements in storage and bandwidth technology since Bitcoin's inception in 2009. Despite these technological improvements, the block size remains at 1MB. This point brings to light the broader issue of governance within the Bitcoin community and the influence of a small group of developers on crucial decisions such as block size. The critique suggests that the decision-making process has strayed from Bitcoin's original principles, which were aligned with the Austrian school of thought promoting free market determinism.

In conclusion, the author expresses disillusionment with the direction Bitcoin has taken, particularly its increasing alignment with institutional interests at the expense of individual freedom and autonomy. The hope is articulated for a reorientation of Bitcoin towards its roots as a tool for human rights and individual liberty, rather than merely a vehicle for speculative investment. The insights shared are drawn from over a decade of experience and reflect a deep belief in the potential of Bitcoin to serve as "freedom money."</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T17:21:52.526000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
