<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:05:12.872674+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-06-03 17:16:36.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:05:12.872704+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/27" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the concept of making pool shares a tradable asset raises interesting points, especially when considering the use of e-cash within this framework. The notion of trading pool shares in a centralized pool context brings up questions about their value, which could presumably align closely with their nominal worth, particularly if the pool already supports withdrawals through mechanisms like e-cash or lightning networks. The premise suggests that implementing direct withdrawal methods would be more straightforward and beneficial than creating a market for trading shares.

However, the discussion takes a nuanced turn when considering the operational model of braidpool, where the tradability of shares emerges as a critical feature. Unlike a typical centralized pool that might support direct payouts to all participating miners, braidpool limits payouts to the top miners based on the amount owed in any given block. This limitation inherently restricts direct financial benefits to those with significant hash power. Consequently, enabling shares to be tradable allows miners with lower hash power an alternative method to realize value from their participation. They can sell their shares to larger miners who are more likely to receive direct payouts, thus introducing a dynamic market mechanism within the mining ecosystem. This approach underscores a unique strategy to enhance liquidity and financial flexibility for participants across the mining spectrum, leveraging both lightning and e-cash solutions to facilitate transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T17:16:36.575000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
