<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:08:00.487848+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags.772000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-03T22:30:05.772000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:08:00.487881+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the demand for block space within the Bitcoin network highlights a nuanced understanding of market dynamics and the technological constraints of block size adjustments. The conversation emphasizes that increasing demand for block space is a complex task, influenced by various efforts and lacking certainty in outcomes. This complexity is further compounded by the non-linear relationship between changes to the block size and transaction fees, making predictions about the impact on the fee market particularly challenging.

The narrative suggests a shift in approach towards discussions on expanding the Bitcoin block size capacity. Reflecting on past attitudes during the 2015 to 2017 period, where a rigid stance was maintained, it advocates for a more open and honest dialogue about the potential benefits and drawbacks of such changes. This change aims to address the community's reactionary stance on the topic, encouraging a more balanced and informed discussion.

A critical point raised concerns the misconception that doubling the block size would directly halve transaction fees. The email explains that market prices, including fees, are determined through the interaction of supply and demand. Specifically, it notes Bitcoin’s block space supply is perfectly inelastic, meaning no increase in price can create a sustainable increase in supply, except through consensus forks that raise the block size. Conversely, user demand elasticity is difficult to measure, especially with advanced Replace-By-Fee (RBF) tactics that allow users to start with low fees and incrementally increase them to ensure their transactions are included in the next block.

An illustrative example used in the discussion demonstrates how a minor increase in block size could potentially eliminate the entire fee market under certain conditions. This underscores the inadequacy of using observed fee levels as the sole basis for determining new block size limits. Instead, there is a suggestion to explore modifications that could alter the elasticity of block supply rather than maintaining its perfect inelasticity while only adjusting the available supply.

In conclusion, the correspondence calls for a normalization of conversations around block size adjustments, moving away from the dismissive attitude prevalent in recent years. It indicates that future discussions should not outright reject considerations of altering block space dynamics, reflecting a more open-minded and analytical approach to blockchain scalability and economic models.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T22:30:05.772000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
