<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:07:20.305378+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2024-06-04 17:25:46.778000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:07:20.305408+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights a significant debate around the value of money, particularly in the context of international standards and the cost of living. It critiques the perception that amounts considered negligible in wealthier countries like the United States are deemed insignificant universally, pointing out the inherent bias in such a viewpoint. This argument extends into the realm of cryptocurrency and blockchain technology, specifically addressing criticisms aimed at the financial inclusivity of networks like Bitcoin.

Furthermore, the text delves into the contentious issue surrounding the scalability and security of blockchain networks, with a specific focus on Bitcoin's ability to handle transactions. The critique targets arguments made by proponents of larger block sizes within the Bitcoin network, suggesting that their concerns over transaction fees and network accessibility are somewhat disingenuous. According to the writer, these proponents fail to recognize that reducing transaction costs to nearly zero might compromise the perceived sovereignty and security of the network, rendering it no more valuable than a conventional database system.

Lastly, the mention of lightning channels as a solution to maintain minimal transaction fees suggests an acknowledgment of ongoing efforts to address scalability and cost issues within the Bitcoin network. This implies a belief in the potential for technological solutions to balance the need for security and inclusivity without compromising the underlying value of the network.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T17:25:46.778000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
