<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:06:23.843007+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:42:57.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:06:23.843037+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the scalability of the Lightning network, specifically addressing the critique that channels are not as freely available or easily established as previously suggested. The critic highlights a discrepancy in the argument by pointing to a hypothetical example where only 3 million edges (or connections) are added to the Lightning network daily. This figure is deemed unrealistic when considering the global population, which stands at approximately 7 billion people. To truly democratize access to what is termed 'ultra sound money' via the Lightning network, it would necessitate every individual on the planet having the capability to open and close multiple channels for transactions.

However, for simplicity and argument's sake, the critique simplifies this requirement to every individual opening just one channel. Even under this simplified scenario, the math presents a logistical challenge; it would take around 7 years to integrate the entire global population into the system if the network could only facilitate the opening of 3 million new channels each day. This calculation starkly illustrates the current limitations in the scaling model proposed for the Lightning network, emphasizing the need for more efficient or alternative solutions to achieve truly universal access and adoption.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T17:42:57.357000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
