<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:05:58.502131+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-06-04 17:58:57.055000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:05:58.502161+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion surrounding the block size within a particular technological community highlights a significant period between 2015 and 2017. During this time, the debate over whether to increase the block size from its then-current state was a central issue. Contrary to what might be assumed, there was not a dominant group advocating to maintain the block size as it was. This absence of a strong "keep the block size the same" camp played a pivotal role in the eventual decision to increase the block size.

The discourse reflects on the strategic choices made by the community and the implications of these decisions. The narrative suggests that adopting a firm stance on the matter was considered beneficial for the community's development and progress during this era. The increase in block size, as a result, marks a noteworthy shift in the technological framework, aiming to address the demands or limitations faced at the time.

This evolution within the community and its approach towards resolving key issues offers insight into the dynamics of technological advancement and consensus-building. It underscores the importance of adaptive strategies in technological governance and the progression of systems to meet emerging needs and challenges.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T17:58:57.055000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
