<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoind Policy Estimator modes Analysis</title>
  <updated>2024-06-13T09:08:17.650729+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2024-06-12 15:32:49.485000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoind Policy Estimator modes Analysis</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T09:08:17.650762+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoind-policy-estimator-modes-analysis/964" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The analysis of fee estimation data from Block 846887 to 847322, which encompasses a total of 435 blocks, provides critical insights into the performance of the [Bitcoind Policy Estimator](https://johnnewbery.com/an-intro-to-bitcoin-core-fee-estimation/) in both its `conservative` and `economical` modes. The methodology employed involved logging and tracing fee estimates in both modes every minute, alongside tracking the percentile fee rates of all connected blocks. This extensive data collection effort was facilitated through branch implementation and cleaned datasets, which are accessible via a [Data repository](https://gist.github.com/ismaelsadeeq/6a6531e9b96bfeed20178e353b187332).

The study meticulously defined the terms `conservative` and `economical` modes for clarity. The `conservative` mode relies on a longer history of blocks to derive fee estimates, thus potentially offering higher fee rates that are more likely to meet the target but with less responsiveness to immediate fee market changes. Conversely, the `economical` mode aims to present lower estimates that adapt more swiftly to the prevailing fee market dynamics.

A significant portion of the analysis focused on evaluating overpaid, underpaid, and within-range estimates relative to the actual fee rates of the targeted blocks. The findings underscored a marked difference in the overestimation tendencies between the two modes. Specifically, the `conservative` mode exhibited a notably higher rate of overestimation compared to the `economical` mode. This disparity is vividly illustrated in logscale and absolute values graphs, which highlight the economic mode’s superior responsiveness to recent fee market adjustments.

One of the key discoveries pertains to the excessive overestimation by the `conservative` mode, particularly evidenced in the case of Block 847088. Here, the `conservative` mode's estimate drastically exceeded the block's 50th percentile fee rate, leading to significantly higher transaction costs for users. In stark contrast, the `economical` mode provided much closer and lower fee estimates. This discrepancy not only emphasizes the economic mode's efficiency but also underscores the potential financial repercussions for users relying on the `conservative` mode for their transactions.

The continuous trend of overestimation by the `conservative` mode raises concerns about its suitability as the default estimation mode, especially considering the current behavior of the fee market. The analysis strongly suggests a shift towards the `economical` mode to avoid unnecessary overpayments and to align more closely with real-time market conditions. For those interested in further exploration or replication of these findings, the study directs readers to the [Fee Estimates Analysis](https://github.com/ismaelsadeeq/fee-estimates-analysis/tree/analyse-bitcoind-estimates) repository, where the methodologies and analyses can be reviewed and utilized.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-12T15:32:49.485000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
