<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-15T02:01:50.102768+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-14T18:10:10.742000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T02:01:50.102802+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussion about enhancing cryptographic protocols, a comparison between two approaches for handling inputs in cryptographic proofs is presented. One method entails assigning a unique share and proof to each input, which aligns with traditional implementations. Conversely, an alternative strategy proposes the amalgamation of all inputs associated with a signer's private key into a single share and proof. This consolidation aims to streamline the process and potentially enhance security by reducing the complexity and number of proofs required.

A suggestion is made to further refine this approach by creating a unified proof for each scan key alongside its corresponding set of inputs. This proposal includes the introduction of a global field designed to contain key data, which would consist of a 33-byte scan followed by a set of indexes. Such a structure would facilitate more efficient management and verification of cryptographic proofs.

Moreover, there's an emphasis on the necessity for constructors to verify the absence of ANYONECANPAY sighashes in any inputs prior to adding a silent payment to the protocol. This precaution is mirrored in the responsibilities assigned to updaters, who are also required to conduct similar checks. The rationale behind these checks is to ensure the integrity and security of transactions, especially when modifications to the `PSBT_GLOBAL_TX_MODIFIABLE` field are not deemed necessary.

To address specific challenges related to transaction types and modifications, the introduction of a "Has Silent Payments" flag within the `PSBT_GLOBAL_TX_MODIFIABLE` field is proposed. This addition draws parallel to the existing "Has Sighash Single" flag, underscoring the importance of identifying and accommodating various transaction modifiers within the cryptographic framework. This adaptation reflects a proactive approach to maintaining flexibility and security within the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency transactions and cryptographic protocols.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T18:10:10.742000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
