<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
  <updated>2024-06-18T02:02:39.577551+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-17T16:15:50.793000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T02:02:39.577590+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/differential-fuzzing-of-bitcoin-implementations/208/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent updates in the realm of cryptocurrency programming have brought to light several technical issues and developments that are worth noting for developers and enthusiasts alike. The programming community has been actively engaging with various libraries and tools, contributing to a better understanding and fixing of bugs as they arise.

One of the notable updates involves the `btcd` support addition, which marks a significant enhancement in the toolkit available to developers. However, this update also comes with its set of challenges, including a discovered API mismatch with Bitcoin Core concerning transaction decoding. Unlike Bitcoin Core, which fails if the input was not entirely consumed during a transaction's decoding process, `btcd` does not exhibit the same behavior, indicating a discrepancy that could affect interoperability and functionality.

Moreover, the `rust-bitcoin` library has encountered an issue where it fails to check for the witness flag in transactions that have empty witnesses. This oversight could potentially lead to problems during the witness verification process, highlighting the need for a more thorough inspection mechanism within the library.

The `rust-miniscript` library faces multiple challenges, one being the rejection of certain miniscripts that were unexpectedly being turned down. Additionally, there exists an inconsistency between `rust-miniscript` and Bitcoin Core in validating miniscripts from strings, particularly in the handling of the `+` sign in expressions like `l:older(+1)` `u:after(+1)`. While Bitcoin Core accepts these due to the `ParseInt64` function, `rust-miniscript` checks the character itself and only accepts numeric characters without the `+`, showcasing a divergence in parsing logic that could impact script compatibility and functionality.

Another critical point of discussion is the parser function within `rust-miniscript`, which remains recursive, diverging from Core's updated approach. This difference in design philosophy leads to some miniscripts being valid for Core but rejected by `rust-miniscript` due to the maximum recursion depth, a limitation that underscores the importance of aligning parsing strategies to ensure broader compatibility and validation success.

These issues underscore the dynamic and collaborative nature of development within the cryptocurrency space, where continuous feedback and contributions from the community drive improvements and solutions. For developers working with these tools and libraries, staying informed about such updates is crucial for navigating the complexities of blockchain programming and ensuring the reliability and security of their applications.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-17T16:15:50.793000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
