<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-18T02:06:09.543868+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-17T19:27:30.806000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T02:06:09.543902+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The communication infrastructure for peer discovery and interaction in this system utilizes a combination of directory nodes, Internet Relay Chat (IRC), and Onion services. Specifically, for messaging channels that are Onion-based, there is a strict configuration requirement where the type must be explicitly set as 'onion', and only one such message channel can be configured. This setup includes specifying the socks5 host and port, which typically points to localhost and port 9050, respectively.

For managing the Tor control configurations, it's noted that most users running the Tor daemon on Linux will not need to make any adjustments. The configurations allow for either a hostname and port or a UNIX socket to specify the Tor control host, with the port being necessary but ignored if a UNIX socket is used. The specifics for the onion service hosting include setting the host and port, with the serving port often being 8080.

Directory nodes have a distinct setup process that involves configuring the hidden service directory and specifying directory nodes. This configuration is crucial for nodes acting as directory servers, requiring them to list their own .onion address and port. However, non-directory nodes are advised against using this setup to preserve privacy. The configuration details extend to providing a list of directory nodes for both mainnet and signet (a testing network), highlighting the importance of correctly setting these parameters for the network's operational integrity.

Additionally, the documentation outlines the IRC server configurations for both primary and backup servers. For IRC communication, it details how to configure connections over traditional IP networks and Tor, emphasizing the option to use Tor as a preferred method for maintaining anonymity. The configurations include specifying channel names, ports, whether SSL is used, and the appropriate settings for using SOCKS5 proxies when connecting over Tor. This comprehensive approach to configuring communication channels underscores the system's emphasis on security, anonymity, and flexibility in peer discovery and messaging within the network.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-17T19:27:30.806000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
