<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DoS Disclosure: LND Onion Bomb</title>
  <updated>2024-06-19T02:10:00.999571+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2024-06-18 17:48:35.668000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DoS Disclosure: LND Onion Bomb</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T02:10:00.999601+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dos-disclosure-lnd-onion-bomb/979" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Lightning Network Daemon (LND) versions earlier than 0.17.0 have been identified as vulnerable to a Denial of Service (DoS) attack that can lead to an out-of-memory (OOM) condition, causing the affected node to crash. This vulnerability stems from LND's handling of onion payloads, where there was no proper bounds checking on the decoded length of these payloads. Malicious actors could exploit this by setting the payload length to up to 4 GB, prompting LND to allocate corresponding memory for decoding, which could quickly exhaust the system's available memory and crash the node. The nature of onion routing makes it easy to conceal the source of such attacks, adding to the risk.

To mitigate this issue and safeguard nodes against potential exploitation, it is crucial for operators of LND nodes running versions older than 0.17.0 to update their software to version 0.17.0 or later. The updated version introduces a bounds check for onion payload lengths, effectively preventing the allocation of excessive memory and protecting nodes from the described DoS attack. For detailed information about the vulnerability, its implications, and further technical details, interested parties are encouraged to consult the comprehensive [blog post](https://morehouse.github.io/lightning/lnd-onion-bomb/) dedicated to this topic. This source offers an in-depth exploration of the root causes and preventive measures related to the vulnerability.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-18T17:48:35.668000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
