<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
  <updated>2024-06-26T02:02:31.488132+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-06-25 19:29:50.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T02:02:31.488161+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/estimating-likelihood-for-lightning-payments-to-be-in-feasible/973/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of incorporating advanced analytical capabilities into user and business software is a noteworthy development, specifically focusing on the management of cryptocurrency transactions. The scenario involving "Businessperson Bob" underscores the potential for node management software to significantly enhance operational efficiency in handling Bitcoin transactions. By regularly calculating the average likelihood of successful transactions (up to 0.05 BTC) across the network, and assessing current liquidity advertisements for potential new channels, this software can autonomously optimize financial operations. This proactive approach not only streamlines transactions but also ensures that businesses remain agile in their financial dealings, adapting to network changes by opening new, more feasible channels when beneficial.

On the other hand, the use case involving "User Alice" illustrates how individual users could benefit from smarter wallet configurations, particularly for recurring payments like monthly bills. By setting the wallet to initiate payment attempts well before the due date and employing a strategic retry logic based on the feasibility of transaction completion, users are afforded a blend of automation and manual oversight. This system mitigates the risk of failed transactions by dynamically adjusting retry intervals, thereby enhancing the reliability of digital currency transactions for regular users. 

Both examples collectively highlight a future where software not only acts on pre-defined instructions but also intelligently assesses network conditions to make informed decisions. This represents a shift towards more autonomous, adaptive financial technologies that can potentially reduce transaction failure rates, improve liquidity management, and personalize the user experience based on real-time network data analysis.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-25T19:29:50.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
