<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
  <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:35.602506+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-06-26 11:28:27.175000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
    <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:35.602540+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blip-bolt-11-invoice-blinded-path-tagged-field/991/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion brings up the consideration of integrating Bolt 12 invoices directly for transactions, bypassing the traditional offer/invoice_request flow observed with Bolt 11. This approach suggests a streamlined method for handling transactions where both the payer and recipient would need to adapt their systems to accommodate the new extension. By doing so, it emphasizes on the adoption of a process that not only simplifies the payment procedure but also sets a foundation for supporting the comprehensive functionalities of Bolt 12 in future developments.

This idea reflects on the efficiency and potential foresight in preparing for the broader implementation of Bolt 12. It presents an opportunity for stakeholders within the transaction process to align their systems with emerging standards, ensuring they are ahead in adopting innovations that promise enhanced operability and user experience. The suggestion implicitly advocates for a shift towards more advanced protocols that can seamlessly integrate into existing frameworks while offering improved transactional capabilities.

Moreover, this proposition underlines the importance of forward-thinking in the development and support of payment systems. It proposes a pragmatic step towards embracing newer technologies by recommending an incremental adaptation, which could mitigate the challenges associated with transitioning to entirely new systems. Such a strategic approach not only facilitates smoother integration but also encourages widespread acceptance and utilization of newer standards, contributing to the evolution of digital payment infrastructures.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-26T11:28:27.175000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
