<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
  <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:14.971383+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-26T22:49:49.832000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
    <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:14.971420+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blip-bolt-11-invoice-blinded-path-tagged-field/991/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the possibility and implications of adopting a new encoding format for BOLT 12 invoices, separate from the current formats used within the Bitcoin Lightning Network. Initially, there was resistance to introducing another format due to concerns about increasing complexity with an additional format alongside BOLT 11 and BOLT 12 Offers. However, recent discussions suggest a reconsideration of this stance, particularly in light of feedback highlighting a reluctance to publicly expose a BOLT 12 invoice format. The suggestion now is to decouple the BOLT 12 invoice format from Offers, allowing for its independent use and adoption, potentially attracting those currently using LN Address/LN-URL with the newer format.

The proposal includes separating the BOLT 12 invoice specifications from the broader Offers specification, specifying that certain fields must be present in an invoice if it originates from an offer, leveraging the TLV (Type-Length-Value) structure for flexibility. This separation could facilitate the adoption of the BOLT 12 format without necessarily binding it to the Offers framework, addressing some of the initial concerns regarding format proliferation.

Moreover, the consideration extends to whether diverting resources to develop this decoupled invoice format is justified, especially when most efforts are focused on completing the remaining aspects of Offers. There's an acknowledgment that finalizing Offers remains a priority, but the discussion opens the door to possibly exploring the BOLT 12 invoice format as a future endeavor, without impeding current priorities.

Additionally, the potential for programmatic applications such as the L402 protocol or sub-swap services like Loop to leverage extensions for blinded paths is highlighted. Blinded paths offer significant advantages, such as allowing receivers to influence the routing of payments to optimize for lower fees or higher reliability. This aspect underlines the broader utility and versatility of adopting new formats or extensions beyond user-facing features, emphasizing their potential impact on enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of payment routing within the network.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-26T22:49:49.832000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
