<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
  <updated>2024-06-29T02:02:00.607662+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-28T08:03:21.279000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
    <updated>2024-06-29T02:02:00.607691+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blip-bolt-11-invoice-blinded-path-tagged-field/991/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the implementation and user experience aspects of bLIPs (Bitcoin Improvement Proposals) within the context of payment protocols in eclair or lightning-kmp, specifically focusing on the handling of encoded Offers compared to BOLT11 invoices. Currently, when an encoded Offer is scanned by Phoenix/Eclair, it triggers a payment UI similar to that for an encoded invoice, where users can specify an amount and add a note for the recipient before initiating the payment. This process involves fetching the invoice as the initial step, a detail that remains abstracted from the user to simplify the experience.

Regarding the transition to exclusively using Offers for payments, the conversation touches upon the necessity for wallet developers to support both BOLT11 invoices and Offers during the interim period. However, there's a projection that in the future, with universal support for Bolt 12, wallets will predominantly utilize offers for receiving payments. A significant shift in user experience is anticipated, moving away from the current QR code-based identification to using DNS address formats, which promises a more streamlined approach by merely requiring the recipient's identifier. Despite this evolution, there remains a commitment to maintain compatibility with BOLT11 invoices for specific scenarios like online merchant transactions, suggesting no significant code alterations are required for this continued support.

Additionally, the dialogue distinguishes between the concerns of blinded paths and the encoding/presentation layer, highlighting that any association between them and Offers is largely due to the way protocols have been packaged together based on prevailing opinions rather than a technical necessity. This differentiation emphasizes the independence of core components from the representation layer, underlining the nuanced considerations involved in protocol development and implementation strategies.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-28T08:03:21.279000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
