<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-30T02:09:32.016170+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-06-29T21:00:11.488000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-30T02:09:32.016203+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent feedback on the Partially Signed Bitcoin Transaction (PSBT) draft suggests a strategic shift in how Discrete Logarithm Equality (DLEQ) proofs are handled within Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs). This recommendation has led to the creation of a new draft that aims to separate DLEQ proofs into their own distinct BIP, a move inspired by existing work found in a gist by RubenSomsen. The draft crafted from this inspiration is accessible for review and contribution at [this link](https://gist.github.com/andrewtoth/df97c3260cc8d12f09d3855ee61322ea).

This action was taken to ensure clarity and focus within the PSBT draft, allowing each proposal to concentrate on its specific domain without overlapping functionalities or causing confusion among developers and users alike. The separation indicates a thoughtful approach to organizing Bitcoin's evolving technical frameworks, ensuring each component is given appropriate attention and development space.

The initiative to create a standalone BIP for DLEQ proofs underscores the importance of specialized topics within the Bitcoin protocol needing dedicated discussion and refinement. It opens the door for more targeted feedback and contributions from the community, facilitating a more streamlined and efficient advancement of Bitcoin's technical infrastructure. The invitation for thoughts and contributions on the newly created draft highlights an inclusive approach to decision-making within the Bitcoin development ecosystem, encouraging a collaborative effort towards innovation and improvement.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T21:00:11.488000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
