<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-02-14T02:19:49.855593+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xfffffffa 2025-02-13 08:39:33.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-10 18:01:14.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xfffffffa  . 2025-02-10 15:37:09.807000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2025-01-11 22:13:01.683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2025-01-02 19:14:16.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-10-22 19:51:57.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4293_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4270_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4266_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4037_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3922_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3397_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-02-14T02:19:49.855662+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing Bitcoin's security against potential quantum computing threats has led to the development of an innovative Layer 2 (L2) solution, termed BitcoinQS. This system is designed to operate independently from Bitcoin's primary network (Layer 1 or L1), aiming to serve as a robust backup in the event that quantum computers compromise the security of the L1 blockchain. The foundational technology behind BitcoinQS incorporates ML-DSA/Dilithium for cryptographic operations, marking a significant step towards achieving quantum resistance. By providing a seamless mechanism for converting L1 Bitcoin into Quantum Wrapped Bitcoin (BQS) and vice versa, BitcoinQS ensures that users can transition their assets between layers without facing discrepancies in value. This approach was chosen over traditional Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) due to the latter's extensive timelines for acceptance and implementation.

BitcoinQS stands out not only for its quantum-resistant features but also for its non-custodial nature, allowing users full control over their keys. Transactions are signed within the user’s browser and then verified by validators, reinforcing the platform's commitment to security and autonomy. The testnet phase currently supports a block size of two transactions, with these transactions subsequently hashed and documented on the L1 Bitcoin blockchain. Future plans include expanding the platform to support BRC20 tokens and smart contracts, signaling ambitious goals for enhancing digital asset management within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The project invites collaboration and has shared contact information for interested parties.

In parallel discussions, there's a focus on evolving cryptographic standards to mitigate quantum threats, with particular attention to post-quantum cryptography. Despite advancements, recent incidents where cryptographic algorithms were compromised underscore the ongoing vulnerability and the need for continuous scrutiny. One proposal under consideration involves disabling key-spending on P2TR addresses and leveraging `OP_SUCCESS` opcodes for validating post-quantum signatures, a method suggested by Matt Corallo. This proposition aligns with efforts to maintain the space-saving benefits of taproot while exploring hash-based signatures like Compact WOTS+C for enhanced efficiency and security. Achieving consensus on the preferred method, developing a reference implementation, and drafting a BIP for community feedback are outlined as critical steps forward.

Furthermore, the conversation acknowledges the importance of a cautious approach in integrating new algorithms into high assurance products, resonating with Adam Back's perspective on the matter. Flexibility in updating BIP-360 to incorporate different methodologies, including DASK for hybrid cryptography, highlights a strategic shift towards accommodating diverse signature types alongside secp256k1 keys. This dialogue also touches upon operational consistency challenges between clients and nodes in validating signatures under the proposed model.

An overarching theme in these discussions is the proactive stance towards quantum resistance in blockchain technology, emphasizing the necessity of preparing for future quantum computing capabilities. A proposed strategy involves utilizing a hash-based signature algorithm (HBS) for deriving secret keys, which could later endorse another post-quantum signing key if needed. This approach suggests a gradual transition to quantum-resistant keys without immediate consensus changes, relying on client-side adaptations until such a shift becomes imperative due to quantum advancements.

The document detailing these proposals and discussions is continuously updated, with the latest version accessible online. This evolving work underscores the dynamic nature of blockchain technology and cryptography, inviting ongoing contributions and reviews from the community to refine and advance the proposals aimed at safeguarding Bitcoin against quantum threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-13T08:39:33.912000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
