<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
  <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:55.166389+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-06-26 22:49:49.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ellemouton 2024-06-26 19:27:03.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-06-26 11:28:27.175000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ellemouton  . 2024-06-26 00:10:57.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2809_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2808_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2803_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2791_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
    <updated>2024-06-27T02:03:55.166440+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blip-bolt-11-invoice-blinded-path-tagged-field/991/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discussions and proposals within the Bitcoin Lightning Network community are focused on enhancing privacy and reliability of payment delivery. One such proposal is a Bitcoin Lightning Improvement Proposal (bLIP) that introduces a new tagged field for BOLT 11 payment invoices, aimed at enabling encoded blinded path information to be communicated to payers. This initiative seeks to leverage the benefits of route blinding, as detailed in the BOLT 4 specification, prior to the full adoption of the more extensive changes suggested by the Offers proposal, which includes features like onion messaging requiring significant network upgrades.

The core of this proposal is the addition of a `bolt11_blinded_path` feature bit within the experimental range, signaling support and understanding of the new tagged field. The proposed structure for this field heavily borrows from encoding techniques outlined in the Offers proposal, including various data points such as fee rates, CLTV expiry deltas, and a series of encrypted elements that create private payment routes. The document carefully considers backward compatibility with existing BOLT 11 invoice readers, allowing for unknown fields to be skipped and facilitating the continued processing of invoices with the new tagged field.

Furthermore, the proposal serves as an interim solution, anticipating its own obsolescence with the broader adoption of the Offers protocol and its associated invoice format. It outlines technical specifications and operational considerations necessary for implementing blinded paths, including restrictions on the number of hops in a path due to size limitations related to `data_length` encoding and QR code capacity.

In addition to providing a detailed example of how the new field can accommodate multiple blinded paths within identified constraints, the proposal invites feedback on several unresolved questions. These include optimizing space within the invoice structure, enhancing the security and integrity of the invoice signing process, and methods for conveying maximum CLTV expiry values. The discussion also touches upon the simplification of introduction nodes within blinded paths and the implications of introducing an experimental tagged field range specifically for BOLT 11 in anticipation of its eventual phase-out.

The dialogue surrounding the possibility of decoupling the Bolt 12 _invoice_ format from Offers itself has been revisited, considering the integration of new encoding formats and the reception of such ideas within the developer community. Despite previous pushback against introducing another format, there's an acknowledgment of the potential benefits of extracting the BOLT 12 invoice format from the greater specification to facilitate its adoption. This suggests a dual approach where both the continuation of BOLT 11 enhancements and the future extraction of the BOLT 12 invoice format are considered viable paths forward. The importance of this development is underscored by the interest in using BOLT 11 extensions for programmatic flows, such as the L402 protocol or sub-swap services like Loop, which could benefit from the privacy and efficiency gains offered by blinded paths.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-26T22:49:49.832000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
