<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:09:45.839402+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2024-06-03 22:30:05.772000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-06-03 21:33:46.546000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-03 20:02:00.662000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-06-03 19:53:06.670000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2024-06-03 19:40:34.364000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-03 17:21:52.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2622_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2621_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2619_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2618_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2617_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2614_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:09:45.839464+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion surrounding the size of Bitcoin's block space has been a contentious subject within the cryptocurrency community. There is a broad recognition of the need to increase demand for block space through various efforts, yet it's acknowledged that predicting the impact of changing the block size on fees and the fee market is exceptionally challenging. The conversation about expanding block size capacity is seen as necessary, with an emphasis on approaching it openly and honestly to address potential solutions and their accompanying costs. It's highlighted that simply doubling the block size might not directly translate to halving transaction fees due to the perfectly inelastic supply of Bitcoin's block space and the complexity of user demand elasticity. The example provided illustrates how minor increases to the block size could potentially eliminate the entire fee market under certain conditions, suggesting that changes aimed at adjusting the elasticity of block supply might be more beneficial than adjustments to supply alone.

Another perspective argues against increasing the block size, advocating instead for a reduction. This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of the Lightning network and low-resource hardware in the ecosystem, citing a presentation ([see video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CqNEQS80-h4)) that supports the argument for smaller blocks as being beneficial.

The debate also touches on Bitcoin's ambition to become a global currency, facing a future where daily transactions could massively exceed its current capacity, leading to significant transaction backlogs and possibly rendering small transactions economically unviable. The current state of blockspace demand, which may not sustain long-term, adds to the complexity of this issue.

Critics of the current small-block philosophy highlight several contradictions and problems, such as the prioritization of node operation costs over transaction costs, the impact on decentralization, and the overall accessibility of Bitcoin. They argue for a reevaluation of the optimum block size that balances revenue for miners, accessibility for users, and the functionality of additional layers like Lightning. Suggested analyses include the implications of different block sizes on the network and its users, proposing sizes significantly larger than the current limit.

Furthermore, there are calls for a reconsideration of Bitcoin's development direction, questioning the sustainability of high transaction fees, the practicality of universal full node operation, and the centralized control over Bitcoin's protocol specifications. These discussions reflect a broader concern for Bitcoin's role as a tool for human rights and individual freedom, challenging the notion that its base layer should primarily serve large institutions and governments. The dialogue underscores a desire to align Bitcoin's evolution with principles of freedom and inclusivity, advocating for a system that enables widespread participation and self-custody.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T22:30:05.772000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
