<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-19T02:08:45.835094+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>real-or-random 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T02:08:45.835169+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The JoinMarket messaging protocol is integral for secure and private Bitcoin transactions in a decentralized manner, as it facilitates communication within the JoinMarket ecosystem without relying on centralized authorities. This system enhances the privacy, liquidity, and fungibility of Bitcoin through peer-to-peer coinjoin transactions. The protocol employs encrypted communication channels to ensure the security of messages between participants, covering transaction creation, error handling, and payment management. Detailed documentation on GitHub provides insights into message formats, cryptographic techniques, and communication sequences, serving as a valuable resource for developers and users interested in contributing to or utilizing the JoinMarket platform.

The communication infrastructure combines directory nodes, Internet Relay Chat (IRC), and Onion services to enable peer discovery and interaction. It mandates specific configurations for onion-based messaging channels and details the process for setting up directory nodes and managing Tor control configurations. This meticulous approach emphasizes the importance of security, anonymity, and flexibility in the network's operation. Moreover, the configuration guidelines highlight the system's reliance on correctly setting parameters to maintain operational integrity and the emphasis on using Tor for IRC communications to preserve user anonymity.

JoinMarket with Jam represents a shift towards a more decentralized method of managing transactions without a central coordinator, despite the lack of detailed technical information on its underlying technology. On the other hand, joinstr.xyz offers an accessible alternative leveraging nostr relays for peer communication, diverging from traditional coinjoin mechanisms by facilitating the public dissemination of pool information and encrypted exchange of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT).

Recent regulatory actions have impacted non-custodial privacy tools like Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet, prompting the community to explore alternatives such as the [BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin](https://docs.btcpayserver.org/Wabisabi/installation). This plugin adapts the WabiSabi protocol for users to host their own coordinator services, enhancing transaction privacy while making coordinators discoverable via Nostr relay. The closures of Samourai and Wasabi's coordinator servers have spurred speculation about the future of Bitcoin privacy techniques, pondering the emergence of decentralized networks of BTCPay coordinators or increased attraction to solutions like JoinMarket.

In summary, the landscape of cryptocurrency privacy and security is undergoing significant changes, driven by technological advancements, regulatory actions, and community responses. While challenges remain in achieving decentralized, secure, and private transactions, ongoing developments in protocols like JoinMarket and innovations such as the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin suggest a resilient and evolving ecosystem poised to address these issues.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-18T12:45:46.196000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
