<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
  <updated>2024-06-28T02:03:29.202440+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-06-27 20:53:27.553000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-06-27 07:06:39.378000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-06-26 22:49:49.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ellemouton  . 2024-06-26 19:27:03.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-06-26 11:28:27.175000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ellemouton  . 2024-06-26 00:10:57.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2813_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2810_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2809_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2808_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2803_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2791_bLIP-BOLT-11-Invoice-Blinded-Path-Tagged-Field.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - bLIP: BOLT 11 Invoice Blinded Path Tagged Field</title>
    <updated>2024-06-28T02:03:29.202531+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/blip-bolt-11-invoice-blinded-path-tagged-field/991/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion primarily focuses on the development and implications of adopting new encoding formats for invoices within the Bitcoin Lightning Network, specifically the consideration between continuing with BOLT 11 invoices with added features versus introducing BOLT 12 invoices. A significant point of debate is whether to incorporate blinded paths into BOLT 11 invoices or to fully embrace BOLT 12 invoices, which would necessitate less coding effort and fewer modifications to existing specifications. The use of blinded paths is seen as a way to enhance the Offers flow, making it more robust by gaining experience with these paths, identifying edge cases, and implementing new pathfinding solutions from the receiver's end. This approach is favored over introducing partial, unrefined components that could extend the deployment timeline and potentially degrade user experience.

The potential benefits of integrating blinded paths into existing protocols like BOLT 11 are contrasted against the adoption of a new, separate invoice format under BOLT 12. Concerns about complicating the ecosystem with multiple invoice formats have led to a reconsideration of exposing BOLT 12 invoices independently. However, it is suggested that separating BOLT 12 invoice specifications from Offers could facilitate their adoption without necessarily complicating the current system. Such separation would allow for flexibility in specifying mandatory fields when an invoice originates from an offer, using the TLV structure for versatility. This adjustment aims to streamline the process, making it more accessible and possibly paving the way for wider acceptance and use of BOLT 12 invoices alongside traditional offerings.

Moreover, the dialogue touches upon the strategic advantage of building upon the bolt 11 protocol by incorporating new features directly into it. This ensures backward compatibility and leverages its widespread adoption to improve user experience by providing informative error messages for unrecognized features. This method contrasts with introducing an entirely new format, which could lead to greater confusion among users unfamiliar with the changes.

Furthermore, there's an exploration of how Bolt 12 invoices could be directly used for transactions, bypassing the conventional offer/invoice request flow associated with Bolt 11. This streamlined approach suggests an efficient method for handling transactions that necessitates adaptation from both payers and recipients, highlighting a forward-thinking strategy in supporting the comprehensive functionalities of Bolt 12 in future developments.

Additionally, the discussion introduces a Bitcoin Lightning Improvement Proposal (bLIP) aimed at enhancing privacy and reliability in lightning payment delivery through a new tagged field for BOLT 11 payment invoices, indicating encoded blinded path information. This proposed improvement seeks to leverage route blinding benefits immediately without awaiting the complete adoption of the Offers framework, which encompasses more extensive network upgrades. The proposal outlines technical specifications, compatibility considerations, and transition strategies, emphasizing this feature as an interim solution pending the broader implementation of Offers and its associated invoice format.

In summary, the conversation encapsulates a complex balance between advancing the Bitcoin Lightning Network's functionality through new features and formats while maintaining usability and backward compatibility. It reflects a broader dialogue within the community about the best paths forward in terms of technological adoption, user experience, and the strategic development of the network's payment protocols.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-27T20:53:27.553000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
