<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-03T02:08:05.012015+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>conduition 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-03T02:08:05.012075+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The cryptocurrency community is witnessing significant changes in the landscape of privacy tools, especially concerning coin mixing services. The recent regulatory actions have led to the shutdown of coordinator servers for well-known services like Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet, which previously facilitated CoinJoin transactions that enhanced users' anonymity. This development has spurred interest in alternatives that do not rely on centralized coordinators. Among these, JoinMarket has emerged with a new interface called Jam, which, while eliminating the need for a central coordinator, presents a more complex setup process compared to traditional wallets. Another notable solution is joinstr.xyz, which leverages existing nostr relays for peer communication, thus avoiding the need for a dedicated coordinator but still maintaining the functionality necessary for coin mixing.

The regulatory crackdown on non-custodial privacy tools underscores a growing challenge within the cryptocurrency ecosystem—maintaining transaction privacy without relying on centralized services that are vulnerable to shutdowns or external pressures. This scenario has catalyzed the exploration of decentralized alternatives and innovations such as the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin. This plugin adopts the open WabiSabi protocol, allowing users to establish their own coordinator services and advertise them via Nostr relay, facilitating discovery by other wallets that support WabiSabi. Such developments not only offer resilience against regulatory pressures but also empower users to take charge of their privacy needs.

However, the transition towards decentralized privacy tools is not without its challenges. New coordinators, for instance, face the issue of attracting enough participants to ensure a robust anonymity set. This problem is exacerbated by the lack of seamless integration within existing wallets, which could guide users towards these alternative coordinators. Moreover, certain wallets have yet to implement features that enable users to switch between coordinator services easily.

Amidst these developments, the potential for future enhancements in privacy technology remains significant. Pointed out is the prospect of using Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT) and Payment Point Lightning Invoices (PTLCs) to further enhance privacy. PTLCs, in particular, hold promise for disrupting traditional payment hash correlation methods, thereby improving the privacy of payment routing. Additionally, the concept of ecash as a means for off-chain coin mixing through routed LN payments across multiple mints presents an intriguing albeit currently impractical solution due to the limited pool of money in any given ecash mint.

In conclusion, the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency privacy tools reflects both the challenges and opportunities presented by regulatory pressures and technological advancements. As the community explores decentralized alternatives and innovations in privacy-enhancing technologies, the future of transaction privacy in cryptocurrencies appears poised for significant transformation.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-02T22:18:52.919000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
