<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-21T02:04:14.927280+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-20 20:29:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake 2024-06-20 09:21:52.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-18 15:50:41.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-18 13:10:57.761000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2773_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2771_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2741_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2740_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T02:04:14.927430+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the intricacies of incorporating silent payments within the framework of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT), highlighting a broad spectrum of technical considerations and proposed enhancements aimed at bolstering privacy and security in cryptocurrency transactions. At the heart of this conversation is the challenge of handling silent payment outputs, necessitating meticulous attention to cryptographic details and transaction integrity to ensure seamless integration into the PSBT structure.

A critical aspect discussed is the necessity for signers to exercise caution when utilizing signature hash types, particularly avoiding `ALL | ACP` in the context of silent payments to maintain transaction privacy and integrity. The dialogue underscores the importance of signers verifying consistent output scripts across transactions, spotlighting the potential vulnerabilities associated with the `ANYONECANPAY` flag and its implications for transaction security. This consideration is paramount in scenarios where inputs might be modified post-signature, raising concerns about the robustness of transactions involving silent payments.

Further elaboration reveals proposals aimed at optimizing the efficiency and security of transactions by suggesting modifications to global fields within the PSBT framework. These proposals include the introduction of new fields tailored to support silent payments, such as `PSBT_IN_SP_ECDH_SHARE` and `PSBT_OUT_SP_V0_INFO`, which facilitate the secure management of ECDH shares and proofs crucial for maintaining the confidentiality of transaction outputs. Moreover, the conversation delves into the potential of streamlining the verification process by consolidating proofs, thereby reducing the computational burden on participants and enhancing the overall efficiency of the system.

Additionally, the discourse explores the conceptual shift towards employing an "ECDH share" technique, which could offer a more secure alternative to direct private key access by output generators. This approach, while promising in theory, is met with caution due to unverified security implications, particularly the response of signing devices to Diffie-Hellman requests. Such discussions indicate a proactive pursuit of innovative solutions to enhance transactional privacy without compromising security.

Notably, the conversation also addresses practical challenges in implementing silent payments, from the complexities of managing input and output dependencies to the nuances of tweaking spend keys for transaction signing. These discussions are enriched by references to ongoing work and proposals, such as a draft BIP by delvingless and andrewtoth, offering a glimpse into the collaborative efforts underway to refine the integration of silent payments into the PSBT protocol.

In summary, the discourse encapsulates a comprehensive exploration of strategies and challenges surrounding the integration of silent payments into PSBTs. It highlights the community's commitment to advancing cryptocurrency privacy and security through meticulous technical scrutiny and innovative cryptographic solutions. The conversation not only underscores the complexity of achieving seamless integration but also reflects the dynamic nature of collaborative problem-solving within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T20:29:14.700000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
