<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:08:59.523803+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-06-05 00:38:14.440000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2024-06-04 18:05:14.401000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-06-04 17:58:57.055000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:44:53.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:42:57.357000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-06-04 17:38:17.336000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2024-06-04 17:36:52.454000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:34:28.649000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2024-06-04 17:25:46.778000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:03:50.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles 2024-06-04 17:00:31.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2024-06-04 16:38:28.909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>shocknet_justin 2024-06-04 15:35:40.240000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth 2024-06-04 03:23:58.250000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-06-03 22:30:05.772000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-06-03 21:33:46.546000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles  . 2024-06-03 20:02:00.662000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-06-03 19:53:06.670000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth  . 2024-06-03 19:40:34.364000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>myles  . 2024-06-03 17:21:52.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2648_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2646_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2645_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2644_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2643_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2642_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2641_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2640_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2639_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2638_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2637_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2636_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2630_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2623_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2622_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2621_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2619_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2618_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2617_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2614_Is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Is it time to increase the blocksize cap?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:08:59.523936+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-it-time-to-increase-the-blocksize-cap/941/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse surrounding Bitcoin's philosophical underpinnings and its technological limitations delves into the intricate balance between ideals and practical constraints. At the heart of the discussion is the aspiration to make Bitcoin a universally accessible currency, enabling even those living on as little as $5 per week in Ethiopia to engage with the digital currency independently. However, this noble goal encounters significant hurdles related to the scalability of the Bitcoin blockchain, particularly when it comes to ensuring access to scalable bitcoin blockchain verification for self-custodied bitcoins. The absence of a scalable Chain-state Delivery Network akin to an SPV further complicates the process, indicating that while there are numerous self-custody solutions available, sophisticated spending policies introduce a new set of challenges such as maintaining just-in-time fees reserves, constant monitoring, and secure backups.

The debate extends to the Lightning Network, regarded as a clunky yet currently best-available scaling solution despite its limitations. Comparisons are drawn with vehicles like the Trabant to underline its inefficiency, alongside mentions of emerging technologies like CoinPool which promise future improvements but require extensive consensus changes. There's a realistic projection of achieving 50 to 70 million channels on lightning within five years, though this falls short of global needs, highlighting the necessity for more intelligent automated liquidity management to keep on-chain fees affordable for end users.

Contrasting viewpoints on block size present a contentious landscape where opinions diverge on the benefits of increasing versus decreasing block sizes. Some argue that reducing block sizes could enhance network efficiency and accessibility, citing [a video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CqNEQS80-h4) that outlines the potential benefits of such a move. This perspective emphasizes the importance of sustainable and inclusive scalability solutions over simply expanding block capacity, questioning the long-term viability of Bitcoin's foundational goal against the backdrop of its current technological capabilities and market dynamics.

The conversation also touches upon the economic and technical dimensions of Bitcoin's scalability challenges. It scrutinizes the stability of transaction fees and the implications of block size adjustments on the fee market and node operation costs. The dialogue calls for a departure from dismissive attitudes towards changing block space dynamics, advocating for a more analytical approach to scalability and economic models within the Bitcoin ecosystem. This includes a reevaluation of past stances during the "blocksize war," suggesting a more nuanced debate about the potential impacts of block size changes on the broader network and its users.

In summary, the discussion encapsulates a range of perspectives on Bitcoin's scalability, from philosophical aspirations to technical constraints and economic considerations. It underscores the complexity of balancing ideological goals with practical realities, pointing to the need for ongoing dialogue and innovation to address the challenges facing Bitcoin as it strives to fulfill its potential as a decentralized, universally accessible form of "freedom money."</summary>
    <published>2024-06-05T00:38:14.440000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
