<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-22T04:35:42.753287+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josibake 2024-06-21 14:07:17.974000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-21 13:41:15.741000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake 2024-06-21 13:15:06.505000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-20 20:29:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-20 09:21:52.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-18 15:50:41.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-18 13:10:57.761000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2778_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2777_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2776_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2773_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2771_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2741_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2740_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T04:35:42.753486+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/27" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the intricacies of implementing secure cryptocurrency transactions, specifically focusing on silent payments and the challenges associated with the `ANYONECANPAY` signature flag. The exchange begins with an analysis of security vulnerabilities that arise when using the `SINGLE | ACP` flag for signing transactions. It is highlighted that this method introduces potential risks, as external observers could manipulate the transaction by altering inputs, potentially redirecting funds. The conversation underscores the importance of ensuring transaction integrity by avoiding the use of `ACP` in scenarios where trust among signers is not absolute.

Further, the discourse explores various technical strategies to optimize silent payment transactions within the Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT) framework. A key point is the requirement for signers aware of silent payments to meticulously check for `ACP` flags on inputs they intend to sign and to ensure no silent payment outputs are present unless all conditions are met. This precaution is crucial for maintaining the confidentiality and integrity of the transaction. Additionally, the dialogue suggests modifications to the PSBT structure to include global fields for shares and proofs, aiming to streamline the verification process and reduce computational overhead for signers. This proposal acknowledges the trade-offs between processing efficiency and memory requirements, suggesting a nuanced approach depending on the signer's computational capabilities.

In addressing the technical execution of silent payment transactions, the conversation highlights the need for precise management of input signatures and output scripts. One proposed solution involves leveraging shared secrets and proofs to generate consistent output scripts across different signers, ensuring the transaction remains intact regardless of input modifications. This approach requires careful consideration of the data structure within the PSBT to accommodate these cryptographic elements efficiently.

Moreover, the discussion touches upon the broader implications for the Bitcoin network, particularly regarding the integration of silent payment features into the BIP174 standard. It proposes adding specific fields to support the silent payment mechanism, such as `PSBT_IN_SP_ECDH_SHARE` and `PSBT_OUT_SP_V0_INFO`, without necessitating a new version of the PSBT format. These additions aim to facilitate the seamless inclusion of silent payment transactions, enhancing privacy without compromising the existing infrastructure.

The exchange also contemplates the practical aspects of implementing these proposals, considering the operational complexities and potential security concerns. The notion of introducing an `OutputGenerator` role is discussed, alongside the possibilities for optimizing the handling of cryptographic proofs. The dialogue advocates for a cautious yet innovative approach to evolving the PSBT standard, emphasizing the importance of security, efficiency, and backward compatibility in fostering advancements in cryptocurrency transactions.

Lastly, the conversation encapsulates the collaborative effort required to address the challenges of silent payment transactions, from the technical nuances of PSBT enhancements to the overarching goal of improving transaction privacy. The discourse reflects a deep engagement with the subject matter, proposing thoughtful solutions while acknowledging the inherent complexities and trade-offs involved in advancing cryptocurrency technologies.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T14:07:17.974000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
