<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:04:30.547527+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:04:30.547607+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The excitement around joinstr, a novel protocol for decentralized coordination in cryptocurrency transactions, is growing due to its potential to offer an innovative alternative to centralized coordinators. Despite its promise, joinstr faces significant challenges, such as threading issues that hinder its immediate deployment on the mainnet, as detailed on its [GitLab page](https://gitlab.com/1440000bytes/joinstr/-/issues/7). Meanwhile, ecash emerges as a viable contender in the realm of digital transaction privacy and security, especially for smaller-scale off-chain coin mixing. Its application involves routing Lightning Network payments through various mints to obscure transaction trails by diversifying payment hashes/preimages, alongside strategies like TOR usage and timing transfers strategically to avoid network-level analysis. However, the limited funds within ecash mints pose a challenge to this approach, potentially making transaction patterns identifiable.

An engaging discussion highlights the integration of ecash with coinjoin, proposing a complementary relationship rather than viewing them as mutually exclusive solutions. This discourse emphasizes the complexity of enhancing bitcoin privacy, suggesting a multifaceted approach involving various tools and techniques to improve security and anonymity. The integration of Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs) into the Lightning Network is anticipated to address vulnerabilities related to payment-hash correlation, offering a promising method for enhancing cryptocurrency anonymization through the use of submarine swaps.

JoinMarket with Jam presents an improved user experience for cryptocurrency transactions without requiring a central coordinator. Despite its enhanced interface, it demands a more complex setup process compared to other options. On another front, [joinstr.xyz](https://joinstr.xyz) offers an accessible alternative by leveraging existing nostr relays for peer communication, highlighting a departure from traditional coinjoin mechanisms. The closure of coordinator servers for Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet marks a significant shift in the Bitcoin privacy service landscape, prompting the search for alternatives like JoinMarket and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin, which uses the WabiSabi protocol to allow users to host their own coordinator services. This development suggests a potential shift towards decentralized networks of BTCPay Coordinators, indicating an evolving landscape in response to regulatory pressures and the quest for enhanced privacy in cryptocurrency transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T16:00:23.138000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
