<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:03:36.761624+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria 2024-06-04 20:21:55.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-06-04 13:47:41.528000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-06-03 17:16:36.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-02 21:08:52.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-31 20:13:43.809000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-24 13:07:52.580000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2647_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2625_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2615_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2604_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2591_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2530_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:03:36.761881+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on the tradability of pool shares within cryptocurrency mining operations, particularly through a centralized pool using e-cash, unfolds a complex landscape that merges financial mechanisms with blockchain technology. The introduction of tradable shares, as discussed, is not merely a financial innovation but also a strategic response to the limitations faced by smaller miners in terms of receiving payouts. Braidpool's model, which restricts direct payouts to the top miners and proposes trading shares for those with lesser hash power, illustrates an attempt to democratize financial benefits across the mining community. This method points towards a broader objective beyond facilitating efficient payouts – it aims to create a market dynamic where shares can be traded, potentially enhancing liquidity for miners at all levels of participation.

Within this framework, the critique centers around the proposal's complexity and its deviation from straightforward payout mechanisms like direct withdrawals through e-cash or lightning networks. The argument posits that while the intent to innovate is clear, the means through which it seeks to achieve its goals may introduce unnecessary complications. The essence of the proposal appears to align more closely with creating a vibrant market for pool shares rather than simplifying the payout process. Such an approach, albeit ambitious, raises questions about its practicality and the added value it brings to the mining ecosystem.

The conversation seamlessly transitions into discussing the technical aspects of cryptographic attestation and its role in ensuring the integrity of transactions within this proposed system. Cryptographic attestation offers a layer of security and trust, enabling verification of shares' authenticity without complicating the core functionality of existing protocols. This aspect underscores the proposal's focus on maintaining robust security measures alongside its innovative payout mechanism. Additionally, the thematic exploration of electronic cash (ecash) transactions emphasizes the critical need for prompt redemption processes to mitigate risks associated with double-spending. This point is pivotal in understanding the operational nuances of ecash within the proposed mining framework, highlighting the importance of timely and secure transactions.

Further, the dialogue delves into the conceptual underpinnings of digital asset management, specifically the handling and redemption of ehashes. The mint's role in tracking ownership changes and the conditional redemption based on the share window period reveal a sophisticated approach to managing digital assets. This system, designed to ensure accurate tracking and valuation of shares, reflects a deep consideration of the complexities involved in digital currency transactions and asset management.

The overarching theme revolves around the integration of privacy-centric mechanisms into the payout process, aiming to enhance the security and discretion of financial transactions within the mining pool ecosystem. Despite the inherent complexities, the pursuit of privacy emerges as a commendable goal, driving the proposal's development. However, the discussion acknowledges the challenges and potential overcomplications introduced by the proposed methodologies, suggesting a reevaluation of the balance between innovation and practical utility.

In summary, the discourse encapsulates a multifaceted examination of the proposed trading of pool shares, cryptographic attestation, and the management of digital assets within a mining context. While the ambition to innovate and improve upon existing systems is evident, the conversations reflect a cautious optimism, underscored by a recognition of the need for clarity, simplicity, and a focused approach towards enhancing liquidity, security, and privacy for miners. The detailed exploration of these themes provides valuable insights into the evolving landscape of cryptocurrency mining, underscoring the importance of balancing technological advancements with practical considerations.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T20:21:55.775000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
