<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-20T02:16:28.510991+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-20T02:16:28.511086+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing dialogue in the cryptocurrency space regarding privacy and transaction anonymity highlights several key developments and challenges. JoinMarket has introduced a novel concept aimed at enhancing Bitcoin transaction privacy through a mechanism known as coinjoin, which involves multiple parties in transactions to obscure the source of bitcoins. This model relies on two participant types: Makers, who provide liquidity by offering their bitcoins for mixing, and Takers, who seek to enhance their transaction privacy. Despite its innovative approach, JoinMarket faces challenges, particularly with its peer discovery system. The use of directory nodes intended to mitigate centralized communication coordination hasn't been as effective as anticipated, primarily due to the difficulties associated with ephemeral Tor onion services.

A significant advancement is observed with the Trezor Suite application's support for CoinJoin transactions using alternative coordinators, offering users more flexibility in selecting coordinators for their transactions. This development, detailed at [Change Coordinator (kravens.nl)](https://wasabi.kravens.nl/trezor), illustrates a move towards enhancing user autonomy in managing transaction privacy.

The email also mentions an initiative to develop a system that operates without reliance on hardcoded directory nodes or specific individuals, aiming for a more sustainable and autonomous infrastructure. This reflects a broader effort within the community to address volunteer fluctuation and the challenges it poses to project continuity.

Central to the conversation is the JoinMarket messaging protocol, crucial for secure and private decentralized Bitcoin transactions. Detailed documentation available on GitHub emphasizes encrypted communication channels and mechanisms for creating and broadcasting transactions, highlighting the platform's commitment to privacy and efficiency.

Configuration complexities for peer discovery and interaction are elaborated upon, with specific requirements for Onion-based messaging channels and the management of Tor configurations. This underscores the intricate balance between usability, security, and anonymity in decentralized systems.

JoinMarket with Jam is noted for its departure from traditional wallet interfaces by eliminating reliance on a central coordinator, despite scant details on its underlying technology. This, along with the emergence of joinstr as an alternative leveraging nostr relays for peer communication, signifies a trend towards decentralization in transaction management.

Recent regulatory actions against non-custodial privacy tools have catalyzed the search for alternatives. The closures of Samourai and Wasabi Wallet's coordinator servers have prompted a shift towards solutions like JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin, which uses the WabiSabi protocol for self-hosted coordinator services. This pivot reflects a broader movement within the cryptocurrency privacy sector towards resilience and self-reliance, amidst growing regulatory pressures.

In summary, the cryptocurrency community continues to innovate in the realm of transaction privacy, with JoinMarket, joinstr, and self-hosted solutions emerging as pivotal elements in the ongoing discourse. These developments illustrate both the challenges and potential pathways forward in enhancing privacy and security in the digital currency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-19T16:21:53.074000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
