<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-06-03T02:04:13.576382+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria 2024-06-02 21:08:52.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-31 20:13:43.809000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-24 13:07:52.580000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2604_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2591_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2530_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-03T02:04:13.576553+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal under discussion aims to introduce a more private and efficient payout process for mining pools, yet it's considered overly complex for its primary goal. Utilizing lightning or ecash for transactions is suggested as a simpler alternative that doesn't necessitate binding shares directly to ecash or implementing elaborate changes. An expanded goal could consider making pool shares a tradable asset, potentially benefiting from the proposed complexity.

Cryptographic attestation emerges as a critical feature, allowing pools or mints to validate individual shares through digital signatures. This process enhances security by immediately highlighting any unauthorized alterations made post-validation, thus preventing malicious tampering. The integration of cryptographic attestation into existing protocols like Sv2 could simplify the validation process without additional system complexities. The proposal prioritizes privacy in payouts without fundamentally changing transaction or share validation mechanisms, targeting an efficient migration process for pools failing in adequate payouts. However, it has drifted towards topics not directly related to its core aim, suggesting a need to refocus discussions on relevant issues to fully realize potential benefits.

The concept of ehashes within a sophisticated management framework allows tracking and ownership transfers before redemption. The mint plays a crucial role in logging which shares correspond to specific ehashes upon their redemption, ensuring the integrity of the tracking system. The redemption mechanism depends on whether the ehash falls within a particular timeframe, known as the share window, maintaining the value and relevance of ehashes in the digital asset space.

The document critiques the practicality of reusing ecash, proposing a system where redeemed ehashes result in another ehash, raising questions about implementation specifics and the feasibility of tracking issuance frequency related to original shares. It highlights the need for a robust system to manage ehash lifecycles securely and efficiently.

A detailed analysis requests technical feedback on a cryptographic protocol's soundness, focusing on potential vulnerabilities. This inquiry indicates a commitment to refining the protocol by addressing identified weaknesses, emphasizing the importance of transparency in mining operations. Methods like sharing log data are suggested to enhance transparency, allowing miners to verify payouts and make informed decisions about their mining pool affiliations.

Regarding auditability and financial transactions, Bolt12 is noted for facilitating micro payouts within Lightning Network channels, enhancing liquidity without requiring prior user liquidity. The proposal also touches on custodial risks associated with mining pools and regulatory implications, particularly KYC regulations affecting non-compliant pools. It discusses the limitations of current Bitcoin Mining ASIC technology and the challenges of reducing payout thresholds due to these limitations.

The email also delves into the valuation of keysets within Cashu, exploring how eShares are converted into satoshis based on the difficulty targets of submitted PoW shares. Ocean's KYC policy is examined, noting operational nuances in payment distributions and legal considerations. Lastly, the use of Cashu for mining payouts is evaluated against objectives of auditability, small payouts, and privacy, acknowledging the trade-offs presented by the Lightning Network's privacy capabilities and Cashu's custodial nature.

The cornerstone of the discussion is a detailed framework aiming to bolster privacy, auditability, and flexibility in cryptocurrency mining rewards distribution, suggesting resources for further exploration. This includes integrating Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange into Stratum v2 Protocol, offering a novel approach to reward distribution tailored for small payouts while maintaining transaction integrity and confidentiality.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-02T21:08:52.095000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
