<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
  <updated>2024-06-26T02:02:50.625287+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>renepickhardt 2024-06-25 22:38:25.065000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-06-25 19:29:50.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntonioPerez  . 2024-06-17 20:00:06.973000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>renepickhardt  . 2024-06-17 18:27:44.834000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2789_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2787_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2729_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2725_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T02:02:50.625337+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/estimating-likelihood-for-lightning-payments-to-be-in-feasible/973/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Rene Pickhardt is pioneering a mathematical framework to deepen the understanding of payment channel networks, with a special focus on the Lightning Network. His research aims to rectify inaccuracies found in previous models that estimated liquidity and payment success probabilities within these networks. Traditional models fell short by assuming independent and uniformly distributed liquidity across channels, which did not accurately represent the true dynamics of the network.

In a significant advancement, Pickhardt proposes the use of bimodal models that more accurately reflect the observed distributions shaped by the unique geometries of payment channel networks. This shift away from the assumption of independent liquidity distributions marks a crucial step towards understanding the actual behavior of such networks.

Through an iPython notebook shared on his [Github repository](https://github.com/renepickhardt/Lightning-Network-Limitations/blob/46e6fce28510be1db646dc8967ed2299e19243d8/likelihood-of-payment-possability/Likelihood%20of%20Payments.ipynb), Pickhardt elaborates on his theoretical findings. This notebook illustrates his method for calculating the likelihood of successful payments between two nodes on the Lightning Network without needing to know the exact liquidity distribution. Instead, this method assumes all possible wealth distributions are equally likely, focusing on whether a wealth distribution remains viable after a payment is made. This approach diverges from conventional methods by emphasizing feasible states and wealth distributions rather than merely estimating liquidity.

The preliminary results showcased in the notebook reveal how the probability of successfully making a payment can vary depending on the amount and the nodes involved. These findings challenge the accuracy of minimum cost flow (MCF) probabilities, indicating that the real feasibility of payments often differs due to the underlying wealth distribution and network topology.

Pickhardt's ongoing work provides invaluable insights into estimating payment success rates within the Lightning Network, highlighting the need to consider the network's complex dynamics and constraints. By moving beyond simplistic models of liquidity estimation, his research underscores the impossibility of achieving 100% success rates in payments due to the dynamic nature of feasible wealth distributions in the network. The development of this mathematical theory is anticipated to influence future improvements in network design and pathfinding algorithms, offering a more nuanced understanding of the operational dynamics of the Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-25T22:38:25.065000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
