<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
  <updated>2024-06-18T02:07:40.683097+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Antonio-Perez00 2024-06-17 20:00:06.973000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>renepickhardt 2024-06-17 18:27:44.834000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2729_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2725_Estimating-Likelihood-for-Lightning-Payments-to-be-in-feasible.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Estimating Likelihood for Lightning Payments to be (in)feasible</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T02:07:40.683139+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/estimating-likelihood-for-lightning-payments-to-be-in-feasible/973/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email from Rene Pickhardt to fellow Lightning Network developers unveils his ongoing work on a paper that introduces a mathematical theory for payment channel networks, specifically focusing on the Lightning Network. The communication highlights a section of an iPython notebook found in his [GitHub repository](https://github.com/renepickhardt/Lightning-Network-Limitations/blob/46e6fce28510be1db646dc8967ed2299e19243d8/likelihood-of-payment-possability/Likelihood%20of%20Payments.ipynb), which serves as a practical example to apply the theoretical concepts he's developing. This part of his research aims to address and rectify certain flaws identified in prior models used for estimating liquidity in payment channels—particularly, the assumptions regarding liquidity distributions and their independence, along with the uniform distribution model used to encapsulate uncertainty. To overcome these limitations, Pickhardt introduces bimodal models as a better representation of liquidity distributions within these networks, supporting his argument with a geometric perspective that suggests these distributions naturally arise from the network's structure once the assumption of independent channel liquilities is discarded.

Pickhardt's contribution through this notebook showcases a methodology to calculate the success rate of payments between two peers within the Lightning Network without needing detailed information about the liquidity distribution in the channels. This approach presumes each possible wealth distribution across the network's topology is equally likely, thereby enabling the estimation of payment success probabilities by testing whether a payment results in a feasible wealth distribution change. This theoretical framework diverges from traditional liquidity and wealth distribution assumptions, proposing instead that despite the uniform likelihood among feasible distributions, the actual distribution of wealth closely follows a power-law distribution skewed by the network's topology.

The provided example illustrates the application of Pickhardt's method, revealing how it significantly differs from and potentially outperforms conventional probabilistic pathfinding techniques based on independent and uniformly distributed liquidity assumptions. By comparing the feasibility of specific payments within a given network topology, the results underscore the inherent limitations and challenges in achieving 100% successful payment transactions over the Lightning Network. It also emphasizes the disparity between the success probabilities of optimal payment flows and those estimated through this new methodology, suggesting the latter offers a more realistic assessment of payment feasibility.

In conclusion, Pickhardt's preliminary findings suggest a promising avenue for improving the estimation of payment success rates within the Lightning Network, inviting further discussion, feedback, and questions from the developer community. His work indicates a significant stride towards understanding and optimizing payment channel network functionalities, with the anticipation of more detailed explanations and expanded methodologies in the completed version of his paper.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-17T20:00:06.973000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
