<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:07:16.697785+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:07:16.697858+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The cryptocurrency community is currently grappling with the challenges and limitations of ensuring transaction privacy. The joinstr protocol, while promising for its innovative approach to bypass centralized coordinators, remains in its infancy and faces technical hurdles, such as a threading issue highlighted on its [GitLab page](https://gitlab.com/1440000bytes/joinstr/-/issues/7). This limitation tempers enthusiasm for its immediate adoption. An intriguing alternative for enhancing transaction anonymity involves ecash, which could potentially use Lightning Network (LN) payments routed through multiple mints to obscure transactions. However, the practicality of this method is currently hindered by the small pool of funds available in ecash mints and predictable transaction patterns. To combat network-level correlation, the use of TOR and strategic timing of transfers is suggested, though the effectiveness of these tactics remains speculative at present.

Looking ahead, the implementation of Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs) within the LN presents an optimistic future for transaction privacy. PTLCs promise to mitigate payment hash/preimage correlation vulnerabilities, offering a more discreet method of conducting transactions by facilitating submarine swaps that divide a single pre-swap UTXO into several smaller post-swap ones. This could significantly obscure individual transactions among a larger set managed by popular services, thus enhancing user anonymity.

In response to the increased scrutiny and regulatory actions against non-custodial privacy tools, the Bitcoin privacy landscape has undergone significant shifts. Notably, the cessation of coordinator services for Samourai and Wasabi Wallets has precipitated a search for viable alternatives. In this context, JoinMarket with Jam emerges as an option that, despite lacking a central coordinator, demands a more complex setup but promises improved user experience. Detailed information about this can be found on [JamDocs](https://jamdocs.org/philosophy/03-joinmarket/). Moreover, [joinstr.xyz](https://joinstr.xyz) offers an innovative solution by leveraging nostr relays for peer communication, adhering to a decentralized ethos that diverges from traditional coinjoin methods.

The recent closures have also paved the way for new adaptations, such as the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin, which utilizes the WabiSabi protocol to enable users to host their own coordinator services. This development not only facilitates private transactions but also integrates with the Nostr relay for enhanced discoverability, marking a significant step towards decentralization. Tools like the one found on [GitHub](https://github.com/Kukks/WasabiNostr) aid in locating active coordinators, hinting at the potential emergence of a decentralized network of BTCPay Coordinators. As the community navigates these changes, the evolution of Bitcoin privacy techniques stands at a crossroads, with the potential for groundbreaking solutions to counteract regulatory pressures.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T06:20:10.278000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
