<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T04:21:00.193511+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-06-24 00:46:03.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-06-04 22:57:12.634000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-23 18:48:34.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-23 12:50:43.605000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-23 12:49:42.885000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-21 15:17:30.948000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-21 01:44:52.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 22:46:58.079000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 15:23:05.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-09-20 14:03:45.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5337_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5215_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3252_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3250_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3249_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3244_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3242_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3241_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3238_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3237_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T04:21:00.193666+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussions and developments in the realm of Bitcoin privacy and transaction security are multifaceted, encompassing a variety of technical challenges and innovative solutions. The utilization of `ALL|ANYONECANPAY` signatures within Bitcoin transactions has sparked interest, particularly for its potential application in crowdfunding scenarios, as well as its limitations in achieving privacy through coinjoin transactions. This signature type, alongside the concept of coinjoins facilitated via IRC channels, underscores the ongoing exploration into enhancing transaction anonymity. Despite the flexibility IRC offers in selecting participants for coinjoins, it highlights the limitations of relying on user coordination and the advantages of larger, unknown peer groups for increased privacy.

The conversation extends into the intricacies of implementing privacy features in blockchain transactions, focusing on overcoming the limitations posed by the `SINGLE|ACP` signature method. The dialogue seeks alternative solutions that offer more flexible and private transaction mechanisms, moving towards utilizing Nostr relay addresses for sharing Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs). This approach indicates a significant infrastructure ready for use, albeit without built-in peer discovery features, emphasizing a decentralized approach to network participation.

Moreover, the development of Joinstr represents an advancement in addressing communication coordination and centralization issues by eliminating the need for hardcoded addresses for bootstrapping. This innovation enhances user flexibility and control over their transaction processes. Additionally, the potential for integrating covenants into Joinstr could further enhance transaction security and functionality, pointing towards future advancements in cryptocurrency transactions and smart contracts.

Joinmarket's evolution in addressing centralized communication coordination through "directory nodes" illustrates the challenges and potential solutions in creating more decentralized transaction systems. However, the operational difficulties encountered with ephemeral tor onion services highlight the complexities in achieving desired levels of decentralization and privacy preservation.

The reliance on centralized coordination mechanisms by protocols such as CoinShuffle and CoinShuffle++ brings to light the persistent challenge of decentralized operation in privacy-oriented cryptocurrency transactions. Despite advancements, these protocols still face hurdles in effectively circumventing centralization, underscoring a broader issue within the domain.

The introduction of the Trezor Suite application's support for CoinJoin transactions with alternative coordinators marks a significant step forward in offering users flexibility in their choice of transaction facilitators. This development, coupled with the dynamic nature of volunteer involvement and the challenges of peer discovery in decentralized systems, reflects the ongoing efforts to enhance the privacy and security of cryptocurrency transactions.

The discourse around ecash as a tool for enhancing Bitcoin privacy, particularly in conjunction with coinjoin and other anonymization techniques, showcases the complexity and diverse strategies within the ecosystem aimed at improving transaction privacy. The speculative nature of integrating Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs) into the Lightning Network to address payment-hash correlation vulnerabilities further exemplifies the continuous search for more effective privacy-enhancing solutions.

In summary, the evolving landscape of Bitcoin privacy services, highlighted by the crackdown on non-custodial privacy tools and the emergence of alternatives like JoinMarket with Jam and BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin, underlines the community's resilience and adaptability. As regulatory pressures mount, the potential for decentralized networks of coordinators and innovative solutions continues to shape the future of Bitcoin privacy techniques, suggesting a pivotal moment in the quest for enhanced transaction anonymity and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:46:03.504000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
