<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2024-06-13T09:07:51.531459+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T09:07:51.531499+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The document in question introduces a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) aimed at incorporating quantum resistance into the Bitcoin protocol to counter potential threats from quantum computing technology. The objective is to select and implement an appropriate signature algorithm that would prepare Bitcoin for the advent of advanced quantum computing capabilities. Given the slow pace of development and activation within the Bitcoin network, there is a sense of urgency to initiate early discussions and actions to ensure the network's preparedness against such quantum vulnerabilities.

This BIP is part of a broader initiative to develop a "QuBit" soft fork, which seeks to protect Bitcoin against quantum computing threats. Currently presented as an early draft, the document does not offer a definitive solution but rather serves as a foundation for validation and feedback from the Bitcoin development community. It acknowledges the legitimate concerns raised by quantum computing and proposes preliminary solutions for consideration and improvement.

The proposer has made this BIP publicly available for review and discussion, emphasizing its status as a work in progress. Through this approach, the goal is to engage developers and stakeholders in assessing the viability of the proposed quantum-resistant measures, determining necessary adjustments, and evaluating the importance of pursuing such initiatives at this stage. For further details and contributions, the BIP is accessible via [this link](https://github.com/cryptoquick/bips/blob/61aac1a91a596cdeed75ed7f5c5c19b0b4b923ef/bip-p2qrh.mediawiki), inviting input from the wider Bitcoin and cryptocurrency community.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-13T02:40:40.509000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
