<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
  <updated>2024-06-05T02:05:07.407626+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2024-06-04 14:02:59.571000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-06-03 08:56:16.868000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2626_Proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2609_Proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
    <updated>2024-06-05T02:05:07.407664+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet/937/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The utilization of the transaction hash for Proof of Work (PoW) verification presents an innovative solution to several issues inherent in traditional methods. By anchoring the PoW to a specific transaction hash, it inherently protects against theft since any modification to the transaction alters its hash, rendering the PoW invalid. This approach also ensures that each PoW can only be used once, bolstering security against potential reuse in what is termed as "history flood attacks." Further, this method promises compatibility with ASICs by maintaining a transaction size of 80 bytes, achievable through specific signature hashes and requirements for leading zeroes in the hash of the signed message. Additionally, this technique allows for claiming multiple coins simultaneously with a single Proof of Work, provided the PoW demonstrates a sufficiently low hash across the entire transaction, thereby streamlining the process of coin acquisition.

The recent activation of `OP_CAT` on signet, facilitated by the bitcoin inquisition client, marks a significant advancement in the execution of complex scripts on the blockchain. This development enables direct validation of PoW on the blockchain through script manipulations, including byte concatenation and validation processes. The capability to validate PoW in this manner introduces a novel method for coin distribution within the signet environment, where access to sBTC typically depends on allocations from block producers. This mechanism leverages cryptographic techniques to ensure that each PoW is uniquely bonded to the claimant's identity, preventing unauthorized or duplicate claims. The integration of work compatible with Bitcoin ASICs aligns with the broader ecosystem, utilizing existing mining infrastructure for PoW generation.

The technical framework for implementing this PoW-based coin distribution relies on detailed scripting to manage difficulty specifications, concatenate necessary data elements, and verify the preimage's validity against cryptographic standards. This ensures that only PoW submissions that meet specific criteria can successfully claim coins. From a practical standpoint, the initiative encompasses setting up a specialized wallet and executing claims against available coins, aiming to optimize the value extracted relative to the effort spent. The collaborative nature of contributions to the bitcoin inquisition project underscores a community-driven approach to overcoming challenges and enhancing the Bitcoin scripting landscape and its applications on signet.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-04T14:02:59.571000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
