<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
  <updated>2024-06-15T02:03:17.811955+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>levantah 2024-06-14 10:15:05.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2024-06-04 14:02:59.571000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-06-03 08:56:16.868000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2713_Proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2626_Proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2609_Proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T02:03:17.812001+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet/937/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The use of transaction hashes as a proof of work (PoW) presents an innovative approach in the cryptocurrency field, offering notable security benefits by minimizing the risk of theft due to the unique nature of each transaction hash. This method ensures that each transaction is unique, thus preventing redundancy and reusability except in rare scenarios indicative of larger systemic issues. The compatibility with ASIC hardware, facilitated by specific signature hashes like `SIGHASH_SINGLE | SIGHASH_ANYONECANPAY`, allows for transactions as small as 80 bytes to meet PoW requirements. This technique enables the simultaneous claiming of multiple coins through a single transaction, exemplified by a [transaction](https://mempool.space/tx/00000000c0747ece95852c2b7d37b09770873ed8b50fb7be2ba3d400defab06c), which simplifies the reward claiming process.

The activation of `OP_CAT` on signet, enabled by the [bitcoin inquisition client](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-inquisition-25-2/838), marks a significant advancement in blockchain scripting, allowing for direct blockchain validation of PoW. This development enhances script capabilities by facilitating the manipulation and validation of hash bytes, thereby enabling the distribution of sBTC based on PoW contributions. A [proof-of-concept transaction](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/25deff74b7775918aa6824cfeab9121a519fb419d31ea74f6cb6a53f98cc863a) and a [Python script](https://github.com/ajtowns/bitcoin/blob/634e72cbfc0aa3f657a35c7b597f688bb2bb29a6/contrib/signet/powcoins) demonstrate this innovative approach to coin acquisition on signet. The method counters potential abuses such as PoW reuse or multiple claims by a single entity through cryptographic techniques that ensure a one-to-one correspondence between PoW and claimant identity, leveraging signature verification and length commitments.

This system's design aims to utilize existing Bitcoin mining infrastructure, aligning with the broader ecosystem while detailing the technical implementation through script components that manage difficulty levels, data concatenation, and preimage validation against cryptographic standards. These scripts ensure that only valid PoW submissions can claim coins. Operational commands guide users in setting up specialized wallets and executing claims, optimizing the effort-to-value ratio for participants. Such collaborative endeavors within the cryptocurrency community underscore a collective commitment to innovation, addressing challenges, and expanding Bitcoin's functional landscape, especially in terms of scripting and applications on signet.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T10:15:05.775000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
