<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Public archive for Delving Bitcoin</title>
  <updated>2024-08-27T03:09:40.387003+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob 2023-09-07 15:53:41.751000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Public archive for Delving Bitcoin</title>
    <updated>2024-08-27T03:09:40.387041+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/public-archive-for-delving-bitcoin/87/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The archive repository created for delving into Bitcoin discussions is made accessible through [this GitHub link](https://github.com/jamesob/delving-bitcoin-archive). A significant feature of this repository is the inclusion of a rendered markdown listing of topic threads, which can be found [here](https://github.com/jamesob/delving-bitcoin-archive/tree/master/archive/rendered-topics), offering an organized view of discussions. Additionally, the repository houses a raw archive of post JSON files located [here](https://github.com/jamesob/delving-bitcoin-archive/tree/master/archive/posts), catering to the needs of search indexers by providing unprocessed data.

For those interested in replicating this archival process, the script necessary for archiving is available and can be installed using pip commands. The script is designed to be straightforward and user-friendly, ensuring that anyone with basic knowledge can set it up for their use. It is available for download and installation at [the script's GitHub page](https://github.com/jamesob/discourse-archive). Users can install the discourse-archive tool via pip and execute it by pointing it to the desired URL, as demonstrated in the guide. However, it is important to note a limitation regarding the script’s ability to detect updates to posts older than a day. This constraint suggests that if a post receives an update after this period, the change might not be captured by the current version of the script. While this poses a challenge, exploring other parts of the API might offer a workaround for capturing such updates.</summary>
    <published>2023-09-07T15:53:41.751000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
