<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
  <updated>2024-04-16T16:59:36.159610+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>melvincarvalho.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-09-10T00:34:18.342000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T16:59:36.159649+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023/32/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing development and adaptation of Bitcoin highlight its efforts to surpass the current banking system's efficiency and scalability while offering a fairer method of allocation. The finite nature of Bitcoin, with 93% of its issuance already in circulation, underscores its value and the significant milestone of distributing wealth more equitably among the community, with Satoshi Nakamoto’s contribution estimated at around $30 billion. This initial phase of distribution and the establishment of a large node network have been critical in navigating Bitcoin through its early challenges. The network’s conservative approach to block size has played a pivotal role in safeguarding against potential threats such as unwanted forks, vandalism, and regulatory overhang, which are considered some of the most significant risks to Bitcoin’s stability.

Despite these successes, the threat of miner centralization and the possibility of reorganization attacks loom as areas of concern that need addressing. The debate over block size, often referred to as the "block size war," was not merely about the technical aspects but fundamentally about maintaining Bitcoin’s unity. The proposed medium-term plan to increase block size to 8MB is approached with caution, emphasizing the need for careful planning to ensure the scalability does not compromise security or decentralization.

Looking forward, the integration of modeling tools and artificial intelligence (AI) is anticipated to play a crucial role in guiding the scalable growth of Bitcoin. AI could help in optimizing fee structures and transaction speeds by creating an equilibrium between miners’ and users’ needs, thus supporting the network’s efficiency. However, the deployment of AI within Bitcoin raises questions about trust and the ability to prevent sub-optimal strategies that could undermine the network. Establishing social conventions within AI protocols, such as discouraging intentional deep reorganizations, is suggested as a method to preserve network integrity without compromising on the principles of self-interest and game theory that underpin L1.

In terms of scaling solutions, a multi-faceted approach is envisioned. This includes increasing L1 block sizes carefully, alongside the implementation of technologies like utreexo for state minimization, stratum vnext, reorg alerts, and defensive BIPs for emergency situations. For L2 scalability, the utilization of platforms such as Liquid/Elements for mass adoption, RGB for privacy and smart contracts, along with other innovative solutions like autonomous agents and hybrid systems like Chaumian e-mints, are highlighted. These developments aim to maintain Bitcoin’s competitive edge by ensuring it can cater to a broad spectrum of users, from casual ones served by regular centralized exchanges to those requiring advanced privacy and contract capabilities, thereby securing its position as a scalable and decentralized financial solution.</summary>
    <published>2023-09-10T00:34:18.342000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
