<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
  <updated>2024-09-10T03:14:29.143111+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-09-29T18:08:28.969000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
    <updated>2024-09-10T03:14:29.143139+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/covenant-tools-softfork/98/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion emphasizes the importance of selecting a specific set of proposals for signaling in a forthcoming Bitcoin Core release, advocating for a decision based on readiness rather than predetermination. A comparison between `CTV` (CheckTemplateVerify) combined with `OP_VAULT` and `APO` (AnyPrevOut) combined with `CTV` is made, highlighting the technical strengths of the former due to the directed use case provided by `OP_VAULT`. This comparison extends to the review process, where it's noted that evaluating `CTV` might focus solely on its application within `OP_VAULT`, whereas `APO` would necessitate a broader understanding, including aspects like ln-symmetry.

The email outlines the complexities involved in reviewing proposals, touching upon the dilemma of whether to limit them to specific use cases or allow for flexibility without guaranteeing utility. The challenges of thoroughly exploring a wide array of potential applications are acknowledged, alongside the significant effort required to sift through extensive discussions and documentation. Mention is made of the changing pace of soft fork cycles within the Bitcoin protocol, noting a slowdown from past processes, with recent deployments like Taproot and SegWit being highlighted for their complexity compared to earlier, simpler proposals.

Additionally, the conversation brings up concerns about the level of detailed examination these proposals have undergone, questioning whether there has been sufficient exploration and practical testing by the community. Despite uncertainties around what constitutes "enough" review, the author muses that the presence of demonstrative projects might indicate a relative maturity of the proposals, comparing this to the state of development for SegWit and lightning network prototypes at their respective times of activation. There's an expressed need for further personal review to adequately assess the effectiveness and integration of these demonstrations within the proposed frameworks.</summary>
    <published>2023-09-29T18:08:28.969000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
