<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
  <updated>2024-09-10T03:12:23.445298+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-09-30T13:14:28.270000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Covenant tools softfork</title>
    <updated>2024-09-10T03:12:23.445327+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/covenant-tools-softfork/98/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion emphasizes the importance of establishing a shared goal in the realm of programming, particularly highlighting how an open and undefined design space can lead to paralysis. By focusing on tooling and demonstrations, such as the [verystable](https://github.com/jamesob/verystable) repository and various demos like the vault demo, ln-symmetry, and spacechains, there's a clear path towards identifying viable applications and refining necessary features. These practical examples serve not only as proofs of concept but also facilitate the evaluation of alternative methods for implementing functionalities, thereby making the development process more efficient and flexible.

Furthermore, the conversation points toward the benefits of tangible demos in streamlining decision-making processes regarding the implementation of functionalities like APO/CTV/OP_VAULT. The ease of deciding on and implementing these functionalities suggests that building applications atop them should be straightforward. This approach could potentially mitigate the issue of decision paralysis by providing clear, workable foundations upon which further development can be based. Essentially, if the practicality of demos is confirmed, it would underscore the utility of this strategy in advancing programming projects. Conversely, if demos prove challenging, the interim period of paralysis might not significantly hinder progress, suggesting that the exploration of different approaches remains valuable.</summary>
    <published>2023-09-30T13:14:28.270000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
