<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
  <updated>2024-04-16T17:00:50.560098+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  ..590000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CubicEarth  ..010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>melvincarvalho.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Ajian.182000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle.873000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob  ..243000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1347_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1189_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2023/182_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2023/167_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/123_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2023/62_Thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Thoughts on scaling and consensus changes (2023)</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T17:00:50.560158+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/thoughts-on-scaling-and-consensus-changes-2023/32" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of a system where only a subset of participants is required to generate off-chain activity offers a potential breakthrough in circumventing the need for all participants to sign, thereby enhancing efficiency. This concept, still in its research phase, suggests using a peer-to-peer (P2P) network with FROST (Flexible Round-Optimized Schnorr Threshold) participants as an alternative to traditional federated minting systems like Fedimint. The challenge of ensuring honesty among participants in such a P2P network is significant, with a proposed solution involving miners doubling as P2P mint participants. This would require miners to demonstrate proof of work shares and maintain good behavior as a prerequisite for securing their payouts, aligning their interests with the integrity of the network. 

Bitcoin's value fundamentally stems from its scarcity and transparent supply, rather than block size limitations or mining structures. Technological advancements that allow for the processing and auditing of extremely large blocks, alongside a reliable and honest mining mechanism, could potentially enhance Bitcoin's utility and value. This perspective emphasizes the importance of scaling and security improvements that do not compromise Bitcoin's core attributes.

Current banking systems, despite their imperfections, manage to scale to billions of people; Bitcoin aims to offer a superior alternative by leveraging its fair allocation method and its ability to challenge historical financial systems. With Bitcoin's issuance nearly complete, its focus shifts towards scalability and addressing threats such as miner centralization, forks, vandalism, and regulatory challenges. Strategies for increasing block size, utilizing AI for fee negotiation, and developing Layer 2 solutions like Liquid/Elements, RGB, and hybrid systems are discussed as means to support Bitcoin's growth and utility.

The concept of "coinpools" is introduced as a solution to improve Bitcoin's scalability by enabling internal payments within a pool and reducing transaction costs through advanced protocols and committed addresses. This approach, along with the development of a market for "L1 insurance" to support users during congestion, reflects ongoing efforts to make Bitcoin more accessible and efficient. 

In conclusion, the future of Bitcoin hinges on successfully balancing scalability with security, preserving its core values while expanding its utility. This involves a collaborative effort across the community to refine concepts like coinpools, implement innovative solutions such as Utreexo for UTXO management, and ensure regulatory compliance for off-chain entities. The integration of tools for efficient Layer 1 exits, enhanced custody solutions, and the continued research into layer-building principles are crucial steps towards achieving a scalable, secure, and user-friendly Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-26T08:15:10.590000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
