<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2012-January-001148</id>
  <title>BIP 20 Rejected, process for BIP 21N</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:21:17.454593+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2012-January-001148</id>
    <title>BIP 20 Rejected, process for BIP 21N</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:21:17.454593+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2012-January/001148.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The methods for forward compatibility in BIP 21 have undergone heavy changes. Instead of a version number, new variables will be added either as-is or with a "mustimplement:" prefix. If a client does not know what the variable is after "mustimplement:", it should consider the entire URI invalid and either notify the user or just drop it silently. This way, things like expiretime can be added without worrying about old clients ignoring the field. However, depending on the names of variables to provide information is considered ugly. The BIP recommends that additional variables prefixed with "mustimplement:" not be used in a mission-critical way until a grace period of 6 months from the finalization of this BIP has passed to allow client developers to release new versions, and users of old clients to upgrade. In terms of the expiretime field being implemented now, it is not appropriate since some clients already have an old implementation, and the possibility of it getting ignored is too large. It is recommended that it not be used in a mission-critical way until a grace period of 6 months from the finalization of this BIP has passed. The BIP aims to keep the list of changes from the Bitcoin-Qt implementation to this BIP minimal this late in the 0.6 release cycle. Some implementations such as Bitcoin-Qt, Electrum, MultiBit, or Bitcoin-JS do not support BIP 20. BIP 21 is still a draft, but it is implemented in all versions of Bitcoin-Qt for drag and drop, and adding a field that restricts the validity of a URI for new clients but which old clients will gladly accept could result in some ugly situations.</summary>
    <published>2012-01-31T18:22:25+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
