<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-09-05T02:12:59.486800+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-04T11:08:40.364000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T02:12:59.486837+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/44" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of verifying a coinbase transaction within the context of Bitcoin mining involves a detailed procedure that leverages the SHA256 hashing algorithm's characteristic of including the size of its input in the hash calculation. This method allows for a more efficient verification process by reducing the required data to a minimal set while still ensuring the integrity and authenticity of the transaction.

In this verification method, the prover is required to supply specific components of the transaction data: the midstate of the coinbase transaction for all but the last chunk of the first of the double SHA256 hashes, the final chunk itself, and a partial merkle branch of the coinbase transaction. These elements are critical as they allow the verifier to reconstruct and validate the coinbase transaction identifier (txid) without needing the entire transaction data.

The verifier utilizes the provided midstate and final chunk to regenerate the coinbase txid. Subsequently, it evaluates the nodes supplied in the partial merkle branch to confirm their correct positioning, specifically ensuring they correlate with the first transaction in a block, namely the coinbase transaction. By inserting the generated txid into the partial merkle branch and validating it up to the merkle root found in the block header, the verifier can authenticate the transaction's legitimacy.

This process offers several assurances to the verifier: It confirms the exact number of bytes used to generate the digest, thereby indicating whether the data pertains to a transaction or an internal merkle node based on the byte count. Additionally, it verifies the transaction as a legitimate coinbase transaction, safeguarded against certain vulnerabilities like CVE-2017-12842, and confirms its proper placement within the merkle tree structure, which inherently validates the block. Through this methodology, the integrity of the blockchain is maintained, allowing for secure and verifiable transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-04T11:08:40.364000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
