<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-09-05T02:14:56.424874+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-04T14:38:47.803000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T02:14:56.424910+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses a technical aspect of cryptographic commitments and their implications. The sender acknowledges a misunderstanding regarding the necessity of committing to a specific value, R1, in the context of cryptographic operations. It's highlighted that for a given equation, where `e1` is defined as `H(k1*G,pubkey,m1)`, the choice of `k1` cannot be influenced after its initial determination. This point is crucial since it underlines the integrity of the commitment process, ensuring that the selection of `k1` remains independent of the outcome of `e1`.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the purpose of such commitments in securing communication channels. Specifically, it points out that these commitments serve a dual function. Firstly, they contain a secret that is exclusively known to the attacker, which is used to encrypt the communication channel. This encryption ensures that the attacker can maintain exclusive access to the information transmitted over this channel. Secondly, the commitment also encapsulates the message and the private key within it. This bundling is significant because it ties the secrecy and authenticity of the message directly to the sender's identity, represented by their private key.

In essence, the email elucidates on the technical foundations of secure communication protocols, emphasizing the role of cryptographic commitments. By explaining how these commitments work to both encrypt a channel and bind a message to a sender's private key, the sender sheds light on the fundamental mechanisms that protect against unauthorized access and ensure message integrity within digital communications.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-04T14:38:47.803000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
