<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:50.860524+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Fi3</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-06T14:33:46.465000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:50.860555+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The technology underlying cryptocurrency mining incorporates a mechanism where every miner is responsible for verifying a random sample of shares. This process is crucial because it ensures the integrity and fairness of the mining effort. Shares, in this context, represent proof of work that miners submit to demonstrate their contribution to the mining process. The design of this system is such that it is impossible to fake these shares.

This verification process plays a pivotal role in maintaining the security of the network. By requiring each miner to verify a random sample of shares, the system effectively prevents any single miner from having undue influence or engaging in fraudulent activities. This decentralized verification method is essential for preventing various types of attacks on the network.

Moreover, the inability to fake shares adds another layer of security. It ensures that all participants in the mining process are genuinely contributing to the computational efforts required for transaction processing and blockchain maintenance. This aspect is fundamental to the trust and reliability of cryptocurrency transactions. By safeguarding against fake shares, the network upholds its integrity and provides assurance to users regarding the validity of transactions and the generation of new coins.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T14:33:46.465000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
