<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:13.891361+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Fi3.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-06T14:58:25.748000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:13.891393+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptocurrency mining, a notable development has emerged concerning the communication between client and server systems. A specific message format, detailed in an extension documentation found on GitHub ([extension.md](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/281c1cbc4f9a07b21a443753a525197dc5d8e18c/extension.md)), outlines a method for mining pools that support a certain extension to exchange data more effectively. This message format is distinguished by its compatibility with pools that are equipped to handle the specified extension, setting it apart from other messages like SV2.

The essence of this development lies in its potential to streamline the process of share accounting between clients and servers within the mining ecosystem. By utilizing this extension, both parties can achieve a higher degree of efficiency and accuracy in their operations. It's important to note that this advancement is tailored specifically for environments that have adopted the extension, thereby necessitating a level of technical readiness and adaptation for optimal utilization.

Moreover, this initiative underscores the ongoing evolution within the mining sector, as stakeholders continuously seek out innovations that can enhance their operational capabilities. Through the implementation of such specialized communication protocols, the mining community can look forward to improvements in how resources are allocated and managed across the network. This progression not only signifies a step forward in technological sophistication but also highlights the collaborative effort among developers to address and optimize the challenges inherent in cryptocurrency mining.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T14:58:25.748000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
