<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:04.224113+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-06T15:03:21.550000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:14:04.224141+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of programming, particularly concerning the development and implementation of share accounting systems, a significant update has been introduced. This update focuses on enhancing the functionality and reliability of data exchange between clients and servers through the introduction of new data types and communication protocols.

A critical component of this update is the `Share` Data Type, which is designed to streamline the handling and representation of share-related information within the system. This data type encapsulates various attributes of shares, making it easier for both the client and server sides of an application to process and manage share transactions efficiently. The detailed specification of the `Share` Data Type can be found [here](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/281c1cbc4f9a07b21a443753a525197dc5d8e18c/extension.mdshare).

To facilitate effective communication between clients and servers, two new messages have been defined: `GetShares` (Client -&gt; Server) and `GetSharesSuccess` (Server -&gt; Client). The `GetShares` message allows clients to request share information from the server. Upon receiving a `GetShares` request, the server processes this request and responds with a `GetSharesSuccess` message, which contains the requested share data. These messages ensure a standardized method for requesting and retrieving share information, thereby improving the efficiency of network communications within share accounting systems. The specifications for these messages are detailed in their respective documentation, accessible via the following links: [`GetShares` message](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/281c1cbc4f9a07b21a443753a525197dc5d8e18c/extension.mdgetshares-client---server) and [`GetSharesSuccess` message](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/281c1cbc4f9a07b21a443753a525197dc5d8e18c/extension.mdgetsharessuccess-server---client).

This update marks a significant advancement in the domain of share accounting systems, offering improved data handling capabilities and more efficient client-server interactions. Through the adoption of these new standards, developers can enhance the scalability, performance, and user experience of their applications.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T15:03:21.550000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
