<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:13:09.021204+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary 2024-09-06 15:22:17.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:13:09.021235+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The scenario presented involves a window with a single slice containing ten shares, numbered from 0 to 10. Within this context, two clients make requests for specific shares from the pool. Client A requests and correctly receives shares numbered 1, 3, 5, and 7. Consequently, Client B's request includes shares 2, 4, 6, and 8. However, an error occurs during this transaction: the pool provides Client B with shares 2, 4, 5, and 8 but incorrectly labels share 5 as share 6.

Detecting the deception hinges on Client B's ability to verify the authenticity and correctness of the shares received. Given that shares 5 and 6 are distinct and neither was submitted by Client B, there must exist mechanisms within the system for verifying each share's integrity and origin. This could involve cryptographic proofs or a ledger of transactions where each share's journey—from creation to current holder—is verifiable. Without such systems in place, discerning the mislabeling would challenge Client B, especially if they lack direct access to a reference or cannot compare notes with Client A or other entities holding the true shares.

This situation underscores the importance of transparency and verification processes in systems handling shared or distributable resources. Whether through cryptographic means, transparent ledgers, or both, ensuring that each party can independently verify the authenticity and correctness of what they receive is crucial. This not only prevents deceit but also enhances trust among participants within the system.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T15:22:17.578000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
