<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:11:36.375679+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash.866000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-06T22:06:12.866000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:11:36.375706+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/31" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the process of examining a recent paper, an individual engaged in creating several visuals to aid in organizing and clarifying their thoughts on the subject matter. These visuals were developed with the intention of offering a clearer representation of the concepts discussed within the paper. Notably, the creator of these visuals has decided to make them available for the authors of the paper to use and modify at their discretion, without requiring any form of attribution for their original creation.

The visuals created encompass various aspects of the topic addressed in the paper, each aiming to provide a distinct perspective or insight into the subject. Unfortunately, due to the nature of this summary, the specific contents of these visuals cannot be directly displayed or described in detail here.

This generous offering underscores a collaborative spirit within the academic and research communities, where resources and tools are freely shared to enhance understanding and facilitate further exploration of complex topics. The decision to allow unrestricted use of these visuals without attribution highlights a commendable commitment to the collective advancement of knowledge and understanding, rather than personal recognition or gain.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T22:06:12.866000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
