<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:34.524988+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>virtu 2024-09-10 08:42:24.774000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:34.525018+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of how darknet-only nodes connect to Bitcoin without using DNS seeds reveals a nuanced understanding of the node's reliance on hardcoded seed data. Through a series of statistics, it becomes evident that the viability of hardcoded seeds varies significantly across different network types, with IPv4 nodes showing a rapid decline in connectivity over time compared to I2P nodes, which demonstrate greater longevity. This discrepancy highlights the dynamic nature of network connectivity and the challenges faced by nodes operating on various networks.

A notable issue identified is the failure to update seed nodes during the release of version 26 of the Bitcoin Core, which underscores the importance of maintaining current seed lists to ensure robust network connectivity. Moreover, the historically low number of Onion and I2P seed nodes prior to version 27 points to a reliance on manual curation, limiting the expansion and resilience of these networks.

In response to these observations, the development of a proof-of-concept darknet seeder represents a significant advancement. This seeder, designed to serve Onion, I2P, and Cjdns addresses, introduces a novel approach to encoding and serving addresses, potentially enhancing connectivity for darknet-only nodes. By leveraging a BIP155-like encoding, the seeder aims to facilitate better integration of darknet addresses into the broader Bitcoin network, addressing both the practicality and necessity of such an endeavor for mixed and darknet-only nodes.

The ongoing dialogue and feedback from the community are crucial for refining this initiative, indicating a collaborative effort toward improving connectivity and functionality within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The exploration of custom DNS `NULL` queries in Bitcoin Core presents a promising avenue for further research, signaling a commitment to overcoming the technical hurdles associated with darknet connectivity.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-10T08:42:24.774000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
