<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-11T02:13:09.471480+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Fi3.500000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-10T10:34:45.500000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T02:13:09.471517+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/33" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent update on the share definition made to the GitHub repository, as detailed in the [extension document](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/8cf48767de3a477ab2b11ada8fb3f05c19cce758/extension.md), introduces two significant changes aimed at improving the efficiency and transparency of share accounting within mining pools. The first modification involves the removal of the `merkle_path` field from the share structure. This alteration is based on the rationale that the `merkle_path` can be derived from the transactions in the job during the later stages of the verification process, rendering the field redundant and unnecessary.

Furthermore, the addition of a new field, `share_index`, marks the second major change. This field specifies the index of the share within its slice, addressing a previously identified issue concerning the verification process for miners. Prior to this update, miners faced challenges in verifying whether the shares submitted by the pool were indeed the ones required. The introduction of the `share_index` aims to resolve this problem by providing a clear and direct method for miners to check the validity and relevance of the shares they receive from the pool.

These updates reflect a thoughtful response to community feedback, particularly highlighting the concern raised by @marathon-gary regarding the need for enhanced verification mechanisms for miners. By simplifying the share structure and introducing a mechanism for easier verification, these changes are poised to enhance the overall functionality and trustworthiness of share accounting practices within the context of cryptocurrency mining.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-10T10:34:45.500000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
