<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:18.034490+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-10T13:13:40.200000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:18.034521+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion advocates for a significant shift in handling DNS dependencies within network protocols, particularly emphasizing the removal of DNS in favor of direct IP address usage for node communication. This approach proposes that nodes maintained by developers should directly handle the `getaddr` requests essential for bootstrapping, thereby eliminating traditional DNS reliance. A practical implementation of this concept is demonstrated through the development of a Proof of Concept (PoC) darknet seeder, which supports a variety of network addresses including Onion, I2P, and Cjdns, alongside conventional IPv4. The PoC seeder utilizes a BIP155-like encoding to facilitate its operations across different networking protocols, with accessibility provided via IPv4 and Cjdns (through DNS/UDP) as well as Onion and I2P (via DNS/TCP), showcasing a versatile approach to address resolution.

Interestingly, the implementation also explores the use of NULL records within the DNS framework, presenting an alternative to the more commonly discussed TXT records. The conversation notes potential issues with TXT records, as highlighted by laanwj in a recent discussion on a related [GitHub issue](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30007issuecomment-2094289500). This observation points out the complexities and challenges involved with using DNS records in unconventional ways, suggesting a need for innovative solutions like the PoC seeder to overcome these limitations. Through this exploration, the dialogue contributes to the ongoing discourse on enhancing network protocols' efficiency and reliability by rethinking foundational aspects such as DNS dependency.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-10T13:13:40.200000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
