<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-12T02:15:09.915418+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>virtu</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-11T08:02:10.537000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T02:15:09.915444+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the use of NULL records in DNS for storing binary data, specifically within the context of a Pull Request on the Bitcoin GitHub repository. The referenced Pull Request, initiated by user achow101, aims to add a new DNS seeder and has sparked a conversation about the advantages and limitations of different DNS record types for this purpose. Initially, TXT records were considered for their potential to store "human-readable" data through base85 encoding of 256-bit keys or hashes pertinent to Onion/Tor addresses. However, this approach was eventually set aside in favor of NULL records. The preference for NULL records stems from their efficiency in handling binary data, despite TXT records' initial appeal due to their readability.

A key issue highlighted in the discussion is the lack of support for caching with certain DNS record types, as mentioned in a comment on the Pull Request. This could theoretically affect the performance and reliability of DNS seeders in the Bitcoin network. Nonetheless, the concern may be mitigated by the fact that most DNS seeds are configured with a Time-To-Live (TTL) of only 60 seconds. This short TTL implies that the impact of caching—or the lack thereof—on the bootstrapping process of nodes might be minimal, considering that very few nodes would utilize cached DNS data within such a brief interval.

The conversation underscores the technical nuances and considerations involved in optimizing DNS configurations for cryptocurrency networks. It reflects a careful balance between data format readability and system efficiency, alongside practical considerations such as caching capabilities and their implications for network performance. The exploration and eventual decision-making process exemplify the ongoing efforts by developers to refine and enhance the underlying infrastructure supporting digital currencies like Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-11T08:02:10.537000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
