<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Privately sending payments while offline with BOLT12</title>
  <updated>2024-09-15T02:22:22.155959+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-14 11:30:29.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Privately sending payments while offline with BOLT12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-15T02:22:22.155989+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/privately-sending-payments-while-offline-with-bolt12/1134/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept discussed involves a novel approach to facilitating payments through encrypted data transfer using onion-message paths. This method allows the payer to securely send necessary messages, such as `update_add_htlc`, over an onion-message path rather than through the standard BOLT8 tunnel. This process is particularly useful when the mobile phone of the payer serves as the client for a Lightning Service Provider (LSP) or when interacting with a high-uptime home node.

The proposal outlines two key standards aimed at enhancing the efficiency and security of transactions. The first standard suggests a mechanism for remote control communication with a high-uptime home node via BOLT8, ensuring that users can manage their transactions remotely without compromising on security or functionality. The second standard focuses on enabling a high-uptime payee to create a "BOLT8 tunnel" over onion messages. This innovative approach facilitates the payee's assistance in helping the payer contact either its LSP or its high-uptime home node. Subsequently, the LSP or the high-uptime home node converts the received onion messages into BOLT8 messages, treating them as if they were transmitted over a BOLT8 tunnel. 

This methodology significantly broadens the applicability of the system, accommodating both scenarios where the payer operates through a remote-controlled home node and where the payer uses a mobile phone connected to an LSP. By implementing these standards, the transaction process becomes more versatile, secure, and user-friendly, catering to a wider range of payment scenarios and user needs.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-14T11:30:29.672000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
