<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Privately sending payments while offline with BOLT12</title>
  <updated>2024-09-15T02:22:11.988190+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andyschroder 2024-09-14 15:48:20.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Privately sending payments while offline with BOLT12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-15T02:22:11.988226+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/privately-sending-payments-while-offline-with-bolt12/1134/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of liquidity service providers (LSPs), the distinction between custodial and non-custodial services emerges as a focal point. Custodial LSPs, by definition, involve a third party that holds and manages the funds on behalf of users. This model is widely recognized for its ability to streamline transactions by reducing the complexity for end-users. It offers enhanced security measures and simplifies the process of engaging with digital assets, making it an attractive option for those new to the space or seeking convenience. However, this convenience often comes at the cost of control, as users must entrust their assets to another entity, introducing potential risks associated with mismanagement or security breaches.

On the other hand, non-custodial LSPs prioritize user sovereignty by allowing individuals to maintain direct control over their assets without intermediary involvement. This approach aligns with the foundational principles of decentralization inherent to blockchain technology, offering users full autonomy and reducing reliance on third parties. Non-custodial services mitigate some risks associated with custodial platforms, notably those related to trust and security. However, they also place greater responsibility on the user to manage and secure their own assets, which can be daunting for those less familiar with the technology.

The choice between custodial and non-custodial LSPs thus hinges on a trade-off between convenience and control. Users must weigh their comfort level with technological complexities against their desire for autonomy in managing their digital assets. Each type of service offers distinct advantages and challenges, making the decision a highly individual one based on personal priorities, technical expertise, and risk tolerance.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-14T15:48:20.342000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
