<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-17T01:55:51.977079+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-16T21:37:03.601000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-17T01:55:51.977107+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry delves into the potential of utilizing a specific technological framework to facilitate small bitcoin transactions in developing nations, emphasizing the significance of low transaction fees and instant transfer capabilities. This raises questions about the scalability and efficiency of such a system for both minor and substantial payments. Furthermore, the discussion points towards the essential role of liveness in maintaining a trustless environment, pondering whether these attributes can be effectively integrated within a mobile application framework.

Concerns are also expressed regarding the resilience of the system, particularly in scenarios where legal or regulatory actions might lead to the shutdown of key infrastructure components like the Lightning Service Providers (LSPs). This leads to an exploration of the worst-case outcomes for users and the overall network stability in such events. The query extends to the system's capacity to handle scaling, specifically with 1MB block sizes, and whether this could support a vast user base—potentially billions—without necessitating modifications to the underlying Bitcoin protocol.

Lastly, the conversation shifts towards practical applications and development progress, questioning whether there are ongoing efforts to implement this technology. It probes the compatibility with existing solutions such as LND (Lightning Network Daemon) or CLN (C-lightning), and whether integration could be achieved through plugins or layers, or if a completely new node infrastructure, possibly developed with the Lightning Development Kit (LDK), would be required to realize this vision.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-16T21:37:03.601000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
