<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
  <updated>2024-09-17T01:54:50.964563+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-16T22:06:50.868000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
    <updated>2024-09-17T01:54:50.964600+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proving-utxo-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge/1142/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The tool currently under discussion represents an early-stage prototype designed for proving UTXO ownership with specific performance metrics recorded on an Apple M1 Max laptop equipped with 32GB of RAM. The process of generating a proof takes approximately 6 minutes, resulting in a proof file size of 1.4 MB. This is contingent upon the UTXO set being pre-loaded into memory utilizing a Utreexo data structure, a method for efficiently storing and verifying UTXO sets. Verification of the generated proof contrasts sharply in terms of speed, requiring only about 300 milliseconds to complete. 

To place these figures in context, a comparison with another solution, [aut-ct](https://github.com/AdamISZ/aut-ct), is suggested, though specific comparative metrics are not provided within the given content. This comparison implies a benchmarking perspective, where the performance (in terms of both speed and proof size) of this tool is evaluated against existing solutions, highlighting its potential advantages or disadvantages. This information is critical for understanding the practicality and efficiency of the tool in real-world applications, especially regarding blockchain technologies where such metrics directly impact usability and scalability.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-16T22:06:50.868000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
