<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-19T02:17:37.805301+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-18 16:17:04.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T02:17:37.805332+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of managing liquidity in Lightning Network Service Providers (LSPs) involves several adaptive strategies to ensure that clients have access to the necessary liquidity for their transactions. When a client's leaf partner is offline or the leaf's liquidity has been depleted, LSPs employ various mechanisms to maintain transaction flow. One primary method includes the use of Just-In-Time (JIT) channels. If a client’s direct partner is not available, instead of reaching out to other potential partners like `C` or `D`, the LSP may opt for an onchain fallback solution by opening a JIT channel with LSP-single-signature funds already available on the blockchain. This approach ensures that transactions can proceed without unnecessary delays, maintaining the network's efficiency and reliability.

In cases where online partners are present but unable to provide the required liquidity due to depletion, the LSP attempts to source liquidity from other leaves within the network. The strategy involves attempting to wake up secondary partners (`C` and `D`) to utilize their leaf's liquidity. However, should these partners also be offline or otherwise unavailable, the LSP defaults back to the onchain JIT channel strategy to fulfill the liquidity requirement. This fallback mechanism acts as a safety net, ensuring the network remains functional even under less-than-ideal conditions.

For more intricate liquidity management and optimization, adopting techniques from the field of transactional memory could offer advanced solutions. Specifically, the concept of optimistic locking and a sophisticated scheduling system for locking and unlocking clients based on their online status and participation capability could enhance liquidity distribution. By "locking" a client, the LSP reserves its participation in a liquidity transfer until all necessary conditions are met and signatures are obtained. This method allows for efficient allocation of liquidity across the network while minimizing the risk of locking resources unnecessarily. High concurrency levels can be achieved by limiting locks primarily to a client and its immediate leaf partner, thus allowing for a more dynamic and responsive liquidity management system.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-18T16:17:04.470000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
