<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-21T02:14:01.749460+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-20T15:23:05.543000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-21T02:14:01.749490+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>CoinShuffle and its improved version, CoinShuffle++, are designed to enhance privacy in cryptocurrency transactions. Despite their advancements, both versions depend on a coordination mechanism for communication. This mechanism operates similarly to a bulletin board, which primarily receives messages and disseminates them to the participants. However, this approach does not completely address the centralization issues associated with transaction mixing methods like CoinJoin. The process of grouping participants into sessions remains a significant challenge, highlighting the limitations of these protocols in overcoming the practical difficulties of decentralized operation.

The discussion also acknowledges a critical aspect of privacy-oriented cryptocurrency transactions - the centralization of communication. While CoinShuffle(++) aims to mitigate one form of centralization through its unique approach, it fails to address the broader issue of communication centralization effectively. This is particularly relevant when considering other implementations such as Wasabi and Samurai, which also grapple with similar challenges. The conversation suggests that the only known method to avoid selective censorship effectively is to utilize the blockchain, though it is impractical for this purpose. An alternative, somewhat humorous suggestion is the use of ham radio, indicating the ongoing search for viable solutions to achieve truly decentralized and uncensored communication within these privacy-enhancing technologies.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-20T15:23:05.543000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
