<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-24T02:22:18.916667+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-23 06:13:27.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-24T02:22:18.916708+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent Lightning protocol development summit introduced an innovative concept that could significantly impact how transactions are managed within the system. A notable suggestion was the implementation of a sign-only-once scheme. This scheme, unlike traditional methods, allows for a more efficient and secure transaction process, particularly in multi-client environments.

The principle behind this proposed method involves the allocation of funds by the Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) in a leaf, which is determined by the number of clients connected to that leaf. Specifically, it was explained that for a leaf supporting two clients, an LSP could allocate one-third of its funds while only one client is online. This allocation strategy scales with the number of clients, suggesting that for a leaf with N clients, an LSP could allocate 1/(N+1) of its funds when just one client is present. This approach not only optimizes fund distribution but also enhances the system's flexibility and responsiveness to varying online client counts.

Additionally, a potential framework for implementing the sign-only-once scheme without the need for `OP_CAT` was shared, offering a glimpse into the practical application of this concept. The document detailing these possible constructions can be found at [https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/025](https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/025). This reference serves as a foundational guide for developers and researchers interested in exploring and applying this innovative scheme within the Lightning network, marking a significant step towards improving transaction efficiency and security.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-23T06:13:27.123000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
