<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-24T02:19:24.459198+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-23 12:49:42.885000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-24T02:19:24.459225+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the technical specifics and challenges associated with implementing privacy features in blockchain transactions, specifically addressing the limitations of using `SINGLE|ACP` (SIGHASH_SINGLE | SIGHASH_ANYONECANPAY). This method historically faced criticism due to its requirement for matching input and output indices in a transaction, which complicates the achievement of privacy. The conversation implies an inquiry into alternative solutions or documentation that might outline how to circumvent these constraints, suggesting a desire for a more flexible and private transaction mechanism.

Moreover, the conversation shifts to explore the functionality and purpose of Nostr relay addresses. Contrary to initial assumptions, it clarifies that the primary aim of Nostr relays is not to facilitate coinjoin transactions—a method used for enhancing privacy by combining multiple payments from several users into one transaction to obscure the source of funds. Instead, it's highlighted that there are nearly a thousand Nostr relays available, which can be utilized for sharing Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs). This indicates a significant infrastructure ready for use, albeit without built-in peer discovery features. Users are required either to discover peers on their own or to operate a relay themselves to share information, emphasizing a decentralized approach to network participation and resource sharing.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-23T12:49:42.885000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
