<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
  <updated>2024-09-25T02:20:46.851571+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson.321000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-24T20:57:13.321000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
    <updated>2024-09-25T02:20:46.851604+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proving-utxo-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge/1142/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and nuances of maintaining privacy within the context of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) in a zero-knowledge setting, specifically in relation to the Lightning Network (LN). It highlights the inherent difficulty in tracking when channels close due to the private nature of transactions, which fundamentally differentiates it from non-private versions. This distinction underscores the complexity of ensuring both privacy and functionality in decentralized networks.

An interesting proposal is made to address this challenge: mandating the generation of proofs at regular intervals, optimistically considering a 24-hour update cycle. This approach suggests that participants could verify their transactions based on snapshots of UTXOs within this timeframe. Although this idea aims to mitigate the issue of untraceable channel closures, it is acknowledged that such a solution might be impractical for larger networks like the LN due to potential performance constraints.

Moreover, the conversation touches upon various subtleties involved in implementing such a system. These include the technical details and potential strategies to balance between privacy concerns and the operational demands of maintaining an up-to-date channel graph within the LN. The discussion implicitly invites further exploration of these finesses, hinting at the broader implications for network performance and the user experience in decentralized financial systems.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-24T20:57:13.321000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
