<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
  <updated>2024-09-28T02:17:26.000409+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon.255000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-09-27T18:42:02.255000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proof-of-work based signet faucet</title>
    <updated>2024-09-28T02:17:26.000440+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proof-of-work-based-signet-faucet/937/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses a specific type of Pay to Proof of Work (P2W) address found in testnet4, which is accessible at [mempool.space/testnet4/address/tb1qzsjnew5qcn75e4cqdsc6r9v8fjy5ensancqmv2l2n82p0q5f5tls758l9d](https://mempool.space/testnet4/address/tb1qzsjnew5qcn75e4cqdsc6r9v8fjy5ensancqmv2l2n82p0q5f5tls758l9d). The script associated with this address utilizes an operation sequence that checks for a signature size of less than 60 bytes. This specificity allows for a unique method of adjusting the difficulty of generating a valid signature by incrementally reducing the signature byte size, thus altering the grinding necessity of the s-value while the R-value remains constant. This technique does not require any changes to the consensus or the addition of new operations, such as OP_CAT, making it applicable across various platforms including the main network.

The method showcases an efficient strategy for implementing Pay to Proof of Work addresses by leveraging the characteristics of DER signatures and the P2WSH format. It highlights the advantage of using P2WSH over P2SH to avoid creating non-standard transactions, thereby ensuring compatibility and standardization within the blockchain framework. This approach stands out for its simplicity and the fact that it can be integrated into existing systems without necessitating significant modifications to the underlying protocol.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T18:42:02.255000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
