<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-10-08T02:22:43.534888+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-10-07 18:52:54.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-10-07 18:44:30.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-10-04 01:08:45.612000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-10-03 02:17:32.089000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-10-02 22:55:05.349000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-10-02 22:48:07.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-10-02 16:41:04.524000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-30 00:10:27.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-09-29 22:59:07.757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-26 04:30:47.207000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-23 06:57:54.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-23 06:13:27.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-20 22:42:45.372000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-18 17:22:08.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-09-18 16:29:35.717000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-18 16:17:04.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-09-18 14:37:42.673000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-17 21:55:37.586000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-09-17 07:28:54.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 23:54:39.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-09-16 21:37:03.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 20:08:19.856000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3329_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3328_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3322_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3312_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3311_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3310_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3309_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3303_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3302_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3271_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3248_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3246_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3240_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3222_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3220_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3219_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3217_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3215_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3206_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3202_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3199_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3197_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T02:22:43.535030+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse provides a deep dive into the complexities and innovations within cryptocurrency transaction management, specifically focusing on Bitcoin transactions and the Lightning Network. It begins by highlighting the inherent issues with custodial Bitcoin wallets and contrasts these with the Lightning and SuperScalar schemes, which offer a potentially more secure offchain state that aims for reconciliation with the onchain state, despite not being guaranteed. This comparison underlines the importance of striving for improvements in transaction mechanisms over seeking perfect solutions, especially when considering the limitations of custodial setups where users' funds are at the mercy of the custodian's integrity.

Further examination delves into the technicalities of addenda like CLTV Locktime and the implications of Decker-Wattenhofer Relative Delays on HTLCs (Hashed Time-Locked Contracts), which introduce minimum CLTV-deltas affecting the liquidity service provider's (LSP) ability to manage channel states efficiently. The discussion extends to asymmetric onchain fee schemes for Poon-Dryja, suggesting innovations in commitment transaction fee structures to better accommodate clients within the Lightning Network, especially in the context of zero-fee commitment transactions and the challenge of exogenous fees.

Practical aspects of transitioning between off-chain and on-chain transactions are scrutinized, revealing the nuanced realities versus theoretical expectations. Through examples like assisted exits and the handling of PTLCs (Point Time Locked Contracts), insights into the operational challenges and strategies for maintaining transaction integrity and fairness between clients and LSPs are presented. These include mechanisms for ensuring timely transaction settlements and addressing potential vulnerabilities within the transaction process.

The narrative also explores alternative liquidity transaction models within the pseudo-Spilman multiparty channel factory setup, emphasizing the reduction of complexity and potential locktime liabilities through structural modifications. However, it also acknowledges the risks associated with direct transaction replacements and the measures to prevent unsafe operations, such as obligating the LSP to ensure the integrity of liquidity stock UTXOs. 

A broader discussion on the incentives for LSPs to cover unilateral exit costs highlights the strategic considerations for maintaining a stable and reliable service. This includes minimizing operational risks and encouraging assisted exits to streamline the reclaiming of funds. The introduction of `nVersion=3` transactions and the SuperScalar framework is noted for its approach to managing zero-fee transactions and ensuring transaction finality and security, including strategies to mitigate risks in high-fee market conditions.

Innovations proposed at the Lightning protocol development summit, such as LSP-assisted exits and a sign-only-once scheme, reflect ongoing efforts to enhance transaction efficiency and privacy within the network. These proposals aim to improve flexibility for clients while exiting and optimize fund allocation among multiple clients in a leaf. 

Lastly, the discussion touches on the challenges and potential of implementing technologies for facilitating small Bitcoin transactions, especially in developing nations. It emphasizes the importance of scalability, efficiency, and the ability to maintain trustless operations, alongside the resilience of the system against regulatory actions. The conversation culminates in speculative considerations about the future implementation and integration of these advancements with existing Lightning Network infrastructure, pondering the practical applications and development progress toward addressing the Last-Mile Problem (LMP) in the Bitcoin Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2024-10-07T18:52:54.385000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
