<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:48.951830+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-10 13:13:40.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2024-09-10 12:51:20.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu 2024-09-10 08:42:24.774000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3152_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3151_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3149_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T02:14:48.951893+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the proposition of eliminating the reliance on DNS for discovering Bitcoin nodes, suggesting an alternative approach that involves using the IP addresses of nodes managed by developers. These nodes would be capable of responding to `getaddr` requests, facilitating bootstrapping without the need for DNS seeds. A proof of concept (PoC) darknet seeder has been developed, showcasing the ability to serve Onion, I2P, and Cjdns addresses through various protocols including IPv4, Cjdns (DNS/UDP), Onion, and I2P (DNS/TCP). This approach utilizes a BIP155-like encoding and demonstrates an innovative use of NULL records for addressing, despite concerns about the feasibility of using TXT records due to potential issues highlighted in a recent GitHub issue comment.

The conversation further explores the compatibility of these NULL encodings with the `getaddrinfo` function across different platforms, considering the limitations that darknet-only nodes face in utilizing DNS seeds to discover Bitcoin network addresses. To assess the viability of hardcoded seed data for these nodes, statistics were compiled showing the longevity and reachability of hardcoded seed nodes over time. The analysis, represented in charts, indicates varying lifespans for seed nodes across network types, with IPv4 nodes showing the shortest lifespan and I2P nodes demonstrating greater durability, even in the face of a DoS attack. Interestingly, there appeared to be an omission in updating seed nodes during the v26 release, affecting network connectivity.

This dialogue underscores the challenges and considerations in enhancing the resilience and accessibility of Bitcoin nodes, especially for darknet-only configurations. The PoC darknet seeder project is positioned as a potential solution to these challenges, offering a method to integrate Onion, I2P, and Cjdns addresses into the Bitcoin network's infrastructure. This initiative raises questions about the necessity and practicality of such adaptations, particularly in the context of mixed clearnet-darknet nodes versus darknet-only nodes. Feedback and further examination are encouraged to explore the implications and effectiveness of this approach in supporting decentralized digital currency networks.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-10T13:13:40.200000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
