<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Expanding on BOLT12</title>
  <updated>2024-11-12T02:15:54.442754+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andyschroder.435000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>accumulator  ..433000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andyschroder  ..582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andyschroder  ..142000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andyschroder  ..934000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3508_Expanding-on-BOLT12.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3373_Expanding-on-BOLT12.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3326_Expanding-on-BOLT12.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3304_Expanding-on-BOLT12.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3280_Expanding-on-BOLT12.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Expanding on BOLT12</title>
    <updated>2024-11-12T02:15:54.442808+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/expanding-on-bolt12/1167" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions and developments around BOLT12 have introduced innovative concepts aimed at enhancing the blockchain ecosystem's efficiency and security. Among these, the notion of "Bundled Payments" stands out as a pivotal addition. This concept allows for the creation of invoices that can accommodate two separate preimages and amounts, primarily targeting services that require an upfront mining fee. This is especially relevant for non-custodian exchanges and plays a crucial role in submarine swaps and Just-In-Time (JIT) channels, which are critical for secure transactions within the blockchain network.

One of the notable gaps identified in the BOLT12 specification is the absence of a defined prefix for invoices. To bridge this gap, there's a proposal to adopt the `lni` prefix, which, while not officially specified, has found its application in Core Lightning (CLN) for certain Remote Procedure Calls (RPC), such as `fetchinvoice` and `pay`. The use of `lni` in these contexts suggests an emerging standard within the community, highlighting the need for a formalized approach to invoice prefixes.

Interestingly, the proposed enhancements to BOLT12, including the adoption of the `lni` prefix and the introduction of bundled payments, are suggested to be implemented as a bLIP (Bitcoin Improvement Proposal) rather than amending the existing specifications. This approach ensures that the core functionalities of BOLT12 remain accessible to users who may not opt for the new features. Further insights into the implementation of trusted contacts within BOLT12, without disrupting its foundational operations, are discussed comprehensively at [delvingbitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bolt-12-trusted-contacts/1046).

Recent developments have seen BOLT12 merged into the main repository, marking significant progress in its practical application. This merger initiates discussions on further enhancements, such as the need for `invoice_request` and `invoice` writers to replicate all fields from their predecessors, including unknown ones. This introduces a level of structural flexibility that could facilitate the addition of new fields in a backward-compatible manner. Proposals under consideration include adding a `user` field within the `invoice_request` and introducing a `refund_invoice_required` field for `offer` writers, which would streamline the refund process by automating refunds and eliminating the need for direct interaction with customers for each transaction. Moreover, the suggestion to establish an `offer_max_amount` within the `offer` structure aims to address operational constraints and preferences, enhancing transaction management and customer relationship expectations.

The absence of an expiration mechanism for `invoice_request`s poses challenges in managing offer lifecycles, particularly where timing is crucial. Implementing an expiry similar to that of `offers` and `invoices` could improve the protocol's efficiency and reliability. These discussions reflect a collective effort to refine BOLT12, inviting community feedback to guide its evolution in addressing the diverse needs and challenges of real-world implementations.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-12T00:26:55.435000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
