<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-24T02:19:44.248213+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson 2024-09-23 18:48:34.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-23 12:50:43.605000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-23 12:49:42.885000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-21 15:17:30.948000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-21 01:44:52.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 22:46:58.079000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 15:23:05.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-09-20 14:03:45.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3252_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3250_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3249_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3244_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3242_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3241_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3238_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3237_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-24T02:19:44.248354+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation largely focuses on the intricacies and challenges associated with implementing privacy-centric protocols in cryptocurrency transactions, particularly those that enhance anonymity without relying on centralized coordination. A key point of discussion is the SINGLE|ACP protocol, which, despite its potential for maintaining transaction privacy, faces scrutiny over its requirement for matching input/output indices. This limitation has historically discouraged further analysis due to privacy concerns. However, the dialogue suggests a keen interest in exploring methods to circumvent these issues, indicating a broader quest within the community to refine and innovate upon existing transaction protocols to better protect user anonymity.

Joinstr and Joinmarket emerge as significant topics, with each platform addressing the centralization of communication coordination in coinjoin implementations from different angles. Joinstr is highlighted for its use of the SIGHASH ALL | SIGHASH ANYONECANPAY signature hash, offering more flexibility in transaction signing. An intriguing aspect of Joinstr’s development is its potential upgrade to support covenants, promising enhanced security and functionality for users. On the other hand, Joinmarket has evolved from relying on a single IRC server for communication coordination to employing "directory nodes" for peer-to-peer encrypted messaging, aiming to mitigate censorship and promote larger coinjoins.

CoinShuffle and CoinShuffle++ are discussed concerning their approach to solving the centralization issue in transaction mixing, although they still rely on a form of coordination mechanism akin to a bulletin board. This reveals a persistent challenge across different implementations in achieving decentralized operation without compromising on privacy or efficiency. The text also touches on the limitations of Joinmarket's directory node model, which, despite facilitating direct maker-taker interactions, has encountered practical challenges that hinder its effectiveness.

A notable advancement is the Trezor Suite application's support for CoinJoin transactions, reflecting a trend towards offering users more flexibility in selecting coordinators. This development underscores an ongoing effort within the community to adapt and improve tools for enhancing transaction privacy.

The discussion extends to the broader implications of recent crackdowns on non-custodial privacy tools, emphasizing the closure of coordinator servers for Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet. These events have prompted a search for alternatives, such as JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin, which represents a shift towards self-hosted coordinator services using protocols like WabiSabi. This situation illustrates the dynamic nature of the Bitcoin privacy landscape as it responds to regulatory pressures and seeks to maintain the integrity of privacy-enhancing technologies.

In summary, the text delves into the technical and operational aspects of various cryptocurrency privacy solutions, highlighting both their achievements and the hurdles they face in striving for decentralization and user anonymity. The ongoing dialogue among developers and users reflects a robust and evolving ecosystem committed to advancing privacy and security in the digital currency space.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-23T18:48:34.794000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
