<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
  <updated>2024-09-18T02:16:02.149699+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2024-09-17 08:55:29.319000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2024-09-17 08:50:38.823000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2024-09-17 08:34:23.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-09-17 07:35:03.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-09-17 02:00:23.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-16 22:06:50.868000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2024-09-16 13:01:59.427000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3211_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3210_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3209_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3207_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3203_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3200_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3195_Proving-UTXO-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proving UTXO set inclusion in zero-knowledge</title>
    <updated>2024-09-18T02:16:02.149765+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proving-utxo-set-inclusion-in-zero-knowledge/1142/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the potential and limitations of using cryptographic proofs to enhance privacy and security in blockchain transactions, particularly within the context of the Lightning Network (LN). A notable suggestion is the publication of a hash of the private key alongside the proof to verify the correspondence with the non-blinded public key. This approach aims to maintain the integrity and confidentiality of transactions while ensuring transparency and trustworthiness.

The conversation further delves into the technical aspects of utilizing the utreexo data structure for efficiently managing and verifying Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) sets. The utreexo model is highlighted for its straightforward conversion to a deterministic representation per block, which facilitates the validation of channel openings on the blockchain. However, concerns are raised regarding the longevity and reliability of these channels, proposing the idea of requiring proofs to be refreshed periodically to include evidence of the channel's age and preventing the reuse of public keys for multiple proofs.

Comparisons are made between different cryptographic tools, namely aut-ct and utxozkp, pointing out their respective advantages in terms of speed, proof size, and the flexibility to reveal additional information about the outputs. Despite these advancements, challenges persist in guaranteeing the uniqueness of UTXO sets in proofs, thus raising doubts about their effectiveness in preventing double-spending and replay attacks against LN nodes.

The discourse also examines the practicality of integrating these cryptographic solutions into the LN's operational framework. It suggests modifications to improve the verifiability and non-reusability of UTXOs in channel announcements. These enhancements aim to prevent potential misuse while promoting more secure and efficient transaction verification processes.

An early-stage prototype tool, referred to as `utxozkp`, emerges as a significant development towards achieving these goals. The tool leverages the RISC Zero STARK platform and Utreexo data structure to facilitate the proof of UTXO set inclusion without revealing specific transaction details, thereby enhancing privacy for LN channel announcements. Despite its preliminary status, `utxozkp` demonstrates promising performance metrics and serves as a foundation for further innovation in blockchain privacy and security mechanisms. Its current capabilities and limitations are documented in the project's [README](https://github.com/halseth/utxozkp/blob/c3402a72005d8d1058f758ed277df9e6cafcac72/README.md), inviting community feedback and collaboration for future improvements.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-17T08:55:29.319000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
