<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-19T02:18:06.429680+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-18 17:22:08.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-09-18 16:29:35.717000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-18 16:17:04.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-09-18 14:37:42.673000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-17 21:55:37.586000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-09-17 07:28:54.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 23:54:39.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-09-16 21:37:03.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 20:08:19.856000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3222_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3220_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3219_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3217_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3215_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3206_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3202_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3199_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3197_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T02:18:06.429754+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around innovative strategies for managing liquidity and transaction outputs within the framework of Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) to optimize Bitcoin transactions. It reveals a multifaceted approach aimed at enhancing the efficiency of small bitcoin transactions, particularly in developing nations where low transaction fees and instant transfers are paramount. The primary focus is on a system that minimizes the reliance on Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) by introducing a mechanism where LSPs manage funds for numerous clients through a structure termed a "factory." This structure significantly reduces the need for individual UTXOs per client, potentially decreasing transaction costs and increasing scalability.

A notable aspect of this system is its reliance on users' online presence during specific periods, which is essential for transitioning between factories or executing unilateral exits. Mobile applications play a crucial role here, utilizing notifications to prompt users for necessary cryptographic operations. This method suggests a significant decrease in asynchronous payment requirements, aiming for an enhanced user experience without sacrificing security.

The proposal also delves into technical challenges associated with unilateral exits, highlighting the need for publishing multiple transactions based on the number of clients in a factory. The complexity of managing these exits efficiently is underscored, with different tree arities affecting the process's overall cost and efficiency. The ultimate goal is to expand channel-opening capacity substantially, likening it to a theoretical increase in block size, thereby supporting millions of clients while maintaining trustless principles.

Furthermore, the inquiry raises pertinent questions about the scalability and resilience of such a system amidst potential regulatory shutdowns of LSPs. It explores the feasibility of supporting a vast user base with existing blockchain parameters and probes into the practicality of integrating this new system with current Lightning Network implementations like LND or CLN. The possibility of requiring new infrastructure, possibly developed using the Lightning Development Kit (LDK), is considered for realizing the proposed vision.

Lastly, the SuperScalar mechanism is introduced as a solution to the Last-Mile Problem in the Bitcoin Lightning Network. This advanced construction combines Decker-Wattenhofer decrementing-`nSequence` mechanisms, timeout trees, and laddering strategies to facilitate efficient, offchain liquidity allocation without necessitating changes to blockchain consensus. It aims to secure against fund theft, operate despite blockchain ossification, and accommodate offline users. This mechanism's practical considerations include incentivizing user online presence, grouping clients for liquidity allocation efficiency, and determining optimal tree structures for balancing update efficiency against the costs of exits. This comprehensive approach addresses liquidity challenges in the Lightning Network, offering a scalable, flexible solution for enhancing Bitcoin transaction efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-18T17:22:08.812000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
