<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-18T02:16:47.089849+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-17 21:55:37.586000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-09-17 07:28:54.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 23:54:39.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-09-16 21:37:03.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 20:08:19.856000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3215_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3206_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3202_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3199_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3197_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-18T02:16:47.089904+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and proposed solutions for managing unilateral exit costs within the Lightning Network, specifically focusing on the responsibilities of Lightning Service Providers (LSPs). LSPs are incentivized to deliver superior service to prevent clients from unilaterally exiting, which could potentially drain the LSP's resources. This situation arises due to the design of the timeout condition within the network, compelling all clients to be online before the timeout expires to either exit the system or engage in an assisted exit with the cooperation of the LSP. However, this mechanism can lead to issues, particularly when there is a mass off-chain force-closure, leading to a congested blockchain as numerous unilateral exits compete for limited block space. The proposed solution involves managing Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) by having LSPs handle them for multiple clients through a system that requires users to come online at least once during the lifespan of a "factory," usually set for about a month. This approach introduces a grace period, or "dying period," towards the end of each factory cycle, during which users must make critical decisions regarding their continued participation.

The proposed system emphasizes mobile application use cases, leveraging notifications to prompt users for necessary cryptographic operations, potentially reducing the need for asynchronous payment receipt. A significant challenge highlighted is the publication of O(N) transactions during a unilateral exit, where N represents the number of clients in a factory. The complexity and cost associated with these transactions are contingent upon the tree structure organizing these exits, affecting overall process efficiency. This methodology aims to significantly enhance channel-opening capacity, equating to an increase in block size to 10Mb, thereby supporting millions of clients without compromising trustlessness. Yet, this concept lacks current implementations and would necessitate the development of new client-side software and integration into existing node software on the LSP side, with CLN mentioned as possibly supporting this via plugins for payment routing.

Additionally, the conversation touches upon the utilization of this technological framework for facilitating small bitcoin transactions in developing countries, highlighting the importance of low transaction fees and instant transfer capabilities. It explores the scalability of the system for handling payments of varying sizes and its ability to maintain a trustless environment within a mobile application context. Concerns about the resilience of the system in face of legal or regulatory actions against LSPs are discussed, considering the potential impact on users and network stability. Questions regarding ongoing development efforts, compatibility with existing solutions like LND and CLN, and whether integration or entirely new infrastructure development is necessary, are raised.

Lastly, the SuperScalar mechanism is introduced as a solution to the Last-Mile Problem in the Bitcoin Lightning Network, combining Decker-Wattenhofer decrementing-`nSequence` mechanisms, timeout trees, and laddering strategies. This mechanism aims to provide efficient offchain liquidity allocation without needing blockchain consensus changes. It addresses fund theft security, blockchain ossification, and user offline status challenges by enabling offchain consensus among multiple users and structuring transactions in a way that supports scalable and efficient exits and updates. The incorporation of laddering strategies allows LSPs flexibility in liquidity management, potentially increasing returns while offering users tailored liquidity options. Practical considerations for implementing the SuperScalar mechanism include incentivizing user online presence, grouping clients based on likely online times for efficient liquidity allocations, and optimizing tree structures to balance update efficiency against unilateral exit costs.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-17T21:55:37.586000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
