<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-09-06T02:14:54.138989+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3101_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3099_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3097_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3095_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3035_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3032_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3031_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3028_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3030_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3029_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3026_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3025_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3024_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3007_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3003_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3006_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3004_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T02:14:54.139183+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of cryptographic security, a novel approach known as "Dark Smoothie" has been brought to light, revealing a significant vulnerability within digital transactions. This method allows an attacker to extract sensitive information, specifically a 256-bit seed, from just two signatures generated by the same device. The attack circumvents the need for complex mathematical manipulations, relying instead on signing transactions with inputs secured by the same private key. This process enables critical information leakage directly to the attacker through an encrypted channel. By leveraging specific values and hash functions in conjunction with the private key and an attacker's secret, the attacker can deduce the `256_bit_secret`. Such vulnerabilities are particularly concerning due to their activation potential through common activities like "dusting" an address, where small amounts of cryptocurrency are sent to unveil identity details. Countermeasures like level 2 or 3 Anti-Exfil protocols offer some defense, assuming the companion applications remain uncompromised.

Further discussions delve into the potential of implementing a 4-bit checksum as a security measure against unauthorized data extraction. Although this strategy introduces computational hardening, its effectiveness remains limited if the checksum doesn't vary, merely delineating a fixed iteration challenge for attackers rather than presenting a quadratic problem. Setting a computational target time for signature verification aims to detect and deter attempts at leaking information, though this strategy's efficacy is contingent on the absence of flaws or oversights.

The complexity of distinguishing signatures derived from a common seed highlights the intricate challenges in cryptographic security, emphasizing the necessity for advanced decoding algorithms that can tolerate and incorporate errors. This consideration underscores the sophistication required in designing security measures capable of defending against such analytical attacks. Additionally, the concept of leaking secrets through deterministically selected bits of a large checksum in every signature presents a theoretically viable yet practically challenging method for secret extraction, reliant on the attacker's knowledge or guesses regarding the origins of signatures.

Concerns extend to securing devices beyond software and firmware threats, pointing towards vulnerabilities inherent in the physical construction of devices, including side channel and radio frequency leaks. This broadens the scope of cybersecurity, necessitating comprehensive protective measures.

The feasibility of employing Forward Error Correction (FEC) codes to estimate the number of signatures required for compromising 128 or 256-bit seeds is discussed, illustrating the balance between computational effort and the ability to leak information. This discussion extends to the computational costs related to double point multiplications and hashing, highlighting the potential for even limited hardware to pose substantial security threats if exploited correctly.

A proposed protocol enhances cryptographic practices through a secure hash commitment, aiming to bolster integrity and confidentiality during data transmission. This involves sophisticated computations and verifications by both software and hardware components, signaling advancements in secure communication protocols.

An anti-exfiltration variant tailored for air-gapped signing devices utilizing Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) integrates into QR code-based signing workflows, offering enhanced protection against private key exfiltration. This protocol underscores the importance of secure transaction signing in isolated environments.

Lastly, the term "vector commitment" and its application to enhancing transaction signing processes through a cryptographically strong hash, `vector_commit`, demonstrates flexibility across different cryptographic standards. This scheme simplifies interactions between host wallet applications and hardware signers, potentially overcoming traditional nonce aggregation challenges found in methods like MuSig2.

These discussions collectively advance the understanding of cryptographic security, emphasizing ongoing efforts to mitigate vulnerabilities and enhance the protection of digital transactions and communications.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-05T09:04:09.379000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
