<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-13T02:15:49.323467+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2024-09-12 21:47:52.189000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu 2024-09-12 19:40:15.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-12 18:41:16.485000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu 2024-09-12 06:03:21.076000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-09-11 18:05:17.683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-11 08:02:10.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-11 07:43:47.522000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-10 13:13:40.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-09-10 12:51:20.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-10 08:42:24.774000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3175_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3174_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3172_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3166_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3163_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3160_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3159_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3152_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3151_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3149_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-13T02:15:49.323549+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion delves into the technical intricacies of using DNS for Bitcoin node discovery, emphasizing the potential benefits and challenges of this approach. It introduces the idea of encoding data within AAAA records, which could be particularly useful for sharing IP addresses with non-default port numbers among nodes. This method would necessitate additional decoding logic in Bitcoin Core, triggered by a reserved prefix to distinguish these encoded addresses from standard IPv6 addresses. The feasibility of encoding Onion v3 and i2p addresses, which are longer than IPv6 addresses, is also considered. An example of encoding an IPv4 address and port number in an IPv6 address is provided, showcasing a practical application of this concept.

The conversation further explores various public nameservers and their caching behaviors concerning TXT and NULL records, concluding that while most support caching if certain criteria are met, the reliance on custom DNS lookups might not be pursued due to potential blockers. The advantages of DNS-based seeding for Bitcoin nodes are highlighted, including reduced operational costs and enhanced privacy through the use of global caching infrastructure and the difficulty for DNS seed operators to ascertain specific details about nodes. However, the complexity of external DNS dependencies and the potential loss of caching reliability when moving away from A/AAA records are recognized as significant concerns.

Technical discussions extend into the optimization of DNS configurations for cryptocurrency networks, with a focus on the efficiency of NULL records over TXT records for binary data handling. The limitations of `getaddrinfo` in only returning A and AAAA records lead to a suggested workaround involving direct DNS queries for NULL records, illustrated through a C++ code snippet. This approach aims at overcoming the conventional limitations of DNS querying within network protocols.

A shift towards eliminating DNS dependency by directly using IP addresses for node communication is proposed, highlighting a Proof of Concept (PoC) darknet seeder supporting various network addresses and utilizing BIP155-like encoding. Issues with traditional DNS record usage are discussed, alongside the exploration of NULL records as an alternative for better system efficiency. Furthermore, the discussion touches upon the cross-platform compatibility of NULL encodings and the importance of ensuring broad functionality across different systems.

Lastly, the viability of hardcoded seeds for Bitcoin connectivity is analyzed, revealing the challenges faced by nodes on different networks and the necessity of updating seed lists for maintaining robust connectivity. The development of a PoC darknet seeder is presented as a solution to enhance connectivity for darknet-only nodes, indicating a collaborative community effort towards improving Bitcoin's networking capabilities. The ongoing examination of custom DNS `NULL` queries within Bitcoin Core signifies a commitment to addressing the technical challenges associated with ensuring seamless connectivity for all types of nodes.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-12T21:47:52.189000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
