<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
  <updated>2024-09-30T02:25:00.936848+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-09-30 00:10:27.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2024-09-29 22:59:07.757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-26 04:30:47.207000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-23 06:57:54.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-23 06:13:27.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-20 22:42:45.372000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-18 17:22:08.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-09-18 16:29:35.717000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-18 16:17:04.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-09-18 14:37:42.673000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-17 21:55:37.586000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-09-17 07:28:54.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 23:54:39.760000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-09-16 21:37:03.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-09-16 20:08:19.856000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3303_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3302_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3271_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3248_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3246_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3240_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3222_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3220_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3219_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3217_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3215_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3206_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3202_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3199_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3197_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories</title>
    <updated>2024-09-30T02:25:00.936954+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories/1143/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>An assisted exit in the context of Lightning Network involves a procedure where a client initiates an exit from an in-factory construction to a Lightning Service Provider (LSP), followed by an onchain transaction from the LSP back to the user. This process is distinct from a scenario where the LSP unilaterally facilitates a user's exit and covers the associated onchain fees. The essence of this strategy is that it allows the LSP to reclaim in-factory funds sooner, particularly if all clients opt for assisted exits, including transitioning to newer factories. This mechanism benefits the LSP by enabling the recovery of funds directly from the funding outpoint immediately, bypassing the need for waiting periods required in unilateral exits and avoiding fees during high-fee periods. 

The SuperScalar protocol represents an advancement over previous versions by mandating non-zero fees for all tree nodes, thus ensuring self-sufficiency in fee generation within the system. It addresses potential attacks in high-fee conditions by modifying node parameters to prioritize transactions. However, vulnerabilities remain, especially with P2A outputs, prompting suggestions to exclude them from state transactions to safeguard against unauthorized confirmations.

Moreover, the proposal introduced at the Lightning proto dev summit focuses on enhancing privacy and flexibility for clients exiting from one factory to another. It outlines a method where clients can transfer their private keys to an LSP via PTLCs, facilitating a seamless transition of funds without planning to return to the original factory. This system provides benefits in scenarios where a client permanently exits, allowing the LSP to reallocate the client's funds efficiently and maintain privacy through Taproot keyspend paths.

Additionally, a sign-only-once scheme was suggested to improve transaction efficiency in multi-client environments. This strategy involves allocating funds based on the number of clients connected to a leaf, optimizing fund distribution and system responsiveness. A framework for implementing this scheme without `OP_CAT` offers practical insights into enhancing transaction security and efficiency.

The discussion also touches on mechanisms for reallocating liquidity within the Lightning Network, highlighting strategies like utilizing `OP_CAT` for direct fund transfers between an LSP and a client. Despite its potential, the proposal acknowledges challenges in adoption due to the necessity of consensus changes on the blockchain.

In terms of managing Bitcoin transactions, there's an emphasis on efficient UTXO usage by LSPs to provide liquidity while minimizing resource requirements. The proposed system envisions leveraging mobile app notifications to ensure client activity, facilitating a trustless environment for executing transactions. This concept aims to significantly increase channel-opening capacity, potentially supporting millions of clients by optimizing the use of blockchain resources.

Furthermore, the document explores technological frameworks to enable small bitcoin transactions in developing countries, focusing on low fees and instant transfers. It considers the scalability of such systems, the role of liveness in maintaining a trustless setting, and the resilience of the network against regulatory shutdowns. Questions about ongoing development efforts and compatibility with existing solutions like LND or CLN are raised, pondering the need for new infrastructure developments.

Lastly, the SuperScalar mechanism is discussed as a solution to the Last-Mile Problem in the Bitcoin Lightning Network, combining Decker-Wattenhofer decrementing-`nSequence` mechanisms, timeout trees, and laddering strategies for efficient offchain liquidity allocation. This approach aims to secure the network against fund theft and offer a scalable and flexible system for liquidity management, addressing the challenges of user onlineness and network scalability.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-30T00:10:27.537000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
