<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-21T02:14:24.821981+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson 2024-09-20 22:46:58.079000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson 2024-09-20 15:23:05.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>real-or-random 2024-09-20 14:03:45.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3241_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3238_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3237_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-21T02:14:24.822090+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the complexities of achieving decentralized communication coordination in cryptocurrency transactions, especially within the context of JoinMarket and CoinShuffle. JoinMarket has evolved from using a single IRC server for communication coordination to employing multiple redundant servers and later introducing "directory nodes." These changes aimed to enhance privacy and decentralization by facilitating peer-to-peer (P2P) interactions and using onion services for encrypted communication. Despite these advancements, challenges with ephemeral tor onion services have hindered the effectiveness of directory nodes, highlighting a persistent issue with decentralizing communication coordination.

CoinShuffle, on the other hand, relies on a bulletin board model for message broadcasting but still requires session assignment for participants, indicating that it too faces hurdles in completely overcoming centralized coordination. The discussion underscores the ongoing struggle within the cryptocurrency community to find a robust solution for decentralized transaction coordination that can avoid central points of control while ensuring privacy and security.

The email further touches upon a recent development where the Trezor Suite application has enabled support for CoinJoin transactions with alternative coordinators, providing a guide for users interested in utilizing different coordinators for their transactions. This represents a significant step towards offering users more flexibility and control over their privacy-enhancing transaction processes.

Moreover, the email highlights an initiative to develop a system that operates without hardcoded directory nodes or reliance on specific individuals, aiming for a sustainable and autonomous infrastructure. This initiative reflects the broader challenge of maintaining a decentralized network when volunteer involvement fluctuates, emphasizing the need for a reliable mechanism for peer discovery and interaction.

The JoinMarket messaging protocol is crucial for secure and private Bitcoin transactions, leveraging encrypted communication channels and a peer-to-peer network to maintain user anonymity. This protocol facilitates coinjoin transactions efficiently, contributing to a more decentralized financial system. The documentation on GitHub provides comprehensive insights into the messaging protocol's implementation, showcasing its importance in the JoinMarket ecosystem.

Lastly, the email discusses the implications of recent crackdowns on non-custodial privacy tools, leading to the shutdown of coordinator servers for prominent wallets like Samourai and Wasabi. In response, alternatives like JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin have emerged, focusing on operating without central coordinators and enabling users to host their own services. This shift towards self-hosted and decentralized solutions reflects the community's resilience and commitment to privacy, despite regulatory pressures. The evolution of Bitcoin privacy techniques continues to navigate through challenges, demonstrating the potential for innovative solutions to emerge in this dynamic landscape.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-20T22:46:58.079000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
