<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
  <updated>2024-09-24T02:21:21.433532+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>virtu 2024-09-23 14:33:41.084000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-09-12 21:47:52.189000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-12 19:40:15.647000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-12 18:41:16.485000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-12 06:03:21.076000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-09-11 18:05:17.683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-11 08:02:10.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-11 07:43:47.522000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-10 13:13:40.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-09-10 12:51:20.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  . 2024-09-10 08:42:24.774000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3251_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3175_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3174_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3172_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3166_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3163_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3160_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3159_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3152_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3151_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3149_Hardcoded-seeds-DNS-seeds-and-Darknet-nodes.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Hardcoded seeds, DNS seeds and Darknet nodes</title>
    <updated>2024-09-24T02:21:21.433617+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/hardcoded-seeds-dns-seeds-and-darknet-nodes/1123/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins by addressing a novel encoding mechanism devised to maintain the integrity of response entries' order. This is crucial given that recursive resolvers may alter the sequence, potentially leading to data misinterpretation. The proposed solution aims to preserve data reliability within systems where the original order of entries is vital.

Further, it delves into the technicalities of encoding information within DNS records, specifically AAAA records, highlighting an innovative approach to data transmission. By utilizing these records beyond their conventional use, it becomes possible to encode arbitrary data, showcasing the flexibility and potential for DNS records to convey additional information outside their original design parameters.

The conversation introduces a technique for encoding data within AAAA records, using a reserved prefix to distinguish encoded data from standard IPv6 addresses, ensuring compatibility with existing operations such as `getaddrinfo`. This method appears promising for sharing IPv4 addresses and their associated port numbers, suggesting a broader application for effectively encoding smaller address formats into AAAA records. Detailed insights into this encoding strategy are available in a shared document, [Encoding IPv4 address and port number in IPv6 address](https://gitlab.com/-/snippets/3746764), which provides further technical elaboration on its implementation.

In examining the caching capabilities of various public nameservers, a commonality in supporting TXT and NULL record caching emerges, contingent upon authoritative server criteria. This capability is pivotal for enhancing DNS query efficiency. However, complexities in implementing a custom DNS lookup strategy via TXT/NULL records lead to considering AAAA records for data encoding, offering an innovative method to embed information within DNS queries without impacting fundamental operations.

The narrative also explores DNS-based seeding for Bitcoin nodes, emphasizing the advantages of global caching infrastructure and universal OS support, which collectively reduce operational costs and bolster privacy. It acknowledges complexities stemming from external DNS dependencies or ad-hoc resolver implementations, suggesting direct P2P connections as a simpler alternative if certain benefits are relinquished. This shifts focus towards maintaining essential node discovery functionalities while navigating DNS-based seeding challenges.

A technical dialogue centers on utilizing NULL records in DNS for binary data storage, highlighting a preference over TXT records for their efficiency despite initial readability benefits. Concerns about caching support for different DNS record types are raised, albeit minimized by DNS seeds' short Time-To-Live (TTL), which suggests minimal impact on node bootstrapping processes. This reflects ongoing efforts to optimize DNS configurations for cryptocurrency networks, balancing data format readability against system efficiency.

The email includes a practical guide for querying DNS records without external libraries, showcasing a C++ code snippet for sending and receiving a NULL query. This illustrates the straightforward nature of DNS queries at a lower level, contrasting with higher-level abstractions that conceal these details.

Lastly, the discussion advocates for reducing DNS dependency within network protocols, proposing direct IP communication for node interactions. It highlights a Proof of Concept (PoC) darknet seeder supporting various network addresses, demonstrating the potential for NULL records in DNS to serve as an alternative for unconventional data transmission. This suggests rethinking foundational aspects like DNS dependency to enhance network protocol efficiency and reliability. Additionally, it emphasizes the need for cross-platform compatibility testing for functions like `getaddrinfo` with NULL encodings, underscoring the importance of broad functionality across different platforms.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-23T14:33:41.084000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
