<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-09-04T02:14:46.339079+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-09-03 21:28:46.874000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 19:35:39.046000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 17:30:10.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:33:51.311000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:12:12.049000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:08:10.563000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 15:06:55.908000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 14:32:38.344000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 14:06:59.185000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-21 13:08:17.268000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-20 18:53:47.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-20 18:40:40.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-20 17:02:38.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-08-20 15:26:52.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3095_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3035_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3032_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3031_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3028_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3030_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3029_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3026_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3025_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3024_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3007_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3003_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3006_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3004_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-09-04T02:14:46.339181+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation introduces a sophisticated cryptographic attack method named Dark Smoothie, which extends upon the previously known Dark Skippy vulnerability. Dark Smoothie exploits a scenario where a transaction is signed with two inputs locked by the same private key, allowing for the leakage of 256 bits (24 words) without complex mathematical operations. This attack leverages simple arithmetic on elliptic curves to extract secret keys from digital signatures when certain conditions are met. It highlights the potential for low probability attacks, such as those triggered by "dusting" an address with a transaction that meets specific criteria, to leak secrets without physical access to the device. The method underscores the importance of adopting robust anti-exfiltration measures like Anti-Exfil protocols to mitigate such vulnerabilities.

Further analysis delves into the challenges of securing cryptographic devices against both software and hardware-based threats. It points out that even with rigorous anti-exfiltration measures, attackers can exploit vulnerabilities in the device's physical construction, such as side channel and radio frequency leaks. This emphasizes the broader spectrum of cybersecurity, beyond just software and firmware protections, highlighting the necessity for comprehensive security strategies that also consider physical device integrity.

The efficacy of incorporating a 4-bit checksum in signature verification as a defensive strategy against these attacks is debated. While it potentially increases the computational effort required from an attacker, its effectiveness is contingent upon dynamically adjusting the checksum to avoid simplifying the attacker's task. The proposal suggests targeting a computational time of around 2 seconds per signature verification to deter unauthorized information leakage effectively.

The discourse also explores the practical aspects of implementing forward error correction (FEC) codes to estimate the number of signatures needed to compromise a seed. This approach sheds light on the computational relationship between the number of bits leaked per signature and the total number of signatures required to fully expose a seed. It introduces a nuanced perspective on the balance between computational feasibility and security, suggesting that even limited hardware capabilities can present a significant threat if exploited properly.

An innovative anti-exfiltration technique tailored for air-gapped signing devices using Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) is proposed. This technique integrates seamlessly with QR code-based signing workflows, enhancing security during the signing process by preventing private key exfiltration. It employs a novel combination of cryptographic operations and nonce utility, ensuring the secure generation and verification of signatures within isolated environments.

Lastly, the discussion touches upon the confusion surrounding the term "vector commitment" within cryptographic contexts. It clarifies its application in relation to ECDSA and Schnorr signatures, referencing a scheme that aligns more closely with ideas discussed in well-known cryptocurrency development forums and documents. This clarification aids in understanding the specific cryptographic mechanisms under discussion and their relevance to enhancing transaction signing security.

Overall, the dialogue encapsulates a comprehensive examination of cryptographic vulnerabilities and proposes innovative solutions to bolster security. It encompasses a range of topics from theoretical attack vectors to practical defense mechanisms, emphasizing the continuous evolution of cryptographic practices in response to emerging threats.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-03T21:28:46.874000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
