<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core 27.2 Released</title>
  <updated>2024-11-05T02:22:14.798953+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-11-04T10:50:46.936000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core 27.2 Released</title>
    <updated>2024-11-05T02:22:14.798985+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-27-2-released/1239" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin Core version 27.2 has been officially released, available for download from the specified [source](https://bitcoin.org/bin/bitcoin-core-27.2/) or via BitTorrent. This update comes with a variety of fixes and improvements aimed at enhancing the overall performance and user experience. Among these are bug fixes, performance enhancements, and newly updated translations, contributing to the software's reliability and efficiency. Users encountering issues are encouraged to utilize the GitHub issue tracker for reporting.

For those looking to upgrade from an older version, it is recommended to first shut down the existing application. This process may require a few minutes to ensure a complete shutdown before proceeding with the installation of the new version. The upgrade procedure involves running the installer on Windows or replacing the relevant files on macOS (`/Applications/Bitcoin-Qt`) and Linux (`bitcoind`/`bitcoin-qt`). It is important to note that upgrading from a Bitcoin Core version that has reached its end-of-life (EOL) might necessitate additional time if a data directory migration is needed. However, old wallet versions remain supported by the new release.

The compatibility of Bitcoin Core extends to operating systems based on the Linux Kernel version 3.17 and above, macOS 11.0 and above, as well as Windows 7 and later versions. While the software is also likely to function on other Unix-like systems, these environments undergo less frequent testing, hence the use of Bitcoin Core on unsupported systems is not advised.

Significant changes in this release are categorized under different aspects of the software such as P2P communications, initialization processes, RPC calls, PSBT handling, testing frameworks, documentation standards, and build configurations. Noteworthy modifications include a solution for a race condition in self-connect detection ([30394](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30394)), adjustments in the shutdown order to enhance system stability ([30435](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30435)), and various fixes aimed at improving functionality and compatibility - such as correcting PSBT processing issues ([29855](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29855)) and ensuring GCC 15 compatibility ([30633](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30633)). Additionally, efforts have been made to streamline continuous integration processes by transitioning certain tasks to GitHub Actions ([30193](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30193)) and refining workflow configurations ([30299](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30299)).

This release was made possible through the contributions of several individuals who played pivotal roles in development, testing, and translation efforts. Contributors to version 27.2 include notable figures within the Bitcoin Core community such as Ava Chow, Cory Fields, and Matt Whitlock, among others. Their collective efforts, along with the support of the wider translation community, have significantly contributed to the advancement of the Bitcoin Core software, ensuring its continued evolution and utility to users worldwide.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-04T10:50:46.936000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
