<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-11-17T02:28:30.728755+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-11-16T23:13:48.002000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-11-17T02:28:30.728791+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In recent developments, an intriguing experiment was conducted involving the use of [pathcoin](https://github.com/AdamISZ/pathcoin-poc/tree/master), specifically focusing on the `fidelitybonds.py` scripts. This test was part of a demonstration by the author and a colleague, aimed at exploring the capabilities and potential applications of pathcoin in a controlled environment. The timing of this experiment coincides with the period just before the San Salvador conference in late 2023, around October or November, though exact records were not meticulously kept. Despite the absence of detailed documentation, there is a high degree of certainty that this event took place during the specified timeframe, as the scripts used for the demo testing match perfectly with those intended for such purposes.

The choice of pathcoin for this experiment, while not necessarily reflecting a scenario that one might encounter under normal circumstances, presents a fascinating glimpse into the innovative uses of blockchain technology. By conducting this trial on signet, the individuals involved were able to ensure a safe and controlled environment for their exploration. This initiative not only highlights the practical aspects of implementing such technology but also contributes significantly to the broader discourse on its potential implications and future developments.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-16T23:13:48.002000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
