<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A Fast, Scalable Protocol For Resolving Lightning Payments</title>
  <updated>2024-11-18T02:26:54.079136+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-11-17T21:43:42.568000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A Fast, Scalable Protocol For Resolving Lightning Payments</title>
    <updated>2024-11-18T02:26:54.079177+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-fast-scalable-protocol-for-resolving-lightning-payments/1233/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights a critical issue within the realm of Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLCs), particularly focusing on the trustworthiness of timestamps in the resolution of these contracts. A scenario is presented where an HTLC between Alice and Mallory raises concerns due to the potential for dishonesty. Specifically, if an HTLC expires and then Mallory learns the preimage, she might manipulate the timestamp to claim the transaction was delayed due to network lag, thus arguing she should still receive the HTLC's value. This situation underscores that relying on the other party's timestamps introduces a vulnerability, as these can be falsified to misrepresent the actual timing of events.

The protocol governing HTLCs is designed with the understanding that timestamps provided by the counterparty cannot be trusted for resolving disputes. Instead, the protocol necessitates that parties dispute any HTLC that has expired according to their own clock, reinforcing the principle that internal verification methods are paramount over externally provided data. The necessity for disputing expired HTLCs is not just an option within the protocol; it is a requirement for adherence, highlighting the protocol's built-in safeguards against fraudulent claims based on manipulated timestamps.

Moreover, the efficiency and practicality of the protocol hinge on the assumption that agreements can be reached without frequent disputes. If disagreements over HTLC resolutions become commonplace, the resulting increase in routing fees would significantly impact the system's viability. There's a consensus that reaching agreement in the majority of cases is feasible, though this remains speculative until tested in real-world applications. The conversation suggests optimism about the protocol's ability to facilitate smooth transactions, yet acknowledges the importance of empirical validation to confirm these theoretical expectations.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-17T21:43:42.568000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
