<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Updates to the Gossip 1.75 proposal post LN summit meeting</title>
  <updated>2024-11-22T02:24:50.088904+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-11-21 15:00:03.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Updates to the Gossip 1.75 proposal post LN summit meeting</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T02:24:50.088940+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/updates-to-the-gossip-1-75-proposal-post-ln-summit-meeting/1202/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The appreciation for the unsigned TLV (Type-Length-Value) format for Simplified Payment Verification (SPV) proof highlights an innovative approach in the discussion, emphasizing its potential benefits. However, certain aspects of the proposal have raised concerns and suggestions for improvement. One such suggestion involves the inclusion of the outpoint in the signed fields. This modification is seen as beneficial for nodes with `txindex` enabled, enhancing the transaction's informational richness. Nonetheless, there's skepticism regarding the proposal to mandate the inclusion of a hash of the SPV proof in announcements. The critique centers on the impracticality for most nodes to generate SPV proofs, especially since many may not prioritize facilitating light client support.

Additionally, there's a debate over the structure of feature bits within the system. The suggestion to merge feature bits 1 and 2 into a single entity aims at streamlining implementation efforts and accelerating network adoption. Despite this, openness to maintaining separate feature bits exists if there's strong consensus within the community on the matter.

On a collaborative note, there's enthusiasm from the eclair team about participating in the development of features 1 and 2, contingent upon the readiness of the specification and a compatible lnd implementation. This willingness to collaborate signifies a positive step towards achieving cross-compatibility and advancing the project's goals.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T15:00:03.792000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
