<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-11-28T02:29:31.619346+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin.116000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-11-27T21:07:42.116000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T02:29:31.619373+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The analysis of CTV (CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) activity on ctv-signet provides an insightful perspective into the usage and distribution of different transaction types within the Bitcoin network. The data compiled highlights a total of 1558 SegWit version 0 spends, 52 legacy spends, and 14 taproot spends. This information was gathered through a meticulous process of scanning for NOP4 operations, reflecting transactions up until 2022. Notably, the count also revealed an additional 24 creations that were not included in the initial figures, suggesting a broader engagement with CTV mechanisms beyond the recorded spends. This aspect hints at a potentially larger base of users utilizing taproot or SegWit outputs, underscoring the inherent challenge in identifying taproot transactions due to their cryptographic nature.

Despite these findings, there's a critical viewpoint regarding the overall utility of signet for assessing network consensus and development practices. The skepticism stems from a perceived lack of correlation between the so-called vanity metrics derived from signet activities and the actual consensus mechanisms governing the network. It appears that the majority of developers prefer leveraging regtest environments for their testing and development efforts. This preference further questions the practical value of signet in providing meaningful insights into the adoption and usage trends of new Bitcoin features like CTV. Consequently, this analysis raises important considerations about the methodologies used to gauge technological adoption and development progress within the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-27T21:07:42.116000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
