<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
  <updated>2024-12-01T02:51:59.024572+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>evoskuil.536000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-11-30T07:02:50.536000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
    <updated>2024-12-01T02:51:59.024603+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/libbitcoin-for-core-people/1222/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin Core and Libbitcoin represent two different approaches to handling Bitcoin transactions and block processing. While Bitcoin Core has a mechanism that allows for the parallelization of requests, its block processing operations are strictly sequential. This system benefits from a parallel download feature, albeit with limited capability, functioning primarily as a read-ahead cache rather than a fully concurrent processing system. In contrast, Libbitcoin offers a more robust solution for dealing with the demands of blockchain management. It is designed to download, check, store, and index data concurrently across all available or specifically configured threads. This method significantly enhances efficiency by allowing the entire chain to undergo these processes simultaneously. To optimize performance and minimize potential issues related to data locality and validation delays, Libbitcoin typically restricts concurrent downloads to a window of 50,000 blocks or fewer.

Libbitcoin's architecture is noteworthy for its fully write-concurrent store and lock-free design, based on the proactor pattern. This advanced setup enables Libbitcoin to perform full validation of blocks concurrently across multiple threads. This includes not only script validations but also all necessary accept/connect checks without being confined to processing a single block at a time. The choice of maintaining a concurrent download window around 50,000 blocks helps in keeping the validator threads engaged and minimizes the chances of them being idle due to lack of data to process. This strategic decision underscores Libbitcoin's capability to manage blockchain operations more efficiently compared to Bitcoin Core's sequential block processing approach.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-30T07:02:50.536000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
