<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-12-04T02:39:11.774928+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-12-03 14:36:07.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-12-03 13:42:34.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-12-03 07:19:56.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-12-03 01:18:20.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-12-03 00:50:23.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-12-02 18:20:14.105000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 21:34:24.602000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-11-27 21:15:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 19:30:52.026000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-27 17:51:11.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-11-27 16:35:31.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-11-25 17:41:41.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-16 14:58:04.341000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3706_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3705_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3703_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3697_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3696_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3679_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3625_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3624_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3620_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3619_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3617_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3599_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3548_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T02:39:11.775022+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around Radpool and Braidpool centers on their approaches to blockchain mining pools, highlighting the crucial role of consensus mechanisms and Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) broadcasts. Radpool operates by utilizing a federation model where Mining Service Providers (MSPs) validate shares from miners and ensure fairness through difficulty adjustments and share normalization. This model promotes decentralization by allowing any new party to contribute Proof of Work (PoW) for a certain number of blocks before gaining membership, thus simplifying the protocol compared to more complex systems like Braidpool which requires consensus for participation. The conversation also touches upon the technical challenges and potential scalability issues related to implementing these systems, especially concerning rate-limiting BFT messages and share announcements to prevent DDoS attacks.

Further discussion explores FROST DKG's role in both proposals, emphasizing the need for efficient broadcast mechanisms to maintain consistent views among participants and ensure fair share distribution. Radpool's strategy focuses on leveraging simple protocols to achieve functionality without the need for building consensus mechanisms from scratch, contrasting with Braidpool's approach that starts with consensus and addresses additional complexities associated with nakamoto consensus. The dialogue extends to examining the implications of these differing methodologies on network efficiency, security, and miner inclusivity.

The email also delves into operational aspects of MSP management within these networks, discussing the authentication of miners, data pruning strategies for efficiency, and the handling of dishonest MSPs. The importance of having a robust mechanism for share accounting and payouts is highlighted, with suggestions for improving transparency and reliability in these processes. The potential for using Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) for payouts and the necessity of a consensus mechanism tailored to share distribution are further explored, indicating areas for development and research.

Radpool distinguishes itself through its federated model, enabling decentralized block template generation and offering a flexible payout system through DLCs. This structure aims to reduce the centralization risks present in traditional mining pools by distributing control over block templates to MSPs and ensuring fair compensation for miners based on their hash contributions. The proposal suggests a shift towards more democratic and transparent operations in mining pools, advocating for systems that can accommodate varying degrees of participation and provide clear incentives for both miners and MSPs.

In summary, the email discussions encapsulate a broad spectrum of technical, operational, and strategic considerations pertinent to the development of decentralized mining pools. They outline the challenges and opportunities presented by Radpool and Braidpool, emphasizing the importance of consensus mechanisms, share distribution fairness, and the potential benefits of adopting technologies like FROST signing and DLCs. These conversations underscore the evolving landscape of blockchain mining and the continuous search for solutions that enhance decentralization, security, and efficiency within this domain.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T14:36:07.186000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
