<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
  <updated>2024-11-04T02:23:12.640202+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-11-03 16:56:25.848000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-10-29 13:53:22.156000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-10-29 13:06:58.632000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2024-10-28 19:09:55.723000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3460_Libbitcoin-for-Core-people.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3442_Libbitcoin-for-Core-people.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3439_Libbitcoin-for-Core-people.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3432_Libbitcoin-for-Core-people.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Libbitcoin for Core people</title>
    <updated>2024-11-04T02:23:12.640254+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/libbitcoin-for-core-people/1222/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a detailed exploration of Libbitcoin's operational efficiencies and methodologies, a comparison with Bitcoin Core reveals Libbitcoin's superior Initial Block Download (IBD) performance, reportedly up to 15 times faster when leveraging the `-assumevalid` option. This advantage is attributed to Libbitcoin's use of an event-based system powered by [Boost ASIO](https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_86_0/doc/html/boost_asio/overview/core/async.html), facilitating concurrent operations that significantly enhance its performance. The database structure of Libbitcoin, designed to be conceptually relational, supports various backends and includes separate tables for headers, transactions, inputs, and outputs. This architecture allows for efficient management of block validation processes, which can be categorized based on their sequencing requirements—ranging from non-sequential initial checks to partially ordered validations and confirmability verifications executed in parallel.

Libbitcoin implements a distinct approach towards transaction validation and blockchain reorganization, wherein it skips certain transaction validations below a defined milestone, akin to the `-assumevalid` feature in Bitcoin Core. This strategy, coupled with the assumption of unspent output validity based on block height, mirrors a blend of `-assumevalid` and `assumeutxo` functionalities, streamlining the validation process. Moreover, Libbitcoin's handling of block downloads, validation checks, and input verification across a spectrum of blocks is conducted through asynchronous tasks, underscoring its capability for rapid IBD. Despite these advancements, pruning remains unimplemented in Libbitcoin, reflecting a deliberate choice rather than a limitation.

The system's transaction table uniquely accommodates both confirmed and unconfirmed transactions, with future updates poised to address minimum fee rates and conflict graphs, aligning more closely with Bitcoin Core's fee management practices. Networking strategies in Libbitcoin aim for optimal resource utilization, initially connecting to a hundred outbound peers, with plans to adjust this number dynamically post-IBD based on network interactions and peer response metrics. However, it's important to note that despite its robust networking and validation mechanisms, Libbitcoin has yet to fully implement DoS protection measures beyond conceptual rate limiting. 

Performance comparisons must also consider technical disparities, such as Libbitcoin's use of an outdated libsecp version and the absence of native SHA256 acceleration—factors that could potentially affect its efficiency benchmarks. Furthermore, the correction from "confirmation" to "confirmation height to header" in the documentation clarifies the process of verifying transactions before dealing with associated metadata, highlighting the precision in terminology needed to accurately describe Libbitcoin's functionalities. This nuanced understanding of terms like "milestone," differing slightly from Bitcoin Core's `-assumevalid`, emphasizes the unique architectural and operational characteristics distinguishing Libbitcoin within the cryptocurrency landscape.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-03T16:56:25.848000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
