<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Empirical Data Analysis of Fee Rate Forecasters for ASAP (next-block) Fee Estimation</title>
  <updated>2024-11-07T02:17:38.786740+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-11-06 19:16:16.740000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-07-03 17:39:54.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3494_Empirical-Data-Analysis-of-Fee-Rate-Forecasters-for-ASAP-next-block-Fee-Estimation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2850_Empirical-Data-Analysis-of-Fee-Rate-Forecasters-for-ASAP-next-block-Fee-Estimation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Empirical Data Analysis of Fee Rate Forecasters for ASAP (next-block) Fee Estimation</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T02:17:38.786780+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/empirical-data-analysis-of-fee-rate-forecasters-for-asap-next-block-fee-estimation/1022" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with a query about the rationale behind distinguishing transactions for fee prediction purposes based on whether they have been confirmed or not. It suggests considering transactions received in the last 10 minutes as a benchmark for competition, implying a more dynamic approach to predicting transaction fees.

The core of the analysis evaluates the effectiveness of various fee rate forecasters over 1293 blocks, from block `848920` to `850213`. This examination is aimed at contrasting these forecasters against the benchmark set by the [Bitcoind Policy estimator](https://johnnewbery.com/an-intro-to-bitcoin-core-fee-estimation/), alongside assessing the enhancements proposed in a new GitHub proposal ([GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30157)). The forecasters scrutinized include those analyzing the entire mempool, transactions within the last 10 minutes, the last single block, and the last six blocks. These methodologies aim to predict fee rates using transaction data and the history of block confirmations. Their performance was measured based on how accurately they could predict fee rates that would align within the 5th to 50th percentile range of fees in the subsequently confirmed block.

The analysis highlights that forecasters like those focusing on the mempool and recent transactions demonstrated higher accuracy, particularly in predicting fees for high-priority transactions. In contrast, methods relying on data from the last block or the last six blocks were found less effective due to the volatile nature of mempool conditions. It also notes the Bitcoind conservative mode's efficacy as a more reliable safety measure than basing predictions on the last six blocks' data, which can be vulnerable to manipulation and abrupt changes in transaction volume.

A significant takeaway from this review is the proposition of a "Smart Mempool-Based Forecaster". This model aims to refine fee rate predictions by adjusting for recent transaction activity and block generation times, suggesting adjustments to fee estimates based on the volume of transactions and the speed of recent block confirmations. Although promising, the practical application of such heuristics necessitates further empirical analysis to ascertain their effectiveness.

In conclusion, the detailed investigation into Bitcoin transaction fee prediction reveals the intricate challenges involved in forecasting fees accurately. It underscores the potential benefits of sophisticated forecasting models in enhancing user experiences by reducing overpayments and ensuring transactions are timely confirmed, thereby addressing a critical aspect of Bitcoin’s usability.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-06T19:16:16.740000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
