<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A Fast, Scalable Protocol For Resolving Lightning Payments</title>
  <updated>2024-11-10T02:23:52.843272+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2024-11-10 00:06:59.715000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2024-11-09 23:59:58.677000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2024-11-09 23:21:48.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-11-05 10:14:19.731000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2024-11-04 23:59:52.234000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2024-10-31 22:50:15.637000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3502_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3501_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3500_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3488_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3482_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3457_A-Fast-Scalable-Protocol-For-Resolving-Lightning-Payments.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A Fast, Scalable Protocol For Resolving Lightning Payments</title>
    <updated>2024-11-10T02:23:52.843357+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-fast-scalable-protocol-for-resolving-lightning-payments/1233/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initiates by addressing the vulnerabilities within the Offchain Payment Routing (OPR) protocol, specifically focusing on the exploitation of its fee structure through failed payment attempts known as "probes". These probes, under the current Lightning Network (LN) protocol, do not incur costs to their initiator, allowing for potential network disruptions without financial consequences to the attacker. The narrative suggests that imposing unconditional fees on every transaction attempt could mitigate this issue, ensuring that each transaction bears a cost regardless of its outcome. This leads to an analysis of the network's operational dynamics, presenting a quantitative perspective on how an increase in routing fees could theoretically compensate for the value lost from unresolved Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLCs) due to random node failures.

Further discussions explore alternative solutions to reduce high transaction costs associated with on-chain settlements, particularly for low-value payments. An innovative approach mentioned is probabilistic payments, which aim to balance the risk and cost of on-chain settlements by wrapping payments in higher value outputs with a chance-based outcome. This method, leveraging `OP_DETERMINISTIC_RANDOM`, presents a scalable workaround to the challenges faced by HTLC settlement costs, though it's noted that progress in this area has been minimal due to a lack of perceived urgency in resolving these issues within the LN community.

Additionally, the conversation touches upon the inherent issue in the Lightning protocol where small, unresolved HTLCs can lead to incremental theft of a channel's balance if not addressed. The OPR protocol exacerbates this problem by increasing the cost implications of force closing due to burned fees, thus creating a perverse incentive to overlook small unresolved HTLCs. The methodology for HTLC resolution involves verifying the provision of the required hash preimage before expiration, with nodes relying on synchronized clocks to mitigate discrepancies due to clock skew. However, the unreliability of networks introduces challenges in distinguishing between genuine delays and malicious actions, leading to concerns over increased complexity, implementation errors, and an uptick in costly force closures under OPR.

In conclusion, the OPR protocol represents a significant improvement in the efficiency and security of Lightning payments, especially for transactions of small value. It facilitates rapid off-chain payment resolutions without necessitating on-chain transactions, enhancing scalability and reducing the need for constant online presence for users. The protocol introduces a griefer-penalized mechanism that deters dishonest behavior by penalizing attackers proportionate to their attempted harm. Despite potential operational risks and the possibility of fund loss due to node failures, the OPR protocol offers strategies for minimizing such risks, including synchronized clocks and multiple communication paths for crucial messages. Overall, the OPR protocol's ability to support immediate payment resolution, combined with its deterrent against dishonest behavior and operational risks, positions it as a promising solution for improving the scalability and accessibility of the Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-10T00:06:59.715000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
