<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
  <updated>2024-11-28T02:30:56.560940+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-11-27 21:34:24.602000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-11-27 21:15:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-11-27 19:30:52.026000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-11-27 17:51:11.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-11-27 16:35:31.060000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2024-11-25 17:41:41.133000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-11-16 14:58:04.341000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3625_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3624_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3620_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3619_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3617_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3599_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3548_Radpool-Decentralised-Mining-Pool-With-Futures-Contracts-For-Payouts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Radpool: Decentralised Mining Pool With Futures Contracts For Payouts</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T02:30:56.561035+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/radpool-decentralised-mining-pool-with-futures-contracts-for-payouts/1262/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence delves into the specifics of Radpool, contrasting it with other proposals like Braidpool, and discussing the technicalities and strategic decisions behind mining protocols. It emphasizes the distinction between Radpool’s reliance on a fixed FROST signing federation and Braidpool's dynamic one. Radpool's federation is made up of share-buying entities rather than miners, granting these entities control over block templates. This structure aims to decentralize block template generation and diverge from traditional centralized mining pools, potentially reducing miner payouts while maintaining a decentralized framework. The proposal outlines that MSPs (Mining Service Providers) within Radpool can independently generate block templates and operate stratum servers, offering miners the flexibility to build their own templates. Moreover, it introduces a payout mechanism using Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) for compensating miners based on hash rate, ensuring MSPs fund these contracts and settle them using FROST threshold signatures.

Discussion around the handling of data, particularly regarding the time decay of shares and jobs, suggests implementing policies to efficiently manage validation and storage. The correspondence advises on enhancing protocol transparency while allowing MSPs flexibility in their operations. It also touches on the enrollment process for miners, advocating for unique identifiers across the network to streamline authentication without strictly prescribing methods such as usernames and passwords. Concerns about dishonest MSPs, their validation, and the implications for syndicate visibility into contract rates are raised, alongside questions about practicality in oracle signature publication by MSPs at scale.

The proposal acknowledges potential risks, including MSPs providing incorrect nonces and how small hash rate miners might be affected by creating dust UTXOs. It calls attention to the lack of performance benchmarks for FROST federation quorums, speculating on latency or throughput bottlenecks during FROST signing. A reference to PPLNS-JD highlights its relevance in the context of mining fee trends, especially as fees become a more significant part of mining revenue. Furthermore, the necessity for clearly defined miner dashboard functions and interactions within the protocol is underscored, emphasizing their importance for effective balance management, contract extensions, or MSP switching by miners.

Radpool aims to position itself uniquely between centralized and peer-to-peer pools by creating an open syndicate of MSPs. This approach seeks to reduce variance for miners and increase yield opportunities for MSPs, fostering a competitive environment for pool fees and encouraging network growth through a classic network effect. Radpool's introduction of decentralization to block template construction, coupled with innovative payment mechanisms and transparent share accounting, presents a novel solution to combat mining centralization. The community is invited to contribute to discussions and development, particularly around the FROST Federation and the implementation of DLC contracts, highlighting an ongoing effort to refine and enhance the mining landscape.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-27T21:34:24.602000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
