<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories With Pseudo-Spilman Leaves</title>
  <updated>2024-11-26T02:26:15.524881+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3601_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories-With-Pseudo-Spilman-Leaves.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3469_SuperScalar-Laddered-Timeout-Tree-Structured-Decker-Wattenhofer-Factories-With-Pseudo-Spilman-Leaves.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SuperScalar: Laddered Timeout-Tree-Structured Decker-Wattenhofer Factories With Pseudo-Spilman Leaves</title>
    <updated>2024-11-26T02:26:15.524920+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/superscalar-laddered-timeout-tree-structured-decker-wattenhofer-factories-with-pseudo-spilman-leaves/1242" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The SuperScalar mechanism addresses the Last-Mile Problem for Bitcoin users on the Lightning Network, facilitating the acquisition of incoming liquidity without high blockchain operation costs. This innovative approach leverages a combination of Decker-Wattenhofer decrementing-`nSequence` offchain mechanisms, timeout trees, pseudo-Spilman channel factories, and laddering within a structure known as the SuperScalar construction. Designed to operate within the existing constraints of the Bitcoin blockchain, it ensures security and scalability without requiring consensus changes. Unlike previous solutions that depend on federations or a one-honest-member assumption, SuperScalar provides a decentralized method for liquidity management and security.

At its core, the SuperScalar construction incorporates several critical components. The Decker-Wattenhofer mechanism allows for efficient state change consensus among parties without needing blockchain recording for each alteration. Timeout trees add a layer requiring universal agreement, mimicking `OP_CTV`, which facilitates secure and efficient fund reallocation even with offline users. Pseudo-Spilman channel factories allow unidirectional liquidity transfers from LSPs to clients, and laddering introduces a flexible approach to managing investments and liquidity.

This mechanism significantly reduces client risk related to fluctuating onchain fees by enabling the LSP to manage unilateral exits on behalf of clients, thus aligning the LSP's incentives with network integrity and reliability. Additionally, the SuperScalar model incorporates practical implementation strategies, such as incentivizing client onlineness, optimizing liquidity provision through client grouping based on activity patterns, and managing channels efficiently within the network. It also suggests extending existing BOLT specifications to accommodate channel factory complexities, proposing a collaboration framework between base node software and plugins or side-daemons for protocol management.

Overall, SuperScalar presents a well-rounded solution to the LSP Last-Mile Problem, emphasizing security, scalability, and user experience without compromising the decentralized and self-sovereign principles of the Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-25T20:18:07.328000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
