<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
  <updated>2024-11-16T02:22:24.052649+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-11-15 21:28:39.675000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-11-14 17:34:11.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3547_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2024/3521_CTV-APO-CAT-activity-on-signet.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CTV, APO, CAT activity on signet</title>
    <updated>2024-11-16T02:22:24.052689+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-apo-cat-activity-on-signet/1257/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The introduction of Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) 118, 119, and 347 has significantly expanded the scripting capabilities within Bitcoin, as demonstrated through their activation on signet. BIP 118, known for introducing `SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT` (APO), facilitates more versatile transaction signatures by not requiring the specification of a previous output. This flexibility has been primarily utilized in transactions involving coinbase payouts, with a recurrent practice observed where APOAS signatures are reused to send block rewards back to faucet addresses, albeit leading to substantial fee losses. Moreover, APO has seen strategic use in circumventing `OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY` (CTV) within scripts, showcasing its potential in structuring transactions using fixed signatures.

In contrast, BIP 119's focus on `OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY` (CTV) has birthed experimental applications that either enforce a timeout pattern necessitating a specific signature path or combine a preimage reveal with a signature. These implementations align with the proposal’s objective to facilitate intricate spend conditions and bolster vault security mechanisms. Some experiments have straightforwardly integrated the CTV opcode within their scriptPubKey, directly tapping into CTV's functional offerings. Although BIP 347's `OP_CAT` activation details are less comprehensively covered, it evidently surpasses APO and CTV in application frequency, chiefly due to its role in the Proof of Work (PoW) faucet process, thereby enhancing its transaction volume. Noteworthy is OP_CAT's involvement in innovative practices like STARK verification and its prospective utility in crafting advanced vault or covenant solutions, leveraging CAT/CHECKSIG for introspection to potentially elevate contract complexity, security, and functionality.

An additional layer of insight into these developments comes from an adapted method of tracking such innovations, which entails altering a signet node’s validation mechanism to log transactions that employ these novel features. This technique highlights the persistent effort and curiosity among the Bitcoin developer community to explore and exploit these enhanced scripting capacities for diverse, secure, and practical uses within the digital currency's ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-15T21:28:39.675000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
