<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2016-January-012248</id>
  <title>Capacity increases for the Bitcoin system.</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:26:44.751746+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anthony Towns</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2016-January-012248</id>
    <title>Capacity increases for the Bitcoin system.</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:26:44.751746+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2016-January/012248.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The effective block size for p2pkh with segwit is estimated to be 1.7MB, which is higher than the previously estimated 1.6MB. For 2/2 multisig, the estimated block size is still accurate at 2MB. Additional post-segwit soft-forked script improvements can further increase the effective block size for p2pkh transactions from 1.7MB to 1.9MB and for 2/2 multisig from 2MB to 2.5MB/3MB. Segwit makes two soft-fork improvements possible, namely ecdsa public key recovery and schnorr signatures, which can improve the space efficiency of both multisig and p2pkh. The revised figures suggest that there could be a 170% increase in the number of transactions per block for p2pkh, while multisig could see an increase of 200%. These estimates assume that the number of inputs will be roughly the same as the number of outputs. However, if a 2MB hard fork is done first, then the 1/4 discount for segwit could mean up to 8MB of total data per block, which is currently infeasible. Without discounting, segwit comes at a slight cost in transactions per block, and additional soft forks will only result in a 25% gain for p2pkh and 50%-100% for 2-of-2 multisig. The caveat is that additional metadata might also need to be accounted for, such as the length for each witness signature or the value of the input.</summary>
    <published>2016-01-18T12:02:51+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
