<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:31:09.942534+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-03T14:55:34.004000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:31:09.942534+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lamport-signatures-and-other-cat-tricks/236/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the context of cryptocurrency transactions, a particular concern is addressed regarding the safety and verification mechanisms for keyspend operations. The sender of the message discusses a method to ensure the legitimacy of such operations by revealing a preimage 't' of a tweak, which clients could then verify through cryptographic calculations. Specifically, they suggest that clients could check if 'Q', presumably a public key or some other point on an elliptic curve, equals the sum of the generator point 'G' and the product of 'G' and 't'. This process would act as a safeguard against unauthorized transactions.

However, the sender acknowledges a potential flaw in this approach. An adversary might circumvent the check by calculating a different point '(a+b)G' that equals '(t+1)G', where 'a' and 'b' are variables in the elliptic curve equation, thus posing a question about the robustness of this verification method.

The sender also raises a question about the possibility of enforcing script-only transactions while maintaining compatibility with the current address format. This suggests a desire to strengthen security measures without having to alter the existing infrastructure significantly. The underlying challenge is finding a balance between enhancing security protocols for keyspend activities and ensuring smooth functionality within the established system.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-03T14:55:34.004000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
