<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Can we get a Lightning Protocol Design Category/WG?</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:37:22.264774+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.667000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-04T20:25:41.667000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Can we get a Lightning Protocol Design Category/WG?</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:37:22.265355+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/can-we-get-a-lightning-protocol-design-category-wg/242/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>When considering the organization of content on a discussion platform, a strategy akin to what Fedora has implemented appears to be effective. Fedora's approach emphasizes broader categories complemented by more specific tags to streamline navigation and topic discovery within their discourse community. This method provides flexibility and ensures that discussions remain accessible while being well-organized. Adopting this system would entail posting under existing general categories and applying specific tags like 'lightning' to distinguish the content easily.

Further customization of the discussion space can be achieved by establishing specialized workgroups. The creation of such workgroups requires clarity on several aspects, including the intended membership composition and the desired level of privacy. Workgroups can be set to different access levels: fully private, public, or public with read-only restrictions. Before proceeding with the formation of a workgroup, it is necessary to specify which individuals should be included as members and to decide on the appropriate accessibility settings that align with the group's objectives.

The referenced Fedora discussion link (https://discussion.fedoraproject.org/t/navigating-fedora-discussion-tags-categories-and-concepts/35555) provides additional insight into how they have successfully navigated the complexities of organizing discussion topics, which could serve as a valuable resource for anyone looking to implement a similar structure in their own discourse environment.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-04T20:25:41.667000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
