<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Mailing list mode</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:38:21.411970+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-12-04 20:45:52.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Mailing list mode</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:38:21.411970+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mailing-list-mode/245" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent update to the system introduces a change regarding the "disable mailing list mode" switch, which has now been turned off. This adjustment has sparked some debate, with a prevailing sentiment that subscribing to specific tags or categories might be more beneficial than the blanket approach the mailing list mode offers. The discourse on this topic is quite active, with many expressing their reservations about the utility of this feature. For those interested in exploring the altered functionality, they can navigate through the user interface by clicking on the favicon located at the top right corner, then selecting the head-and-shoulders icon followed by the preferences option, and finally accessing the email tab to adjust settings as desired.

The discussion around this feature references an ongoing conversation found at a Discourse community link (https://meta.discourse.org/t/completely-disable-mailing-list-mode/37334), where various users have shared their perspectives on disabling the mailing list mode. Despite the concerns raised, the option to test out the current configuration remains available to users who wish to see how it affects their experience with the platform. It’s worth noting that these changes reflect an effort to fine-tune how notifications and updates are received and managed, potentially impacting the way users interact with content and each other within the system.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-04T20:45:52.360000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
