<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Can we get a Lightning Protocol Design Category/WG?</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:35:58.153909+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.146000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-05T02:47:32.146000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Can we get a Lightning Protocol Design Category/WG?</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:35:58.153909+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/can-we-get-a-lightning-protocol-design-category-wg/242/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post begins with an update on the changes to Discourse's mailing list mode. The referenced page, which was last updated 3.5 years ago and created 6.5 years prior, has become outdated due to ongoing discussions and modifications within the Discourse community. These discussions have resulted in significant adjustments to the functionality of the mailing list mode, culminating in its deactivation by default in 2021 as part of a broader effort to improve the platform. This decision is documented in a pull request on GitHub, providing evidence of the change.

Further information about current Discourse functionalities and user guides can be found in the new user guide hosted on Discourse's meta forum. For individual users looking to customize their email interaction with the platform, a generic link is available which directs to the email preferences section of a user's profile.

Moreover, there is a mention of a delay in email notifications sent by Discourse. This feature ensures that if any immediate edits are made to a topic post-publication, the recipient will receive the updated content in their email. This delay serves to enhance the accuracy and relevance of the information received by subscribers via email notifications.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-05T02:47:32.146000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
