<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:29:56.690038+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-05T12:33:44.469000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:29:56.690038+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lamport-signatures-and-other-cat-tricks/236/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a proposal for a soft fork in blockchain technology, specifically concerning the implementation of new script operations and encoding methods. The suggestion involves creating an alternative to the existing Pay to Script Hash (P2SH) by introducing a new Pay to X Script Hash (P2XSH) with a different template that uses `OP_HASH256 OP_EQUAL` in place of `OP_HASH160 OP_EQUAL`. This change aims to incorporate additional script tricks like Lamport signatures and re-enabling the `OP_CAT` operation.

Furthermore, the proposed P2XSH would recognize scripts that conform to a `0xC0`-version script pattern similar to tapleaf structures, inclusive of the `OP_SUCCESS` opcode. By doing so, it would be possible to execute any compatible extensions supported within the `0xC0`-version tapleaves inside the P2XSH script. One of the significant benefits of this approach is the avoidance of quantum-non-resistant paths when executing scripts.

There's also an alternative recommendation to integrate the version information at the beginning of the script, effectively turning it into a tapleaf structure. This would enable the use of `OP_CAT` if it becomes available within the tapscript version `0xC0`, thereby enhancing script capabilities while maintaining security against potential quantum computing threats. 

This innovative approach suggests a strategic advancement in script processing on the blockchain, which could potentially improve both functionality and security in the face of evolving technological challenges.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-05T12:33:44.469000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
