<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Cluster Mempool RBF Thoughts</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T18:56:49.359655+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2023-12-05 23:02:55.835000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Cluster Mempool RBF Thoughts</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T18:56:49.359655+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-rbf-thoughts/156/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of handling transaction conflicts and optimizing the mempool involves a multi-step strategy aimed at maintaining efficiency while ensuring improvements. Initially, the proposal is to address conflicts by removing the conflicting transactions and their related data, followed by restructuring the remaining elements of the old clusters. This step does not necessitate relinearising and is computationally efficient, with a time complexity of O(n).

Subsequently, the modified clusterings are utilized to generate a new diagram which is then compared to the existing one. Here, the computational effort increases modestly to O(n log(c)), where 'c' represents the number of chunks. If this comparative analysis reveals that the new diagram does not offer an enhancement over the current one, the proposed Replace-by-Fee (RBF) transaction can be discarded as the changes are deemed non-beneficial.

In the event that the new diagram demonstrates an improvement, further steps are taken. This includes splitting and relinearising the old clusters, followed by updating the mempool. These actions are more computationally intensive, with a time complexity of O(n^2/c), but they are justified by the potential benefits realized in the mempool's performance.

The decision to defer the relinearising step until after confirming that the modifications indeed result in an improved mempool is strategic. It avoids unnecessary computational expenses on complex cases that may not yield any actual benefit, thereby prioritizing efficiency in the optimization process.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-05T23:02:55.835000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
