<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Draft BIP for OP_TXHASH and OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T11:21:14.427393+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose.331000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-11T09:06:51.331000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Draft BIP for OP_TXHASH and OP_CHECKTXHASHVERIFY</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T11:21:14.427393+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/draft-bip-for-op-txhash-and-op-checktxhashverify/121/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) has progressed from its draft phase into a more concrete stage, signaling a development in the ongoing evolution of the Bitcoin network. This advancement is further substantiated by the implementation within Bitcoin Core, which can be found at the provided GitHub repository link: [Bitcoin Core Implementation](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29050).

The progression of this BIP from draft to an active state indicates a significant milestone for developers and stakeholders involved with Bitcoin, as it reflects consensus on proposed changes or enhancements to the network. The availability of the code for review and use in the Bitcoin Core repository not only increases transparency but also allows for wider testing and potential adoption.

This transition also serves as an invitation for developers, miners, and users to engage with the new BIP, analyze its implications, and prepare for any adjustments they might need to make to their systems or practices. The shared link provides direct access to the specifics of the implementation, enabling interested parties to delve into the technical details, contribute to further development, or commence integration processes.

As the summary omits casual sign-offs and focuses solely on the informational content, it underscores the shift in the BIP's status and the community's opportunity to interact with the changes through the accessible Bitcoin Core repository.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-11T09:06:51.331000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
