<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2023-12-22T19:11:09.671731+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2023-12-19 15:23:41.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2023-12-22T19:11:09.671731+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin address creation, a significant technical challenge has been identified concerning the use of partial descriptors. The core of this issue lies in the requirement for additional information beyond what is available on-chain to successfully generate addresses. This constraint implies that relying solely on the blockchain's data is insufficient for this process.

Partial descriptors are a concept within the Bitcoin protocol that provides a way to specify certain parts of a complex script without detailing the entire script. The discussion at hand revolves around an inherent limitation when utilizing these partial descriptors for address generation. The limitation arises because one cannot create a complete and usable Bitcoin address without supplementary off-chain information, which is not contained within the blockchain itself.

The implication of this challenge is multi-faceted. It affects the autonomy of Bitcoin address creation by introducing a dependency on external data. This could have repercussions on the privacy, security, and simplicity of address management within Bitcoin wallets and applications. Furthermore, it raises questions about the scalability of such systems if they must rely on data not inherently verifiable through the blockchain.

Addressing this issue requires a nuanced understanding of the Bitcoin protocol and the mechanisms of script descriptors. Developers and users must be aware that while partial descriptors offer a powerful tool for specifying components of Bitcoin scripts, their use is not entirely self-contained. The need for off-chain data introduces complexity that must be managed carefully to maintain the integrity and functionality of cryptocurrency wallets and transactions.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T15:23:41.886000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
