<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2023-12-22T19:04:20.539708+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>amiti.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-20T21:54:22.898000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2023-12-22T19:04:20.539708+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal under discussion receives a positive reception, with the sender agreeing to the suggested approach and expressing gratitude to AJ Towns for their contributions. The sender is open to experimenting with more than 100 nodes while recognizing the merits of reducing this number. They express interest in comparing the effects of testing with both 4 and 8 nodes to determine if outcomes align with expectations. It's suggested that these configurations be included as initial parameters for further examination.

The core purpose of the proposal appears to revolve around establishing a deterministic methodology for generating a substantial number of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) to facilitate a variety of transaction patterns. This method involves incrementally increasing the transaction creation rate during tests until a noticeable increase in transaction request numbers is observed. This strategy aims to pinpoint the threshold at which system performance begins to degrade, thus assessing the robustness of the network.

An area of ongoing contemplation is the imbalance between inbound and outbound transaction rates among peers. With the current patch suggesting a rate of 14 transactions per second (tx/s) for inbound connections and an application of a 2.5x multiplier for outbound peers, there remains a question about reconciling these node-level metrics with those deemed acceptable across the entire network. The sender seeks to understand how individual node performance can be effectively measured against broader network standards to ensure consistency and reliability.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T21:54:22.898000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
