<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Package aware Fee estimator post cluster mempool</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:40:45.008930+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-12-24T13:22:00.976000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Package aware Fee estimator post cluster mempool</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:40:45.009400+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/package-aware-fee-estimator-post-cluster-mempool/312/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence delves into the intricacies of a transaction fee estimation mechanism, specifically focusing on an internal component referred to as the MapMempoolTxs. It is explained that for the purpose of estimating fees, transactions within the mempool are assessed based on their associated time spent awaiting confirmation. This duration is calculated from the point at which the youngest transaction, labeled as the sponsor of a group or 'chunk' of transactions, enters the memory pool until the moment the chunk is included in a mined block.

Further elaboration reveals an approach where this time-in-mempool metric is determined by subtracting the block height at which the chunk was successfully mined from the block height when the youngest transaction entered the mempool. To provide clarity with an example, if one considers a particular transaction 'P', the relevant measurement would be the difference between the block height at which 'P' was first recorded in the mempool and the block height at which 'P' was confirmed through mining. 

This method offers a nuanced perspective on how transactions are evaluated and selected based on their time pending in the mempool, thus reflecting a dynamic and temporal aspect of the fee estimation process. It underscores the importance of understanding the life cycle of transactions within the blockchain environment, as it directly influences fee calculations and, consequently, transaction prioritization.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T13:22:00.976000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
