<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Lampo v23.12-beta.1 aka Santa Claus lives in Area 51</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:44:26.492456+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vincenzopalazzo 2023-12-24 19:57:40.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Lampo v23.12-beta.1 aka Santa Claus lives in Area 51</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:44:26.492456+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lampo-v23-12-beta-1-aka-santa-claus-lives-in-area-51/321" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of a new lightning node, named Lampo, has reached an exciting phase with the release of its first public beta version v23.12. Originating as a project intended to support lnprototest for Lightning Development Kit (LDK), Lampo has evolved into a more comprehensive toolkit. Over 1.5 years of dedicated effort, the creator of Lampo recognized the potential to expand beyond a toy lightning node and crafted an SDK capable of building a fully operational lightning node with LDK.

The current iteration of Lampo includes basic commands that are essential for operation, with acknowledgement that improvements such as a 'help' command are forthcoming. The developer has also made significant strides towards enabling integration tests between c-lightning and Lampo, thereby enhancing compatibility and performance. Furthermore, protocol tests have been incorporated via lnprototest, which augments the robustness of the node.

With this launch, the developer invites users and contributors to engage with Lampo, providing feedback on desired features and functionalities. While there is no guarantee that all suggestions will be implemented, contributions in the form of patches are encouraged to foster growth and improvement of the Lampo lightning node. This initiative represents a substantial contribution to the LDK ecosystem, offering a new tool for developers interested in building and refining lightning network nodes.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T19:57:40.736000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
