<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
  <updated>2024-06-18T02:02:56.079079+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno 2024-06-17 16:15:50.793000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2024-04-15 09:37:33.247000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2023-12-18 18:03:14.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2023-12-01 19:30:21.802000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-11-29 23:01:43.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2023-11-18 15:06:59.397000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2724_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2229_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/786_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/541_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/516_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/448_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
    <updated>2024-06-18T02:02:56.079138+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/differential-fuzzing-of-bitcoin-implementations/208/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent advancements and discoveries in the domain of Bitcoin programming libraries, particularly concerning `rust-miniscript` and `rust-bitcoin`, along with issues related to `btcd` and Bitcoin Core, have been substantial. Notably, a bug was identified in `rust-bitcoin` where it fails to verify the witness flag in transactions that have empty witnesses, which is crucial for maintaining the robustness of the library. This issue, documented under number 2681 on GitHub, is pivotal to enhancing the security measures within the Rust Bitcoin library. The documentation and subsequent addressing of such vulnerabilities are vital steps towards fortifying the library against potential threats, ensuring its reliability for developers within the Bitcoin ecosystem.

Furthermore, an inconsistency has been observed between the handling of miniscripts in `rust-miniscript` and Bitcoin Core. Specifically, while Bitcoin Core accepts the usage of the `+` sign due to its `ParseInt64` function, `rust-miniscript` does not support this, only accepting numerical characters. This discrepancy points to a broader issue of compatibility and standardization across different implementations of Bitcoin's scripting language. Additionally, the recursive nature of the parser function in `rust-miniscript`, contrasting with Core's non-recursive approach, has led to certain miniscripts being valid in Core but rejected by `rust-miniscript`. These insights were derived through differential fuzzing efforts aimed at uncovering discrepancies and vulnerabilities in Bitcoin implementations.

The collaborative effort to address these challenges underscores the importance of community involvement in open-source projects. By documenting and sharing findings such as the bug in `rust-bitcoin` and the inconsistencies in miniscript handling, contributors can rally together to propose solutions and enhancements. This collective endeavor not only improves the technical foundations of Bitcoin but also fosters an environment of innovation and shared responsibility. The ongoing project focused on differential fuzzing, highlighted in the [bitcoinfuzz](https://github.com/brunoerg/bitcoinfuzz) GitHub repository, serves as an invitation for further contributions. It emphasizes the need for a concerted effort to enhance the security and efficiency of Bitcoin's underlying technology, inviting experts and enthusiasts alike to contribute their knowledge and expertise to this critical cause.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-17T16:15:50.793000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
