<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Liquidity griefing in multi-party transaction protocols</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:51:46.310146+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2023-12-22 21:52:24.874000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2023-12-08 15:13:07.203000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2023-12-08 08:11:22.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2023-12-07 19:14:57.154000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2023-12-07 19:12:45.205000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2023-12-07 19:12:18.623000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2023-12-07 14:35:49.640000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2023-12-07 11:21:18.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/853_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/694_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/692_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/690_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/682_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/675_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/679_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/678_Liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Liquidity griefing in multi-party transaction protocols</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:51:46.310146+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/liquidity-griefing-in-multi-party-transaction-protocols/264/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed mempool strategy aims to enhance transaction processing security, specifically targeting pinning attacks and witness inflation, by requiring transactions to enter the mempool only if they are in the top block. This approach benefits CPFP and ANYONECANPAY transactions but does not fully address the risk of attackers using low feerate transactions to create mempool partitions, which can lock liquidity until conflicts are resolved.

The system's design to combat witness inflation may inadvertently increase fees due to anti-DoS rules that evict transactions from the mempool. Matt Corallo's experiments indicate low feerate transactions can still propagate, but repeated witness inflation via large descendant transactions remains a concern, as highlighted in GitHub discussions regarding financial impacts on Lightning Service Providers.

Dual funding and splicing protocols face liquidity griefing attacks through various tactics such as withholding signatures or employing low feerate ancestors. Defenses are available but have tradeoffs; for instance, having initiators sign first provides partial mitigation. The community is actively debating mandatory RBF and other protective measures to bolster network resilience while minimizing negative effects on legitimate transactions.

In multi-party transaction protocols, there are strategies to prevent liquidity locking and griefing. For example, allowing Bob to back out if Mallory withholds signatures during a transaction initiation or inspecting witnesses before broadcasting to prevent inflation. However, these methods may limit transaction batching and do not fully protect initiators from griefing. Delaying UTXO locking can prevent liquidity from being stuck, but risks accidental double-spending.

Confirmed inputs and mempool monitoring offer solutions to unconfirmed ancestor issues but come with delays and the need for full node access, respectively. Restricting inputs to p2wpkh and requiring anchor outputs can prevent witness inflation but at the cost of usability and increased complexity and fees.

Version 3 transactions, currently under research, provide partial solutions but introduce new challenges like higher RBF-related fees. Dedicated wallets for liquidity ads are mentioned as a way to manage on-chain fees and reduce griefing impact.

Despite many explored mitigations, each comes with drawbacks. Progress at the mempool layer, with technologies such as package relay and cluster mempool, is seen as a promising solution, though their integration may take years. Optimism remains for balancing mitigations and risks in selling liquidity with these advancements.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-22T21:52:24.874000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
