<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
  <updated>2024-02-16T01:53:40.444998+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-02-15 10:44:20.568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2024-02-11 22:49:38.527000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-02-11 22:04:22.542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-11 19:03:26.496000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-02-09 11:24:28.710000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-09 03:13:23.990000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-02-08 22:19:48.787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-05 15:06:11.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2023-12-05 12:33:44.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-03 15:52:18.925000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-03 15:24:03.158000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-03 15:09:21.396000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-03 14:55:34.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-03 12:14:11.259000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-03 10:33:10.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-03 07:39:02.642000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2023-12-03 00:47:43.909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1577_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1513_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1512_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1511_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1497_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1494_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1492_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/619_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/615_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/554_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/553_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/552_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/551_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/550_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/549_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/548_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/546_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
    <updated>2024-02-16T01:53:40.445119+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lamport-signatures-and-other-cat-tricks/236/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion among programmers centers on advancing Bitcoin's script functionality with a focus on security, efficiency, and scalability, particularly through a proposal for a neutered CAT. This proposition seeks to cap the maximum output size at 80 bytes, preventing the assembly of SIGHASH or CTV templates for detailed stack introspection. It aims to balance the conservative and progressive elements within the Bitcoin community by allowing for signed data carriers within 'standard' limits while contemplating future enhancements through specialized opcodes for complex functions.

In optimizing blockchain transactions, especially for the Lightning Network, a method involving the annex section of transactions to store tapleaf information is explored. This strategy is designed to streamline updates without retaining every previous settlement transaction's outputs and HTLCs, thus reducing database storage requirements. The specification of this approach can be reviewed in detail [here](https://github.com/instagibbs/bolts/blob/a17b60f42077a785c625430e8f6e8e2828d4d898/XX-eltoo-transactions.mdrationale-1).

The conversation also highlights the challenges in managing on-chain states and channel coins movement, emphasizing the need for access to all non-deterministic components of the script for smooth transitions between transaction states. Techniques like the Asynchronous Proof of Ownership (APO) are vital for aligning private states with publicly committed ones, ensuring the continuity of transactions on the chain.

Cryptographic techniques are discussed to enhance security and data integrity in cryptocurrency transactions. This includes the use of `nLockTime` parameters, hashing for secure state transitions, and an additional SHA256 layer to safeguard the immutability of signatures. Enhancements akin to Tapscript, part of the Bitcoin Taproot upgrade, are considered for facilitating complex transactions while easing upgrade and deployment processes.

Proposals for soft forks introduce new script operations and encoding methods, such as Pay to X Script Hash (P2XSH) and a limited re-enabling of the `OP_CAT` operation. These suggestions aim at avoiding quantum-non-resistant paths and improving script functionality, despite existing technical constraints in Bitcoin's architecture.

Security protocols against potential quantum attacks are proposed, including the disclosure of additional data like the script hash in transaction annexes and creating a 'quantum proof exit hatch' for treasuries. The dialogue extends into cryptographic security and the Discrete Logarithm (DL) problem's implications on cryptocurrency transactions. Concerns over vulnerabilities in key path spends due to potential breakthroughs in solving the DL problem are raised, suggesting complete disabling of key path spends as a countermeasure. Script path spends are viewed as more resilient to cryptographic vulnerabilities, relying on SHA256's resistance to preimage attacks.

Issues in the verification process for keyspend operations are acknowledged, alongside debates on the feasibility of enforcing script-only transactions without altering current address formats. The significance of cryptographic security is underscored through the risks posed by the discrete logarithm problem to transaction privacy and security mechanisms, advocating for robust practices against advanced mathematical breakthroughs.

In anticipation of quantum computing threats, a soft-fork proposal to enhance taproot security by restricting the use of 'G' as an internal public key is discussed. A quantum-resistant, script-only Pay-to-Taproot (P2TR) output is suggested, with interim measures including a Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve (NUMS) point. Additionally, the email proposes optimizations related to Merkle trees for generating single-use public keys and verifying signatures, introducing technical refinements and questioning the viability of extensive data management scripts against quantum threats.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T10:44:20.568000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
