<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - [BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
  <updated>2024-01-02T09:42:43.655924+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2023-12-30 17:47:32.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2023-12-28 13:55:39.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GregTonoski  . 2023-12-27 20:54:30.891000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/882_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/879_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/873_-BUG-spammers-get-Bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-Let-s-fix-it.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - [BUG]: spammers get Bitcoin blockspace at discounted price. Let's fix it</title>
    <updated>2024-01-02T09:42:43.655924+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bug-spammers-get-bitcoin-blockspace-at-discounted-price-lets-fix-it/327/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email in question addresses a significant issue within the Bitcoin blockchain, specifically concerning the pricing disparities between different types of transactions and their use of block space. It details how the current pricing model can lead to a range of inefficiencies, such as misallocation of block space, devaluation of block space due to these inefficiencies, disincentivization of simple transactions, and potential centralization around entities that manage complex transactions. The sender provides two examples of transactions with links to mempool.space for reference: one [transaction](https://mempool.space/tx/aabbcce67f2aa71932f789cac5468d39e3d2224d8bebb7ca2c3bf8c41d567cdd) with 616 weight and 205 bytes and another [transaction](https://mempool.space/tx/1c35521798dde4d1621e9aa5a3bacac03100fca40b6fb99be546ec50c1bcbd4a) with 1140 weight and 767 bytes, where the former is priced higher than the latter despite being simpler.

The sender proposes a formula `WUtx = 4·size(tx_data|segwit_data) - 3·min(3·size(tx_data), size(segwit_data))` with the aim of not disadvantaging normal users of Bitcoin but instead making disproportionate use of witness space less competitive. It is acknowledged that most spam involving brc-20 would not be significantly affected by this change. However, it is anticipated that future alternative assets will likely utilize either runes or RGB technology, potentially offering more efficiency regarding block space usage.

Further examination into the system's transactions reveals an overlooked aspect—the differing resource footprints of transaction components. To effectively propose changes, it is suggested that a thorough understanding of the motivations behind the current state of the system is necessary. Without this insight, modifications may fail to address the complexities of the system adequately.

Finally, the sender suggests that uniform pricing might be implemented in a future version of Segwit transactions. This approach could normalize costs across all transactions by treating every byte of data equally in terms of "weight", thus rectifying the skewed incentives and vulnerabilities of the present system. The sender is seeking consensus on this proposal, which they believe would equitably restructure the incentive framework and contribute to the overall improvement of the blockchain network's functionality.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-30T17:47:32.037000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
