<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mailing list mode</title>
  <updated>2024-01-30T08:14:23.739989+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-01-30 01:03:09.962000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2024-01-30 00:39:25.334000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2024-01-29 22:33:31.813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-04 20:45:52.360000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1376_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1375_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1373_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/572_Mailing-list-mode.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mailing list mode</title>
    <updated>2024-01-30T08:14:23.740039+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mailing-list-mode/245/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The functionality of interacting with forum posts via email, specifically on the DelvingBitcoin site, has been a subject of inquiry. Users have demonstrated the ability to organize their forum notifications using traditional email filters, categorizing posts from different sections or tags into separate labels for efficient management. A screenshot provided illustrates this setup, and it is mentioned that some users prefer to utilize the mailing list mode to stay updated with forum activities. 

Concerns have been raised about the capability to reply to emails received from the mailing list mode due to the sender address being `noreply@delvingbtc.erisian.com.au`, which suggests that direct replies may not be supported. This limitation is notable for users who favor the mailing list method for its similarity to traditional mailing lists, which they might be accustomed to for community interaction.

Recent updates have brought changes to the system, notably turning off the "disable mailing list mode" switch. This decision has generated discussion among users, with some advocating for the option to subscribe to specific tags or categories rather than using the broad approach of mailing list mode. To explore these changes, users can adjust their preferences through the user interface by clicking the favicon at the top right, selecting the head-and-shoulders icon, and then navigating to the preferences and email tab. 

The ongoing debate regarding the utility of the mailing list mode feature and its potential disabling is referenced in a thread on a Discourse community forum ([Discourse community](https://meta.discourse.org/t/completely-disable-mailing-list-mode/37334)), where various viewpoints are shared. Despite mixed opinions, users still have the opportunity to test the current settings to determine how they impact their forum experience. These alterations are part of an effort to refine the notification and update systems within the platform, which could influence user engagement and interaction with content.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-30T01:03:09.962000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
