<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:39:15.579952+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2023-12-28 16:38:10.719000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>wydengyre 2023-12-28 02:34:27.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 20:05:49.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RandyMcMillan  . 2023-12-19 18:56:24.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 16:59:33.416000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:22.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:40:16.610000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:33:53.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:30:02.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 15:26:33.367000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 15:23:41.886000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:21:22.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:12:37.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 15:09:50.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 15:00:06.516000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2023-12-19 14:55:19.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 14:52:51.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2023-12-19 14:49:37.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-19 13:35:30.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2023-12-19 13:29:37.600000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/880_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/877_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/836_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/835_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/808_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/804_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/803_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/802_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/800_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/801_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/799_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/798_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/797_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/796_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/791_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/795_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/794_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/793_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/790_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/789_Unspendable-keys-in-descriptors.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:39:15.581017+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Developers are actively discussing methods to enhance the security of Bitcoin transactions, focusing on improving extended public keys (xpubs) handling. Different techniques include altering the chaincode or generating new pubkeys, with the former being preferred for its simplicity and cleaner integration with wallet descriptors. XOR operations using BIP85-derived xpubs are also considered for increasing security without sacrificing compatibility.

The use of ROT13 encryption as a basic obfuscation method for 'xpub xpub' data is recognized, but it's not recommended for protecting against serious threats due to its weak cryptographic strength. Privacy is emphasized in transactions, particularly in maintaining the confidentiality of unspendable key paths. Solutions such as generating signatures without exposing sensitive details are explored to prove unspendability while preserving privacy.

Backup strategies are shifting towards wallet policies instead of descriptors, as they more accurately reflect user accounts and could simplify digital asset management. The distinct roles of output descriptors and wallet policies are pointed out, with descriptors explicitly defining spendability and policies potentially relying on deterministic frameworks.

The debate includes concerns over script complexity in transactions, advocating for privacy by not mandating disclosure of unspendability, supported by standards like BIP341 that allow for secret components to remain undisclosed. A technical challenge is acknowledged in creating Bitcoin addresses with partial descriptors, underscoring the need for methods that contain all necessary entropy within the descriptor itself.

The concept of digital fingerprinting in cryptocurrency transactions is examined, with an emphasis on the importance of voluntary disclosure to protect user privacy. The balance between transparency for security and privacy concerns is a recurring theme in these discussions.

BIP352, which focuses on script-only spends, raises concerns about compromising user privacy and potential discrimination based on transaction types. Unspendable keys, essential for entropy quality and privacy enhancement, should appear indistinguishable from random keys. Standardizing a public Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve number (NUMS) is suggested, though this brings up privacy and security concerns.

At TabConf 2022, advancements in miniscript and descriptors were discussed, with a Gist by sipa providing foundational insights ([Unspendable Keys Gist](https://gist.github.com/sipa/06c5c844df155d4e5044c2c8cac9c05e)). The integration of miniscript with taproot in Bitcoin Core presents challenges for wallet developers in using unspendable keys within spending policies. Several methods for generating these keys are debated, with a focus on balancing properties like indistinguishability, uniqueness, identification ease, and hardware signer compatibility.

Using a root xpub with a random chaincode currently appears to be practical, despite some user experience trade-offs. Recycling descriptor entropy to generate an unspendable xpub is seen as a cleaner long-term solution, especially for inclusion in wallet policies. However, the transition to wallet policies as a backup standard is still in early stages. Ongoing discussion and innovation are required to refine methods for creating secure and practical unspendable keys within taproot and miniscript constraints.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-28T16:38:10.719000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
