<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A High-Privacy Key-Value Store</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:46:30.649482+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2023-12-06 22:58:59.437000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2023-12-05 14:25:53.350000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/674_A-High-Privacy-Key-Value-Store.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/617_A-High-Privacy-Key-Value-Store.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A High-Privacy Key-Value Store</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:46:30.649482+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-high-privacy-key-value-store/253/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Network communication systems face reliability challenges that can lead to credential loss during transactions. A server-based idempotency mechanism has been developed to prevent the repeated use of credentials, enabling clients to reuse them safely after unintentional disconnections by recording each credential as spent in the server’s database.

The proposed framework includes a cloud-based storage service that prioritizes client privacy and data recoverability, relying on a client-server model with a key-value store. The keys are SECP256K1 public keys, and the values are encrypted blobs. Operations such as insertion, deletion, and lookup are fortified with security measures to protect against unauthorized access and maintain encryption.

A payment model for this service utilizes WabiSabi credentials as tokens for insertions and deletions, with an epoch system for token lifecycle management. Additionally, a secondary "break glass" storage provides emergency access to credentials through a specific interface for managing emergency recovery operations.

Clients operate within a vast public key space to avoid collisions, using mechanisms like CLN's `db_write` hooks or LDK's monotonic counters for data insertion and recovery. The system supports various data storage schemes, such as immutable b-trees, by transforming equality indexes into public keys, thus facilitating the creation of versatile key-value stores that leverage the expansive SECP256K1 key space.

Regarding anonymity in data storage and retrieval, direct TCP tunnels are bypassed in favor of more secure methods due to the internet's public nature. Despite Tor being a potential solution, its TCP emulation could enable service correlation of requests to a single client. To counteract this, clients should frequently change TCP-over-Tor tunnels and circuits. A stronger alternative is the Lightning Network Onion Messages (LN OM) system, which preserves privacy through its reply_path feature and minimizes the risk of client identification by distributing interactions across multiple paths. While limited to established channels, LN OM is favored over both OHTTP and Tor for ensuring discrete messaging and its capacity for different routing of responses compared to requests.

In conclusion, the update and recovery process of an immutable Merklized data structure is efficient, while LN OM emerges as the preferred transport layer security technology, providing discreet messaging and leveraging multiple communication paths, transcending the capabilities of other privacy-focused protocols.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T22:58:59.437000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
