<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T19:27:32.491271+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2023-12-18 18:03:14.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno 2023-12-01 19:30:21.802000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2023-11-29 23:01:43.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/786_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/541_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2023/516_Differential-Fuzzing-of-Bitcoin-implementations.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Differential Fuzzing of Bitcoin implementations</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T19:27:32.492335+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/differential-fuzzing-of-bitcoin-implementations/208/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent communications have brought to light a critical technical concern within the rust-miniscript repository, marked by a system crash that has spurred discussion among developers. An open issue with identifier 633 has been logged on the project's GitHub page, which can be visited at [rust-miniscript issue #633](https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-miniscript/issues/633issuecomment-1856401701) for an in-depth look at the problem. The involvement of influential contributors, including @sipa, underscores the significance of this issue and the need for expert intervention.

The crash in question poses significant challenges to the functionality of applications that rely on rust-miniscript, making its swift resolution vital to preserve the software's integrity. The open-source nature of projects like rust-miniscript is a testament to the power of community collaboration in software development. Such issues are not only a call to action for those skilled in Rust programming and familiar with miniscript but also an opportunity to demonstrate the collective strength in addressing and overcoming software hurdles.

Further investigations into the crashes are underway, indicating a proactive approach to understanding and documenting these incidents before making them public. Additionally, a notable discovery has been made, evident from another issue posted on GitHub, accessible at [sipa/miniscript issue #140](https://github.com/sipa/miniscript/issues/140). This reflects the ongoing efforts to scrutinize the miniscript library comprehensively, aiming to ensure its robustness and reliability for users across various applications.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T18:03:14.347000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
