<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
  <updated>2024-02-17T01:52:06.222557+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.146000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi.556000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi.498000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..568000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..527000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  ..496000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..710000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  ..990000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..787000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  ..469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..925000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..158000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  ..396000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  ..259000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  ..642000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  ..909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1589_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1587_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1586_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1585_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1577_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1513_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1512_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1511_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1497_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1494_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1492_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/619_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/615_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/554_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/553_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/552_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/551_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/550_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/549_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/548_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/546_Lamport-signatures-and-other-CAT-tricks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Lamport signatures and other CAT tricks</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T01:52:06.222702+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lamport-signatures-and-other-cat-tricks/236/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion encompasses several facets of enhancing Bitcoin's scripting language, focusing on the implementation difficulties and potential solutions for incorporating binary bitwise arithmetic using Categorical Availability Theory (CAT). It outlines the challenges faced in executing operations such as XOR, ROTR, SHIFTR, NOT, and AND within Bitcoin script due to the absence of native support. A feasible workaround proposed includes performing these operations bit-by-bit or utilizing lookup tables, with a practical example available in a [GitHub repository](https://github.com/coins/bitcoin-scripts/blob/405f3b0dbf64115eab7035482397b322822c6d19/op_lookup.md).

A key proposal discussed is the introduction of a 'neutered CAT' to evolve Bitcoin scripting by limiting the maximum output size to 80 bytes, aiming to mitigate unintended consequences in assembling SIGHASH or CTV templates. This measure seeks to balance conservative and progressive views in the community by aligning with the size requirements for signed data carriers and addressing cryptographic needs.

The conversation further explores strategies for managing on-chain states and transaction updates efficiently in blockchain systems. It presents a technique that involves storing the tapleaf of a previous settlement transaction in the annex section, which could streamline state updates and reduce database storage demands. This approach is designed to enhance efficiency and scalability by facilitating the reflection of peer-published states in local databases.

Challenges in managing channel coins in off-chain transactions are also examined, emphasizing the necessity of accessing all non-deterministic components of the script for reconstructing transactions based on the latest state. Proposals to encode essential data for channel state recovery through new opcodes and mechanisms are discussed, aiming to improve the robustness of the Lightning Network.

Innovations similar to Tapscript from the Bitcoin Taproot upgrade are proposed to increase script functionality, offering more flexibility for developers. These include suggestions for a soft fork to introduce new script operations and encoding methods that could accommodate advanced features like Lamport signatures and potentially re-enable the OP_CAT operation.

From a security perspective, there's an acknowledgment of the challenges in implementing certain scripts due to Bitcoin's existing architectural constraints, which may hinder the introduction of new features aimed at innovation. Discussions highlight proposals for mandatory disclosure of additional data in transaction annexes and emphasize the need for 'quantum proof exit hatches' for treasuries as a countermeasure against quantum attacks. The dialogue underscores the importance of secure scripts alongside cryptographic functions, considering SHA256's resilience and the potential vulnerabilities in keyspend operations.

A proposed enhancement for Taproot's security involves implementing a soft-fork to limit the usage of the internal public key ('G'), aiming to create a quantum-resistant script-only Pay-to-Taproot (P2TR) output. An interim solution suggests adopting a Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve (NUMS) point as a placeholder to future-proof the system against quantum computing threats.

Finally, the email delves into optimizing scripting for Merkle tree construction and verification to generate single-use public keys, suggesting a `DIVMOD` operation to improve efficiency. It also discusses a blockchain-based script designed to manage significant signature data inputs and ensure data integrity against future quantum threats, highlighting the importance of privacy and verifiability in transactions through deterministic public keys derived from BIP-32 HD wallets.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T13:18:10.146000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
