<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Aggregate delegated exit for L2 pools</title>
  <updated>2023-12-22T19:03:22.563917+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2023-12-20 13:25:42.864000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2023-12-19 15:52:31.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ErikDeSmedt 2023-12-19 15:45:30.461000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2023-12-16 14:11:01.540000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/839_Aggregate-delegated-exit-for-L2-pools.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/807_Aggregate-delegated-exit-for-L2-pools.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/806_Aggregate-delegated-exit-for-L2-pools.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/735_Aggregate-delegated-exit-for-L2-pools.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Aggregate delegated exit for L2 pools</title>
    <updated>2023-12-22T19:03:22.563917+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/aggregate-delegated-exit-for-l2-pools/297/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Blockchain fraud proofs and their application in secure transaction protocols are key areas of focus for enhancing security within blockchain systems. A withdrawal protocol enables users with insufficient funds to cover transaction fees to participate in aggregated withdrawals, relying on the collective action of users.

This protocol uses vector commitments within a Merkle tree structure to store user balances. In case of fraud or contract errors, an "Unwind" contract is triggered, allowing pooled UTXO withdrawals. For high-value users, immediate withdrawals are possible through direct Merkle proofs; however, this is not cost-effective for users with low balances due to high transaction fees.

An alternative, the optimistic withdrawal method, allows users to claim their balance by locking additional funds as a bond during a challenge period. If the claim is disputed and proven false, the challenger gains half of the bond and the other half is destroyed, thus preventing sybil attacks and promoting honesty.

To assist users with minimal balances, an intermediary known as Ingrid can facilitate withdrawals. Users delegate their rights to Ingrid, who claims the aggregate balance while posting a bond and creating a time-locked output for potential challenges. If Ingrid's claim is incorrect, it can be challenged using a fraud proof protocol related to the state's Merkle tree. Successful challenges result in a reward of half of Ingrid's bond, while the other half is destroyed, and her withdrawal attempt is voided. If unchallenged, Ingrid completes the withdrawal and redistributes the funds.

The design of the system allows intermediaries to be selected after the creation of the Unwind UTXO, fostering user cooperation and keeping costs for claiming funds nearly constant for Ingrid. Any fraudulent action results in financial loss, discouraging dishonesty.

Improvements to the system could include a non-custodial role for intermediaries and a withdrawal protocol that doesn't scale costs with the number of users, ensuring a constant cost regardless of pool size. The possibility of conducting parallel optimistic withdrawals across separate UTXOs with cross-input introspection capabilities also represents an area for development.

Fraud proofs play a crucial role in solving the L2 exit problem, providing economically viable solutions for users with low balances and improving trust and efficiency in unwinding processes. However, the mechanism's complexity raises questions about the impact of withdrawals on concurrent transactions and the need for specific script requirements. The potential use of features such as OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and 64-bit arithmetic operations, while not essential, would enhance the system's functionality. Although workarounds for missing opcodes exist, they are less than ideal.

In summary, the strategy for secure blockchain transactions through fraud proofs shows promise, with several details yet to be refined. Further discussion and analysis are invited to perfect the approach.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T13:25:42.864000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
