<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - This is a shitpost thread</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T10:39:56.960722+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2023-12-04 23:52:27.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2023-12-04 23:39:35.547000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2023-12-04 23:28:25.311000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2023-12-04 23:24:56.111000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>GeorgeTsagk 2023-12-04 23:13:55.266000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2023-12-04 23:11:36.756000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef 2023-12-04 22:25:48.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/607_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/606_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/605_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/603_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/602_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/601_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/578_This-is-a-shitpost-thread.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - This is a shitpost thread</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T10:39:56.961719+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/this-is-a-shitpost-thread/249/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The communication addresses some technical aspects and features of a user interface and email functionality. The writer is currently unable to receive email responses and mentions having contacted a colleague named AJ regarding the matter, who seems to be investigating spam-related concerns. A user interface (UI) test was conducted to assess the thread capability, with the writer replying directly to an individual named George. The initial email and the subsequent reply are illustrated with an included screenshot, but the specific contents of the image are not described in text.

Additionally, the writer conducted a test involving Go programming language syntax for struct definition, as well as LaTeX equations to evaluate their rendering within the forum's environment. The reference to LaTeX equations suggests that they are working satisfactorily or are impressive ("dope"), indicating that the forum supports complex mathematical expressions.

Finally, the author describes their post as an experimental "shit post thread" aimed at understanding the functionalities of the forum, specifically testing the mailing list mode, which has been activated. The author is interested in observing how emails are structured when sent, including whether they contain context and prior replies. A link to instructions on enabling the mailing list mode is provided for further clarification on this feature.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-04T23:52:27.937000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
