<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2024-01-21T02:05:39.974333+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-01-20 03:46:40.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:56:02.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2024-01-19 23:48:45.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-22 03:04:11.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-21 18:03:33.954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2023-12-21 11:23:16.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-20 21:54:22.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-18 02:43:32.230000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-14 21:14:15.928000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1238_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1235_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1237_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/849_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/848_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/845_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/843_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/783_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/732_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T02:05:39.974453+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The blog post begins with an overview of a recent simulation aimed at understanding the behavior of a Bitcoin network under various conditions. This exercise involved a Warnet scenario with 100 nodes and focused on transaction relay and confirmation. The simulation did not visualize the initial distribution of 50 BTC to each node, rather it examined the network after establishing normal block production rates. A block timing function was used to replicate realistic mining intervals, and the results indicated that the pending update (PR) being tested did not significantly affect performance at moderate transaction rates. Metrics such as transaction reconstruction requests, mempool size, and outbound connections were measured, though the latter was deemed less relevant for this test.

The email highlights the importance of accurate timekeeping in simulations, suggesting mocktime as a viable option, yet also acknowledges the potential advantages of using real-time for comparisons. The sender agrees with AJ Towns' contributions and is willing to experiment with node numbers beyond 100 while also considering smaller sets for comparative purposes. The goal is to create a deterministic method for generating UTXOs and to observe system performance at increasing transaction creation rates. Questions regarding the balance between inbound and outbound transaction rates are raised, particularly with respect to aligning individual node metrics with overall network standards.

An in-depth study is proposed to assess the impact of varying transaction insertion and confirmation rates, concentrating on RBF transactions and their patterns on the mainnet. A 100-node network will be utilized, with adjustments like reducing the `MAX_OUTBOUND_FULL_RELAY_CONNECTIONS` parameter to mimic larger networks. Mining will occur every ten minutes by a random peer, with transactions split into smaller amounts and additional transactions generated at specified rates using Taproot or P2WSH formats. Fees will be dynamically set using the `estimatesmartfee 5` command, modified by a random factor. Key metrics include compact block relay efficiency, with expectations of mempool inconsistencies and increased transaction request numbers when rates exceed certain thresholds.

To emulate mainnet conditions, transaction dynamics and network configuration must be carefully considered. The simulation aims to replicate mainnet behaviors, particularly those involving RBF transactions, within the constraints of mainnet's obscure structure and warnet resources. Kubernetes support via warnet may allow for handling larger node numbers. The discussion revolves around achieving the most effective network topology to mirror mainnet conditions and determining which metrics are crucial post-implementation. These include estimating bandwidth and CPU usage increases due to relay rate changes, the effect of these rates on mempool turnover during congestion, and the memory impact on internal send queues across peers. Community feedback is sought to refine the approach, identify any overlooked aspects, and prioritize elements of the simulation process, all aimed at creating a representative and insightful simulated environment for understanding mainnet behavior.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-20T03:46:40.964000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
