<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
  <updated>2023-12-30T11:23:37.446858+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-22 03:04:11.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-21 18:03:33.954000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mdwards  . 2023-12-21 11:23:16.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti  . 2023-12-20 21:54:22.898000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2023-12-18 02:43:32.230000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>amiti 2023-12-14 21:14:15.928000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/849_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/848_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/845_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/843_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/783_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/732_Warnet-Increase-Tx-Relay-Rate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Warnet + Increase Tx Relay Rate</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T11:23:37.446858+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/warnet-increase-tx-relay-rate/294/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of mocktime's utility in programming offers a compelling avenue for achieving more accurate results swiftly, though it requires careful consideration to avoid inaccuracies. Establishing a real-time baseline is posited as a simpler alternative for comparison, highlighting the trade-offs between simulated time and real-world time tracking in software testing scenarios. In the realm of blockchain technology, specifically Bitcoin Core, the production rate of blocks has a direct correlation with the clearance of transactions from the mempool. Configurations exist that could double transaction creation rates, but this approach introduces complexities due to non-scalable transaction relay parameters within Bitcoin Core's codebase. The use of mocktime is presented as a potential solution to adjust the system's perception of time, allowing for manipulation of block mining times which may address the issue of fixed transaction relay values.

An accelerated block mining frequency can provide insightful feedback and robustness assessments during peer-to-peer network tests. By increasing block production speed, developers can simulate high-load conditions to evaluate how the network would respond under stress, revealing issues with block propagation and peer selection algorithms not evident under normal operation. However, adopting such a strategy must be approached cautiously to ensure test results remain applicable to real-world usage patterns.

The sender of the email endorses a proposal for network testing while suggesting experiments involving different node configurations, such as comparing the outcomes between testing with 4 and 8 nodes. This approach aims to establish a deterministic method for generating Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) to test various transaction patterns. An incremental increase of the transaction creation rate will help identify the threshold at which performance degrades. A disparity between inbound and outbound transaction rates is acknowledged, highlighting an ongoing challenge of aligning individual node metrics with broader network standards.

Further investigation is warranted into the effects of varying transaction and confirmation rates on blockchain networks, focusing on Replace-By-Fee (RBF) transactions. A study proposes using a 100-node network setup to manipulate size, transaction creation rate, and confirmation rate. Nodes will operate on Bitcoin Core version 26.0 to maintain consistency. Adjustments like reducing `MAX_OUTBOUND_FULL_RELAY_CONNECTIONS` could better reflect larger network dynamics. Mining will occur every ten minutes, with rewards split into smaller transactions in Taproot or P2WSH formats, and fees dynamically calculated. Performance will be gauged by compact block relay efficiency, with debug logs indicating successful reconstructions. High transaction creation rates exceeding 18 tx/s are expected to cause mempool inconsistencies, particularly in RBF and CPFP scenarios.

Lastly, a representation of mainnet conditions in testing scenarios involves two critical aspects: introducing transactions to the mempool and removing them via blocks, as well as the network setup, including node count and connection graph. Mimicking the real network as closely as possible poses challenges due to mainnet's obfuscation and resource limitations. Desired outcomes focus on quantifying impacts on bandwidth and CPU usage, mempool churn, transaction propagation, and memory usage in response to increased relay rates. Community feedback is sought to validate the conceptual framework, identify missing elements, and prioritize objectives for effective test design and outcomes.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-22T03:04:11.956000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
