<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-08-06T02:05:41.849816+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vazertuche</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-05T21:35:18.395000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-08-06T02:05:41.849856+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/30" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the implementation of the Anti-exfil protocol in the secp256k1 library is gaining traction, especially with the upcoming version 3 of PSBT (Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions) that will necessitate DLEQ (Discrete Logarithm Equality) proofs. This suggestion is particularly pertinent given the landscape of hardware wallets, many of which do not support specific software wallets and rely solely on the functionality provided by core implementations, the secp256k1 library, and a robustly tested PSBT specification. The integration of Anti-exfil protocols directly into the secp256k1 library could significantly enhance security measures, making hardware wallets more resilient to vulnerabilities.

The recent [darkskippy.com attack](https://www.darkskippy.com) underscores the urgency and relevance of adopting more stringent security protocols within the cryptographic community. Such attacks not only highlight existing weaknesses but also serve as a reminder of the ongoing arms race between security professionals and malicious actors. By incorporating the Anti-exfil protocol into the secp256k1 library, developers have the chance to address multiple security concerns simultaneously. This approach not only mitigates specific vulnerabilities exposed by the likes of the darkskippy.com incident but also fortifies the PSBT specification against a broader range of potential threats, leveraging this development phase as an opportunity to introduce critical, wide-reaching improvements to the security infrastructure underpinning Bitcoin transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T21:35:18.395000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
