<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
  <updated>2024-08-10T02:06:37.230363+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-08-09 07:01:37.418000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T02:06:37.230402+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bolt-12-trusted-contacts/1046/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the potential vulnerabilities and user interface design considerations in cryptocurrency wallets, focusing on how contacts and payment codes are managed. The conversation begins with a hypothetical scenario where Alice is deceived into associating Mallory's key with Bob's name, highlighting concerns about the clarity and security of associating contact information with payment codes. This example raises questions about the effectiveness of wallet designs in preventing such deceptive practices and whether users can easily be misled into making erroneous associations.

Further, the conversation delves into the repercussions of a compromised contact key, particularly for organizations that use a single key with numerous customers. The compromise of a contact key implies a more significant underlying security breach, possibly leading to the loss of funds. In such situations, an organization's primary recourse would be to inform their users about the change in their contact key, drawing parallels to the procedure followed when user passwords are compromised. Although this is not seen as a critical issue compared to other potential security breaches, it still poses a considerable inconvenience and risk.

Another aspect discussed is the functionality of wallets that support multiple keys or offers for a single contact. This suggests a flexibility in managing contacts within wallets that could potentially mitigate some risks. However, the conversation also touches upon the challenge of educating users about the security aspects of payments. Specifically, it critiques the reliance on the 'payer_note' field, which businesses and protocols might use to convey information to users. The concern here is that contrary to advising users to only trust the payment amount, they might be encouraged to pay attention to additional fields like 'payer_note', which could lead to security oversights.

In conclusion, while the discussion acknowledges the inherent risks associated with digital wallet transactions and the potential for key compromise, it also considers the importance of designing wallet interfaces that clearly communicate the association between contacts and payment codes. Additionally, it reflects on the broader challenge of user education and the need for secure practices in handling payments, recognizing that achieving perfect security may be unattainable due to the possibility of key compromise.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-09T07:01:37.418000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
