<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-12T02:11:13.291117+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2024-08-11 09:44:37.218000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-12T02:11:13.291142+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed solution addresses significant vulnerabilities within the blockchain's consensus mechanism, specifically targeting the timewarp attack. The suggested fix, when integrated with the consensus cleanup's timewarp correction, aims to ensure that retarget periods become monotonic, thereby enhancing the system's resilience against specific types of attacks. The timewarp attack presents two major threats: firstly, it substantially increases the power of a 51% attacker, making the network more susceptible to malicious activities. Secondly, it encourages behavior that is detrimental to the long-term sustainability of the system by tempting miners and users to increase the block rate for short-term gains.

Moreover, the discussion highlights the Murch-Zawy attack, which, unlike the timewarp, necessitates the non-publication of blocks for an extended period (16 weeks) but similarly allows an adversary to benefit from continuously reduced difficulty levels. This aspect of the Murch-Zawy attack aligns with the timewarp in enabling attackers to significantly lower the difficulty, potentially down to the lowest possible level, within a comparable timeframe. The dialogue suggests incorporating the solution as part of broader efforts to revive and strengthen the consensus cleanup initiative, indicating a strategic approach to mitigating vulnerabilities and ensuring the robustness of the platform. For further information on the consensus cleanup and its implications, interested parties can visit [this link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710should-we-really-fix-it-3).</summary>
    <published>2024-08-11T09:44:37.218000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
