<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-14T02:08:47.986253+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2024-08-13 18:47:55.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-14T02:08:47.986284+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of blockchain timestamps and their correlation with mining difficulty adjustments, presenting a detailed analysis of how block rates and difficulty levels are inherently linked within a blockchain framework. The conversation elucidates that block timestamps are pivotal in ensuring that the construction of a valid chain does not exceed a certain block rate, specifically averting scenarios where blocks are mined faster than a set benchmark of one per ten minutes without corresponding adjustments in mining difficulty.

It is articulated that the adjustment mechanism for mining difficulty operates on a cyclical basis, influenced directly by the time taken to mine blocks within specific periods. Initially, if the first period approximately spans 2.83 weeks, the subsequent adjustment sees the difficulty halved (to $D/\sqrt{2}$) for the second period. This adjustment aims at maintaining the average block creation rate by altering the computational challenge presented to miners. As the second period mirrors the duration of the first, the difficulty level further adjusts to half its original value ($D/2$), effectively responding to the sustained pace of block mining.

Following these two adjustments, a significant shift occurs after the third period, where the difficulty level is designed to double, returning it to its original state (denoted as D). This recalibration is a direct consequence of the protocol’s inherent cap on difficulty adjustments, which does not permit more than a twofold increase during any adjustment phase. This mechanism ensures a balanced dynamic between block creation rate and mining difficulty, maintaining the network's stability and security by preventing excessively rapid or slow block generation rates.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T18:47:55.515000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
