<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-14T02:07:51.542172+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-08-13 20:40:52.852000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-14T02:07:51.542199+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the enforcement of blockchain timing rules, specifically focusing on the Fixed Time Limit (FTL) and its implications on the Proposed Time Limit (PTL). The conversation starts with an exploration of how enforcing FTL across all nodes could lead to an indirect implementation of PTL. This notion stems from the observation that if nodes begin to enforce a rule where the timestamp cannot progress more than two hours between blocks, it would cause a significant change in the network's operation. Specifically, the rule being considered is that for each block \(B\) with height \(n\), the condition \(∀n∈N: nTime_{B_n} + 3600 s \geq nTime_{B_{n+1}}\) must be met.

However, confusion arises regarding the interpretation of this rule and its impact on the blockchain's temporal properties. The counterargument presented questions the logical progression, or rather, the inference that this rule would automatically mean \(∀n∈N:time_{B_n}\leq time_{B_{n+1}} - 3600 s\). The concern here is about the mathematical manipulation of the inequality which does not necessarily imply a reversal in the direction of the inequality. This part of the discussion highlights a critical analysis of the proposed timing control mechanism within blockchain technology, emphasizing the complexity of implementing such temporal restrictions and their potential effects on mining and block organization.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T20:40:52.852000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
