<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-15T02:00:17.093619+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-15T00:13:58.746000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-15T02:00:17.093648+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>FTL and PTL are acronyms commonly used in the logistics and transportation industry, representing two distinct methods of shipping goods. FTL stands for Full Truckload, while PTL denotes Partial Truckload, also known as Less Than Truckload (LTL). 

Full Truckload shipping is utilized when the quantity of goods is sufficient to fill an entire truck. This method is cost-effective for large shipments since it involves direct delivery from the point of origin to the destination without any intermediate stops or handling. FTL is preferred for high volume shipments, fragile or high-risk cargo, and when the shipment needs to be delivered on a strict timeline. The exclusivity of using the entire truck also provides a higher level of security for the cargo.

Partial Truckload or Less Than Truckload shipping, on the other hand, is designed for shipments that do not require the full space of a truck. This option allows multiple shippers to share space on the same truck, making it a more economical choice for smaller shipments. LTL shipments typically involve more stops and handling as the cargo is consolidated at hubs and then distributed to various destinations. This method is ideal for businesses with flexible delivery schedules and those looking to save costs on smaller shipments. However, the increased handling can raise the risk of damage to the goods, so it's less suited for fragile items.

Each shipping method has its advantages and is chosen based on the specific needs of the shipment, including size, urgency, budget, and the nature of the goods being transported. Businesses must weigh these factors carefully to decide which method will best suit their logistical requirements and ensure the safe, efficient delivery of their products.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-15T00:13:58.746000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
