<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-16T02:08:02.146962+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-15T19:45:06.437000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T02:08:02.146993+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion raises concerns over the terminology used to describe the enforcement of both Fast Transaction Limits (FTL) and Precision Timing Limits (PTL), questioning the appropriateness of referring to it collectively as a "properly enforced FTL." It highlights a misunderstanding or disagreement on the necessity and distinct roles of FTL and PTL, emphasizing that each plays a critical role that warrants separate recognition. The discourse eventually finds common ground on other aspects, particularly regarding solutions to identified issues within blockchain technology.

One key point of agreement is on a proposed solution aimed at addressing a specific class of problems related to blockchain difficulty adjustments. This solution involves making minimal changes to the existing consensus rules, focusing on how difficulty readjustments are calculated. By concentrating solely on the timestamps of the first and last blocks in a difficulty period, the solution aims to streamline the process without introducing additional, potentially cumbersome regulations. The argument suggests that adding more rules to restrict other timestamps would not only be unnecessarily complicated but also unlikely to offer significant benefits, highlighting a preference for simplicity and efficiency in solving this problem.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-15T19:45:06.437000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
