<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:06:36.736806+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-20T15:47:06.186000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:06:36.736842+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/27" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the proposal to set the nLockTime parameter of transactions to the block height, which would simplify the extraction of block height from the coinbase transaction. This approach is particularly beneficial for scenarios where it's necessary to ascertain that a transaction occurred after a certain block height, such as in the case of air-gapped embedded hardware devices. These devices could enforce rules requiring transactions to exist above a specified height, using the cumulative difficulty of surrounding headers as proof. The proposition suggests that this rule be enforced immediately upon the activation of a soft fork, without delay until a specific future block height, like 1,983,702, to avoid potential complications.

There is an acknowledgment of potential challenges miners might face with the introduction of this new rule, especially considering the diverse custom software solutions utilized in processing coinbase transactions. It's uncertain how these systems will adapt to the change, suggesting a need for thorough testing before full implementation. A GitHub branch has been created by Sjors, featuring a pull request that implements the `-coinbaselocktime` parameter, aiming to facilitate mining code adjustments to accommodate this new rule ([GitHub PR](https://github.com/Sjors/bitcoin/pull/60)). The proposal encourages miners to test this solution well in advance of any formal activation parameters being established. This proactive approach aims to identify and address any unforeseen issues, ensuring a smooth transition for all parties involved.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T15:47:06.186000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
