<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:11:17.131739+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-20T18:53:47.953000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:11:17.131789+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptographic security, a novel approach has been discussed where a cryptographically secure hash commitment is utilized to enhance the integrity and confidentiality of a list of parameters. This method involves the generation of a random variable 't' by the software (SW), which is then used alongside other parameters (Q, m) to request a signature from the hardware (HW). The HW computes several key values through a series of operations involving hashing and elliptic curve multiplications, which include generating k0 from a hash of d, m, t, and subsequently R0 from k0. Through further computations, it derives 'k' and 'R', finalizing the process with the calculation of 's'. These computed values (R0, R, s) are sent back to the SW.

Upon receipt, the SW undertakes the verification of these values by checking if 'sG' equates to 'R + H(R,Q,m)Q' and whether 'R' is equal to 'R0 + H(R0,t)G'. If these verifications succeed, it indicates the legitimacy and integrity of the process, leading to the publication of the signature (R, s) as confirmation. 

This method's acceptance suggests a significant step forward in enhancing cryptographic practices, particularly in the context of secure communications and data protection. The correspondence also hints at an anticipation within the community for the formal specification of this methodology and its potential incorporation into the secp256k1 library, acknowledging the widespread interest and the prospective applications of this cryptographic scheme in securing digital transactions and communications.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T18:53:47.953000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
