<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:08:42.591028+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-20T19:56:44.865000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:08:42.591058+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dnm-ecash-and-privacy/916/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the critical need for escrow services in Darknet Markets (DNMs), underlining its importance due to the pseudo-anonymous nature of buyer-seller interactions in these platforms. Escrow services are emphasized as essential for reversing payments in instances of fraud, thereby acting as a protective measure for buyers. The role of the DNM operator is highlighted as potentially pivotal, given their ability to influence transactions with the possession of two out of three necessary keys for trade facilitation.

Further examination reveals concerns regarding the mechanisms through which funds are transferred into and out of DNMs. This process is identified as a significant challenge, suggesting that DNMs might benefit from operating within a larger anonymous set. A "gray market" mint is proposed as an ideal solution for DNMs. It would allow users to blend in more effectively while ensuring they can still legally cash out their funds. Such a system would necessitate a level of anonymity and security that could potentially be facilitated by private enough Lightning Networks (LN). However, skepticism is expressed regarding the current and near-future capabilities of LN to provide the required privacy and unmonitored channels for fund transfers, casting doubt on its viability as a solution for DNMs at present.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T19:56:44.865000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
