<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Flagging posts/topics</title>
  <updated>2024-08-22T02:11:58.527430+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-08-21 10:08:20.432000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Flagging posts/topics</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T02:11:58.527460+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/flagging-posts-topics/1085" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The "inappropriate" flag on the forum has been updated to a more encompassing "not constructive" flag. This modification aims to broaden the scope of content moderation by including non-constructive behaviors such as repetitiveness, trolling, argumentativeness, and any content deemed offensive or abusive in violation of the community guidelines. The updated description encourages members to actively participate in maintaining the quality of discussions by flagging posts that detract from productive conversation. This change is part of an effort to improve the signal/noise ratio within the community and to provide clarity without intimidating users with harsh messages from moderators.

Additionally, there has been concern regarding discussions on patent-protected techniques which could potentially ensnare unsuspecting individuals into legal issues. To address this, the phrase "This includes deceptively encouraging the use of patent-encumbered techniques." has been added to the "It's Illegal" flag category. This adjustment serves as a preliminary step to mitigate the risks associated with sharing and implementing patented methods, contributing to a safer and more informed community environment. For further details on community guidelines, one can visit [our community guidelines](https://delvingbitcoin.org/guidelines).</summary>
    <published>2024-08-21T10:08:20.432000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
