<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-08-22T02:10:01.434276+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-21T17:30:10.227000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T02:10:01.434301+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and considerations involved in identifying signatures derived from a common seed, especially in the context of cryptographic security. The complexity of this task is highlighted by the potential for combinatorial explosion if an attacker lacks prior knowledge about which signatures to target. The transaction graph's structure might inadvertently assist in narrowing down the possibilities, yet this approach is not foolproof.

There is an acknowledgment of the feasibility of designing algorithms that can tolerate a degree of error by incorporating incorrect values alongside correct ones. This would necessitate a higher number of correct values and result in more sophisticated decoding algorithms. However, this strategy has its limitations, particularly when dealing with a vast array of signatures, as it may not significantly expedite the process of isolating those carrying a specific signal.

The conversation underlines the inherent risk in assuming that attackers cannot deduce or make educated guesses about which transactions are pertinent. This underscores the importance of considering potential threats and vulnerabilities in cryptographic schemes, emphasizing the need for robust security measures to protect against such analytical attacks.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-21T17:30:10.227000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
