<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
  <updated>2024-08-22T02:08:50.715158+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-08-21T19:20:24.757000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zawy’s Alternating Timestamp Attack</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T02:08:50.715188+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zawy-s-alternating-timestamp-attack/1062/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion highlights a nuanced aspect of blockchain technology, specifically focusing on the balance between hash power and difficulty levels in the context of maintaining an optimal block production rate. The sender points out an intriguing phenomenon where possessing 50% of the hashing power paradoxically introduces a challenge due to the Maximum Time Past (MTP) rule, which imposes an effective cap on the block rate. This cap ensures that difficulty increases if the block production rate attempts to exceed six blocks per second, a threshold determined by the system to prevent faster than normal increases in MTP relative to wall time. The detailed calculation provided illustrates how a significant decrease in difficulty is required for someone with 50% hash power to hit this maximum rate, based on the pre-attack production time of one block every 1200 seconds.

Further, the conversation delves into the technicalities of block timestamping within the blockchain network. It clarifies a previously misunderstood point regarding the handling of future block timestamps, emphasizing the need for a system that does not strictly bind the timestamp of a forthcoming block to the exact time of the previous block. This flexibility is deemed necessary to accommodate the operational realities of ASIC miners and the potential queuing of jobs for subsequent blocks. The current timewarp mitigation strategy, however, seems to grapple with similar constraints, indicating room for improvement in how blockchain networks manage time-related parameters.

Additionally, the email references empirical data to contextualize the discussion on network delays and orphan rates, drawing upon findings from a study available at [this paper](https://sites.cs.ucsb.edu/~rich/class/cs293b-cloud/papers/bitcoin-delay). The cited research provides a statistical basis for estimating propagation delay within the Bitcoin network, further supported by data from [this page](https://forkmonitor.info/feeds/stale_candidates/btc.rss) concerning the frequency of orphaned blocks. This empirical backdrop underscores the importance of designing network protocols that can withstand adverse conditions, including potential major attacks, without compromising on efficiency or security. The ongoing exploration of these dynamics reaffirms the complexity and criticality of maintaining equilibrium in blockchain systems, where even dominant computational power must navigate inherent technical limitations.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-21T19:20:24.757000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
