<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
  <updated>2024-08-23T02:07:28.885181+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-08-22 20:42:44.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
    <updated>2024-08-23T02:07:28.885211+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dnm-ecash-and-privacy/916/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses the capabilities and challenges associated with implementing escrow services within the Lightning Network (LN). It highlights that the LN can indeed support proper escrow transactions, specifically referring to a 2-of-3 setup. This means that out of three parties involved in the transaction, two must agree for the transaction to proceed. However, the email also points out a limitation in verifying hashes without the preimage, indicating a challenge in distributing "custody" over a transaction without revealing certain critical information beforehand.

The potential solution offered involves the use of Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs), which could address the issue of hash verification without preimages. Yet, the development or implementation status of PTLCs remains unclear, posing an unresolved challenge. Additionally, the email touches upon the problem of long-lived Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLCs) within the LN framework, suggesting that these too present obstacles for efficient and secure transactions.

An alternative to complex escrow mechanisms on the LN is proposed through the use of predicated e-cash escrows. These are deemed less technically challenging and involve techniques like Merkle Abstract Syntax Trees (MAST) to conceal spending conditions from the mint unless they become relevant. The straightforward scenario described involves a simple public key authentication between the seller and buyer using MuSig 2-of-2, highlighting the possibility of maintaining privacy and security in transactions.

Furthermore, the email suggests that mints could be federated to enhance the scalability and reliability of transactions. Similarly, arbitration processes could also adopt federation by utilizing Flexible Round-Optimized Schnorr Threshold (FROST) signatures for specific paths within the transaction process. This indicates a move towards more decentralized and secure methods of managing disputes and agreements in digital transactions, particularly within the context of LN and blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T20:42:44.620000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
