<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Deflationary money is a Good Thing</title>
  <updated>2024-08-24T02:06:47.555599+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>HubertusVIE 2024-08-23 13:48:46.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Deflationary money is a Good Thing</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T02:06:47.555633+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deflationary-money-is-a-good-thing/22/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The skepticism surrounding the concept of a deflationary currency, particularly in the context of Bitcoin, highlights significant concerns about its viability as a stable form of money. The argument posits that deflationary currencies can lead to economic downturns due to a cycle known as the deflationary spiral. This cycle begins with falling prices, which then cause consumers to reduce spending and businesses to slash their investments. Reduced demand leads to further price drops, resulting in a vicious cycle of economic contraction, job losses, and decreased demand. This scenario paints a bleak picture of deflationary currencies, suggesting they can exacerbate economic hardship rather than alleviate it.

Criticism is also directed towards central banking systems, which are viewed as flawed due to their approach to managing the money supply and interest rates. Central banks are criticized for intervening in the economy based on insufficient knowledge and delayed data, leading to decisions that might not be timely or effective. This critique extends to the notion that central banks, influenced by political appointments, inherently possess an interventionist bias that could be detrimental to economic stability. The argument further contends that in a Bitcoin-dominated future, the existence of central banks and their economists would be counterproductive. Instead, the development of the Bitcoin system should emphasize permissionless and non-custodial principles to prevent government usurpation and misuse of the monetary system.

The discussion also critiques the central bank's monopoly on currency issuance, arguing that such institutions do not require "backing" for their currency since banknotes are not redeemable. The historical example of the European Central Bank's gold backing decreasing over time is used to illustrate this point. This perspective advocates for the elimination of government involvement in currency and calls for the privatization and liberalization of currency issuance. By adopting methods and policies based on proof of work or real value, it is suggested that the private sector could adequately supply the economy with a stable currency, free from government manipulation and central bank mismanagement.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-23T13:48:46.952000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
