<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2024-08-05T02:08:17.019691+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2024-08-04 15:45:21.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-02 12:08:52.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2913_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2911_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T02:08:17.019730+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The study delves into the nuances of compact block reconstructions within the Bitcoin network, focusing on the efficiency and necessity for additional transactions during the reconstruction phase. The research hinges on log data from monitoring nodes enabled with `debug=cmpctblock`, offering a granular view into the dynamics of block reconstruction. This encompasses an analysis of transactions pre-filled in the compact block, those sourced from the node's mempool, transactions fetched from an extra pool, and instances necessitating a transaction request. Despite variations across node configurations, most align with Bitcoin Core's default settings, with all nodes configured to accept inbound connections. Notably, adjustments to node setups were observed, such as an increase in maximum connections for node `dave` and a shift towards `mempoolfullrbf=1` for node `erin`, indicating a strategic pivot towards handling transaction replacements in the mempool more effectively.

Throughout the observation period, distinct intervals were identified where the rate of compact block reconstructions that did not require additional transaction requests decreased significantly. These intervals corresponded with periods of increased mempool activity, suggesting a direct impact of network congestion on block reconstruction efficiency. Specific changes in node configuration, like `erin`'s adoption of `mempoolfullrbf=1`, were shown to enhance the block reconstruction process, proposing a potential network-wide benefit from deviating from the default Bitcoin Core policy.

Further exploration into block reconstruction times uncovered disparities in the median duration of block reconstructions, particularly between scenarios that did or did not necessitate additional transaction requests. This variance was evident across nodes located in well-equipped data centers, highlighting the influence of network connectivity and hardware capability on block reconstruction performance. The research also opens discussions on several fronts, including the differential need for additional transactions between low- and high-bandwidth block reconstructions, the role of extra pool sizes in reconstruction efficiency, and the historical performance metrics of block reconstructions before the widespread adoption of full Replace-By-Fee (RBF) by miners. Additionally, the comparison between outbound-only nodes and those accepting inbound connections could yield insights into further optimizations in block reconstruction methodologies across the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T15:45:21.037000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
