<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-09-22T02:23:18.063494+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson 2024-09-21 15:17:30.948000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-09-21 01:44:52.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 22:46:58.079000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 15:23:05.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-09-20 14:03:45.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3244_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3242_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3241_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3238_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3237_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T02:23:18.063639+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around SINGLE|ACP and its implications for privacy in cryptocurrency transactions highlights a significant challenge: the requirement for matching input and output indices, which could compromise privacy. This issue is particularly relevant when considering the design of systems like nostr, where relay addresses are initially hardcoded but can be expanded upon through discovery of new addresses. The comparison between joinstr and Joinmarket in addressing communication coordination centralization offers an insightful perspective on the evolution of privacy-enhancing technologies. Joinstr’s use of SIGHASH ALL | SIGHASH ANYONECANPAY and potential for upgrade to covenants presents a notable advancement in facilitating more private and decentralized transaction coordination.

Joinmarket has progressed from relying on a single IRC server for communication to implementing directory nodes that facilitate encrypted peer-to-peer messaging, thereby reducing dependency on centralized coordinators. This shift towards using .onion services and exploring integration with nostr relays represents an ongoing effort to decentralize and secure transaction coordination further. Despite these advancements, challenges such as operational issues with onion services after about nine months illustrate the complexities involved in achieving fully decentralized and private transactions.

CoinShuffle and CoinShuffle++ aim to address privacy concerns through a bulletin board-like coordination mechanism. However, they still face centralization issues, particularly in grouping participants into sessions for transaction mixing. This emphasizes the persistent challenge of coordinating decentralized operations without compromising privacy or efficiency. The broader issue of communication centralization remains a hurdle for privacy-oriented cryptocurrency transactions, underscoring the need for innovative solutions to mitigate selective censorship and enhance decentralization.

The role of volunteer contributions and the development of systems that operate independently of hardcoded directory nodes or specific individuals highlight the dynamic nature of project involvement and the quest for sustainable, autonomous infrastructure. The importance of reliable peer discovery mechanisms and the utilization of directory nodes by makers and takers raise questions about the efficacy and privacy implications of such approaches.

The JoinMarket messaging protocol details crucial aspects of decentralized Bitcoin transactions, emphasizing encrypted communication channels and mechanisms for creating and broadcasting transactions. This protocol enhances transaction privacy and liquidity, demonstrating the potential of peer-to-peer networks in fostering a more decentralized financial system.

The configuration of communication infrastructure, including directory nodes, IRC, and Onion services, underscores the emphasis on security, anonymity, and flexibility in peer discovery and messaging within decentralized networks. JoinMarket with Jam’s approach to transaction management without a central coordinator marks a shift towards enhanced privacy and security, despite the lack of detailed technical insights into its methodologies.

Recent developments in cryptocurrency privacy tools reflect the changing landscape following law enforcement actions against non-custodial privacy services. Alternatives like JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin offer new avenues for maintaining transaction privacy without central coordination. These shifts highlight the community’s resilience and adaptability in response to regulatory pressures, pointing towards a future where decentralized and private cryptocurrency transactions could become more prevalent.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-21T15:17:30.948000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
