<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
  <updated>2025-04-29T02:41:12.321271+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-04-28 21:44:53.398000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  . 2025-04-27 12:48:37.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  . 2025-04-27 12:45:15.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2025-04-15 08:55:58.168000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Lazmv  . 2025-04-06 08:26:53.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>victorkstarkware  . 2024-08-29 11:21:23.206000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4886_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4879_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4880_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4784_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4714_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3081_The-path-to-general-computation-on-Bitcoin-with-OP-CAT-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The path to general computation on Bitcoin (with OP_CAT)</title>
    <updated>2025-04-29T02:41:12.321331+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-path-to-general-computation-on-bitcoin-with-op-cat/1106" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse begins by analyzing the implications and challenges associated with implementing STARK proof verification within the Bitcoin blockchain, specifically in relation to LNhance's capabilities. It elucidates that while LNhance supports covenant mechanisms through `CTV` and `CSFS`, and multi-commitments via `PAIRCOMMIT`, it falls short of fully enabling functional STARK proofs. The necessity for specific functionalities such as data carrying across transactions, Merkle-decommitment, algebraic checks on decommitted data, and deriving randomness from Fiat-Shamir hash accumulation is highlighted as critical to dividing the verifier process into manageable segments and ensuring the scalability and efficiency of cryptographic proofs. The discussion raises concerns about `PAIRCOMMIT`’s inadequacy in supporting these requirements, particularly in the aspects of Merkle-decommitment and algebraic validation, which are essential for deriving randomness and thus, critical for the protocol's overall functionality.

Further exploration delves into the broader challenges of extending Bitcoin’s functionality to encompass smart contract-like features, focusing on the limitations imposed by the absence of automatic transaction triggers, a defining characteristic of smart contracts in other blockchain systems. This section critically examines the use of "covenants" as a workaround to achieve a semblance of smart contract functionality within Bitcoin’s existing framework, despite inherent limitations related to state tracking and execution of complex operations. The discourse underscores the necessity of redefining conventional smart contract terminology to suit Bitcoin's unique operational context and explores technical specifics concerning the storage of state information and implementation of covenant-based systems. Additionally, StarkWare's contributions towards enhancing blockchain technology through advanced proof systems capable of handling significant transaction volumes are acknowledged, situating the discussion within the broader narrative of ongoing innovation in blockchain technology optimization.

The conversation then shifts focus to the potential role of the OP_CAT opcode in facilitating both covenants and STARKs within Bitcoin. It describes how OP_CAT’s ability to concatenate elements on the stack could unlock new possibilities for Bitcoin’s scripting capabilities, particularly in hashing operations crucial for STARKs and covenant implementations. The Circle-STARK variant, compatible with Bitcoin’s four-byte restriction, exemplifies how algorithmic compatibility can be achieved within Bitcoin’s framework. The discourse outlines how OP_CAT could enable covenants through specific manipulations using `OP_CHECKSIG`, highlighting innovative approaches to leveraging Bitcoin’s script for enhanced functionality. This segment accentuates the ongoing dialogue around Bitcoin's evolving script capabilities and the technical sophistication driving its development forward.

In critiquing a blog post on Bitcoin's UTXO model, locking scripts, and covenants, the email emphasizes inaccuracies and omissions in the discussion of Bitcoin scripts, state tracking, and the implementation of covenants. It questions the original post's avoidance of the term "smart contract" and the practicality of automatically triggered transactions within Bitcoin’s covenant system. The critique further probes the necessity of OP_CAT for concatenation in covenant implementation and scrutinizes the handling of state tracking at the node level. A specific implementation example, the Circle-STARK verifier, is provided to illustrate practical applications of state verification on Bitcoin signet, challenging the post’s assertions on Bitcoin smart contracts and advocating for a more accurate portrayal of covenants.

Conclusively, the narrative encompasses the endeavours to enhance general computation on Bitcoin, pinpointing the pivotal role of the OP_CAT opcode in this transformation. By addressing Bitcoin's inherent script limitations and introducing covenants and STARK proofs, the discourse envisions a future where Bitcoin's computational capabilities are significantly expanded. The Taproot upgrade marks a crucial step toward this goal, suggesting a path forward through soft forks and minimal code adjustments. The discussion not only reflects on the technical hurdles but also celebrates the collaborative efforts within the Bitcoin community to push the boundaries of what is programmatically possible on the blockchain, laying the groundwork for a more versatile and capable Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T21:44:53.398000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
