<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - PPLNS with job declaration</title>
  <updated>2024-09-06T02:16:02.378071+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash 2024-09-06 00:54:55.817000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash 2024-09-05 23:33:41.250000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Fi  . 2024-08-28 14:21:15.076000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3105_PPLNS-with-job-declaration.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3106_PPLNS-with-job-declaration.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3073_PPLNS-with-job-declaration.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - PPLNS with job declaration</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T02:16:02.378137+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The StratumV2 Reference Implementation (SRI) is a significant contributor to the Bitcoin mining protocol, focusing on decentralization and improving the fairness in mining operations. One of the pivotal discussions surrounding this implementation is the recent proposal introduced by Demand Pool, aiming to navigate Bitcoin away from the risks of mining centralization caused by the Bitmain FPPS debt-slavery cartel. The proposal, titled "PPLNS with Job Declaration," presents academically sound strategies that could potentially offer solutions to the current predicaments faced by the Bitcoin community. This document is accessible [here](https://github.com/demand-open-source/pplns-with-job-declaration/blob/5e3e7666f177e9a1e217e72da65a35b612505613/pplns-with-job-declaration.pdf), showcasing the talent and innovative thinking within Demand Pool's team.

StratumV2 emphasizes giving miners the ability to select their own job templates through Job Declaration (JD). This feature is crucial for the protocol's agnostic stance on share accounting and reward distribution. It opens up possibilities for pools to either place blind trust in pool fairness or to reduce this trust dependency through feedback mechanisms. However, should pools opt for the latter, protocol extensions become necessary. The new SV2 extension proposes to leverage the PPLNS system over FPPS, aiming to ensure fair compensation for mining jobs, including those that might be economically suboptimal due to various factors such as remote node locations, ideological biases, or specific transaction prioritization strategies like MEVil.

Furthermore, the discussion extends to how the proposed SV2 extension would interact with transactions that could penalize low-end nodes, referred to as GCC vectors. The consideration of GCC vectors is critical for maintaining Bitcoin's decentralized nature, emphasizing the need to protect low-end nodes which are vital for keeping block sizes small. The debate outlines three potential paths for handling GCC vectors within the SV2-JD-enabled pools: outright rejection, imposing economical penalties, or ignoring them altogether. The preference clearly leans towards options that do not compromise the integrity and inclusivity of low-end nodes in the mining process.

In addition to theoretical proposals, active development efforts are ongoing to refine the SV2 extension, which seeks to enhance transparency and fairness in mining pool payouts significantly. This initiative allows miners more autonomy in selecting transactions, thus influencing the jobs they undertake based on different fee structures. Detailed information about this development can be found in the specification document hosted on GitHub, available through this [link](https://github.com/demand-open-source/share-accounting-ext/blob/281c1cbc4f9a07b21a443753a525197dc5d8e18c/extension.md). The project is in its developmental stage, welcoming reviews and contributions to optimize the proposed framework, aiming for a balanced and equitable mining ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T00:54:55.817000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
