<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
  <updated>2024-08-10T02:06:53.828248+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-08-09 07:01:37.418000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-07 14:12:45.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-08-07 10:28:25.289000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-05 20:53:19.731000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-07-30 15:12:09.428000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2930_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2926_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2925_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2917_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2905_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T02:06:53.828301+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bolt-12-trusted-contacts/1046/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the complexities and potential vulnerabilities associated with digital payment systems, particularly focusing on the scenario of adding contacts and the possible phishing exploits therein. It paints a picture where the process of making payments could be manipulated by attackers to mislead users into associating their payment keys with incorrect identities, thus compromising the security of transactions. The sender emphasizes the difficulty in ensuring that users accurately understand the source of payments, suggesting that education around trusting only the payment amount might offer a simpler solution to security concerns than relying on potentially compromised contact lists or payer notes.

Further elaboration is provided on the risks associated with the lack of mutual authentication in payment notes. The discussion points towards the necessity of treating payment notes as "untrusted" by default to safeguard against phishing attacks. The idea here is to instill caution among users when dealing with payment origins that aren't clearly authenticated, suggesting mechanisms for wallets to differentiate between verified and unverified communications effectively.

A significant part of the conversation revolves around the proposal to use cryptographic methods for mutual authentication during transactions, exemplified by the need for Alice to ensure Bob recognizes a payment as genuinely coming from her. This section raises concerns about the security of simply adding a `from` field within encrypted messages, while also acknowledging the practical benefits of such a feature for scenarios requiring payment on behalf of another person. This highlights the ongoing struggle to balance convenience and security in digital payment systems.

Lastly, the email touches upon Bolt 12's introduction of a user-friendly experience for lightning wallets, including the challenges of maintaining privacy and authenticity in transactions among known contacts. It discusses the technical aspects of distributing cryptographic keys for mutual authentication, proposing several methods for integration and seeking feedback on these approaches. The aim is to refine the standards for Bolt 12 payments, enhancing both user experience and transaction security without sacrificing either. This part of the discussion embodies the broader theme of evolving digital payment infrastructures to meet the dual demands of ease of use and robust security measures.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-09T07:01:37.418000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
