<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Casual research on running `mempoolfullrbf`</title>
  <updated>2024-08-27T02:12:12.298671+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>valuedmammal 2024-08-27 01:31:46.969000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>valuedmammal 2024-08-27 01:15:31.823000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>valuedmammal  . 2024-08-19 11:09:32.817000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-19 08:21:15.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>valuedmammal  . 2024-08-17 20:18:46.144000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3062_Casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3061_Casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2997_Casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2996_Casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2979_Casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Casual research on running `mempoolfullrbf`</title>
    <updated>2024-08-27T02:12:12.298727+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/casual-research-on-running-mempoolfullrbf/1077/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a unique approach to evaluating transactions on the blockchain through a novel metric termed as the "score." This score is designed to measure how well the transaction data in newly confirmed blocks matches with what was anticipated by the node's most recent block template. Essentially, it gauges the predictability and efficiency of transaction processing and confirmation within the blockchain network. An essential aspect of this examination is the ability of the score to serve as an indicator of the node's prediction accuracy and, by extension, the health of the entire blockchain network. The methodology behind this innovative metric, along with its implications for improving the performance and reliability of blockchain systems, is thoroughly discussed on a dedicated webpage. Interested readers can delve deeper into the subject by visiting [this link](https://valuedmammal.github.io/), which offers an in-depth exploration of the calculation process and potential applications of the score.

Further analysis is presented through the examination of variance in the score across different nodes, specifically comparing a full-RBF (Replace-By-Fee) node to a BIP125 node. The study highlights the impact of node uptime on network visibility and the potential for variability in scoring due to the decentralized nature of the network. Nodes operating continuously tend to demonstrate less variance in their scores compared to those that are intermittently online, as seen in the case of a pruned node running on an older laptop. Efforts were made to minimize this variance by ensuring the nodes were peered, enabling them to share mempool contents and potentially smooth out discrepancies in score. The exploration also touches upon the broader implications for the peer-to-peer (P2P) network's health, emphasizing the importance for node operators to monitor statistics regularly to keep abreast of changes in network usage.

Additionally, the conversation includes a reflection on policy considerations related to node operation and transaction handling within the mempool. It does not advocate for a specific stance on whether nodes should align with miner practices or vice versa but suggests finding a balance that ensures the mempool remains an efficient and appealing place for users to transact. This balance involves setting reliable defaults while also being open to evolving these policies to adapt to changing needs within the network. Observing high P2P scores consistently was an unexpected yet welcome finding, indicating a robust network. However, large or prolonged deviations in score could signal a misalignment with broader network policies or issues with transactions confirming without entering the mempool, underscoring the complexity and dynamic nature of managing a distributed network like the blockchain.

The project's progress is further elucidated through a GitHub repository, which serves as a hub for the ongoing analysis of CSV data related to this study. The repository, available at [https://github.com/ValuedMammal/mempool-util/tree/main/assets](https://github.com/ValuedMammal/mempool-util/tree/main/assets), indicates that while substantial advancements have been made, an analysis of variance remains a pending task. This step is crucial for understanding the differences between groups within the data set, thereby ensuring the validity and reliability of the conclusions drawn from this research.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-27T01:31:46.969000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
