<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-08-29T02:11:52.858884+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kravens 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T02:11:52.858974+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The cryptocurrency transaction landscape is continuously evolving with the advent of new technologies and methodologies aimed at enhancing user privacy and security. Among these developments, JoinMarket represents a significant shift towards decentralized financial transactions by facilitating coinjoin operations without the need for a central coordinator. Users known as Makers provide liquidity by making their bitcoins available, while Takers select from these Makers to execute coinjoin transactions, paying a fee for the service. This model emphasizes the importance of maintaining anonymity and improving the fungibility of Bitcoin through a peer-to-peer network.

A notable advancement in this domain is the integration of CoinJoin transactions within the Trezor Suite application, offering users the flexibility to choose alternative coordinators for their transactions. A comprehensive guide detailing this setup process is accessible via [Change Coordinator (kravens.nl)](https://wasabi.kravens.nl/trezor), showcasing the method for initiating the Trezor Suite app with a debug argument that connects to a custom coordinator server, such as the Noderunners Coordinator. This update underscores the growing demand for customizable privacy options in cryptocurrency transactions.

In addressing the challenges associated with decentralized systems, the conversation extends to the development of infrastructures that operate independently of hardcoded directory nodes or specific individuals. This initiative aims to create a sustainable and autonomous system that adapts to the changing roster of volunteers, thereby ensuring a more reliable and resilient project infrastructure. The discussion also delves into the intricacies of peer discovery and the role of directory nodes, highlighting the essential need for a dependable mechanism to manage these nodes effectively.

The JoinMarket messaging protocol is foundational to the privacy and efficiency of coinjoin transactions. Detailed documentation on GitHub provides insights into the technical framework, emphasizing encrypted communication channels and mechanisms for managing payments and broadcasting transactions. This protocol is pivotal in facilitating secure and private exchanges between participants, bolstering the overall integrity of the Bitcoin ecosystem.

Moreover, the configuration of communication infrastructures involves a meticulous process that includes setting up directory nodes, Internet Relay Chat (IRC), and Onion services. This setup is critical for ensuring secure and anonymous peer discovery and interaction within the network. Specifically, the configurations detail the requirements for onion-based messaging channels and the management of Tor control configurations, highlighting the system's emphasis on security and anonymity.

JoinMarket with Jam presents an alternative wallet interface that operates without a central coordinator, though it presents a more complex setup process and leaves some gaps in understanding its underlying technology. On the other hand, joinstr.xyz offers a simpler approach by leveraging existing nostr relays for peer communication, distinguishing itself through the public dissemination of pool information and the exchange of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT).

The closure of coordinator servers for prominent privacy services like Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet has precipitated significant changes in the Bitcoin privacy service landscape. In response, alternatives such as JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin have gained prominence. The BTCPay plugin, in particular, enables users to host their own coordinator services using the WabiSabi protocol, illustrating a move towards more decentralized and resilient privacy-enhancing solutions. This shift towards self-hosted and decentralized coordinators may pave the way for a new era of cryptocurrency privacy techniques, potentially fostering a network that grows stronger in the face of regulatory pressures.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-28T17:15:28.379000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
