<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP Draft: Flag day activation based on nLockTime signaling</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:12:41.677423+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-08-20 19:00:22.622000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2024-08-20 18:57:04.498000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-08-20 18:49:54.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2024-08-20 16:21:45.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3011_BIP-Draft-Flag-day-activation-based-on-nLockTime-signaling.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3010_BIP-Draft-Flag-day-activation-based-on-nLockTime-signaling.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3008_BIP-Draft-Flag-day-activation-based-on-nLockTime-signaling.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3005_BIP-Draft-Flag-day-activation-based-on-nLockTime-signaling.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP Draft: Flag day activation based on nLockTime signaling</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:12:41.677472+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-draft-flag-day-activation-based-on-nlocktime-signaling/1078/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights concerns regarding the Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) and the dynamics of transaction processing, particularly focusing on the implications of `nLockTime` transactions and the potential for censorship by miners. The core issue raised revolves around how transactions with `nLockTime` values set in the past or to a lower height are currently treated within the bitcoin network – they are typically mined and relayed by default. This default behavior could inadvertently create an incentive for miners who are opposed to certain changes to engage in transaction censorship. Similarly, there's an apprehension that users who disagree with certain updates might attempt to censor transaction relays, particularly pointing towards recent attempts with inscriptions as an example.

There's also a discussion about the concept of "readiness" signaling within the network, though it is not entirely clear whether this pertains to miner or user actions. The argument against miners signaling their readiness through transaction inclusion is based on the premise that doing so should not be viewed as an endorsement of the transaction itself. Conversely, if the signaling comes from users, relying on transaction inclusion as an indicator becomes unreliable due to the possibility of manipulative practices by miners. This touches upon the broader debate on network governance and the mechanisms through which consensus and readiness for changes are gauged, underscoring the complexity of managing a decentralized network like Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T19:00:22.622000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
