<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:08:57.691314+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-08-20 20:33:00.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-08-20 20:23:52.294000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-08-20 19:56:44.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-31 09:42:41.916000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>aspargus  . 2024-05-30 08:24:12.671000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-27 13:03:36.400000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-05-27 03:16:05.749000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-26 13:22:19.940000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3016_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3015_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3012_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2579_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2571_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2543_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2542_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2536_DNM-eCash-and-privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:08:57.691386+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dnm-ecash-and-privacy/916/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The narrative delves into the necessity of escrow systems in darknet markets (DNMs) to mitigate the risk of fraudulent sellers, emphasizing that such mechanisms are vital for maintaining transaction integrity by allowing payment reversibility. It discusses the challenges faced by DNMs in managing funds, highlighting the potential of Lightning Network (LN) and eCash to enhance privacy and facilitate unsupervised fund movement, albeit skepticism remains regarding LN's current capabilities to fully support DNM operations without surveillance.

The text also introduces [Joinstr](https://joinstr.xyz/), a non-custodial financial tool resistant to shutdowns, contrasting it with eCash, which operates on a custodial basis and is deemed more suitable for regulated entities rather than DNMs due to its alignment with traditional financial regulations. The inherent risks of operating an eCash mint are explored, including legal repercussions and the danger of fund loss from shutdowns, underscoring the delicate balance of anonymity, trust, and risk within the digital currency ecosystem.

Further analysis reveals the declining use of Bitcoin in DNMs due to privacy concerns, with a preference shift towards Monero for its enhanced privacy features. This shift is part of broader changes within DNMs, including the adoption of multi-signature technologies and the exploration of eCash to improve operational security (opsec) and user experience (UX). Despite the risks associated with custodial models, such as exit scams, the community's interest in eCash signifies a pursuit of better privacy and security measures.

Lastly, the document mentions the ongoing development and application of eCash within DNMs, suggesting that its integration could significantly benefit users by leveraging existing Bitcoin infrastructure and trust networks. The open-source project [moksha](https://github.com/ngutech21/moksha) is referenced for those interested in the technical aspects of implementing eCash in these environments, highlighting the continuous evolution of digital currencies in response to the demands of illicit markets while emphasizing the critical importance of privacy and security.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T20:33:00.794000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
