<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Flagging posts/topics</title>
  <updated>2024-08-22T02:12:10.713992+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-08-22 00:02:48.293000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-08-21 10:08:20.432000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3037_Flagging-posts-topics.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3020_Flagging-posts-topics.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Flagging posts/topics</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T02:12:10.714031+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/flagging-posts-topics/1085/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an effort to refine the moderation tools and improve the community experience, a recent update has been made to the flagging system used within the forum. The "inappropriate" flag, previously denoted for content deemed offensive, abusive, or in violation of community guidelines, has been redefined as the "not constructive" flag. This change aims to encompass a broader range of non-constructive behaviors including repetitive posts, trolling, argumentative comments, and any content that could be considered offensive or abusive by reasonable standards.

Additionally, the description of this newly named flag emphasizes its purpose: to identify and reduce noise within discussions by highlighting content that detracts from productive conversation. Community members are encouraged to utilize this flagging option to help maintain a high quality of discourse, making it easier for others to differentiate between constructive and non-constructive contributions without instigating confrontations with moderators.

Furthermore, in response to concerns about the potential legal pitfalls associated with discussing patented techniques, the "It's Illegal" flag category has been expanded. It now includes warnings against encouraging the use of techniques under patent protection without clear disclosure. This adjustment serves as a preventive measure to protect forum participants from inadvertently infringing on patents, thereby fostering a safer and more informed community environment.

For more detailed information on what constitutes a violation of these guidelines, members can refer to the [community guidelines](https://delvingbitcoin.org/guidelines). This resource provides comprehensive insights into the standards expected within the community, aiming to ensure a respectful and legally conscious space for discussion.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:02:48.293000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
