<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-09-05T02:15:32.136942+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-09-04 14:38:47.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-09-04 03:39:06.312000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-09-03 21:28:46.874000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 19:35:39.046000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 17:30:10.227000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:33:51.311000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:12:12.049000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 15:08:10.563000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 15:06:55.908000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-21 14:32:38.344000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-21 14:06:59.185000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-21 13:08:17.268000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-20 18:53:47.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-08-20 18:40:40.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-08-20 17:02:38.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2024-08-20 15:26:52.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3099_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3097_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3095_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3035_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3032_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3031_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3028_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3030_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3029_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3026_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3025_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3024_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3007_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3003_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3006_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3004_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T02:15:32.137060+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse introduces a sophisticated cryptographic vulnerability referred to as the "Dark Smoothie" approach, which delineates a method through which an attacker can decipher a 256-bit seed from merely two signatures sourced from the same device. This method does not necessitate complex mathematical operations, instead relying on the exploitation of digital transaction protocols where cryptographic signatures are utilized. The process involves calculating specific values using the private key, the attacker's secret, and hash functions to unveil the `256_bit_secret`. This vulnerability is particularly alarming due to its ability to be triggered by seemingly innocuous activities like "dusting," thereby revealing the identity or other sensitive details of a wallet owner. Furthermore, it elaborates on countermeasures like the implementation of Anti-Exfil protocols, which aim to fortify the security measures against such vulnerabilities, contingent upon the companion application's integrity.

The inquiry delves into the potential efficacy of integrating a 4-bit checksum as a deterrent against attackers, proposing that such an integration would compel attackers to exert additional computational efforts. The effectiveness of this strategy, however, is contingent upon the dynamic nature of the checksum; a static checksum does not significantly complicate the attacker's challenge but rather imposes a predetermined number of iterations for them to bypass. It posits setting a computational target time to verify a single signature, making it substantially more challenging for attackers to exfiltrate more than one bit of information stealthily.

Further discussion highlights the intricacies involved in identifying signatures originating from a common seed, underscoring the complexity and potential for combinatorial explosion absent prior knowledge of which signatures to focus on. While algorithms capable of tolerating errors by mixing incorrect with correct values exist, their efficacy diminishes with the increasing volume of signatures, illustrating the sophisticated nature of potential attacks and the necessity for robust security protocols.

An innovative leakage method through large checksums alongside every signature is explored, emphasizing the method's reliance on unique criteria known only to attackers or malicious manufacturers for selecting bits of the checksum for leakage. This technique underscores the gradual reconstruction of the original secret as more checksum bits are exposed, albeit demanding specific insights into which signatures share a common origin from the same seed—a factor complicating the attacker's endeavor.

The text addresses the challenges of securing devices against not just software or firmware threats but also those stemming from physical device construction. It acknowledges that while anti-exfiltration measures provide a defense mechanism, they may fall short in scenarios where devices are designed with inherent vulnerabilities, highlighting the multifaceted nature of cybersecurity threats and the imperative for comprehensive protective strategies.

A further aspect of the discussion revolves around employing Forward Error Correction (FEC) codes to estimate the number of signatures necessary to compromise a seed, drawing attention to the direct relationship between the number of signatures and the feasibility of leaking seed bits. This exploration points to the nuanced balance between computational effort and potential security breaches within cryptographic systems.

Additionally, the conversation transitions towards the feasibility of executing exploits via firmware modifications alone or if intrinsic malicious design intentions are requisite. It introduces FEC codes as a strategy to obviate the need for tracking leaked seed portions, detailing a method whereby parts of a large "checksum" are deterministically leaked across signatures. This approach, while theoretically sound, faces practical detection challenges during routine integrity checks of signature generation processes, indicating the complexities and considerations necessary in formulating defenses against sophisticated cryptographic attacks.

Lastly, the dialogue touches upon the constraints faced by low power devices in managing continuous cryptographic computations and the impracticality of such attack vectors given the robustness of routine operational testing designed to detect anomalies. This part of the discussion suggests ongoing deliberations on enhancing security protocols to thwart attacks leveraging firmware vulnerabilities, reflecting the continuous evolution of cybersecurity measures in response to emerging threats.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-04T14:38:47.803000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
