<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
  <updated>2024-08-21T02:12:07.726136+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-08-20 18:53:47.953000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-08-20 18:40:40.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2024-08-20 17:02:38.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2024-08-20 15:26:52.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3007_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3003_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3006_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3004_Non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non interactive anti-exfil (airgap compatible)</title>
    <updated>2024-08-21T02:12:07.726184+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-interactive-anti-exfil-airgap-compatible/1081/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exchange details a sophisticated approach to enhancing the security of air-gapped signing devices, particularly when integrated with PSBTs (Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions) and compatible with traditional QR code-based signing workflows. The core innovation lies in the use of a cryptographically secure hash commitment to improve the signing protocol for both Schnorr and ECDSA signatures. This method involves generating a signature by computing a series of cryptographic operations that ultimately allow the signing device to produce a valid signature, which can then be verified by the wallet app.

The signing process begins with the generation of a random nonce and the computation of various cryptographic parameters based on the private key, message to sign, and nonce. For Schnorr signatures, the protocol specifies the calculation of a signature using private key multiplication and hash operations. Similarly, for ECDSA signatures, it outlines a mechanism for signature computation involving the inversion of a key parameter and arithmetic operations with the message and private key. The protocol ensures that the generated signatures can be securely returned to the wallet application for verification, employing hash and public key operations to affirm their validity.

Moreover, the discussion makes an important distinction regarding the term "vector commitment," noting its specific meaning within cryptography and how it differs from the concept being described. The method discussed is identified as closely related to Scheme 2 from a proposal found in the archives of the Bitcoin development mailing list, which itself draws upon an idea introduced by Greg Maxwell in 2014. This scheme is designed to work efficiently with both ECDSA and Schnorr signatures, leveraging a double nonce mechanism reminiscent of those used in advanced signature aggregation techniques like MuSig2 and FROST. However, it simplifies the nonce commitment and combination process by allowing the hardware signer to directly know the combined secret nonce, which is particularly beneficial for ECDSA signatures where such direct knowledge facilitates the signing process.

Clarifications provided in the discussion highlight the flexibility of the scheme in terms of hash function selection, accommodating variations across different signature variants and proposals. It elucidates the use of uniformly random values supplied by the host wallet application and the significance of employing a cryptographically strong hash for the concatenation of critical values, suggesting possible compatibility with standard hash mechanisms used in various signing protocols. This innovative approach not only reinforces the security of the signing process but also maintains the necessary transparency and verification capabilities required for robust digital transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T18:53:47.953000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
