<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2017-January-013485</id>
  <title>Anti-transaction replay in a hardfork</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:29:45.126458+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Johnson Lau</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2017-January-013485</id>
    <title>Anti-transaction replay in a hardfork</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:29:45.126458+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-January/013485.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a proposal for a planned hardfork and the issue of replay attacks. A replay attack is when an attempt is made to replay a transaction from one network on another network, which could result in a permanent incompatible split. The writer suggests that the replay effect should be seen as a good thing, not an attack, and instead proposes creating a "bridge" that replays all transactions from one network over to the other, and vice versa. However, this proposal is deemed technically infeasible due to mining being a random process and the fact that there could be orphaning in the old chain, leading to different miners of the new chain seeing a different history of the old chain. Furthermore, the proposal would be unfair to new chain miners who may not be satisfied with the fees they are paid while being forced to include old chain transactions. It is noted that the technical issues are not solvable when both forks are decentralised mining. The BIP50 hard fork is also mentioned, which did not create two incompatible ledgers as it could have, but rather the replay effect allowed Bitcoin to survive that hard fork. Finally, a reference implementation of the proposal is available in the writer's forcenet2 branch.</summary>
    <published>2017-01-26T09:20:54+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
