<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2017-January-013510</id>
  <title>Extension block softfork proposal</title>
  <updated>2023-05-04T21:15:02.394249+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo</name>
  </author>
  <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-January/013510.html" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-January/013510.html</id>
    <title>Extension block softfork proposal</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T21:15:02.395246+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-January/013510.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email exchange discusses a proposal for a pre-BIP that allows extra block space through a soft-fork. The proposal allows new wallets taking advantage of the extra block space to have a different user experience, but it is completely transparent to existing wallets. The email also covers why soft forks are preferable to hard forks and debunks much of the "soft forks are less secure" arguments. However, when extension blocks are introduced, they become coercive and set a terrible precedent. Extension blocks make it a social cost, not an individual trust problem; instead of opting into a soft fork's security (or lack thereof) for your transaction, the entire network is forced to trust the extension block. Furthermore, miners can start soft-forking sidechains, which is a massive risk and allows individual large miners and individual economic users to force others to switch to new consensus rules with potentially little consensus or review. The email also includes a detailed specification and terminology for the proposed pre-BIP, which describes how to provide more block space through a soft fork while being completely transparent to existing wallets and not breaking any current security assumptions. The proposal drastically changes the user experience, and there are questions around simplifying the design without compromising security, doing it without the 100-block maturity requirement, and whether 100-blocks is an overkill.</summary>
    <published>2017-01-28T00:35:55+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
