<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Revisiting BIP21</title>
  <updated>2024-03-03T01:55:46.813656+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josibake</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-02T10:49:42.050000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Revisiting BIP21</title>
    <updated>2024-03-03T01:55:46.813691+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/revisiting-bip21/630/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the pursuit of optimizing QR code space and enhancing compatibility across different client versions, a novel approach has been suggested to address the concerns surrounding the existing key-value (KV) method used in encoding addresses. The proposal entails the introduction of an optional dummy value `=v` at the end of the address. This innovation is designed with backward compatibility in mind, ensuring that newer implementations do not disrupt the functionality of older clients. By adopting this strategy, it is anticipated that after a transitional period, during which both old and new clients adjust to this change, the dummy values could eventually be phased out. This phase-out would result in further conservation of space within the QR codes, aligning with the goal of efficiency.

The suggested protocol specifies guidelines for both the senders and receivers of the information. New clients are advised that they may include the `=v` dummy value when generating addresses. This inclusion serves as a safeguard to maintain interoperability with systems still operating under the old schema. Conversely, senders are mandated to detect and omit the `=v` value from addresses before processing them. This requirement ensures that the transition towards the new format is seamless, preventing any potential misinterpretation or data loss during the exchange between updated and outdated systems.

Additionally, the proposed method promises to eliminate the ambiguity that currently exists due to the dual possibility of embedding a new address either directly within the root or within a KV pair. By simplifying the parsing process—whereby senders only need to split the URI at the `?` character and identify their preferred Human Readable Part (HRP) or `extensionkey`—the system becomes more straightforward. This simplicity not only facilitates easier implementation for new clients but also obviates the need for extensive testing scenarios aimed at distinguishing between root-level and KV pair-level address placements. The overarching aim of these recommendations is to streamline the handling of addresses, thereby enhancing the overall user experience while simultaneously adhering to the principles of backward compatibility and spatial efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-02T10:49:42.050000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
