<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Chia Lisp For Bitcoiners</title>
  <updated>2024-03-05T01:52:16.984385+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-04T22:45:13.618000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Chia Lisp For Bitcoiners</title>
    <updated>2024-03-05T01:52:16.984428+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/chia-lisp-for-bitcoiners/636/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Chialisp presents an interesting approach to managing the complexities and costs associated with script execution in blockchain technologies. The introduction of templates within this programming language plays a crucial role in reducing these costs. Complex scripts, when required to be executed repeatedly, can become financially burdensome. Templates address this issue by allowing for the reuse of code, significantly diminishing the overall cost involved. Additionally, Chialisp offers an innovative feature wherein code from earlier blocks can be extracted for use, further enhancing cost efficiency.

The design of Chialisp also includes a unique conditions language and coin format, drawing parallels to Bitcoin’s transaction format. While Bitcoin Script is external to its transaction format, it references the latter and adheres to a specific set of rules. Chia's approach not only facilitates the implementation of covenants but also introduces capabilities that extend beyond the current functionalities observed in Bitcoin. This advancement suggests potential enhancements in Bitcoin through the integration of additional opcodes, specifically designed for transaction handling. Such improvements could potentially replicate the benefits seen in Chialisp, albeit requiring considerable adaptation, possibly through extensive utilization of OP_CAT.

Concerning security measures against potential attacks, Chialisp has instituted a cost mechanism for string creation, which scales linearly with the length of the string. This measure aims to mitigate the risks associated with string growing attacks, ensuring that the computing resources of machines validating blocks remain within practical limits. The definition of what constitutes a 'reasonable' machine varies, but the cost settings in Chialisp are designed to prevent overflow issues within the capacities of standard machines tasked with block validation, considering Chia's block size constraints.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T22:45:13.618000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
