<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
  <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:19.871699+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-06T14:36:26.070000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
    <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:19.871732+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gitlab-backups-for-bitcoin-core-repository/624/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins by addressing the challenge of continuous import between GitLab and GitHub, highlighting that a direct, ongoing synchronization is not feasible. An alternative strategy is proposed, involving the operation of two instances in an alternating fashion to manage displays and imports within a 48-hour cycle, considering the import process takes approximately 36 hours.

Further into the conversation, the focus shifts to the topic of GitHub backups and mirroring, particularly for Bitcoin-related repositories. A comprehensive approach to backing up and providing mirrors for these repositories has been implemented, with details and links shared for those interested in accessing these resources. The backup and mirror setup includes a GitHub-like read-only mirror for the bitcoin/bitcoin repository, accessible at [https://mirror.b10c.me/bitcoin-bitcoin](https://mirror.b10c.me/bitcoin-bitcoin). This effort extends to rewriting issue and pull request (PR) links to avoid redirecting back to GitHub, enhancing accessibility and user experience. Additionally, a Tor hidden service is available for users requiring anonymous access to the mirror.

Backups of the repositories have been systematically pushed to both GitHub and GitLab across several links. These include repositories for bitcoin metadata backup on various components such as bitcoin core GUI, secp256k1, and BIPs (Bitcoin Improvement Proposals), available on both platforms for redundancy and wider access. The repositories related to the backup code and mirroring process are openly accessible, encouraging transparency and community involvement. Links to these repositories and a detailed write-up on the project can be found at [https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-backup](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-backup) for the backup code, [https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-mirror](https://github.com/0xB10C/github-metadata-mirror) for the mirroring code, and [https://b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/](https://b10c.me/projects/021-github-backups-mirror/) for an extended discussion on the initiative. This approach to data preservation and accessibility underscores the importance of redundancy and availability in managing critical open-source project repositories, particularly those with significant impacts like Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-06T14:36:26.070000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
