<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>State minimization in MuSig2 signing sessions</title>
  <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:55.408136+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi.781000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-06T18:17:29.781000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>State minimization in MuSig2 signing sessions</title>
    <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:55.408166+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/state-minimization-in-musig2-signing-sessions/626/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of enhancing security for Ledger device implementations, an intriguing discussion emerged regarding nonce generation methodologies. The conversation highlighted a proposal for utilizing the True Random Number Generator (TRNG) available in the Secure Element of Ledger devices as a foundational element for nonce generation. This approach contrasts with the alternative method involving CounterNonceGen, which necessitates the development of a secure atomic counter to serve as the nonce generator. The discourse suggests that despite the differing mechanisms—TRNG versus an atomic counter—the overarching strategy for managing psbt-level signing sessions could remain consistent.

The dialogue further explored the complexities associated with employing CounterNonceGen for psbt-level sessions, particularly emphasizing the importance of committing to both the initial counter value and the anticipated number of signatures for a given psbt within the session's state, identified by `session_id`. This commitment is deemed crucial, especially when facilitating multiple psbt signing flows concurrently, to ensure the security and integrity of the signing process. Such a structured approach aims at mitigating risks related to nonce reuse, thereby bolstering the overall auditability and reliability of the nonce generation and management system.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-06T18:17:29.781000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
