<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Unilateral Exit</title>
  <updated>2024-03-12T01:51:50.346368+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj.524000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-11T22:05:05.524000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Unilateral Exit</title>
    <updated>2024-03-12T01:51:50.346403+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unilateral-exit/664/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of cryptographic commitments, especially within the context of efficiency and blockchain technology, a notable method emerges for extending the capability of commitment schemes that are primarily designed to commit to points. This method allows for an adjustment to commit not only to a point but also to a value, thereby enhancing the utility and application of such commitment schemes. Known as the standard pay-to-contract scheme, this technique is instrumental in broadening the scope of commitments. 

The essence of this method lies in its formula: `committed_point = point + hash(point || value) * G`. Here, the original point is augmented by the product of a hash function and a generator point (G), where the hash function takes the concatenation of the original point and the value as its input. This approach is not merely theoretical but has been practically applied in Taproot, a significant innovation in the Bitcoin protocol, which enables the commitment of a point on the blockchain. 

This method's significance is underscored by its adoption in Taproot, indicating its practical viability and value in real-world applications. It represents a pivotal advancement in cryptographic commitments, offering a blend of efficiency and enhanced functionality by allowing commitments to both points and values within the same schema. This dual commitment capability opens new avenues for the implementation of cryptographic protocols, particularly in the domain of blockchain technology, where efficiency and security are paramount.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-11T22:05:05.524000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
