<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
  <updated>2024-03-15T02:00:54.006252+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>prozacchiwawa.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-14T22:23:35.310000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T02:00:54.006283+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/btc-lisp-as-an-alternative-to-script/682/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The individual reaching out is involved with Chia, specifically working on the chialisp compiler. Their main intent for communication is to introduce themselves and share insights and resources related to the modernization efforts of the chialisp language. An overview of these efforts can be found [here](https://chialisp.com/modern-chialisp/), highlighting the progress and direction of their work. Further, they mention ongoing development, which is accessible through a [Rust code repository](https://github.com/Chia-Network/clvm_tools_rs/tree/base/src/compiler) dedicated to this task.

Additionally, they share information about a gradual type system being developed for chialisp, with an [introductory document](https://github.com/Chia-Network/clvm_tools_rs/blob/7aa40d44fb3310c6dde14af181d40f9dd4029fef/types.md) available for those interested in exploring or contributing to this aspect. This initiative is part of their broader effort to enhance the language and its ecosystem.

One crucial piece of advice from the sender emphasizes the importance of establishing a robust system early in the development process for mapping high-level Lisp to low-level code. This suggestion stems from their experience, as Chia has encountered challenges in this area, leading to significant negative feedback from the chialisp development community. The sender hopes that sharing their experiences and current efforts will aid others in avoiding similar pitfalls and contribute to the overall advancement of Lisp-inspired programming languages.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-14T22:23:35.310000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
