<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
  <updated>2024-03-16T01:58:03.951616+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josibake</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-15T15:20:27.262000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
    <updated>2024-03-16T01:58:03.951649+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip324-proxy-easy-integration-of-v2-transport-protocol-for-light-clients-poc/678/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with an expression of enthusiasm towards the idea of rewriting an existing tool in Rust, a programming language known for its performance and safety features. The initiator, although not highly proficient in Rust, proposes this transition with optimism but also acknowledges the potential time investment required due to their learning curve with the language.

There is a suggestion to transform the tool into a Rust library, which could serve as a foundational component for other projects. This idea is supported by mentioning the Nakamoto project ([Nakamoto](https://github.com/cloudhead/nakamoto)), which plans to integrate BIP324, a Bitcoin Improvement Proposal aimed at enhancing the protocol’s security. The mention of Nakamoto's roadmap implies that there is a broader interest within the developer community for such a library. It suggests that creating a Rust-based library could be beneficial not only for personal projects but also for others within the ecosystem looking to implement similar features.

Additionally, there is an offer of collaboration from the person initiating the conversation. Despite their own admission of not being fluent in Rust, they express a willingness to contribute to the development of a BIP324 Rust library. This gesture highlights a collaborative spirit within the programming community, where individuals are eager to learn and contribute to open-source projects, even in areas where they might not have full expertise. The proposal aims to foster a partnership that leverages mutual interests in learning Rust and working on manageable projects, thereby advancing both personal skills and contributing to the wider developer community.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-15T15:20:27.262000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
