<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
  <updated>2024-03-16T01:58:46.897954+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roconnor-blockstream</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-15T22:53:08.354000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
    <updated>2024-03-16T01:58:46.897988+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/btc-lisp-as-an-alternative-to-script/682/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence delves into the nuances of programming languages, particularly focusing on the adaptability and translation capabilities between high-level and low-level languages within the context of Bitcoin's scripting. The discussion underscores an intrinsic principle where values computed from an environment are essentially functions, a perspective that significantly eases the translation or compilation efforts across different programming paradigms. This foundational understanding paves the way for translating high-level BTC Lisp language constructs into Simplicity, notwithstanding potential hurdles like unbounded recursion and the selection of primitives.

Moreover, it is highlighted that irrespective of the eventual design intricacies of Simphony, there exists a feasible pathway to translate or compile its constructs back into the discussed low-level BTC Lisp language. This reciprocity not only showcases the flexibility inherent in these programming languages but also opens the door to exploring various complexity and optimization opportunities through different translator/compiler language pairs. The exchange essentially posits that with diligent effort, a bridge can be built between the seemingly disparate domains of low-level and high-level programming languages, facilitating a rich ground for innovation and efficiency improvements in the realm of Bitcoin scripting and beyond.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-15T22:53:08.354000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
