<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
  <updated>2024-03-17T01:59:27.168713+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>theStack.962000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-16T08:46:33.962000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
    <updated>2024-03-17T01:59:27.168740+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip324-proxy-easy-integration-of-v2-transport-protocol-for-light-clients-poc/678/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation revolves around the potential development of a Rust library for BIP324, emphasizing its utility and applicability in enhancing privacy for Bitcoin light-client implementations. The dialogue kicks off with the suggestion to consider transforming the tool into a Rust library, recognizing the value it could bring to projects like Nakamoto, which has already earmarked the addition of BIP324 to its roadmap. This proposition is supported by referencing a post that highlights the integration of a BIP324 proxy for easing the implementation of the v2 transport protocol for light clients.

Further, there's an expression of interest in collaborating on this project, despite a self-admitted lack of fluency in Rust, showcasing a willingness to learn and contribute to small-scale projects. The invitation for collaboration is warmly extended, underscoring an inclusive approach towards community contributions. It is suggested that initiating the development with a module for the BIP324 cipher suite would be a pragmatic first step, mirroring the interface utilized by `BIP324Cipher` in Bitcoin Core. The feasibility of this endeavor is bolstered by the availability of Rust crates for cryptographic primitives, which could streamline the coding process. This discussion not only reflects the collaborative spirit within the programming community but also underscores the technical considerations and resources that can facilitate the development of such a library.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-16T08:46:33.962000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
