<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
  <updated>2024-03-18T01:56:20.661248+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>theStack 2024-03-17 19:48:10.014000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
    <updated>2024-03-18T01:56:20.661278+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip324-proxy-easy-integration-of-v2-transport-protocol-for-light-clients-poc/678/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development and enhancement of BIP324, particularly focusing on peer-to-peer (p2p) communication towards version 2, have sparked notable interest among programming enthusiasts. A collaborative effort is underway to create a Rust implementation aimed at integrating seamlessly with pre-existing TCP logic through an API. This initiative emphasizes minimizing dependencies, achieving significant progress by narrowing down to a few essential ones from `rust-bitcoin`. The forthcoming task involves constructing a top-level API around the Floresta Rust client, with efforts concentrated on this aspect within the current week. The project repository can be accessed [here](https://github.com/rustaceanrob/bip324).

The motivation behind reducing cryptographic dependencies and opting for their reimplementation has been questioned, considering whether it stems from specific limitations within available Rust crates or represents a broader philosophical approach akin to strategies employed in Bitcoin Core. Despite Rust's efficient package management system and the potential advantages of relying on well-supported cryptographic libraries for optimization purposes, the decision leans towards dependency minimization.

Furthermore, a related project has initiated a Rust rewrite, currently in its nascent stages. This early version establishes a local server socket capable of acknowledging incoming client connections without engaging in thread creation. The immediate strategy includes developing a basic proxy (v1&lt;-&gt;v1) before incorporating BIP324-specific functionalities. This endeavor and its progress can be followed through the repository located at [https://github.com/theStack/bip324-proxy/tree/rust_rewrite](https://github.com/theStack/bip324-proxy/tree/rust_rewrite). Contributions across various forms, including code, recommendations on network programming in Rust, and insights into common pitfalls, are highly encouraged to foster these projects' growth and refinement.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-17T19:48:10.014000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
