<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-20T02:08:42.051225+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell.791000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-19T02:38:56.791000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-20T02:08:42.051256+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/33" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discussion revolves around the concept of implementing future discounting within diagram checks, aiming to standardize the comparability of diagrams during these evaluations. This approach would effectively segregate the considerations of incentives and denial-of-service (DoS) checks into distinct categories, facilitating a more precise focus on devising alternative strategies for anti-DoS measures. The conversation acknowledges that while initially both aspects were discussed together, perhaps in anticipation of discovering a unified solution, the consensus now leans towards treating them as independent issues for clearer understanding and resolution.

Furthermore, the dialogue touches upon the topic of stackable transactions (txs) and their susceptibility to potential problems. However, it suggests that this vulnerability might not be a significant concern. The reasoning provided is that with the appropriate introspection technology available to manage stackable transactions, it would also be feasible to regulate the total transaction size. This regulatory capability implies that if there exists an active and healthy marketplace where stacked transactions are routinely made with reasonable fees, the need for direct intervention might be mitigated. This part of the discussion underscores the importance of technological advancements and market dynamics in addressing the challenges associated with transaction management and security.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-19T02:38:56.791000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
