<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
  <updated>2024-03-20T02:17:46.925139+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2024-03-19 13:17:31.522000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
    <updated>2024-03-20T02:17:46.925170+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gitlab-backups-for-bitcoin-core-repository/624/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent update to the Bitcoin Core development wiki introduces a new section dedicated to GitHub alternatives for repository backups and tooling. This addition aims at providing developers and contributors with a comprehensive guide on how to ensure their work is safely backed up outside of GitHub's ecosystem. The importance of this initiative stems from the need for redundancy and security in software development, particularly in projects as significant as Bitcoin Core.

The wiki now hosts a variety of suggested tools and platforms that could serve as alternatives or complements to GitHub. This includes both proprietary and open-source solutions, each with its own set of features catering to different needs within the development workflow. The goal is to equip developers with the knowledge and resources to choose the best backup solutions that align with their project requirements and personal preferences.

Contributors are encouraged to add their recommendations and experiences to the wiki. By sharing insights and tools they find effective for backing up repositories, the Bitcoin Core community can collectively enhance the robustness of its development practices. This collaborative effort not only improves individual projects but also strengthens the overall resilience of the Bitcoin Core ecosystem against data loss and other potential disruptions.

For more details and to contribute your suggestions, visit the wiki page at [GitHub alternatives for Bitcoin Core repository backups and tooling](https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/GitHub-alternatives-for-Bitcoin-Corerepository-backups-and-tooling).</summary>
    <published>2024-03-19T13:17:31.522000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
