<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
  <updated>2024-03-23T01:54:32.171969+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-22T11:40:39.031000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T01:54:32.172002+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-based-fee-estimation-on-bitcoin-core/703/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and potential solutions in estimating transaction fees within a blockchain network, particularly focusing on how to avoid inaccurately low or high fee rate estimations. The primary concern highlighted is the adaptation towards lower estimates, especially when previously mined blocks have lower fee rates. This could lead to an underestimation of fees when compared with the current state of the mempool, which is the collection of all transactions waiting to be confirmed. To address this issue, an approach was suggested to use the minimum between the confirmed estimate and the mempool estimate. However, this method also tends toward underestimation, indicating that while it may solve the problem of overestimation by the `CBlockPolicyEstimator`, it does not fully rectify the estimation inaccuracies.

An important aspect of the discussion includes the introduction of checks that could prevent nodes from using this estimation mode during soft forks, which are updates to the blockchain protocol that are backward compatible. This indicates a proactive measure to ensure that the network's functionality remains stable during such updates. Additionally, the concern about miners potentially manipulating the mempool to artificially inflate fee estimates was addressed. It was suggested that such manipulation would involve mining empty blocks or intentionally delaying mining to congest the mempool. However, the decentralization of mining activities is believed to mitigate this risk, suggesting that in a sufficiently decentralized environment, such scenarios would be unlikely to occur.

The dialogue also incorporates a visual representation comparing mempool fee estimates with actual block median fees, alongside a [link to a spreadsheet](https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1CMIS3miHLwEc8hmT5ZdZy0TVAxVi61folaoZgJBPQpg/edit?usp=sharing) providing additional data. These resources are essential for understanding the practical implications of fee estimation methods and the performance of the proposed solution in real-world conditions. Overall, the conversation underscores the complexity of accurately estimating transaction fees in a dynamic and decentralized blockchain environment and explores potential strategies to improve the reliability of these estimates.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T11:40:39.031000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
