<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
  <updated>2024-03-27T01:51:44.284139+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding.587000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-26T21:43:43.587000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T01:51:44.284168+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/improving-transaction-sponsor-blockspace-efficiency/696/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of enhancing Bitcoin's script capabilities, specifically for the verification of Simplified Payment Verification (SPV) proofs, a variety of proposals have been discussed. These proposals aim to expand the scripting language to allow more complex operations such as merkle proof verification and proof of work verification. Among these proposals are [BIN24-1](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/binana/blob/a1d1daab524007819aca70132e0dd97e0e8caf51/2024/BIN-2024-0001.md), [Simplicity](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/simplicity), [BTC Lisp](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/btc-lisp-as-an-alternative-to-script/682), Elements-style streaming SHA opcodes, and [MATT](https://merkle.fun/). These enhancements could theoretically enable scripts to accommodate various consensus-compatible transaction formats and conditions by utilizing opcodes like `OP_CAT`, `OP_SHA256`, and `OP_IF`.

The discussion also touches upon the potential risks associated with allowing arbitrary third parties to attach to the transaction graph of any relayed transaction. Concerns about Denial of Service (DoS) attacks and the complexities arising from transaction graph dependencies highlight the need for careful consideration in implementing such features. The suggestion of an opt-in flag was mentioned as a possible solution, albeit with reservations due to its implications for blockchain analysis and privacy.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the topic of transaction sponsorship and the challenges it seeks to address within the Bitcoin network. The critique revolves around the existing policy-induced issues, such as transaction pinning and the high costs associated with exogenous fee bumping. The latter poses a threat to Bitcoin's decentralization by potentially incentivizing direct interactions between users and large miners. An improved sponsor proposal was highlighted for its efficiency benefits, offering a cost-effective alternative to traditional fee bumping methods while aiming to preserve decentralization. This approach underscores the importance of consensus rules in ensuring the fair prioritization of transactions without undermining the UTXO model's integrity.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T21:43:43.587000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
