<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-03-27T01:53:48.239525+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2024-03-26 23:31:32.536000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T01:53:48.239552+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the complexities and potential risks associated with implementing a mechanism to track block heights in blockchain technology. It emphasizes that the effort and risk involved in creating such a mechanism may not justify its benefits, particularly highlighting the concern that a miner might produce an invalid block 21 years from now due to outdated software. This timeframe is based on projections that the issue discussed would not arise before block height 1,983,702.

An interesting aspect of the analysis involves examining future blocks for the possibility of duplicate coinbase transactions without contravening BIP34. The examination covered the first 227,931 blocks of the chain, identifying 189,023 coinbase transactions with potential for duplication. A significant finding is that there are instances where coinbase transactions could be duplicated across various future block heights—10 occurrences before block 5,000,000, 24 before block 10,000,000, and 80 before block 100,000,000. Specifically, it lists 24 duplicable transactions occurring before block 10,000,000 along with their original and duplicable block heights, showcasing the potential for such duplicates to occur at significant future milestones.

For individuals interested in delving deeper into the specifics of potential future violations regarding duplicate coinbase transactions, a comprehensive list has been made available. This list offers detailed insights into the blocks that could potentially host these duplications, contributing to the ongoing discussion about the scalability and security of blockchain technology. The full list of potential future violations can be explored through the provided [link](https://gist.github.com/darosior/3a5ac0a8d935fa9d3e90310590ca6699).</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T23:31:32.536000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
