<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
  <updated>2024-03-27T01:51:28.423740+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar.655000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-26T23:36:27.655000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T01:51:28.423773+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/improving-transaction-sponsor-blockspace-efficiency/696/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the capabilities enabled by specific opcodes in blockchain technology, particularly focusing on the verification of merkle proofs and proof of work through combinations of existing opcodes such as `OP_SHA256`/`OP_HASH256`, along with `OP_IF`. These combinations are believed to support the verification of consensus-compatible shapes of partial merkle branches and ensure that scripts remain reorg safe by necessitating a connection to the active headers chain for data validation. This approach is deemed secure against reorganization attacks since it relies on internal transaction validation without inspecting external transaction elements.

Another significant aspect highlighted is the differentiation between exogenous and endogenous fees within smart contract transactions. The conversation touches upon the terminology introduced by @instagibbs, which categorizes fees based on their origin relative to the transaction - whether they are added externally (exogenous) or arise from within the transaction itself (endogenous). The discourse suggests a preference for protocols to adopt a model that minimizes blockchain space usage, although acknowledging that layer 2 protocol development might not strictly adhere to this minimalist approach due to various constraints.

Furthermore, the email delves into the complexities and inefficiencies surrounding the use of Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) mechanisms in transactions, particularly those that cannot inherently include endogenous fees. A proposed solution involves the adoption of transaction sponsorship models as an alternative to CPFP/RBF (Replace By Fee), aiming to reduce costs and improve efficiency. Jeremy's contribution to this subject, through a [mailing list post](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2020-September/018179.html), emphasizes the need for policy adjustments atop consensus changes to mitigate traditional pinning issues and streamline the implementation of sponsors in the mempool.

The narrative critically analyzes the balance between blockchain efficiency and the potential miner-centralization issue posed by exogenous-fee-CPFP protocols. The writer expresses skepticism towards altering the consensus model merely to save a minimal amount of blockchain space, advocating instead for the demonstration of utility and adoption through existing methodologies before considering any consensus changes. The overarching caution is against inadvertently affecting existing transactions and users by introducing arbitrary third-party interactions within the transaction graph, emphasizing the importance of thoughtful soft-fork design to prevent unintended consequences.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T23:36:27.655000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
