<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
  <updated>2024-03-28T01:59:04.679915+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin.320000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-27T16:36:12.320000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
    <updated>2024-03-28T01:59:04.679941+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/improving-transaction-sponsor-blockspace-efficiency/696/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin security, the principle of "progress friendliness" stands paramount. This concept emphasizes that a secure protocol must function as intended regardless of which transactions from a set of currently minable transactions are processed. The essence here is that any transaction being mined should be viewed as a positive development, eliminating concerns over specific transaction preferences. This approach negates the issue of transaction pinning when policies ensure sponsors contribute by including a transaction cluster in the forthcoming block or shortly thereafter. Such a stance ensures user satisfaction by guaranteeing protocol progress through the mining of any transaction, thus sidelining the relevance of pinning concerns.

The discussion extends to the adaptability of protocols like LN-Symmetry to this progress-friendly paradigm. For instance, even if a miner opts for a different transaction state due to sponsorship, it doesn't impede the ability to later broadcast and finalize the intended state without extra costs. This flexibility is further bolstered by each update extending the timeout before a final claim can be made, providing ample time to accommodate sequences of unfavorable updates. The narrative underlines that protocols attaching undue importance to the mining order of transactions, expecting both broadcasting and guaranteed mining of preferred transactions, veer away from the tenets of security within the Bitcoin ecosystem.

Moreover, the discourse clarifies that transaction preference essentially boils down to financial incentives, whether direct payments or through sponsorship packages. Any discontent arising from the mining of one transaction over another stems from misconceived assumptions about Bitcoin's operational mechanics. It implicitly critiques protocols reliant on rapid execution assumptions, such as Lightning, for not aligning with the inherent unpredictability and competitive nature of transaction mining. This exposition underscores a broader critique of strategies that fail to embrace the stochastic nature of transaction processing in Bitcoin, advocating for a reevaluation of secure protocol design that harmonizes with the foundational principles of Bitcoin transaction dynamics.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T16:36:12.320000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
