<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:46:49.988304+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ganava.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-28T22:13:55.853000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:46:49.988336+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/39" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses a critical aspect of blockchain technology, focusing on the vulnerability associated with transaction resubmissions. The primary concern highlighted is the negligible cost to attackers who exploit this vulnerability by continuously resubmitting the same or similar transactions. This tactic not only burdens the network but also disproportionately consumes bandwidth, impacting the overall functionality and efficiency of the system.

The sender points out that the collective weight of these transactions significantly exceeds the data capacity intended for block inclusion. This discrepancy indicates that such transactions underpay for relay costs, further straining network resources. This situation underscores the necessity for a mechanism that mandates an increase in total fees for transaction replacements in the mempool, aiming to mitigate bandwidth depletion and ensure equitable use of network resources.

A reference is made to a previous issue described as the "infinite cycle problem," suggesting that it might be related to the current discussion. The sender questions whether this issue was addressed by Todd, implying that solutions or improvements may have already been proposed within the community.

Moreover, the email includes a mention of experimenting with Libre Relay, a tool presumably used for network operations or security enhancements. The sender notes that their node appears unaffected by the discussed attack, hinting at potential variations in vulnerability across different nodes or configurations.

The conversation concludes with a link providing additional information or a possible solution to the problem. The provided URL ([https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2024-January/022326.html](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2024-January/022326.html)) suggests that further details or discussions regarding the issue can be found on the Linux Foundation's mailing list dedicated to Bitcoin development. This resource may offer insights or proposals aimed at resolving the identified network weakness.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-28T22:13:55.853000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
