<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-03-29T03:08:37.892718+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ganava</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-28T22:32:29.012000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T03:08:37.892751+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the potential inefficiencies and exploitation possibilities introduced by OP_EXPIRE in blockchain transactions. The concept of OP_EXPIRE, which allows transactions to expire if not mined within a certain timeframe, could lead to a misuse scenario where an attacker deliberately floods the network with such transactions. This is done with the intention of occupying bandwidth without bearing significant costs, as these transactions are strategically placed to be pushed out of the block by subsequent transactions of the same type. The concern is that if the required fee rate for these transactions is set very high to ensure their mining before expiration, it could paradoxically result in wastage of block space.

A counterargument presented highlights that executing such an attack would inherently involve the generation of fee-paying transactions that are expensive to create in the first place. Therefore, the actual cost of conducting an attack might deter potential attackers since each transaction must carry a sufficiently high fee rate to be considered for mining promptly. Moreover, the practice of replacing transactions through Replace-By-Fee (RBF) protocol is mentioned, indicating that the introduction of OP_EXPIRE does not substantially alter the existing dynamics concerning transaction replacement and associated bandwidth costs. The RBF protocol allows transactions to be replaced with another paying a slightly higher fee, thus already providing a mechanism where additional fees compensate for the bandwidth used by transaction replacements.

For further reading and details on the technical discussion surrounding OP_EXPIRE and its implications on Bitcoin's transaction handling mechanisms, refer to the thread on [BitcoinDev](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/qEx4K8lGnLk).</summary>
    <published>2024-03-28T22:32:29.012000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
