<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:57:00.166715+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-03-29 16:50:26.252000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:57:00.166747+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dsl-for-experimenting-with-contracts/748" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The domain-specific language (DSL) currently being developed is aimed at streamlining the process of working with bitcoin contracts. Unlike existing methods that attempt to simplify Script into higher-level languages, this DSL focuses on a more comprehensive approach. It enables users to describe transactions, interact directly with a bitcoin node, and perform system state assertions all through a declarative syntax. This approach simplifies the complex processes involved in handling bitcoin transactions by abstracting the underlying technical details.

One of the core advantages of this DSL is its ability to provide a high-level descriptive syntax for detailing transactions. This includes the creation of locking and unlocking scripts using various methods such as miniscript, descriptors, and traditional Script. The runtime of this DSL is designed to automatically manage witness programs, which is crucial for generating signatures without manual intervention. Moreover, it supports executing multiple contract branches based on system state transitions, thus offering flexibility in how contracts are managed and executed.

Interaction with a bitcoin node is streamlined through the DSL, facilitating direct communication and operation execution within the bitcoin network. Additionally, it includes functionalities for asserting the state of the system, allowing users to verify the outcome of their transactions and contracts effectively. The goal is to further expand the DSL's capabilities by incorporating taproot constructions and providing support for running experimental versions of bitcoin, thereby enhancing its utility for advanced use cases.

Documentation and examples of the DSL, including example contracts for lightning and ARK, are made available for those interested in utilizing or contributing to the development of this tool. The provided examples illustrate the practical application of the DSL in creating and executing bitcoin contracts on regtest environments using a high-level syntax. These resources can be found at the documentation site [here](https://opdup.com/bitcoin-dsl/index.html) and the repository [here](https://github.com/pool2win/bitcoin-dsl). Through these examples and the ongoing development efforts, the DSL is poised to offer significant benefits to users by simplifying the complexities associated with bitcoin transactions and contracts.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T16:50:26.252000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
