<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:46:25.121545+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch.137000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-29T18:36:34.137000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:46:25.121579+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/41" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email contains a discussion on several technical issues and proposals, beginning with a mention of Todd's resolution of an infinite cycle problem. This indicates that there has been an ongoing effort to tackle bugs or design flaws within a project. The conversation quickly shifts to a critique of a proposal deemed flawed due to its foundational approach. This criticism is rooted in the author's demonstration through an example, highlighting a general issue. However, the response to this critique was focused narrowly on the specific mechanism presented in the example rather than addressing the broader flaw identified. This led to the conclusion that further engagement on this matter would not be a productive endeavor.

Additionally, the message touches upon the use of Libre Relay, noting the sender's personal experience with their node's performance under potential security threats. It points out a crucial misconception in cybersecurity assessments: the absence of attacks does not inherently signify a system's security. This statement underscores the importance of adopting a proactive and comprehensive approach to evaluating security, rather than relying on the lack of evidence as proof of safety. The emphasis on looking beyond surface-level indications for security vulnerabilities suggests a deeper understanding of and concern for robust system protection mechanisms.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T18:36:34.137000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
