<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:55:08.957639+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding.785000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-03-29T22:33:16.785000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Improving transaction sponsor blockspace efficiency</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:55:08.957671+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/improving-transaction-sponsor-blockspace-efficiency/696/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of transaction fee optimization in blockchain protocols, comparing different methodologies like Ephemeral Anchors and Sponsor Transactions. It begins with an acknowledgment of a misconception regarding the validity of scripts post-reorganization (reorg) in the blockchain, emphasizing that scripts remain valid even if the referenced Merkle root is not part of the active chain. This correction leads into a deeper analysis of cost-saving strategies for Child-Pays-For-Parent (CPFP) transactions, highlighting the potential for saving 10-15% of the costs by implementing efficient sponsors over alternatives like Ephemeral Anchors.

The narrative then delves into the nuances of absolute versus marginal costs in transaction fees, presenting a hypothetical scenario where regular transactions could sponsor additional ones without prior setup. This model assumes consistent transaction activity from users, exemplified by "Alice," who could be compensated to sponsor another user's ("Bob's") transaction, marginally increasing her transaction size by approximately 0.5 vbytes. This method contrasts with the more cumbersome process of including ephemeral anchor outputs, which would significantly increase the transaction size and cost for both parties involved. The discussion points out the absence of a trustless mechanism for off-chain payment between Bob and Alice, underlining the inherent risk of non-fulfillment associated with third-party fee bumping, irrespective of the method used.

Exploring further, the conversation shifts towards the challenges faced by users lacking readily available unencumbered UTXOs due to the adoption of pooling technologies, delayed spending protocols, and an overall increase in feerates. For such users, acquiring an unencumbered UTXO promptly might necessitate additional on-chain transactions, complicating the process further. 

Moreover, the talk provides a detailed cost analysis for a hypothetical future transaction, breaking down the total expenses associated with different fee bumping strategies, including endogenous fees, out-of-band (OOB) payments to miners, and utilizing sponsor transactions or ephemeral anchors. This analysis illuminates the varying costs and risks tied to each approach, including the potential for delays, the necessity of paying premiums, and the impact on the UTXO set.

Lastly, the discussion acknowledges the potential for substantial savings through OOB payments to miners in a future with higher feerates, suggesting a significant interest in mechanisms that offer even modest discounts on transaction fees. The conversation concludes by recognizing the need to address several challenges related to the implementation of sponsor transactions, specifically concerning reorg safety, the avoidance of new pinning vectors, and ensuring compatibility with mempool structures and algorithms, indicating ongoing investigations into these issues.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T22:33:16.785000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
