<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Liquidity provider utxo management</title>
  <updated>2024-03-22T01:52:08.391605+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-03-21 19:36:01.685000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-20 15:37:05.120000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-20 14:40:41.291000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-20 14:39:32.741000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-20 09:50:16.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-20 09:12:04.546000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-18 19:48:30.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-03-02 13:03:49.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  . 2024-02-22 14:49:27.076000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1984_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1955_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1951_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1953_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1952_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1950_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1928_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1766_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1672_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Liquidity provider utxo management</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T01:52:08.391684+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/liquidity-provider-utxo-management/600/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion primarily focuses on optimizing Lightning funding transactions by leveraging the flexibility in funded amounts, which deviates from conventional precision-focused transactions. An innovative approach is introduced, utilizing 'excess' funds in the coin selection process through the adaptation of the Branch and Bound (BnB) algorithm. This method aims for changeless transactions by using slightly larger or smaller UTXOs within a tolerance range to reduce total transaction fees. The effectiveness of this strategy is being evaluated through simulations to assess its impact on fee reduction and optimization of Lightning channel funding.

Further analysis explores strategies for optimizing liquidity transactions through efficient management of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). The concept of a "changeless solution" targets specific amounts to refill depleted buckets, maximizing UTXO usage efficiency. However, the unpredictability of closing channels generating random UTXO amounts challenges initial assumptions. An alternative strategy involves creating transactions that precisely refill buckets using the largest available non-bucketed UTXO, potentially consolidating UTXOs when fees are low. This highlights the need for flexible and adaptive approaches to UTXO allocation to streamline transactions and improve cryptocurrency management practices.

The potential advantages of integrating CoinGrinder (CG) and Branch and Bound (BnB) algorithms over traditional methods are discussed, emphasizing the refinement of the coin selection process for liquidity transactions and bucket refills. A modification to the `sendmany` RPC could allow selective algorithm usage, tailoring the process to specific transaction requirements. Initial simulations indicate the possibility of lower fees and fewer median inputs with unrestricted algorithm selection, prompting further investigation into coin selection efficiency and the optimal application of algorithms.

Optimizing coin selection also involves adjusting the `min_change` parameter and selectively creating outputs based on the current feerate environment. Tailoring output types without altering coin selection mechanics presents a nuanced optimization technique that adapts to external fee conditions. Proactive measures for refilling depleted buckets under low fee rates, leveraging large, non-bucketed UTXOs for tailored change outputs, are emphasized, facilitating efficient resource utilization.

The proposal further elaborates on an algorithmic approach for efficient distribution of transaction fees, identifying optimal funding inputs and change outputs. This method computes each bucket's capacity for targeted refill needs, allowing for strategic coin selection to replenish target buckets adequately. The [CoinGrinder GitHub repository](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/27877) provides additional resources for exploring recommended coin selection algorithms, indicating broader applications such as batching withdrawals and coin join operations.

The email outlines a strategy for optimizing transaction costs while ensuring sufficient liquidity for wallets managing Lightning nodes. It proposes importing a user-defined set of target UTXOs for funding liquidity transactions, aiming to eliminate the need for additional inputs and change outputs. The strategy emphasizes proactive UTXO bucket refilling under specific conditions, introducing a nuanced approach to coin selection. Modifications to the [coin_selection_simulation](https://github.com/achow101/coin-selection-simulation) and Bitcoin Core, as seen in draft PR [29422](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29442), have been tested, showing potential fee reductions by approximately 15% compared to standard practices. The email concludes with questions intended to refine the strategy further, inviting community input to enhance the efficacy of the suggested approach.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T19:36:01.685000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
