<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
  <updated>2024-03-08T01:53:19.593994+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell 2024-03-07 02:53:25.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-03-07 00:58:22.648000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 09:43:17.844000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 06:48:42.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-27 06:32:35.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-27 05:39:39.452000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-26 20:04:01.039000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-26 15:09:35.021000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-26 05:19:43.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-25 03:56:28.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-24 11:18:37.781000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 06:33:02.619000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 06:25:07.893000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-24 04:29:01.677000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:47:35.020000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-24 03:42:41.318000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-23 12:13:17.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-02-23 06:06:54.686000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-22 19:14:14.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-22 14:57:46.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell  . 2024-02-22 02:45:53.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-14 15:13:07.637000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-14 01:25:53.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  . 2024-02-13 19:19:39.167000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1808_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1807_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1715_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1713_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1711_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1704_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1702_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1698_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1695_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1689_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1688_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1686_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1685_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1684_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1682_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1681_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1678_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1677_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1674_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1673_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1659_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1567_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1553_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1526_Mempool-Incentive-Compatibility.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Incentive Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T01:53:19.594156+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation explores a novel approach to Bitcoin's transaction management, suggesting an incremental fee strategy for transactions evicted from the mempool. This method contrasts with current practices by proposing that subsequent transactions from the same sender incur higher fees, aiming to manage network resources more effectively by prioritizing transactions willing to pay more post-eviction. However, challenges in implementation are acknowledged, given its potential less effectiveness compared to directly collecting fees from transactions.

It delves into the limitations of Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) in version 3 (v3) of Bitcoin transactions, particularly under rising transaction fees. The discussion advocates for future protocol enhancements to allow inline fees and cost-sharing among transactions through covenant technology, aimed at navigating high-fee environments without renegotiating terms. The concept of transaction introspection and aggregation is proposed as a means to alleviate high fees by compiling multiple transactions into one, distributing costs more efficiently among participants.

An examination of Bitcoin’s transaction fee mechanism reveals its dynamic nature, governed by a decay system influenced by network congestion. The adaptive feature is designed to lower the barrier for transaction processing during low-demand periods, optimizing the fee market's responsiveness to changing network conditions. Furthermore, misconceptions regarding the permanence of fee increases following eviction from the mempool are addressed, clarifying that such increases are temporary and aim to manage mempool congestion.

The intricacies of pinning transactions within the blockchain are discussed, exploring speculative solutions for overcoming excessive fees associated with transaction conflicts. Technical and economic considerations of transaction replacement policies, including First-Seen-Safe and Replace-by-Fee mechanisms, are highlighted, pointing to the complexity of ensuring network robustness.

The dialogue also touches upon strategies concerning blockchain transaction fees and policies, emphasizing the need for fair cost replacement and a refined theoretical framework to guide Replace-By-Fee (RBF) policies. It critiques version 3 transactions for their limitations in supporting CPFP in rising fee situations, suggesting that future technologies might offer more efficient fee distribution methods.

Two policy suggestions, the "Feerate Diagram Policy" and the "Next Block Policy," are presented to refine RBF within Bitcoin’s protocol, with the former favored for enhancing economic efficiency and robustness against DoS attacks. Challenges related to transaction pinning are acknowledged, alongside the importance of precise language in virtual block management and adherence to transaction size limits for network integrity.

A cautious approach to Bitcoin development is advocated, focusing on manageable improvements. The discourse extends to cryptocurrency mining, emphasizing the significance of understanding miner incentives and the practical implications of accepting non-standard-size transactions. The economic rationality behind large mining pools retaining transactions despite competitive dynamics is explored, along with the complexities of transaction selection within blockchain mining.

Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms are discussed, suggesting variable fee adjustments within the same block to address the unpredictability of the mempool and network states. Concerns about higher fees incentivizing behaviors that undermine network integrity, such as transaction censorship, are raised. Proposals to address concerns related to RBF protocols suggest a hysteresis approach to alleviate friction points without significantly altering miner behavior.

Lastly, optimizing transaction ordering in Bitcoin's mempool is examined, highlighting innovative strategies aimed at maximizing fee collection considering block size constraints. Pieter Wuille’s theorem and the cluster mempool proposal offer insights into managing and ordering transactions within the Bitcoin network, found [here](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-definitions-theory/202optimal-linearizations-6) and in the [cluster mempool proposal](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393/1). These discussions contribute to understanding incentive-compatible behaviors important for maintaining network integrity and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-07T02:53:25.889000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
