<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Chia Lisp For Bitcoiners</title>
  <updated>2024-03-05T01:56:49.405365+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen 2024-03-04 22:45:13.618000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-03-04 20:37:46.561000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake 2024-03-04 12:51:37.350000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-03-04 02:46:38.231000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1787_Chia-Lisp-For-Bitcoiners.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1784_Chia-Lisp-For-Bitcoiners.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1779_Chia-Lisp-For-Bitcoiners.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1777_Chia-Lisp-For-Bitcoiners.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Chia Lisp For Bitcoiners</title>
    <updated>2024-03-05T01:56:49.405417+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/chia-lisp-for-bitcoiners/636/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email provides a comprehensive analysis of Chialisp, a Lisp variant used in the Chia blockchain, contrasting it with Bitcoin Script and exploring its unique features and potential for enhancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities. It underscores the benefits of using Chialisp templates for code reuse to minimize costs associated with complex scripts. The architecture of Chia is designed to support covenants and capabilities, offering more flexibility than what Bitcoin Script allows. Furthermore, it discusses the feasibility of integrating similar functionalities into Bitcoin through new opcodes.

Chialisp's approach to treating code and data equivalently on the stack is highlighted as beneficial for scenarios involving unexpected code in transactions. This contrasts with Bitcoin Script's limitations in handling recursion and structured data management. Chialisp's use of a binary tree structure for data, instead of a traditional stack, facilitates more complex data manipulation. The "apply" opcode in Chialisp enables recursion and looping, showcasing its advanced capabilities over Bitcoin Script.

The conversation also delves into the potential of Formal Verification tools for Lisp variants, acknowledging the challenges posed by cryptographic security in proving program correctness. It mentions ongoing discussions within the cryptocurrency development community aimed at improving Bitcoin's scripting language, providing links to resources for further reading, including discussions on Bitcoin development ([Bitcoin Dev Mailing List March 2022](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2022-March/020036.html), [Bitcoin Dev Mailing List October 2023](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022099.html)), an introduction to Chialisp ([Chialisp.com](https://chialisp.com/)), and foundational knowledge on Bitcoin Script ([Bitcoin Wiki](https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Script)) and Lisp programming ([Build Your Own Lisp](https://www.buildyourownlisp.com/)).

Further discussion includes Chialisp's cost management strategies to prevent denial-of-service attacks and the introduction of spend bundles in Chia for optimizing transaction processing. However, concerns about block validation complexity and potential centralization are raised. Resources such as [chia-dev-tools](https://github.com/Chia-Network/chia-dev-tools/) are recommended for developers interested in Chialisp and clvm, along with a Rust implementation for those preferring that language.

Finally, addressing defects in clvm and the resolution of issues like the "CATbleed" incident through smart contract updates and new opcodes demonstrate the community's commitment to improving blockchain programming languages. The exploration highlights significant advancements in Chialisp's functionality and security while emphasizing the need for ongoing improvement and bug fixing. The introduction of new opcodes and conditions under [CHIP-11](https://github.com/Chia-Network/chips/blob/b096b5735989b243f7c2dec8533aa0080d084dc8/CHIPs/chip-0011.md) and [CHIP-14](https://github.com/Chia-Network/chips/blob/b096b5735989b243f7c2dec8533aa0080d084dc8/CHIPs/chip-0014.md) marks significant progress in expanding Chialisp's capabilities, setting the stage for more sophisticated blockchain contracts and applications.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T22:45:13.618000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
