<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
  <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:29.701636+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2024-03-06 14:36:26.070000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>fjahr  . 2024-02-29 16:29:34.172000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1802_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1739_GitLab-Backups-for-Bitcoin-Core-repository.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - GitLab Backups for Bitcoin Core repository</title>
    <updated>2024-03-07T01:37:29.701676+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gitlab-backups-for-bitcoin-core-repository/624/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The project aimed at establishing a self-hosted GitLab instance for backing up the Bitcoin Core GitHub repository has evolved into an elaborate initiative focused on preserving data and ensuring uninterrupted development. The journey to achieve a comprehensive backup included setting up a GitLab server, engaging in extensive research, and overcoming challenges through trial and error, with significant assistance from GitLab support. This endeavor culminated in a successful complete backup, with the most recent data as of February 26, 2024, now available at [GitLab](https://gitlab.sighash.org/bitcoin/bitcoin). To assist others in creating their own GitLab backup servers, all findings and instructions have been detailed in a [gist](https://gist.github.com/fjahr/9a28abefe0ab8413d96aa1dd7903c5d4), designed to serve as a thorough guide and solicit community feedback for improvements.

The process highlighted the potential limitations imposed by the GitHub API, which can extend the import operation to GitLab up to 36 hours, rendering the data temporarily inaccessible. Despite these challenges, the project underscores the viability of using GitLab for repository backup purposes. It emphasizes the necessity of adaptability and preemptive planning in software development projects. While the focus has been on the Bitcoin Core repository, the tools and methodologies developed through this project are applicable to other repositories as well, although smaller projects may not necessitate the specialized configurations required for Bitcoin Core. This initiative not only demonstrates the practicality of GitLab backups but also contributes valuable insights and resources to the wider developer community.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-06T14:36:26.070000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
