<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - DNS seed node filtering</title>
  <updated>2024-03-02T01:48:04.045838+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mzumsande.848000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cdecker.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  ..823000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>virtu  ..861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1760_DNS-seed-node-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1745_DNS-seed-node-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1568_DNS-seed-node-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1565_DNS-seed-node-filtering.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - DNS seed node filtering</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T01:48:04.045892+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dns-seed-node-filtering/570" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the intricate ecosystem of Bitcoin's network, DNS seeds play a crucial role in ensuring the system's stability and security by facilitating the initial connection process for new nodes. These seeds help new nodes find peers to connect with, thereby integrating them into the larger network. Notably, different seeds employ varied strategies concerning version-based filtering, where nodes running older software versions might be excluded from the lists provided to newcomers. This practice aims at promoting a network environment dominated by up-to-date and secure software, thus enhancing overall network reliability. Among the seeds, `dnsseed.bitcoin.dashjr.org` is recognized for its strict filtering criteria, which aligns with the broader goal of maintaining a robust and secure network infrastructure.

The conversation around DNS seed policies gained traction following a specific pull request (PR29149) on the Bitcoin GitHub repository, which was eventually closed due to controversies and a lack of consensus within the community. Despite this setback, the incident sparked further inquiries into how DNS seeds manage version-based filtering across the network. A programmer took it upon themselves to investigate the matter by collecting data on the Bitcoin Core versions run by reachable nodes as advertised by various DNS seeds over time. This research unveiled that certain seeds, such as `dnsseed.bitcoin.dashjr.org`, adhere to stringent filtering protocols against outdated versions, while others like `dnsseed.bluematt.me` and `seed.bitcoin.wiz.biz` implement these measures with less severity. The data collected indicated a range of minimum version thresholds across different seeds, suggesting a deliberate filtering approach by some, albeit the observed discrepancies could also result from the natural decline in nodes operating on significantly older versions.

To make these findings widely accessible and foster transparency within the Bitcoin community, the programmer established a platform providing daily updated monitoring data on the distribution of Bitcoin Core versions among the network's nodes ([here](https://21.ninja/dns-seeds/node-version-range/)). This initiative not only illuminates the practices surrounding version-based filtering across Bitcoin's DNS seeds but also offers critical insights into the adoption rates of various Bitcoin Core versions. Such efforts are instrumental in navigating the ongoing dialogue about balancing inclusivity with the imperative of adhering to current standards and security protocols within the digital currency landscape, thereby contributing to the continuous improvement and resilience of the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-01T18:12:35.848000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
