<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
  <updated>2024-04-10T01:57:34.299913+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>shesek 2024-04-09 22:47:42.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-04-09 09:08:16.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  . 2024-04-06 20:43:12.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-04-06 20:25:08.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-04-02 10:56:33.502000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Luckylee  . 2024-04-02 08:42:43.055000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-31 19:04:06.072000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-31 17:31:14.749000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-31 16:42:27.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-03-31 10:20:06.175000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-30 21:52:17.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-30 18:44:58.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-29 16:50:26.252000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2189_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2185_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2179_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2178_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2131_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2129_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2109_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2108_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2106_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2105_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2101_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2100_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2086_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
    <updated>2024-04-10T01:57:34.300011+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dsl-for-experimenting-with-contracts/748/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Minsc is a programming language that introduces functional constructs such as `repeat($n, $script)` for looping, aiding in the creation of scripts like `rollFromAltStack` for known quantities and allowing dynamic script generation based on runtime conditions. Its `unrollLoop` feature enables script fragments to execute based on certain conditions, showcasing Minsc's efficiency in defining MiniScript-level spending conditions. Despite its capabilities, Minsc suffers from outdated documentation, with more current resources and examples available online, including uses of CTV and Liquid's introspection opcodes.

The discussion contrasts Temporal Logic of Actions (TLA+) with a Domain-Specific Language (DSL) developed for Bitcoin contracts. TLA+ offers a robust framework for documenting and verifying concurrent systems through model checking, which could automate the verification process for Bitcoin contracts when integrated with the DSL, potentially enhancing their integrity and reliability. The utility of TLA+ in preempting errors in projects like Braidpool by specifying protocols is also noted.

An exploration into BitVM demonstrates a shift towards simplifying programming with declarative syntax, proposing a `times` generator to ease scripting processes. This innovation suggests a potential evolution in programming paradigms towards efficiency and intuitiveness. In Rust Bitcoin Script development, macros have been utilized to simplify script writing, offering syntactic sugar for loops and complex structures, thus making scripting more accessible and expressive.

A commitment to implementing a `reorg_chain` command reflects an ongoing effort to enhance blockchain technology functionality, addressing community feedback and needs. This method preserves the original block of funding transactions, unlike resetting the chain, ensuring testing environment reliability and uninterrupted contract functionality in complex scenarios such as lightning networks.

The integration of DSL with advancements in contract definitions aids in achieving objectives in advanced scripting and transaction graphs, though the statefulness aspect requires further exploration. A forthcoming Jupyter notebook for DSL script construction and execution indicates a move towards interactive programming environments. Queries about engagement with BitVM contributors and technical specifics highlight the importance of these elements in sophisticated integration between DSL and BitVM.

BitVM's invitation for collaboration aims to enhance outcomes through partnerships within the programming community, as illustrated at [BitVM](https://bitvm.org/treeplusplus). The development of `features.py` using DSL tests the language's expressiveness, aiming for better developer communication and rapid prototyping. The concept of `reorg_chain` suggests flexibility in managing chain reorganizations. Recommendations include rewriting the `feature_block.py` script in the Bitcoin repository ([Bitcoin GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/61de64df6790077857faba84796bb874b59c5d15/test/functional/feature_block.py)) using DSL to facilitate easier adaptation of tests across different node implementations.

The DSL under development simplifies bitcoin contract handling with a high-level descriptive syntax, automating the creation of locking and unlocking scripts and managing witness programs. It supports executing multiple contract branches based on system state transitions, streamlining interaction with bitcoin nodes and incorporating taproot constructions. Documentation and examples are available at [the documentation site](https://opdup.com/bitcoin-dsl/index.html) and [the repository](https://github.com/pool2win/bitcoin-dsl), showcasing the DSL's applications in creating and executing bitcoin contracts.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-09T22:47:42.178000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
