<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-03-04T02:04:35.004773+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget 2024-03-03 02:22:15.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-02-29 19:29:30.553000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-21 04:47:51.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic  . 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1770_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1740_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1649_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T02:04:35.004858+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around implementing a transaction expiration mechanism within blockchain networks delves into various complexities and potential ramifications. Such a feature introduces a layer of uncertainty regarding the finality of transactions, as it might incentivize miners to reorganize the blockchain to exclude blocks containing transactions on the verge of expiration. This could undermine the network's stability and open avenues for bandwidth-wasting attacks by cluttering the network with low-priority transactions. A proposed solution involves creating conflicting transactions that are time-locked until the original transaction's expiration, offering a higher fee to ensure miners prioritize them once the time lock expires. This aligns with miners' incentive structures without disrupting network efficiency.

Concerns extend to the possibility of unintentionally benefiting currency holders through the censorship of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), leading to their expiration and consequent unavailability. This scenario could inadvertently increase the value of remaining coins. Additionally, there's apprehension about users mistakenly applying constraints on confirmed outputs, rendering them unspendable due to inactivity before their expiration. However, when dealing with Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) specifically tailored for asset swaps, these issues are mitigated. PSBTs are designed to ensure that the output meant for the creator remains spendable, thus safeguarding against loss due to transaction expiration or accidental constraints.

The conversation also explores the implications of transitioning PSBTs from an off-chain to an on-chain framework, especially concerning Miner Extractable Value (MEV) dynamics. The current off-chain resolution of MEV issues may shift significantly with an on-chain approach, requiring a careful examination of how CheckSequenceVerify (CSV) and CheckMultiTimeVerify (CMTV) mechanisms would operate in this new context. There's a nuanced debate over using block height versus block time as a metric for transaction expiration, with a consensus leaning towards block height due to concerns over miners' potential manipulation of block time. Despite these challenges, the introduction of an op code for transaction expiration is argued to potentially balance economic incentives across the network, especially if both high fee rate transactions with expiration times and those with lock times coexist in the mempool.

The email references the [OP_EXPIRE post](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2023-October/022042.html) as a foundational resource for understanding the merits and considerations of adding an expiratory mechanism to Bitcoin transactions. This adds another dimension to the dialogue, emphasizing the exploration of innovations within the Bitcoin protocol that could enhance its functionality and address emerging needs.

Lastly, the proposal for a new opcode aimed at making peer-to-peer asset swaps more efficient underscores a broader objective of reducing reliance on centralized marketplaces and fostering decentralization. An early draft BIP proposes enabling transactions to become invalid beyond a specified block height or time, addressing economic inefficiencies of unconfirmed transactions and potentially competitive block space between asset swap transactions and traditional Bitcoin transactions. Feedback from the broader community is sought to refine the concept and ensure its practicality and effectiveness in promoting a more decentralized ecosystem and mitigating centralization pressures.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-03T02:22:15.038000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
