<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
  <updated>2024-03-15T01:53:36.256960+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-03-14 13:00:12.989000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-13 13:55:05.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-12 23:45:54.753000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-03-12 20:09:36.208000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-03-03 02:22:15.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-02-29 19:29:30.553000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-21 04:47:51.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>orkunkilic  . 2024-02-20 12:12:48.309000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-20 02:12:32.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-02-19 19:39:00.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EvanWinget  . 2024-02-18 02:35:08.738000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1887_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1871_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1866_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1863_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1770_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1740_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1649_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1644_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1622_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1619_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1596_Op-checkmaxtimeverify.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_checkmaxtimeverify</title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T01:53:36.257046+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkmaxtimeverify/581/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The introduction of `OP_EXPIRE` marks a significant advancement in blockchain technology, specifically enhancing decentralized exchange functionalities as demonstrated in Chia's [CHIP 14](https://github.com/Chia-Network/chips/blob/ace05086365fd9b5d9c9cb18e93bd2025aae6887/CHIPs/chip-0014.md). This new feature addresses the efficient use of block space and minimizes the accumulation of unspendable outputs by allowing transactions to execute only after all related conditions have expired. It challenges the existing narrative around potential inefficiencies in block space utilization due to high transaction fees.

Despite concerns about incentivizing blockchain reorganizations (reorgs) for economic gain, analyses indicate that the risks are minimal. Peter Todd has proposed higher minimum relay fees for expiring transactions as a method to manage these risks without compromising network integrity. The introduction of expiration mechanisms also raises questions about transaction finality and network stability, suggesting the need for strategies like creating competing transactions with higher fees to maintain efficiency.

The discussion extends to the implications of transaction expiration on the unspent transaction output (UTXO) set, highlighting issues of asset unspendability and the role of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) in mitigating such risks. The potential transition of PSBTs from off-chain to on-chain contexts could impact Miner Extractable Value (MEV) and requires careful consideration of its effects on transaction dynamics and miner behaviors.

Debates on preferring block height over block time for implementing transaction expiration in the Bitcoin protocol underline the complexity of this integration. These discussions provide foundational insights into the intricacies of adding expiration mechanisms to Bitcoin transactions, emphasizing the importance of community feedback in refining proposals aimed at enhancing economic efficiency and decentralization in the cryptographic space. The proposed opcode seeks to improve peer-to-peer asset swaps and reduce reliance on centralized marketplaces, underscoring ongoing efforts to foster a decentralized ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-14T13:00:12.989000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
