<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Payjoin-in-Potentiam: Externally fund an LSP channel open with one transaction</title>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:58:00.872742+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-03-30 00:06:01.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>doglegs 2024-03-29 22:53:14.685000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bitgould 2024-03-29 20:57:53.897000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2092_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2091_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2089_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Payjoin-in-Potentiam: Externally fund an LSP channel open with one transaction</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:58:00.872803+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/payjoin-in-potentiam-externally-fund-an-lsp-channel-open-with-one-transaction/749/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Swap-in-Potentiam protocol offers a streamlined method for transferring funds from the blockchain to the Lightning Network, emphasizing trust minimization and efficiency. This approach circumvents the traditional waiting period required for onchain-to-offchain transactions by employing a novel mechanism where funds sent to a special onchain address can be directly utilized within the Lightning Network post-minimum confirmation depth. The process begins when a user (referred to as Alice) generates a swap-in-potentiam address using BIP32 HD derivation, which is then shared publicly. Another party can then deposit funds into this address, enabling Alice to spend these funds on the Lightning Network immediately after they achieve the required confirmation depth, without additional delays typically associated with moving funds offchain.

Further enhancing this system, the proposal introduces the concept of Payjoin-in-Potentiam. This involves a contract between two parties, Alice and Bob (a potential swap partner or Lightning Service Provider), which facilitates the direct funding of a Lightning channel through a single transaction. Initially, Alice requests a unique swap-in-potentiam address from Bob. Upon receiving funds at this address, Bob can open a Lightning channel on behalf of Alice, eliminating the need for multiple transactions. Notably, this process leverages a payjoin output substitution technique ([BIP 78](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/b3701faef2bdb98a0d7ace4eedbeefa2da4c89ed/bip-0078.mediawikiuser-content-span_idoutputsubstitutionspanPayment_output_substitution)) to ensure that only the final, combined transaction appears on the blockchain, thereby maintaining privacy and reducing blockchain bloat.

The execution of swap-in-potentiam relies on the integrity of the participating Lightning Service Provider (LSP). While the protocol inherently reduces reliance on trust, the introduction of a trustless intermediary could further minimize the need for trust by mediating disputes and facilitating output substitution processes. This would significantly decrease dependency on any single trusted entity, aligning with the decentralized ethos of blockchain technology.

In essence, swap-in-potentiam and its extension through payjoin-in-potentiam represent significant advancements in the realm of cryptocurrency transactions. They offer a more efficient, private, and trust-minimized method for moving funds from the blockchain to the Lightning Network, potentially accelerating the adoption and usability of Lightning Network for various applications.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-30T00:06:01.726000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
