<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Revisiting BIP21</title>
  <updated>2024-03-05T01:52:00.484724+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>john 2024-03-04 22:09:34.206000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-02 10:49:42.050000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-03-01 18:35:38.569000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 18:05:00.158000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-03-01 17:41:34.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 17:30:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 17:22:07.284000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-03-01 17:16:26.045000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 16:03:29.205000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 15:48:10.545000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RubenSomsen  . 2024-03-01 15:29:08.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 14:51:14.800000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-03-01 14:47:51.494000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-03-01 14:35:17.579000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1785_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1765_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1761_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1759_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1758_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1757_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1756_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1755_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1754_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1753_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1752_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1747_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1749_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1748_Revisiting-BIP21.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Revisiting BIP21</title>
    <updated>2024-03-05T01:52:00.484828+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/revisiting-bip21/630/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the potential expansion of Bitcoin Improvement Proposal 21 (BIP21) to include features such as split payments, necessitating wallet adaptations for enhanced transaction capabilities. A new format is suggested, incorporating multiple addresses with specific amounts and labels within a single URI scheme to improve payment flexibility and user experience. This proposal is partly elaborated in [John Zaprite's Tweet](https://x.com/john_zaprite/status/1506112407990677507?s=20).

A novel approach recommends adding an optional dummy value at address ends for backward compatibility, facilitating a smooth transition between old and new formats without affecting existing implementations. This strategy aims to maintain interoperability, minimize QR code clutter, and simplify sender parsing processes.

The conversation also debates two potential new address schemes, emphasizing thorough testing to ensure seamless transitions and ecosystem interoperability. One scheme is preferred over the other due to its lower risk of introducing breaking changes, underscoring the importance of careful testing before adopting new technologies in the Bitcoin network.

Technical aspects of URI parameter parsing, including the need for "=" signs in key/value pairs and spec compliance, are discussed. A backward-compatible adjustment to parameter parsing is proposed, balancing innovation with adherence to standards as seen in the resource [BitcoinQR.dev](https://bitcoinqr.dev/).

There's concern about how modifying BIP21 parameters could affect existing systems, highlighting the need to weigh efficiency gains against potential functionality disruptions. The compatibility of Silent Payment instructions with Lightning Network options is clarified, showcasing the interoperability within Bitcoin's payment infrastructure.

A significant part of the dialogue advocates for refining BIP21 to better support modern transactions, proposing a 'addr' key for self-identifying address types to streamline transaction processing across different formats. It suggests a prioritization mechanism for integrating multiple address formats within the same URI, aiming for clear communication of address priority.

The need for an updated BIP21 framework is underscored, reflecting the deviation from initial specifications that led to privacy issues and unrecognized address types. A simplified solution proposes specifying the desired address type directly within URI parameters to facilitate immediate recognition by wallets, improving transaction efficiency. This approach not only streamlines BIP21 URIs but also anticipates future innovations in address types.

Overall, the discussions aim to enhance BIP21's relevance in the evolving cryptocurrency landscape, focusing on interoperability, privacy, and the usability of bitcoin transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T22:09:34.206000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
