<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Economic-Majority Signaling for OP_CTV Activation</title>
  <updated>2024-03-04T02:06:58.390010+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-03-03 12:01:01.289000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-03-03 11:55:20.499000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2024-03-03 11:52:58.644000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-03-03 11:36:44.222000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1776_Economic-Majority-Signaling-for-OP-CTV-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1775_Economic-Majority-Signaling-for-OP-CTV-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1774_Economic-Majority-Signaling-for-OP-CTV-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1772_Economic-Majority-Signaling-for-OP-CTV-Activation.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Economic-Majority Signaling for OP_CTV Activation</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T02:06:58.390082+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/economic-majority-signaling-for-op-ctv-activation/635/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of Bitcoin's potential protocol upgrade involving `OP_CTV` (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) and its implications for consensus change within the network. The `OP_CTV` opcode is part of a broader conversation about introducing covenant opcodes to Bitcoin, which has sparked a counter-movement advocating for the ossification of Bitcoin's protocol to avoid risks associated with changes. This debate underscores the significance of consensus in the network, highlighting that any modification relies heavily on the economic majority's willingness to either support or block such changes. The concept of an "economic majority" influencing miners through market mechanisms is not new and plays a central role in how Bitcoin undergoes alterations in its consensus rules.

The process of consensus change involves convincing miners to adopt new rules by demonstrating that there is an economic incentive to do so. This can be achieved by users indicating their preference for certain rules through economic actions, such as selling coins on a chain that does not adopt the desired modifications. This economic pressure can coerce miners to mine the chain preferred by the majority, thereby aligning mining activity with the preferences of the coin holders. This mechanism is critical because miners are incentivized to maximize earnings, which are affected by the value of the coins they mine. Since the cost of hashing (mining) is significant, miners will naturally gravitate towards mining activities that promise the best return on investment, taking into account the preferences of the economic majority.

A novel method proposed for signaling support or opposition to `OP_CTV` involves using bets placed on whether the opcode will be activated or not. This method leverages softforks that replace `OP_NOP` opcodes, allowing participants to create transactions that effectively bet on the outcome of `OP_CTV`'s activation. The structure of these bets is designed to reflect the outcome of the activation, with different scenarios laid out for whether `OP_CTV` becomes active or remains non-operative. If `OP_CTV` is activated, participants who bet on its activation can claim their funds; conversely, if `OP_CTV` fails to activate, those betting against it win. This betting mechanism provides a clear signal of the community's preference regarding `OP_CTV`, potentially influencing miners' decisions on which chain to support.

The technique discussed is applicable specifically to opcodes that replace an `OP_NOP` in P2WSH scripts and cannot be directly applied to opcodes replacing an `OP_SUCCESS` in Tapscript due to technical limitations. However, the overall approach offers a generalizable method for gauging and influencing community support for various proposed changes to Bitcoin's protocol, including but not limited to `OP_CTV`. By leveraging economic incentives and market mechanisms, it is possible to navigate the complex landscape of consensus change within decentralized networks like Bitcoin, ensuring that changes reflect the preferences of the majority while minimizing risks associated with protocol modifications.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-03T12:01:01.289000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
