<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
  <updated>2024-03-26T02:03:11.434692+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2024-03-25 08:36:40.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-22 23:41:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:40:39.031000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:38:27.559000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2024-03-21 20:55:55.854000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-21 17:33:00.972000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-21 16:27:09.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2022_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1991_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1989_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1990_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1985_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1982_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1980_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
    <updated>2024-03-26T02:03:11.434759+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-based-fee-estimation-on-bitcoin-core/703/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers around the intricacies of fee estimation within blockchain networks, specifically addressing the challenges that arise in accurately determining transaction fees due to potential manipulation tactics by miners and the dynamic nature of the mempool. One suggested strategy to mitigate the risk of underestimation and overestimation involves implementing a mempool-based estimate using the `CBlockPolicyEstimator` threshold. This proposal aims to enhance the current approach by considering transactions only after they've been broadcasted for a certain period, thereby introducing a potential financial deterrent for attackers engaging in selfish mining variations. The suggestion also contemplates the introduction of a verbose option enabling users to view their node's mempool state, aiding in more informed decision-making during fee bumping processes.

The conversation further explores a sophisticated manipulation technique where miners could artificially inflate fee estimates by withholding large, high-fee transactions from broadcast and subsequently releasing them strategically to deceive other network participants. This tactic underscores the inherent vulnerabilities in fee estimation algorithms, which could either lead to significant overbidding due to manipulative increases or underbidding, potentially causing transactions to remain unmined. The dialog suggests that lowering fee rates based on mempool data may be a safer, user-friendly approach, provided users retain the flexibility to adjust their transaction fees without substantial inconvenience.

Moreover, an alternative method is discussed for improving fee estimation accuracy by combining mempool state information with direct blockchain data. This hybrid approach could offer a more realistic reflection of current network conditions and miner behaviors, hence enhancing the reliability of fee estimations. However, the discussion acknowledges the fluidity within block compositions over time, raising questions about the viability of selecting transactions for inclusion based on percentile rankings and the potential discrepancies between user and miner mempools.

Kalle Alm's research presented at Scaling Bitcoin 2017 is highlighted as a valuable resource for delving deeper into optimizing fee estimation through mempool state analysis. Alm recommends a strategy that involves leveraging both confirmed and mempool estimate data to adjust fee rates efficiently, emphasizing the trade-offs between optimizing fee costs and maintaining transaction privacy. 

Lastly, the email touches upon the technical and operational aspects of implementing mempool-based fee estimation within Bitcoin Core. While acknowledging its potential benefits in adapting to changing network conditions, the discussion also points out the limitations and challenges in ensuring accurate estimations. An experimental RPC offering this feature is under development, aiming to improve alignment with actual block median fee rates, even as ongoing research seeks to refine this method further.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T08:36:40.132000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
