<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Payjoin-in-Potentiam: Externally fund an LSP channel open with one transaction</title>
  <updated>2024-03-31T02:04:57.220345+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2024-03-30 23:42:18.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bitgould 2024-03-30 17:02:46.714000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-03-30 00:06:01.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>doglegs  . 2024-03-29 22:53:14.685000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bitgould  . 2024-03-29 20:57:53.897000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2102_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2098_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2092_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2091_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2089_Payjoin-in-Potentiam-Externally-fund-an-LSP-channel-open-with-one-transaction.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Payjoin-in-Potentiam: Externally fund an LSP channel open with one transaction</title>
    <updated>2024-03-31T02:04:57.220431+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/payjoin-in-potentiam-externally-fund-an-lsp-channel-open-with-one-transaction/749/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussions surrounding cryptocurrency transactions have introduced a novel concept known as swap-in-potentiam. This innovative approach focuses on streamlining the process of transferring funds from the blockchain layer to the Lightning Network layer, prioritizing trust minimization throughout the transaction. The central premise revolves around using public keys known between transacting parties to facilitate transactions without necessitating additional waiting periods for moving funds from onchain to offchain. This mechanism allows for a unique transaction method where a third party can fund a swap-in-potentiam address, inadvertently opening a channel through a modified Spilman channel mechanism. Such transactions are streamlined, requiring only onchain confirmation and eliminating intermediary waiting periods.

A key aspect of this proposal involves incorporating a trustless intermediary to enhance the integrity and reliability of fund transfers. This entity would act as a mediator in disputes and facilitate output substitution processes, reducing dependency on any single trusted party. This approach aims to secure interactions between involved parties and preserve the integrity of fund transfers across layers.

The Swap-in-Potentiam protocol, proposed by Jesse Posner and ZmnSCPxj, is structured to facilitate swift transitions of funds from an onchain address to the Lightning Network while minimizing trust. It features a contractual agreement with two branches: one dedicated to onchain or channel transactions and another equipped with a time lock for Alice. This setup is particularly beneficial for mobile wallet users, offering a seamless transition without the delays associated with additional confirmations.

One of the significant innovations within this framework is the incorporation of Payjoin. This method allows external funds to directly fund a channel opening from the LSP without posting a swap output address on the blockchain. By substituting the payjoin output in the first transaction that funds a swap address, the combined result is visible on the blockchain, enhancing privacy. Through Payjoin-in-Potentiam, the commitment transaction to the LSP's Swap-in-Potentiam address is initially prepared. However, before broadcasting, the funder sends it as a PSBT to the LSP, which then substitutes the original PSBT's Swap-in-Potentiam address with a channel opening address in a new PSBT. This system aligns closely with the Lightning Payjoin concept but distinguishes itself by involving the LSP in facilitating the channel opening. The sequence diagrams provided offer a detailed illustration of the transaction flow, highlighting the importance of timely communication to ensure the success of this innovative single transaction approach.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-30T23:42:18.063000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
