<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
  <updated>2025-08-02T03:00:18.334535+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>danielabrozzoni</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-01T10:41:24.862000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fingerprinting nodes via addr requests</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T03:00:18.334567+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fingerprinting-nodes-via-addr-requests/1786/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of removing timestamps from certain network operations to enhance privacy and security within a network. The primary focus is on addressing the potential for fingerprinting vulnerabilities by altering how timestamps are managed in network communications. Several strategies have been proposed to mitigate these risks, each with its own set of considerations.

One approach under consideration involves changing the way `nTime` is utilized within addrman, suggesting a move away from using timestamps as a metric to judge the quality or reliability of an address. This idea stems from the broader goal of refining metrics in light of solutions that aim to minimize the relevance of `nTime`, thereby necessitating a search for more effective alternatives.

Another significant point of strategy pertains to the restructuring of the `ADDR` message format to potentially exclude the `nTime` field. This proposal acknowledges the technical challenges and limited benefits associated with redesigning message formats, especially for `GETADDR` responses, which would require substantial effort for minimal gain. This underscores a preference for simpler, more efficient solutions to the fingerprinting issue without overhauling existing protocols.

Furthermore, the conversation explores various methods to randomize or alter the `nTime` value in `GETADDR` responses to prevent any linkage with the internal timestamps used by addrman. Proposed solutions include: randomizing `nTime` by a few days, setting `nTime` to zero (with nodes backdating the timestamp upon receipt), assigning a randomized but fixed past value to `nTime`, and updating `nTime` to reflect the current time (`now()`) at the request moment. Each of these options aims to obscure the original timestamp data, thereby reducing the risk of network activity being traceable or fingerprintable.

However, concerns have been raised about the potential for synchronized patterns in address management, particularly regarding how batches of addresses might be simultaneously deemed 'Terrible' and filtered out, posing a risk to network diversity and integrity. This highlights the need for careful consideration of how timestamp adjustments could impact broader network dynamics and the effectiveness of anti-fingerprinting measures.

In conclusion, while there is a clear intent to modify the handling of timestamps to enhance network security and privacy, the dialogue emphasizes a cautious approach. It seeks to balance the benefits of such modifications against the practical challenges and potential unintended consequences, aiming for solutions that offer substantive improvements without compromising the network's functionality or resilience.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-01T10:41:24.862000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
