<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-03T03:13:12.788750+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-02T19:24:55.469000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-03T03:13:12.788785+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The topic of non-standard transactions in the context of Bitcoin and their potential evolution into standard transactions raises significant questions within the cryptocurrency community. This issue touches upon the flexibility of network rules, particularly regarding transaction standardness and the implications of miners' practices on these rules. The discussion highlights a scenario where miners could potentially alter the landscape of Bitcoin transactions by choosing to confirm free transactions or using future Segwit versions for inserting random data into blocks, allowing for transactions up to 4 MB. Such practices challenge the existing limitations and bring to light the dynamic nature of what constitutes a "standard" transaction.

The debate extends to the consideration of whether rules governing the standardness of transactions should be reevaluated or even discarded in light of these potential changes. The inherent question revolves around the adaptability of the network to new miner behaviors and the possible outcomes of such an adaptation. It suggests a scenario where, through collective action or consensus among a significant portion of miners, previously non-standard transactions could gain acceptance and become part of the norm, thereby shifting the boundaries of what is considered standard in the Bitcoin network.

This discourse was notably addressed during discussions on IRC, as indicated by the provided [link](https://bitcoin-irc.chaincode.com/bitcoin-core-dev/2025-05-221123266;), yet it appears that a definitive answer or consensus on how to approach these evolving dynamics remains elusive. Additionally, the mention of specific [non-standard transactions](https://mempool.space/tx/bb41a757f405890fb0f5856228e23b715702d714d59bf2b1feb70d8b2b4e3e08) that are time-consuming to validate adds a practical dimension to the theoretical considerations, underscoring the real-world implications of such transactions on the network's operation and the broader cryptocurrency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-02T19:24:55.469000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
