<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T03:08:20.669019+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-04T11:24:34.635000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T03:08:20.669052+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a specific aspect of the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal 68 ([BIP68](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/31450c3dbde336cd8503197d78e06ece46c28d7a/bip-0068.mediawiki)), which introduced relative lock-time using nSequence. The suggestion is to expand the current mask used in BIP68 from `0x0000ffff` to `0x0001ffff` by including an additional bit, specifically bit 16. This change proposes a method for enhancing the functionality of the protocol, allowing for more nuanced control over transaction lock times. 

The primary advantage of this modification would be to introduce a soft fork, enabling new features while maintaining backward compatibility with older software versions. Older software versions would interpret transactions with the 16th bit set as being spendable earlier than they are under the proposed new rules. However, there's a significant caveat to consider: if bit 16 were accidentally set by a user, it could lead to an unexpected and potentially problematic delay. Specifically, transactions could be locked for a decade longer than the user intended, leading to funds being inaccessible for that period. 

This proposal underscores the delicate balance between advancing blockchain technology and ensuring user safety and accessibility. It highlights the need for careful consideration and robust debate within the development community before implementing changes that could have far-reaching implications.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-04T11:24:34.635000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
