<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T03:09:11.874029+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-04T17:09:18.310000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T03:09:11.874064+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the implications of miners starting to confirm free transactions and the potential for future Segwit versions to allow for random data pushes, extending up to 4 MB per transaction. This raises questions about the abandonment of standardness rules, suggesting that any existing limit could effectively be bypassed. The topic touches on the possibility of [non-standard transactions](https://mempool.space/tx/bb41a757f405890fb0f5856228e23b715702d714d59bf2b1feb70d8b2b4e3e08), which are typically slow to validate, gaining acceptance as standard if a certain percentage of miners begin to include them in blocks.

The conversation further explores the idea that if current policy rules are overly strict to the point of preventing nodes from being aware of transactions likely to be mined, there should be an adjustment to make these rules as lenient as necessary. This approach aims at balancing the need to protect against denial-of-service attacks while ensuring that valid transactions do not get unnecessarily blocked.

However, there is skepticism regarding the feasibility of imposing new requirements on signing devices due to the significant work requirement needed for such measures to be effective. The dialogue suggests a critical examination of policy adjustments, weighing the need for security against the benefits of increased flexibility in transaction handling.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:09:18.310000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
