<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T03:10:26.807289+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-05T03:36:29.160000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T03:10:26.807322+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The integration of Proof of Work (PoW) with existing Script, excluding TapScript, introduces a novel approach to enhancing the security and functionality of Bitcoin transactions, particularly for second-layer solutions such as Lightning Network (LN) transactions or sidechains. The use of PoW allows for an optional layer of security that can be applied selectively by users, utilizing `OP_IF`, `OP_ELSE`, and `OP_ENDIF` for conditional execution. This feature is not merely theoretical but has already been implemented in a form of a faucet that rewards puzzle solvers with satoshis, as detailed in a forum post on [BitcoinTalk](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5551080.0).

This mechanism permits multiple users to work collaboratively on the same transaction, where ultimately, a single user broadcasts the solution. This collaborative effort ensures that if the majority of second-layer miners are honest and possess more computing power than potential attackers, the security of these transactions is significantly bolstered. The primary aim here is to accumulate enough PoW to ensure a transaction is included in the next block. Given the computational effort required for PoW, if a transaction achieves confirmation within the typical ten-minute block time, the likelihood of successful double-spending attacks is drastically reduced. This applies even to potentially vulnerable scenarios like outdated state broadcasts in LN channels.

The system offers a dual approach to combat spam and enhance transaction integrity: traditional transaction fees and the innovative option of PoW. Users have the flexibility to choose between spending more coins through fees or dedicating computational resources to PoW. The openness to allowing free transactions, provided they meet stringent PoW requirements, underscores a significant shift towards prioritizing robust security measures over financial barriers, ensuring the network's resilience against abuse while fostering greater inclusivity.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T03:36:29.160000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
