<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T03:06:22.311040+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C.849000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-05T15:27:54.849000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T03:06:22.311080+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/35" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>David Gumberg's contributions to the project have been acknowledged, highlighting their significance without delving into specifics. An update on transaction reconstructions over recent months has been shared, including statistical data linked to discussions on GitHub. Specifically, a link to a GitHub issue comment ([GitHub Comment](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106issuecomment-3155627414)) provides detailed insights, alongside visual representations of the data discussed, though the images are mentioned without direct inclusion in the summary.

The evolution of transaction request sizes since the implementation of logging in a previous update ([GitHub Pull Request](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32582)) is examined. Initially, in early June, the average size of requested transactions per block per day was less than 10kB for approximately 40-50% of blocks where a request was necessary. As of the current status, there has been a significant increase, with an average request size close to 800kB for 70% of the blocks, indicating that 30% of the blocks no longer require requests. This substantial growth in the average transaction request size indicates an evolving demand and workload associated with processing Bitcoin transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:27:54.849000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
