<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-08-08T03:06:14.545892+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>pyth.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-07T06:54:43.188000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-08T03:06:14.545933+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing project focuses on a Rust implementation that expands the capabilities of encrypted backups, as outlined by conversations and suggestions within a specific GitHub thread ([view thread](https://github.com/pythcoiner/encrypted_backup)). This development is part of an effort to enhance security and functionality in data encryption processes. The initiative is documented through a draft specification available for public viewing on GitHub ([see draft spec](https://github.com/pythcoiner/encrypted_backup/blob/6c165bc871c81e8dd1abde7fc20f16989f608ca3/BIP.mediawiki)). This document outlines a comprehensive approach to encrypting a wider range of content while integrating several critical metadata into the encrypted payload.

The proposed specification introduces several key enhancements to the encrypted backup scheme. It specifies the inclusion of a version identifier for the encryption schema, ensuring that the encryption process remains up-to-date with the latest security standards. Additionally, it allows for the optional listing of derivation paths, enhancing the flexibility and control users have over their encryption keys and how they are managed or derived. The type of content being encrypted is clearly defined, providing clarity on what can be securely backed up using this method. 

An important aspect of the specification is the detailed description of the encryption protocol employed, which in this case is AES-GCM. This choice underlines the commitment to utilizing robust and widely recognized encryption standards. Furthermore, the use of a nonce in the AES-GCM encryption process is specified, which is crucial for maintaining the integrity and security of the encrypted data by ensuring that each encryption instance is unique.

This endeavor represents a significant step forward in the realm of encrypted backups. By broadening the scope of encryptable content and incorporating essential metadata, the project aims to provide a more versatile and secure framework for data encryption. The involvement of the community and the open-source nature of the project encourage collaboration and continuous improvement, making it a noteworthy contribution to the field of cybersecurity and data protection.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-07T06:54:43.188000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
