<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-09T02:53:04.566068+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-08T19:49:40.980000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T02:53:04.566101+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a formula for calculating work, represented as $W = \text{S} \times \frac{2^{256}}{T}$, which is applicable when analyzing blockchain activities, specifically within the context of Proof of Work (PoW) systems. This equation necessitates retaining a significant number of block headers, referred to as 'S', to stay within the standard deviation error range. This retention is crucial for ensuring accuracy in the calculation, highlighting the importance of recent blocks in this dataset.

Further exploration into the matter reveals that if the target difficulty remains constant, the formula simplifies to resemble the conventional work calculation method, where 'S' equates to the total number of blocks 'b', and the variance inversely correlates with the square root of 'S'. This insight underscores the intrinsic relationship between block count and variance in the context of work calculation.

Moreover, the dialogue touches upon Proofs of Proof-of-Work (PoPoW) schemes, noting their tendency to adjust the quantity of retained low-hash headers in proportion to the logarithm of the blockchain height. This adjustment suggests a scalability mechanism within PoPoW protocols to manage header storage efficiently as the chain grows. Additionally, it's pointed out that the selection of blocks for analysis should be driven by an initial interest in examining the hashrate over a predetermined time period, thereby necessitating the selection of this interval prior to determining the specific values for 'T' and 'S'. This approach aims to mitigate selection bias and implies that despite the apparent complexity introduced by varying difficulty levels, the process closely mirrors traditional chain work summation practices, assuming relatively stable difficulty conditions.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-08T19:49:40.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
