<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-10T03:08:12.502514+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-09T13:28:09.403000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T03:08:12.502544+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the variance of a specific mathematical expression, highlighting its approximation under certain conditions. The core assertion presented is that the variance, denoted as $\mathrm{Var}[\frac{k-1}{H_{(k)}}]$, closely approximates to $\frac{n^2}{k-2}$ when the value of $k$ is predetermined before conducting an experiment. This relationship suggests a significant insight into how the variance behaves based on the values of $n$ and $k$. However, the certainty of this approximation raises questions when the variable $k$ is influenced by the outcomes of the experiment itself, particularly in scenarios utilizing the "use largest-hash block among those beating the lowest target" strategy.

This nuance introduces a layer of complexity in understanding the behavior of the variance as it possibly alters when $k$ is not fixed but rather determined by experimental results. Such a condition could imply that the initial approximation might not hold true or requires further investigation to ascertain its validity under these new circumstances. The distinction between a fixed $k$ prior to the experiment and a variable $k$ contingent on experimental results illuminates the intricate dynamics at play in calculating and predicting variance in this context.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T13:28:09.403000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
