<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-10T03:07:39.033612+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-09 19:54:27.552000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T03:07:39.033649+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the mathematical adjustments required when transitioning between models that handle event occurrences differently, specifically within the realms of statistics and probability theory. When dealing with fixed blocks or intervals, different statistical distributions are preferable to accurately model the expected outcomes.

For situations characterized by fixed blocks, such as specific quantities or counts, the Beta distribution is typically employed. However, when adapting a model built on the Poisson distribution, which is ideal for events occurring in fixed time intervals, to accommodate fixed block scenarios, certain corrections are necessary. These modifications ensure the model remains accurate despite the change in underlying assumptions about how data is distributed or events occur.

The proposed adjustment involves applying a correction factor to the Poisson equations to make them suitable for fixed-block contexts. This entails modifying the expected value and variance formulas to account for the fixed-block nature of the data. Specifically, the expected bandwidth (E[bw]) and its variance (Var[bw]) are recalculated using the provided formulas, where \(n\) represents the average rate of occurrence, and \(b\) signifies the number of blocks or intervals considered. The adjustment effectively aligns the Poisson-based model more closely with what would be achieved using the Erlang (or Gamma) distribution, which is another approach for handling events distributed across fixed blocks.

Moreover, when the context shifts from fixed blocks to fixed time intervals, the recommendation is to substitute the Beta distribution with the Binomial distribution in analyses initially based on the Poisson framework. This substitution accounts for the differences in how these distributions manage the probabilities of occurrences over their respective domains—fixed quantities versus fixed durations.

In essence, this guidance bridges the methodological gap between employing statistical distributions for different types of data occurrences—quantitative blocks versus temporal intervals. By applying these corrections, one can transition between using the Poisson distribution for time-based events and other distributions better suited for count-based or blocked events without losing analytical integrity.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T19:54:27.552000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
