<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>RGB yellow paper: the formal specification of Bitcoin &amp; Lightning smart contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-08-10T03:09:13.197206+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VigSeth.971000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-09T14:59:34.971000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>RGB yellow paper: the formal specification of Bitcoin &amp; Lightning smart contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T03:09:13.197238+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/rgb-yellow-paper-the-formal-specification-of-bitcoin-lightning-smart-contracts/1885/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email to Dr. Orlovsky hails the comprehensive nature of the RGB yellow paper and queries about the future steps for its implementation and widespread adoption. The sender suggests that the development of a suite of tools, or "Toolboxes," is essential for writing, editing, debugging, and deploying RGB-compatible smart contracts, as well as for secure interaction with them. 

The conversation further delves into potential groundbreaking applications for RGB-smart contracts. It highlights their use in securing complex multiparty agreements among various stakeholders such as hardware and software product vendors, infrastructure operators (like DePINs), end-users, and in managing the Digital Twins of software-intensive hardware assets. These assets include mobile devices, wearable computers, automobile parts, and avionics components. The sender believes these smart contracts could be particularly effective when deployed on high-performance blockchains like OpBNB, TON, and more efficient versions of Liquid.

Moreover, the sender expresses a keen interest in collaborating with Dr. Orlovsky to explore these opportunities further, indicating a desire to contribute to the development and application of RGB-smart contracts in the specified areas.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T14:59:34.971000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
