<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-08-13T02:52:08.043513+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>pyth.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-12T03:35:40.352000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Exploring Extended Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T02:52:08.043551+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/exploring-extended-relative-timelocks/1818/25" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In analyzing the usage of nSequence on blockchain transactions, a specific tool, [nsequence_runner](https://github.com/pythcoiner/nsequence_runner), was employed to examine its application across various cases. The examination revealed that every bit within nSequence has been utilized at least once, indicating a wide range of uses and interpretations in blockchain operations. Particularly, a unique combination was noted where bit 31 equals 0, bit 22 equals 0, bit 21 equals 1, and the lower 16 bits of nSequence are greater than 0. Additionally, this combination is specifically observed when the spending script includes an OP_CSV operation, with the analysis limited to segwitv0 and taproot scripts.

This observation underscores the complexity and versatility of nSequence in transaction scripting, highlighting its potential for various functionalities beyond simple time-locking mechanisms. However, the implications of these findings remain open to interpretation, as there is no consensus on how these particular usages should be understood within the broader context of blockchain technology and transaction management. The diverse application of nSequence bits, especially in conjunction with specific script operations, suggests a need for further exploration and possibly a reevaluation of existing assumptions about transaction dynamics on the blockchain.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T03:35:40.352000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
