<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-13T02:53:45.069411+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow.384000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-12T13:56:31.384000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T02:53:45.069444+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin Core incorporates several hardcoded elements that are periodically updated every 6 to 12 months, reflecting real-world values and technological advancements. These updates are essential for maintaining the software's relevance and efficiency in processing transactions. Among these hardcoded features, the headers sync parameters are particularly noteworthy. They are based on the processing capabilities of modern CPUs, specifically the hashing speed of a Ryzen 5950X CPU thread. This metric is crucial for ensuring that Bitcoin Core can efficiently handle the synchronization of block headers, a task central to its operation.

Additionally, the software utilizes fallback fixed seeds, which serve as a static snapshot of the current nodes on the network. Given the dynamic nature of the Bitcoin network, where nodes frequently join or leave, these fixed seeds represent a temporary solution to maintain network connectivity and resilience. However, such hardcoded values also pose challenges due to their ephemeral nature and the gradual changes in network size, computation, and bandwidth costs. The proposal to keep these values within an order of magnitude of back-of-the-envelope calculations suggests a pragmatic approach to balancing accuracy with the need for periodic updates.

Moreover, the discussion extends into the realm of network policies, particularly concerning compact block reconstruction rates. An identified discrepancy in policy strictness between network participants and miners highlights the necessity for more regular reviews and updates. The suggestion to revisit certain policies more frequently than once every decade underscores the importance of adaptability in network management practices. Such adaptations are vital for addressing inefficiencies and ensuring the Bitcoin network remains robust and responsive to evolving technological landscapes and economic realities.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T13:56:31.384000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
