<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-15T02:54:37.369866+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-08-14 11:23:54.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T02:54:37.369898+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/28" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry raises a significant point about the methodology used in analyzing blockchain data, specifically focusing on the implications of selecting a fixed number of blocks, for instance, five blocks, within a predetermined time interval for hash rate estimations. This approach could potentially skew the data analysis, given that the actual number of blocks discovered within any given time frame can fluctuate due to various factors such as changes in mining difficulty and hashrate variability.

The sender underscores an alternative method where, rather than fixating on a specific number of blocks, the calculation considers all possible outcomes observed within the window. By employing the formula `sum(block.work for block in window) / window.duration`, it's suggested that one can attain an unbiased estimate of the average hashrate throughout the duration of the window. This method accommodates variations in both the hashrate and the mining difficulty during the specified timeframe, offering a potentially more accurate reflection of network activity without necessitating additional corrective measures.

This perspective invites a reconsideration of conventional practices in blockchain data analysis, advocating for a more dynamic and comprehensive approach. It challenges the prevailing methodologies by highlighting the limitations inherent in restricting analyses to a fixed number of blocks and suggests a shift towards incorporating the full spectrum of observed data to enhance the accuracy of hashrate estimations.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-14T11:23:54.178000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
