<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-15T02:55:49.995504+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-08-14 22:46:08.656000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T02:55:49.995535+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The analysis of the inter-release USD/BTC changes provides a method for estimating the network relay cost in recent Bitcoin Core releases. By dividing 3,600 by the USD/BTC conversion rate, one can determine the approximate cost of relaying transactions on the network. This calculation is significant in understanding the financial dynamics of maintaining robustness against denial-of-service (DoS) attacks within the Bitcoin peer-to-peer network.

The discussion further delves into the philosophy of adjusting policy defaults based on the fluctuating price of Bitcoin in USD terms. There's an agreement with Matt Corallo's stance, expressed through a [tweet](https://x.com/TheBlueMatt/status/1953115648101613619), that the cost to launch an attack on the network should incrementally rise over time. This approach is deemed necessary to preserve the network's integrity and resilience against potential threats.

Moreover, the economic context surrounding Bitcoin and the broader monetary system is highlighted, noting the devaluation of the USD and the substantial increase in average salaries over the past decade, as shown in the provided links ([USD devaluation](https://i.ibb.co/4wzZdyNY/fredgraph.png) and [average salaries increase](https://i.ibb.co/nspxp4pd/LT-Wages.png)). These economic shifts underscore the argument that adjustments in the Bitcoin network's defensive mechanisms cannot solely rely on traditional financial metrics or trends due to their inherent volatility and the unique nature of digital currencies. The implication is that adversaries targeting networks like Bitcoin might not be deterred by rising costs, suggesting a need for a more nuanced approach to security and policy adjustments within the cryptocurrency space.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-14T22:46:08.656000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
