<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>New paper on Proof of Usable Work</title>
  <updated>2025-08-16T02:47:23.911524+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VigSeth.643000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-15T17:12:45.643000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>New paper on Proof of Usable Work</title>
    <updated>2025-08-16T02:47:23.911557+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/new-paper-on-proof-of-usable-work/1867/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed collaboration aims to develop a new high-performance Layer 1 (L1) protocol that leverages Proof of Useful Work (PoUW) consensus mechanism, focusing on arbitrary matrix multiplication. This innovative approach is designed to enable the power of distributed digital twin replication, diagnostics, and repair technologies across significant industries including automobile, aerospace, and consumer electronics. The objective is to achieve an initial transaction throughput of over 1000 transactions per second (TPS), which underscores the project's ambition for high scalability and performance.

The initiative to create the "Twinstor Blockchain" is positioned as not only a more profitable venture but also a highly practical tool for industry applications, surpassing the current trends of mass AI inference using large language models (LLMs). The emphasis is on creating a tangible and impactful use case that serves multiple sectors by providing a robust infrastructure for digital twin technologies. 

A domain has already been secured for this project under the name twinstor.xyz, indicating the project's readiness for further development and collaboration. Stakeholders and potential collaborators are encouraged to engage with the project, bringing their insights and suggestions to help shape the future of Twinstor Blockchain. To facilitate deeper understanding and foster collaboration, a whitepaper has been made available for download at [https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xqfk99fbXz5ZSGiVSHeVhJi1bEUgCWuU/view?usp=sharing](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xqfk99fbXz5ZSGiVSHeVhJi1bEUgCWuU/view?usp=sharing), providing comprehensive details about the project's vision, technical framework, and implementation strategy.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T17:12:45.643000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
