<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-16T02:46:16.030322+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-15 14:00:40.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-16T02:46:16.030359+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745/32" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email outlines a sophisticated method for estimating the hashrate of a computing process over a small fixed time period, using mathematical formulas and statistical concepts. The approach is based on observing the lowest hash seen during the time interval and employing this data to calculate work done (W) in relation to the total possible outcomes in the hashing space (2^256). By defining the exponential cumulative distribution function (CDF) of the observed lowest hash, an error signal can be derived which indicates the accuracy of previous work estimates. This error signal is then utilized within an Exponential Moving Average (EMA) equation to adjust future work estimates, thus refining the hashrate estimation over time.

The formula incorporates several key variables: \(L\) represents the lowest hash observed in the time period, \(W\) denotes the work done, and \(\lambda\) is the rate at which hashes are found. The error signal (\(E\)) is calculated from the CDF of \(L\), measuring the deviation from the median expectation, which is essential for adjusting the EMA of work done across measured intervals. The standard deviation is approximated to assess the variability of work estimates, contributing to understanding the precision of the hashrate estimate.

Furthermore, the methodology includes a mechanism for calculating the initial value needed for the EMA calculation, suggesting a startup phase where work is summed over a specific set of preceding intervals to establish a baseline work estimate. This initial estimate is crucial for beginning the iterative process of refining the hashrate estimate through the EMA formula. 

Additionally, the text hints at the practical challenges of implementing such a difficulty adjustment algorithm securely due to the dynamic nature of hashrates and the complexity of accurately measuring work done within these small intervals. The underlying principle of this method is to achieve a balance between the stability and responsiveness of the hashrate estimate by carefully choosing the "mean lifetime" (N) of the EMA estimate, which directly influences how quickly the estimate adapts to changes in actual work done.

In summary, this complex estimation method offers a potentially more accurate way to determine the hashrate over short periods by dynamically adjusting based on the observed lowest hash and correcting for any errors in prior estimates. This approach, while theoretically sound, underscores the intricate relationship between statistical analysis and practical implementation challenges in cryptocurrency mining and other similar computational processes.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:00:40.923000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
