<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Confidential Script: Emulate soft forks using stateless TEEs</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:34:51.910711+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin.348000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-18T02:45:37.348000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Confidential Script: Emulate soft forks using stateless TEEs</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:34:51.910741+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/confidential-script-emulate-soft-forks-using-stateless-tees/1918/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The provided information introduces two significant resources related to advancements in blockchain technology and smart contracts. The first resource is a comprehensive guide to the CTV emulator, available at [https://learn.sapio-lang.org/ch05-01-ctv-emulator.html](https://learn.sapio-lang.org/ch05-01-ctv-emulator.html). This emulator is a crucial tool for developers working with blockchain technology, offering a practical way to test and refine smart contracts before deploying them on the blockchain. It represents an important step forward in smart contract development, providing a sandbox environment where developers can experiment with and validate their contracts.

The second resource is a scholarly paper that presents a generalized formalism for covenant-oracle with script as key tweak paradigm, accessible at [https://rubin.io/public/pdfs/unfedcovenants.pdf](https://rubin.io/public/pdfs/unfedcovenants.pdf). This document delves into the theoretical underpinnings of smart contracts, specifically focusing on the covenant-oracle model. It outlines a sophisticated framework that extends beyond conventional implementations, offering insights into how integrity checks can be effectively implemented using BitVM. This work not only adheres closely to established formalisms but also expands upon them by introducing novel approaches to ensuring smart contract integrity. 

Together, these resources provide a deep dive into current innovations within the realm of blockchain technology and smart contracts. They offer both practical tools and theoretical knowledge necessary for advancing the field, catering to developers seeking to leverage blockchain technology to its fullest potential. Through the combination of the CTV emulator's practical applications and the theoretical frameworks discussed in the scholarly paper, readers gain access to a comprehensive suite of tools and knowledge designed to enhance the development, security, and reliability of smart contracts.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-18T02:45:37.348000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
