<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Selfish mining fix with a simulation</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:35:48.406224+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-18T14:01:55.850000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Selfish mining fix with a simulation</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:35:48.406256+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/selfish-mining-fix-with-a-simulation/1934" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The document provided offers a detailed evaluation of a solution proposed to address a specific vulnerability in cryptocurrency mining algorithms. The analysis was conducted by an individual named Grok, who performed simulations to assess the impact of the proposed fix on an attacker's profit margins when controlling a significant portion of the network's hashrate.

The core of Grok's findings revolves around a simulation that demonstrates the economic outcome for an attacker possessing 40% of the network's hashrate under the new algorithm adjustments. Prior to these adjustments, an attacker with such control could expect a 15% gain from their efforts. However, post-adjustment, the same attacker would instead face a 16% loss, essentially nullifying the profitability of the attack. This dramatic shift from profit to loss signifies a substantial improvement in the security and fairness of the mining process, as it disincentivizes the accumulation and misuse of disproportionate computational power.

The evaluation is encapsulated in a comprehensive report accessible through a link to a GitHub issue page. This documentation not only provides insights into the technical aspects and outcomes of the simulation but also serves as a valuable resource for further research and discussion within the community. It underscores the importance of continuous scrutiny and adaptation of cryptocurrency algorithms to combat vulnerabilities and ensure the stability and integrity of the network.

In essence, the document highlights a significant stride towards enhancing the security measures against potential attacks on cryptocurrency networks. By making such attacks economically unviable, the proposed fix contributes to the ongoing efforts to safeguard the decentralized nature of these digital assets, ensuring a fairer and more secure ecosystem for participants.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-18T14:01:55.850000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
