<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:34:09.440678+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>hodlinator 2025-08-19 20:19:33.462000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:34:09.440711+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the efficiency of propagating Proof of Work (PoW) block templates among nodes within a blockchain network. The primary focus is on whether sharing a PoW block template in advance by the originating node with its direct peers can enhance the reconciliation rate of compact blocks throughout the network. This approach suggests a potential for increased efficiency among directly connected peers, as they would be able to prepare and reconcile incoming blocks more swiftly due to having access to the template ahead of time.

However, the conversation also brings up questions regarding the impact of such a strategy on indirect peers—those not directly connected to the originating node. There's an underlying inquiry about whether these indirect peers would benefit from this method, considering they might not have the same immediate access to the block template shared ahead of time. It raises the point that indirect peers likely wouldn't be forwarding templates they've received, questioning if this action is even considered within the proposed design. Essentially, the dialogue seeks to understand the broader implications of pre-sharing block templates on the network's overall efficiency, particularly how it affects nodes that are not in direct communication with the block originator.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-19T20:19:33.462000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
