<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:33:59.974266+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-19T20:45:19.700000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:33:59.974297+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In discussing the dynamics of network policies and their alignment with miner activities, it becomes evident that the landscape is quite diverse. At one end of the spectrum, there's a scenario where almost every participant, including miners, adheres to a uniform policy. Conversely, there exists a situation where participants follow a similar policy, albeit miners operate under a different set of rules. Between these two extremes lies a complex intermediate state characterized by a variety of policies coexisting within the network. Among these, one particular policy closely mirrors that of the miners. This policy is not only widely adopted by a significant portion of the network but also ensures that many participants are in direct connection with peers who share the miners' policy preferences.

This intermediate scenario, marked by its nuanced policy alignment between regular network participants and miners, holds substantial benefits. It represents a balanced ecosystem where diversity in policy does not hinder operational harmony but rather supports a more resilient and interconnected network structure. The significance of this arrangement lies in its ability to maintain coherence and efficiency across the network, despite the presence of multiple divergent policies.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-19T20:45:19.700000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
