<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>The state of bitcoinfuzz</title>
  <updated>2025-08-28T02:28:35.859429+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno.455000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-08-27T14:04:57.455000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>The state of bitcoinfuzz</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T02:28:35.859462+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-state-of-bitcoinfuzz/1946" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>**Bitcoinfuzz: Elevating Security in Bitcoin and Lightning Network Implementations**

The project bitcoinfuzz emerged as an experimental venture aimed at differential fuzzing of Bitcoin protocol implementations and libraries. It has significantly evolved from its initial version, adopting a modular approach for enhanced flexibility. This design allows users to selectively fuzz various projects, enabling individual builds of these so-called modules. Initially focusing on descriptor and miniscript parsers, the project has successfully identified numerous bugs across a variety of targets including script evaluation, descriptor parse, miniscript parse, addrv2, psbt, and address parse among others. Notable findings have been reported in implementations like sipa’s miniscript, btcd, rust-bitcoin, and rust-miniscript, leading to the discovery of over 35 bugs in prominent projects such as Bitcoin Core, Core Lightning, and LND.

The integration support within bitcoinfuzz spans a wide array of projects coded in diverse programming languages ranging from C++, Rust, Python, Golang, Scala, to Kotlin. This inclusivity fosters a comprehensive fuzzing environment, though it's noted that certain implementations may be reevaluated or removed to avoid complications arising from immature codebases. Among the latest advancements is the exploration into Lightning Network implementations, with differential fuzzing uncovering critical discrepancies and bugs. This effort is bolstered by contributions from Erick Cestari and Morehouse, underlining the project's commitment to improving both Bitcoin and Lightning Network protocols through rigorous testing.

Differential fuzzing's application to the Lightning Network is particularly noteworthy given the network's well-maintained specification, which aids in benchmarking correct behavior against found discrepancies. Through this method, bitcoinfuzz not only facilitates bug identification but also contributes to refining the Lightning specification itself. Examples of bugs uncovered include issues with invoice processing in Core Lightning and LND, as well as UTF-8 validation errors in rust-lightning and Eclair. 

However, challenges persist, especially when fuzzing projects lacking continuous fuzz target execution. Instances of bugs discovered in such scenarios underscore the importance of basic fuzz testing practices. Moreover, the nuances between different implementations sometimes reveal interesting cases rather than outright bugs, demonstrating the complexity involved in achieving consistent behavior across diverse codebases.

To enhance its infrastructure, bitcoinfuzz aims to integrate into OSS-Fuzz, Google’s continuous fuzzing initiative, which promises significant benefits for ongoing and future testing efforts. Additionally, the creation of a corpora repository mirrors strategies employed by Bitcoin Core to share fuzzing targets, facilitating more effective CI/CD pipeline integrations.

Looking ahead, bitcoinfuzz is set to expand its capabilities to support a broader range of fuzzing engines, introduce new fuzzing targets related to the Lightning Network, and address build system improvements. These endeavors highlight the project's dedication to strengthening the security and reliability of Bitcoin and Lightning Network implementations, ensuring a safer ecosystem for users and developers alike.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-27T14:04:57.455000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
