<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
  <updated>2025-08-30T02:23:23.821185+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-08-29 16:34:57.613000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T02:23:23.821211+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-and-quantum-computing/1730/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around a proposed security mechanism for cryptocurrency transactions, specifically focusing on the Hourglass strategy. This strategy is designed to mitigate risks associated with vulnerable Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) by implementing rate limits on their spending. The concept posits that if the community widely adopts this approach and moves coins to and from addresses protected by such a mechanism, then the window of vulnerability to attacks would be significantly reduced. Short exposure attacks, which exploit brief periods of vulnerability, remain a concern, but the strategy suggests a mitigation path through the use of Proof of Work verification for each signature. This method would enable a soft-fork implementation where coins can be time-locked for a varying number of blocks, depending on the size of the transaction's signature.

The technical details of the Hourglass strategy are encapsulated in a specific script, showcasing a sequence of operations designed to secure transactions through cryptographic methods. This script includes commands for swapping values, duplicating and adding sizes, verifying sequences, and checking hashes and signatures, all integral to ensuring the integrity and safety of transactions within the blockchain framework.

Further insights into the strategy and its potential for adoption are discussed in a related topic by Saint Wenhao, available at [BitcoinTalk](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5557305.0). The conversation there elaborates on the technical underpinnings and community perspectives regarding the implementation of the Hourglass strategy, providing a comprehensive understanding of its mechanisms and implications for enhancing transaction security in the blockchain realm.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:34:57.613000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
