<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T03:11:31.033297+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei 2025-08-05 15:32:01.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-04 19:21:46.121000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5650_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5638_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T03:11:31.033349+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-simplicity-programs-with-simplicityhl/1900" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of using a reverse Dutch auction for transaction fees is highlighted as an innovative strategy within the context of blockchain smart contracts, particularly when examining SimplicityHL contracts. The resemblance of SimplicityHL to "normal code" despite its specialized application in blockchain is noted, alongside the implementation of a custom signature hash (sighash) mechanism, which is termed as a noteworthy feature.

Simplicity is described as a programming language tailored for blockchain smart contracts, with its minimalistic design being simple enough to be encapsulated on a T-shirt. Despite this simplicity in core semantics, the language's functional and low-level nature makes it challenging to use, likening its complexity to that of assembly language rather than more accessible higher-level languages such as Java or Python. This complexity notwithstanding, Simplicity's capacity for formal verification positions it as an appealing option for specific blockchain endeavors. The deployment of Simplicity on the Liquid mainnet marks a significant step, enabling developers to utilize this language for writing and deploying contracts in production settings.

A practical use case of SimplicityHL is presented through an example addressing the challenge of fee estimation in Bitcoin transactions, traditionally managed through mechanisms like Replace-By-Fee (RBF) and Child Pays For Parent (CPFP) that require active involvement from senders or third parties. The example elucidates how embedding fee bumping logic within a contract’s script can independently adjust transaction fees based on the time elapsed since broadcast, circumventing the need for external inputs. This showcases SimplicityHL’s proficiency in defining spend conditions as functions over transaction data, thereby facilitating the creation of sophisticated and self-regulating smart contracts. The provided code snippet illustrates a base fee structure with incremental increases over time, exemplifying the utility of SimplicityHL in establishing a non-interactive fee adjustment mechanism that ensures comprehensive control over transaction authorization logic. This serves to underscore the potential of SimplicityHL in streamlining the development of secure and auditable smart contracts, focusing on the programming model while acknowledging, yet not extensively discussing, broader implications such as miner incentives and ecosystem integration. Additional resources for developers keen on exploring these technologies further include [SimplicityHL](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/SimplicityHL) and [rust-simplicity](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/rust-simplicity), which provide tools and examples pertinent to Simplicity and its applications.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:32:01.444000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
