<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
  <updated>2025-08-16T02:48:21.143405+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei 2025-08-15 16:12:24.488000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-06 22:37:56.383000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei  . 2025-08-05 15:32:01.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-04 19:21:46.121000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5719_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5667_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5650_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5638_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
    <updated>2025-08-16T02:48:21.143473+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-simplicity-programs-with-simplicityhl/1900" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse introduces a nuanced method within SimplicityHL, a programming model for blockchain smart contracts, highlighting the potential of employing a custom sighash implementation to defer program commitment decisions to the signing phase, an approach facilitated by delegation. This contrasts with the traditional requirement in SimplicityHL that programs must be committed at the address creation stage. The suggested *universal sighash* mode proposes a flexible framework that could significantly enhance the utility and adaptability of SimplicityHL, despite its theoretical nature and lack of practical application thus far. The concept is supported by a reference to [universal sighash](https://blog.blockstream.com/simplicity-taproot-and-universal-sighashes/), suggesting a broader interest and potential for future exploration in this area.

Further discussion centers on the introduction of a reverse Dutch auction mechanism for transaction fees within a SimplicityHL contract, portraying it as a novel and innovative solution diverging from traditional fee determination methods. The narrative underscores the resemblance of the contract's structure and syntax to conventional programming languages, positing this similarity as a means to lower entry barriers for developers new to SimplicityHL. This segment also touches upon the advanced customization embodied by the incorporation of a custom sighash, highlighting the developers' efforts to push beyond standard practices to optimize functionality or security.

Simplicity is defined as a minimalist programming language tailored for blockchain smart contracts, noted for its simple core semantics juxtaposed with a functional, low-level operational nature akin to assembly language. Despite its complexity for users, Simplicity's potential for formal verification makes it appealing for certain blockchain applications. The recent deployment of Simplicity on the Liquid mainnet marks a significant step forward, enabling the development and execution of contracts in production settings. A practical demonstration of SimplicityHL's capabilities is provided through an example addressing Bitcoin transaction fee estimation challenges. By incorporating fee bumping logic directly into a contract, the need for external intervention is eliminated, showcasing SimplicityHL's ability to facilitate complex and self-regulating smart contracts. This is exemplified via a code snippet that implements a base fee with incremental increases over time, illustrating a novel, non-interactive fee bumping mechanism. Although the discussion remains focused on the programming model, it acknowledges the wider implications for miner incentives and blockchain ecosystem integration. For those interested in deeper engagement, resources such as [SimplicityHL](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/SimplicityHL) and [rust-simplicity](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/rust-simplicity) are recommended, providing tools and examples for developer interaction with these technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T16:12:24.488000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
