<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-16T02:46:37.136933+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5717_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5709_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5708_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5706_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5705_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5700_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5683_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5682_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5680_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5681_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5676_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5675_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5674_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5673_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5668_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-16T02:46:37.137130+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain technology, particularly within Bitcoin mining, an accurate estimation of the network's hashrate becomes a pivotal aspect due to its direct correlation with both the security and efficiency of the network. The hashrate signifies the aggregate computational power per second utilized for mining and processing transactions on the blockchain. A refined approach towards estimating this hashrate emphasizes analyzing the work accomplished in each block, factored alongside the duration it takes to solve these blocks. This methodology underscores the use of a mathematical framework that leverages the difficulty target adjustments—designed to maintain consistent block discovery times despite fluctuations in total network mining power—and the observable durations of blocks as foundational elements.

A significant advancement in this analytical discourse is the derivation of a maximum-likelihood estimator (MLE) for the hashrate, which, when compared to traditional methods (`getnetworkhashps`), showcases alignment under constant difficulty levels yet reveals an inherent overestimation bias by a factor of $\frac{n}{n-1}$. To mitigate this bias and render an unbiased estimation of the hashrate, a corrective formula is proposed, enhancing the fidelity of blockchain analytics by rectifying the overestimation to closely mirror the actual hashrate across sampling instances.

Moreover, the exploration delves into the statistical properties of this unbiased estimator, suggesting its sufficiency and completeness—indicating that no additional data is necessary for an accurate hashrate estimate and that it operates with minimal variance, positioning it as potentially the most efficient unbiased estimator available. This insight, grounded in statistical theory, notably the Lehmann–Scheffé theorem, illuminates the estimator's significance in optimizing hashrate estimation practices within blockchain analysis.

The discourse further navigates through the intricacies of Erlang versus Poisson distributions, elucidating why the former, rather than the latter, presents a more apt methodological fit for blockchain network analysis due to its accommodation of fixed numbers of blocks to gauge time intervals. This shift from a traditionally employed Poisson distribution, which assumes a fixed time interval for accurate calculations, to an Erlang distribution that better aligns with the operational dynamics of blockchain networks, marks a critical pivot in understanding and accurately modeling blockchain behavior.

The conversation also addresses common misunderstandings prevalent within the industry, particularly the significant overestimation error in calculating the network hash rate using current methods. By proposing a correction that involves adjusting the estimated rate by multiplying it by (N-1)/N, a more accurate reflection of the actual hash rate is achieved. This corrective measure not only enhances the precision of hash rate estimations but also prompts a reevaluation of prevailing methodologies, advocating for a transition from counting a fixed number of blocks to delineating blocks over a set period to harness Poisson statistics effectively.

This collective analysis, enriched by contributions such as those by PW and observations analyzed by Lopp, underscores a broader industry challenge in reconciling theoretical models with practical realities. It highlights the necessity for ongoing dialogue, experimentation, and refinement in methodologies to ensure that our understanding and estimations of blockchain network parameters, like the hashrate, are as accurate and reflective of actual conditions as possible. Through such rigorous analytical endeavors, the domain of blockchain technology continues to evolve, promising enhancements in network security, efficiency, and overall understanding of its foundational mechanics.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T14:00:40.923000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
