<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-05T03:09:29.168365+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2025-08-04 17:09:18.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-02 19:24:55.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-01 06:27:52.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-31 20:07:11.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5636_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5623_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5610_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5601_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T03:09:29.168423+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing dialogue within the Bitcoin community concerning the adaptability of network rules to accommodate changing miner behaviors and the potential for non-standard transactions to evolve into standard ones underscores a broader debate about the flexibility and limitations inherent in the Bitcoin protocol. This conversation, largely focused on whether miners could significantly impact the landscape by confirming free transactions or utilizing future Segwit versions for random data insertions up to 4 MB, challenges existing constraints and explores the dynamic nature of transaction standardness. The discourse raises questions about the appropriateness of current policy rules if they prevent nodes from recognizing likely-to-be-mined transactions, suggesting a reevaluation of these rules to maintain only the necessary level of strictness for DoS protection without entirely loosening policy.

The discussion extends to the technical implications of integrating Proof of Work (PoW) with transactions to enhance legitimacy and scalability through batching techniques. Such approaches would allow for the aggregation of multiple transactions at minimal fees, promoting efficient propagation across the network. This method implies a reconsideration of the necessity for second-layer solutions if on-chain transactions can be managed effectively at low costs. Moreover, the conversation touches upon the speculative outcomes of miners unilaterally lifting existing limits, which could lead to ongoing adjustments in network defaults, highlighting an active debate on balancing innovation with network stability and decentralization principles.

A specific proposal to lower Bitcoin Core's minimum relay feerate from 1000 satoshi per kilobyte to 100 satoshi per virtual byte is part of this broader discussion, driven by the observation of sub-1sat/vB transactions being mined and circulated. This proposal aims to address issues related to block propagation delays caused by nodes not receiving information about these low-fee transactions. It emphasizes the importance of maintaining a balance to prevent block relay problems and avoid creating avenues for potential DoS attacks through low-cost transactions. The concept of incremental relay feerate is introduced, highlighting its significance in ensuring that replacement transactions adequately compensate for the resources they consume. Furthermore, the conversation delves into the economic aspects of transaction fees, considering the impact of Bitcoin’s price fluctuations on determining appropriate feerates. This multifaceted discussion invites further exploration of how minimum feerates are determined and their implications for the broader Bitcoin ecosystem, including wallets and applications relying on the network.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:09:18.310000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
