<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
  <updated>2025-08-07T03:10:51.982386+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary 2025-08-06 18:12:22.593000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-08-06 12:29:34.302000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>portlandhodl 2025-08-06 11:25:57.048000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-08-05 19:08:31.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5666_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5660_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5659_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5654_Sharing-block-templates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Sharing block templates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:10:51.982440+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/sharing-block-templates/1906" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights significant developments in Bitcoin's transaction policies and network operations, focusing on the evolution of mempool policies among nodes and miners. Recent years have seen the adoption of strategies such as full replace-by-fee, enhanced spam filtering by Bitcoin Knots, uncapped data carrier/OP_RETURN capacities, and an adjustment to the minimum fee rate to 0.1 satoshi per virtual byte. These changes reflect the dynamic landscape of Bitcoin's operational protocols, impacting block relay efficiency and influencing factors like mining centralization and security concerns, including selfish mining.

A pivotal advancement in enhancing network efficiency is the introduction of compact block relay with Bitcoin Core version 0.13.0 in August 2016. This feature significantly accelerates the propagation of blocks across the network by enabling nodes to predict upcoming transactions more accurately, thus reducing the time needed to update the blockchain tip. The implementation of compact block relay has notably decreased block propagation times from approximately 5 seconds to nearly zero, as evidenced by the DSN Block Propagation History charts. This improvement plays a vital role in lowering expected orphan rates and mitigating potential centralization issues.

In response to the challenges posed by varying mempool policies on the efficacy of compact block relay, innovative solutions like weak blocks and template sharing are being explored. Weak blocks allow miners to publish incomplete proof-of-work shares, offering peers insight into ongoing mining efforts. Template sharing, on the other hand, involves the regular generation and exchange of block templates among peers to facilitate efficient compact block reconstruction. This approach enhances network robustness by enabling quick mempool updates with high-fee transactions, improving privacy through automated rebroadcasting, and aiding in the analysis of network behavior and transaction relay challenges. A proof of concept for template sharing has shown its potential in updating node templates swiftly with relevant transactions and in facilitating more effective block reconstructions.

Moreover, the conversation touches upon the integration of GETDATA with the proposed template responses, which could potentially allow access to transactions deemed private by miners. This aspect raises considerations about the mechanisms currently preventing transaction relay and how they might be adapted to restrict inclusion in template responses. Notably, entities like Antpool and MARA Pool, along with services offered by Rebar labs, participate in practices that prioritize certain transactions based on their value, despite their low propagation properties.

The dialogue also references [stratum.work](https://stratum.work), which provides template timing data points relevant to the discussion, underscoring the ongoing exploration and implementation of strategies aimed at optimizing Bitcoin network performance and security. Through addressing the implications of diverse mempool policies and investigating forward-thinking solutions like template sharing, the Bitcoin community continues to advance in its efforts to tackle emerging challenges and harness opportunities for improvement.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T18:12:22.593000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
