<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
  <updated>2025-08-02T03:01:57.630069+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>danoprey</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>danoprey</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidtaubmann  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5618_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5609_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5608_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5606_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5603_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5586_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5587_Paralel-Bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Paralel Bitcoin only for conscious living individuals</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T03:01:57.630149+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/paralel-bitcoin-only-for-conscious-living-individuals/1877/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse begins with a critique of the current trajectory of Bitcoin and its implications on decentralization, expressing concern over the potential dominance of Western oligarchies regardless of Bitcoin's success or failure. The author argues this dominance undermines true decentralization, suggesting an alternative approach to Bitcoin that would prevent institutions from gaining significant control. This alternative involves creating a fork of Bitcoin with mechanisms to limit the maximum amount of currency any single wallet can hold, aiming to reduce wealth concentration and promote a more dynamic distribution of money within society. The emphasis is on viewing money not as a symbol of success but as a tool for facilitating broader societal dynamism and equity.

Further exploring the relationship between technology, institutions, and humanity, the conversation shifts towards how these entities impact human life and societal well-being. It highlights concerns that many institutions prioritize their own growth and power consolidation over addressing fundamental human needs such as hunger, inequality, and quality of life. This critique extends to the governance of non-conscious entities like machines and AI, proposing the idea of sub-wallets controlled by humans to ensure these technologies serve life-expanding purposes rather than contributing to existential risks. The narrative underscores the need for aligning institutional and technological activities with humanistic values to prevent them from exacerbating inequalities and existential threats, framed as a conflict between humanism and extinctionism.

The discussion further delves into the concept of fungibility and its implications on economic systems, questioning the fairness of applying uniform inflationary effects across living beings and non-living entities like institutions and AI. It raises philosophical and economic inquiries about the differential impact of inflation on various types of entities and the ethical considerations of prioritizing the needs of non-living entities over living beings. The argument advocates for a reevaluation of our economic and value systems to better recognize and accommodate the unique nature and needs of living consciousness, suggesting a shift towards economic practices that support life's expansion rather than constraining it through misaligned value assignment and resource management. This call for change is rooted in the belief that the universe's fundamental purpose is the expansion of life, urging a reconsideration of how societies value and interact with both living and non-living entities to align more closely with this overarching goal.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-01T19:50:10.820000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
