<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Qubic attack on Monero</title>
  <updated>2025-10-22T02:43:31.411004+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>zawy  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-08-13 11:39:34.003000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jungly</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-21 07:17:29.643000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5699_Qubic-attack-on-Monero.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6123_Qubic-attack-on-Monero.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Qubic attack on Monero</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T02:43:31.411525+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/qubic-attack-on-monero/1920/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-08-13 11:39:34.003000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent Qubic attack on Monero has highlighted significant security concerns within Proof of Work (PoW) systems, particularly around the principle of non-repurposability. This concept is crucial in understanding why ASIC-resistant PoWs, which aim to democratize mining by preventing the optimization through specialized hardware, may actually compromise security by allowing for the repurposing of mining efforts or hardware. Such systems contrast with those requiring substantial capital expenditure (CAPEX), which naturally discourages repurposing due to the significant financial investment involved, thereby enhancing security.
A point of discussion involves the creation of &quot;cash coins&quot; through operational expenditure (OPEX), primarily electricity costs. These could theoretically adjust in quantity to reflect demand and technological progress following Moore's law. However, accurately measuring such advancements on a decentralized scale proves challenging. The conversation also explores alternative PoW mechanisms like Optical-PoW and Chia's proof of space, suggesting a potential for security benefits despite uncertainties in their effectiveness compared to more established methods like Bitcoin's.
Further analysis delves into the security of merge-mined coins and the X11 PoW system, which combines several PoW algorithms including Bitcoin's. This hybrid approach could offer enhanced security through sufficient non-repurposability, defined as a scenario where the majority of the hashing power, including outdated equipment, would prioritize long-term rewards over the immediate gains from double-spending attacks.
However, a significant concern arises with the threat posed by state-level actors who might attempt to undermine cryptocurrencies to maintain control over fiat currencies and financial surveillance. The defense against such threats hinges on the operational costs of the network surpassing what a group of colluding states might be willing to spend on an attack. Bitcoin's resilience is thus seen as dependent on its perceived threat to state authority, with speculations that sustaining an offensive might be financially viable for major governments.
Moreover, the discussion touches upon selfish mining, especially in light of the Monero attack, indicating it as a minimal threat to Bitcoin given a consensus on maintaining timestamp accuracy. This comprehensive examination underscores the complex interplay of technological innovation and adversarial threats in the security of cryptocurrency networks.
Addressing a counterpoint, there's speculation that reliance on ASIC chips introduces a vulnerability whereby states could potentially seize control over ASIC production, posing a challenge in dislodging such state-operated miners. This perspective suggests a nuanced balance in the debate over cryptocurrency security, highlighting the multifaceted vulnerabilities and considerations that must be navigated.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>