<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-02T03:02:43.586793+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-08-01 06:27:52.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-31 20:07:11.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5610_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5601_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T03:02:43.586833+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse explores the intricacies of modifying Bitcoin Core's minimum relay feerate from 1000 satoshi per kilobyte to 100 satoshi per virtual byte, a suggestion put forth in a GitHub pull request. This proposition is catalyzed by instances where transactions with fees lower than 1 sat/vB were not only relayed but also mined, signaling a potential shift in network practices. Two specific pull requests are at the heart of this discussion, one aiming to lower the minimum relay fee ([see PR here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106)) and another addressing the inclusion of low-fee transactions within Bitcoin Core ([related PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32959)). The narrative underscores a broader concern regarding the speed at which blocks filled with sub-1sat/vB transactions propagate across nodes, particularly those nodes that had initially disregarded or missed these transactions.

A pivotal aspect of the debate centers on maintaining equilibrium between preventing block relay obstacles and safeguarding against potential abuse by attackers leveraging low transaction costs for malicious purposes. The minimum relay feerate emerges as a critical mechanism to thwart denial-of-service attacks, imposing a cost barrier for bandwidth consumption that spans tens of thousands of nodes engaged in the verification and broadcasting of transactions. Additionally, the conversation introduces the concept of incremental relay feerate, which ensures that replacement transactions incur additional fees for the resources they consume. This concept plays a vital role in adjusting dynamic mempool minimum feerates, reflecting the cost implications of displacing existing transactions within the memory pool.

The dialogue further delves into the relationship between transaction fees and their representation of real-world resources. It suggests that fluctuations in Bitcoin’s valuation in USD might influence decisions regarding suitable feerates. A notable point of reference within the discussion is a GitHub comment that provides insight into considerations surrounding the adjustment of minimum feerates ([view comment](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32959issuecomment-3095260286)). The conversation extends an invitation for additional reflections on the utilization of minimum feerates, the process of determining an optimal minimum feerate, and formalizing these concepts. It also considers the repercussions for wallets and applications operating within the ecosystem, highlighting the need for a balanced approach to ensure the network's resilience against both operational challenges and security threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-01T06:27:52.381000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
