<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
  <updated>2025-08-30T02:24:22.637214+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>fanquake 2025-08-29 13:47:12.343000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-28 19:16:27.695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5780_Bitcoin-Core-v29-1-release-candidate-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5585_Bitcoin-Core-v29-1-release-candidate-available.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Core v29.1 release candidate available</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T02:24:22.637261+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-v29-1-release-candidate-available/1881" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest release candidate for Bitcoin Core, version v29.1rc1, has been released and is available for download. This new minor version marks a significant step in the development of Bitcoin Core, offering several updates and enhancements over previous versions. Users and developers interested in testing or exploring this version can access the binaries from the [Bitcoin Core's official website](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-29.1/test.rc1/) and find the source code on GitHub under the signed tag [v29.1rc1 on GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v29.1rc1). 

This release includes detailed preliminary release notes which highlight the changes and improvements made. These notes are crucial for understanding the specifics of what has been updated or fixed in this version and can be found at the [release notes document](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/565af03c37d8262632543a078b2d8d29459d0b91/doc/release-notes.md). The purpose of releasing a candidate like v29.1rc1 is to identify and rectify any critical issues before the final version is officially launched. As such, developers encourage the community to actively participate in testing this release candidate and to report any problems encountered through the [GitHub issue tracker](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues).

Release candidates are essential for ensuring the stability and functionality of the final release. Therefore, feedback from users testing these versions is invaluable for the development team. The team commits to providing updates on this release candidate and future ones to keep the community informed about progress and developments.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T13:47:12.343000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
