<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:32:36.377154+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-08-26 14:01:55.976000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-08-25 21:45:56.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hodlinator 2025-08-19 19:59:33.487000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei  . 2025-08-15 16:12:24.488000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-06 22:37:56.383000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei  . 2025-08-05 15:32:01.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-04 19:21:46.121000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5774_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5772_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5748_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5719_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5667_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5650_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5638_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:32:36.377219+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-simplicity-programs-with-simplicityhl/1900" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent dialogue on Simplicity, a programming language designed for blockchain smart contracts, unveils significant strides towards enhancing its functionality and application. An integral part of this discussion is the exploration into the potential of integrating a universal sighash mode within Simplicity. This innovative feature proposes the ability to create custom signature hashes, affording developers greater flexibility in how transactions are signed and verified. Such an advancement could lead to the development of more sophisticated smart contracts and blockchain-based solutions by allowing for selective commitment to transaction contents, potentially bolstering security and introducing functionalities like rangeproof style signature commitments or key delegation mechanisms. The integration process, however, would demand extensive coding efforts and thorough testing to ensure the reliability and security of the enhanced system.

Another focal point of the conversation is the concept of utilizing a custom sighash implementation in SimplicityHL, diverging from the traditional model which requires program commitment during the address creation phase. By leveraging a mechanism known as *delegation*, it becomes possible to defer decisions regarding program commitment until the signing phase. Despite the absence of technical barriers to adopting this more adaptable sighash-based check, it remains unexplored in practical applications. This suggests that implementing such a feature could significantly increase the utility and versatility of SimplicityHL.

Additionally, the discourse sheds light on the notion of a reverse Dutch auction for transaction fees, highlighting its novelty and potential advantages over conventional fee determination methods. A particular simplicityHL contract under scrutiny reveals similarities with traditional programming code, suggesting an ease of understanding that could lower entry barriers for developers new to blockchain programming. The inclusion of a custom sighash within this contract indicates an advanced level of customization, pointing towards efforts to optimize functionality or security beyond standard practices.

Simplicity itself is noted for its minimalistic design, making it powerful yet challenging to use due to its functional and low-level nature, likened to programming in assembly language. Its recent deployment on the Liquid mainnet marks a significant milestone, enabling the practical application of Simplicity in writing and deploying smart contracts. A showcased example emphasizes SimplicityHL's capability to embed fee bumping logic directly into a contract's script, facilitating autonomous adjustment of transaction fees based on elapsed time since broadcast. This example illustrates the language's power in expressing spend conditions as functions over transaction data, offering a glimpse into the potential for creating complex, self-adjusting smart contracts without requiring external intervention.

For those interested in further exploring these advancements, resources such as [SimplicityHL](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/SimplicityHL) and [rust-simplicity](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/rust-simplicity) provide valuable tools and examples for developers aiming to harness the capabilities of these technologies in blockchain application development.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-26T14:01:55.976000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
