<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
  <updated>2025-08-07T03:10:09.162623+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sanket1729 2025-08-06 22:37:56.383000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>niftynei  . 2025-08-05 15:32:01.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-08-04 19:21:46.121000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5667_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5650_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5638_Writing-Simplicity-Programs-with-SimplicityHL.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Writing Simplicity Programs with SimplicityHL</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:10:09.162667+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/writing-simplicity-programs-with-simplicityhl/1900" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins by acknowledging the potential of a custom sighash implementation within SimplicityHL, a programming language designed for blockchain smart contracts. This approach allows for more flexible transaction verification processes by enabling the signer to decide on the commitment to programs at the signing stage rather than at address setup. This flexibility is made possible through a feature known as *delegation*, enhancing the utility and adaptability of SimplicityHL contracts. Despite the technical feasibility of integrating a universal sighash mode to facilitate this advanced functionality, it has not yet been implemented in SimplicityHL.

An intriguing aspect of SimplicityHL is its exploration of a reverse Dutch auction mechanism for transaction fees, which represents a significant deviation from traditional fee determination methods. This innovative model has the potential to redefine how fees are calculated and applied within blockchain transactions. The analysis further notes the structural and syntactical similarities between SimplicityHL contracts and conventional programming languages, which could significantly lower the learning curve for developers new to blockchain development. The inclusion of a custom sighash implementation within these contracts indicates a move towards bespoke optimizations, highlighting the developers' commitment to pushing the boundaries of what's possible within smart contract design and functionality.

Simplicity itself is characterized by its minimalistic yet potent design, tailored specifically for the development of smart contracts on blockchain platforms. Its core semantics are deliberately straightforward, though its functional and low-level nature presents a steep learning curve, likening its use to programming in assembly language. Despite these challenges, Simplicity's capacity for formal verification and its recent deployment on the Liquid mainnet position it as a powerful tool for blockchain application development. Notably, an example provided demonstrates how SimplicityHL can be used to autonomously adjust transaction fees over time without external input, leveraging its unique capabilities to address common issues such as fee estimation in Bitcoin transactions.

The code snippet shared illustrates the practical application of SimplicityHL in implementing a non-interactive fee bumping mechanism, showcasing the language's potential to streamline and secure transaction authorization processes. This example underscores the broader utility of SimplicityHL in crafting complex, self-adjusting smart contracts, while also hinting at the potential implications for miner incentives and ecosystem integration. For those interested in delving deeper into SimplicityHL and its associated technologies, resources such as [SimplicityHL](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/SimplicityHL) and [rust-simplicity](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/rust-simplicity) offer valuable tools and examples for further exploration.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T22:37:56.383000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
