<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-10T03:08:31.120566+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-09 19:54:27.552000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-09 19:50:18.775000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-09 14:35:01.394000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-08-09 13:28:09.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-08 19:49:40.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-08 02:23:35.114000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-08 00:32:21.279000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-08-07 21:56:29.740000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-07 00:45:21.764000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 10:32:27.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5683_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5682_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5680_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5681_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5676_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5675_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5674_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5673_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5668_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T03:08:31.120754+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens with a nuanced understanding of statistical distributions applicable in blockchain analysis, specifically focusing on the differentiation between Beta and Poisson distributions for fixed blocks and fixed time intervals, respectively. An interesting correction is proposed to adapt Poisson equations to reflect fixed-block scenarios accurately, suggesting an alignment closer to the Erlang distribution for fixed number of blocks or Binomial distribution in place of Beta for fixed time intervals. This adjustment is pivotal in refining the accuracy of work calculation in blockchain contexts, particularly in proof-of-work systems where such calculations are critical for assessing network security through mining activities.

Further exploration into the methodological nuances reveals a detailed approach to estimating computational work within blockchain operations. The dialogue intricately dissects the formula for calculating work, emphasizing the retention of recent block headers to maintain accuracy within standard deviation errors. This aspect is crucial for ensuring precise work calculation, highlighting a direct relationship between block count and variance. Moreover, the discussion extends into proofs of Proof-of-Work schemes, indicating a scalable mechanism to manage header storage efficiently as blockchain height increases. The selection process for blocks under analysis underscores the importance of pre-selecting an interval to analyze hashrate effectively, mitigating selection bias and closely mirroring traditional chain work summation practices.

A correction regarding the variance of the bandwidth estimator elucidates a more accurate representation of the standard deviation, pivoting from previous assumptions. This adjustment bears implications for algorithms estimating work over a specified range of blocks, offering a systematic approach to quantifying work done within blockchain operations. Furthermore, the conversation sheds light on the experimental results concerning hashing estimates, revealing a proportional relationship between the standard deviation of these estimates and the variables involved, thereby enhancing the reliability of hash-related computations.

The dialogue transitions to an examination of statistical models based on hash values for estimating the amount of computational work in blockchain mining. It introduces a mathematical model where the k'th lowest hash follows a Beta distribution, facilitating the calculation of expected value and variance of the work estimate. This model suggests that accuracy improves with higher values of \(k\), although it acknowledges a high level of estimation uncertainty due to variance being proportional to \(n^2\).

In dissecting the concept of "work" within mining contexts, the discourse illuminates how work is quantified in blockchain networks, particularly under proof-of-work systems. It highlights the comparative difficulty measure provided by the second lowest hash, offering a nuanced perspective on miners' challenges. This understanding not only deepens the insight into mining dynamics but also emphasizes the stochastic nature of mining achievements beyond mere surpassing of a predefined difficulty threshold.

Addressing a significant error in document correction, the discussion emphasizes the need for meticulous review to ensure the accuracy and reliability of presented information, especially in documents guiding implementations or conveying data. This reflects a broader theme of precision and accountability in technical documentation within the blockchain sector.

Lastly, the conversation ventures into a comprehensive analysis of chain work and hashrate estimation methodologies, proposing innovative approaches for more accurate measurements. By delineating calculations for unbiased estimators and adjusting for real-time conditions, the dialogue contributes significantly to refining blockchain network performance and security analytics. These methodological enhancements underscore the evolving landscape of blockchain technology, highlighting adaptive techniques pivotal for accurate and dynamic analysis in this domain.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T19:54:27.552000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
