<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-13T02:54:01.286237+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidgumberg 2025-08-13 00:48:40.417000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-08-12 16:53:22.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidgumberg 2025-08-12 15:26:50.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow 2025-08-12 13:56:31.384000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-08-06 16:47:35.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sceptic  . 2025-08-06 15:44:53.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-05 07:40:00.709000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-05 03:36:29.160000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-08-04 17:09:18.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-02 19:24:55.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-01 06:27:52.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-31 20:07:11.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5694_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5693_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5686_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5691_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5664_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5662_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5644_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5641_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5636_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5623_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5610_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5601_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-13T02:54:01.286329+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse delves into the nuanced considerations surrounding hardcoded values within Bitcoin Core releases, particularly focusing on the minimum relay feerate and its implications for network security and transaction processing efficiency. The initial argument questions the viability of hardcoding given the potential volatility in blockspace demand and BTC to network bandwidth conversion rates. However, a detailed examination of historical data suggests that these rates have remained relatively stable, supporting the practice of hardcoding minimum relay feerates with periodic reviews to ensure relevance and accuracy.

A significant aspect of the discussion is the Bitcoin Core's strategy for managing the mempool and transaction fees. By implementing a dynamic approach to the minimum relay feerate, Bitcoin Core aims to mitigate denial-of-service (DoS) attacks without relying solely on transaction fees. This system allows for a balance between maintaining network security and facilitating efficient transaction processing, even allowing for transactions with fees as low as one satoshi per byte under certain conditions. The proposal of a subpool for low-fee transactions introduces an innovative method to manage the mempool without compromising network integrity or incentivizing free transactions, which could potentially devalue transaction fees.

The conversation also touches upon the broader economic implications of fee policies on mining revenue and the sustainability of the Bitcoin network. With observations of declining fee revenue in BTC terms since 2017, there's a growing concern about the long-term viability of mining operations. This concern is juxtaposed with the optimism that transaction fees will remain a significant part of the network's economic model, encouraging users towards Layer 2 solutions for lower-cost transactions.

Furthermore, the dialogue explores the integration of Proof of Work (PoW) within transactions, offering a dual-layered approach to security and spam prevention. This approach emphasizes the flexibility for users to choose between traditional fee structures and computational efforts to prioritize their transactions, potentially enhancing the security of second-layer solutions significantly.

The discussion extends to the evolving notion of transaction standardness and the potential for miners to confirm free transactions. This raises critical questions about the adaptability of network policies and the balance between ensuring security and fostering innovation. The possibility of future Segwit versions accommodating larger data inserts per transaction could challenge existing limitations, highlighting the need for ongoing evaluation of network rules to reflect changing practices and technologies.

Finally, the proposed change to lower the minimum relay feerate in Bitcoin Core from 1000 sat/kvB to 100 sat/vB, as outlined in a GitHub pull request, reflects a response to observed trends and technical analyses. This adjustment aims to address the challenges associated with block propagation delays for transactions below 1 sat/vB while maintaining the network's resilience against DoS attacks. The inclusion of this change underscores the importance of adapting to real-world data and ensuring the Bitcoin network remains secure, efficient, and responsive to the evolving landscape of digital currencies.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:48:40.417000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
