<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Chain Code Delegation: Private Access Control for Bitcoin Keys</title>
  <updated>2025-08-27T02:31:34.344488+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jurvis 2025-08-24 00:01:41.912000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pinheadmz 2025-08-20 15:51:59.920000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jaonoctus  . 2025-07-29 08:08:38.123000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>marathongary  . 2025-07-16 20:15:30.976000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jurvis  . 2025-07-15 00:41:07.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5766_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5755_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5593_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5506_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5469_Chain-Code-Delegation-Private-Access-Control-for-Bitcoin-Keys.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Chain Code Delegation: Private Access Control for Bitcoin Keys</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T02:31:34.344548+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/chain-code-delegation-private-access-control-for-bitcoin-keys/1837" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The innovative concept of using moderators in transactions was employed by [OpenBazaar](https://github.com/OpenBazaar/openbazaar-go), where a unique protocol facilitated private transactions between buyers and sellers with the option of involving a moderator only when disputes arise. This system utilized a static public key posted by moderators, which could be tweaked for each transaction to include them in a dispute resolution path without their knowledge unless their intervention was required. This approach ensured privacy while also providing a mechanism for resolving conflicts, demonstrating a practical application of cryptographic techniques in enhancing transaction security and trust.

Schnorr signatures are highlighted for their simplicity, robustness, and the elegance of their algebraic structure, making them a strong candidate for cryptographic protocols. They maintain the integrity of signatures even when public keys are altered through a specific tweaking process. The method involves adding a tweak variable to the public key, ensuring that the signature remains valid due to the linear relationship within the Schnorr signature formula. This characteristic exemplifies the use of algebra in securing digital communications, underlining the potential of Schnorr signatures in bolstering cybersecurity measures by integrating tweaks without compromising signature integrity.

The advancement in minimizing security risks associated with extended public keys (xpubs) is discussed, referencing a technique similar to blinded xpubs available on [GitHub](https://github.com/mflaxman/blind-xpub). This method significantly enhances privacy and security by controlling the visibility of keys derived from an xpub once the blinded path is revealed. It represents a crucial step forward in managing and tracking the usage of xpub-derived keys, offering a safer and more confidential approach to handling cryptographic operations.

Chain Code Delegation emerges as a novel strategy developed by Jesse Posner, focusing on privacy and security through selective information sharing in collaborative custody scenarios. By withholding BIP-32 chain codes and only providing scalar tweaks at the time of signing, this approach allows for policies such as spending velocity controls without compromising privacy. Chain Code Delegation addresses the limitations of traditional multisig and ECDSA by preventing custodians from having complete visibility into the key tree or transaction history, thereby reducing security risks. The methodology introduces a way for custodians to sign transactions with limited knowledge, confining potential damage in case of a compromise and enhancing privacy and security in cryptographic operations. Further discussions and technical insights into Chain Code Delegation and its applications in secure, privacy-focused collaborative custody solutions can be found in the provided references, including analyses on Private Collaborative Custody with FROST and Concurrently Secure Blind Schnorr Signatures, offering a comprehensive understanding of this groundbreaking approach.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-24T00:01:41.912000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
