<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
  <updated>2025-08-08T03:09:26.799384+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-08-08 00:32:21.279000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-08-07 21:56:29.740000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-08-07 00:45:21.764000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 10:32:27.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-12 00:55:02.853000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-07-01 19:53:03.275000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 20:57:19.615000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 17:03:02.352000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 15:56:54.666000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-30 14:04:44.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 13:16:54.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-30 12:45:13.061000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-29 14:43:12.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-28 12:18:04.434000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-28 07:49:41.937000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 22:25:19.851000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-06-27 18:57:42.941000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-27 18:43:30.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-06-02 10:53:31.141000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5674_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5673_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5668_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5443_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5441_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5382_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5381_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5378_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5377_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5376_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5375_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5370_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5362_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5364_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5359_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5358_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5354_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5355_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5190_Correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Correcting the error in getnetworkhashrateps</title>
    <updated>2025-08-08T03:09:26.799518+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/correcting-the-error-in-getnetworkhashrateps/1745" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of blockchain technology and its mechanisms, specifically within the context of mining, reveals a nuanced understanding of how "work" is quantified in networks utilizing a Proof of Work (PoW) system. The analysis starts with a mathematical exploration of how work can be estimated based on the distribution of hashes. It posits that the k'th lowest hash seen normalized to $[0 \ldots 1]$ provides an estimate for the amount of work completed. This estimation uses formulas derived from the Beta distribution for the k'th lowest hash and the Poisson distribution for block counts, offering insights into how statistical distributions can inform our understanding of work in blockchain contexts.

Further discussion delves into the effective difficulty of mining, illustrated through the comparative difficulty measure provided by the second lowest hash during the mining process. This conceptualization emphasizes the stochastic nature of mining, where success is measured not only against a predefined threshold but also in relation to near-successes, adding depth to the analysis of computational efforts in blockchain mining.

An essential correction highlighted in the discourse pertains to a significant error involving the inversion of 'D' and 'W' in a document, which had led to numerous subsequent inaccuracies. This issue underscores the importance of precision in documentation and the potential impacts of such errors on the interpretation and application of blockchain technology.

The relationship between chain work and the lowest hash in blockchain operations is examined through statistical analysis and mathematical modeling. The discussions propose formulas that suggest chain work is inversely proportional to twice the value of the lowest hash observed. These models, while simplistic, offer foundational insights into estimating chain work, albeit acknowledging the challenges posed by variances in calculation outcomes due to small number involvements.

A refined approach for calculating the hashrate and total work over specific timespans introduces a more accurate method than previously utilized formulas. This approach considers the sum of difficulties for N blocks, providing a precise calculation that avoids the misestimations common with earlier methods. Importantly, this methodology emphasizes the significance of using the correct timespan in calculations to accurately reflect the amount of work done within a specified period.

The email also examines the efficiency and security implications of hashrate versus actual work completed in PoW protocols. A hypothetical scenario illustrates how different difficulty settings among miner groups affect work output and hashrate, suggesting that a higher hashrate does not necessarily correlate with increased efficiency or security in terms of mined blocks.

Addressing the methodology for estimating the number of hashes performed, the discussion acknowledges the assumption of a constant hashrate as a limitation. This part of the conversation highlights the specificity required in applying theoretical models to practical situations, especially in computational tasks where variables significantly impact outcomes.

The narrative further explores the complexities of accurately measuring and predicting computational efforts within blockchain networks. It suggests that sophisticated statistical methods are crucial for analyzing decentralized systems, emphasizing the importance of distinguishing between predictive models and observational data in evaluating network performance.

Finally, the dialogue culminates in an innovative method for estimating the hashrate of a blockchain network, moving beyond fixed block numbers to consider fixed time windows. This approach aims at enhancing accuracy by adjusting for real-time conditions and leveraging statistical properties of observed hashes, thereby providing a more comprehensive understanding of blockchain network performance and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:32:21.279000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
