<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T03:10:47.877006+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-08-05 07:40:00.709000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-08-05 03:36:29.160000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-08-04 17:09:18.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-08-02 19:24:55.469000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-08-01 06:27:52.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-07-31 20:07:11.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5644_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5641_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5636_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5623_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2025/5610_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5601_Changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Changing the minimum relay feerate</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T03:10:47.877065+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/changing-the-minimum-relay-feerate/1886" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation centers on the adjustment of Bitcoin's policy regarding transaction fee rates and the handling of transactions that are likely to be mined. It suggests a more lenient approach towards transactions with fees below 1 satoshi per virtual byte (sat/vB), proposing the creation of a subpool for such transactions with distinct `maxmempool` and `mempoolexpiry` settings, for instance, 32 MB and 36 hours, respectively. The idea is to lower the `minrelaytxfee` to a figure slightly above zero, provided it does not incentivize [free relay](https://bitcoinops.org/en/topics/free-relay/). This discussion acknowledges the impact of lower fee rates on miners' revenue, highlighting a decline in fees since 2017 despite a significant increase in Bitcoin's USD price and a reduction in block rewards.

The debate extends to the use of Proof of Work (PoW) as an optional means to limit spam by incorporating it within transactions. This mechanism could work alongside transaction fees to maintain network integrity, especially for second-layer solutions like the Lightning Network. A notable implementation of this concept is already deployed on-chain, functioning as a faucet for puzzle solvers, as detailed in a [Bitcointalk forum post](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5551080.0). The dialogue also touches upon the potential for future Segwit versions to allow for non-standard data pushes that could extend up to 4 MB per transaction, raising questions about the abandonment of standardness rules and the acceptance of [non-standard transactions](https://mempool.space/tx/bb41a757f405890fb0f5856228e23b715702d714d59bf2b1feb70d8b2b4e3e08) if they begin to be included by miners.

Further, the discourse explores the implications of changing the minimum relay feerate from 1000 sat/kvB to 100 sat/vB, as proposed in a GitHub pull request ([see PR here](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/33106)). This proposal is motivated by the observation that blocks containing many sub-1sat/vB transactions face slower propagation, which can be mitigated by adjusting how these transactions are managed in the Bitcoin Core software ([related PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/32959)). The conversation emphasizes the need to balance the avoidance of block relay issues and the prevention of DoS attacks, shedding light on the technical and economic considerations behind setting transaction fees and their role in the network's security and efficiency.

This comprehensive discussion reflects ongoing efforts to optimize the Bitcoin network's handling of transactions, focusing on adjustments to fee rates, the introduction of novel methods like PoW for transaction verification, and the broader implications of such changes for miners' revenue and network scalability. It illustrates a keen awareness of the technical challenges and economic factors influencing network policies, underscoring a dynamic dialogue aimed at enhancing Bitcoin's functionality and user experience.</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T07:40:00.709000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
