<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-01-03T02:19:03.176948+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-02T19:14:16.333000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T02:19:03.176985+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the cautious approach towards adopting new algorithms into high assurance products, echoing Adam Back's sentiments on the importance of careful consideration in such integrations, as highlighted through a [high assurance products](https://x.com/adam3us/status/1874877560427004190) link. The conversation suggests flexibility and openness to explore different methodologies for updating BIP-360, with a particular interest in starting with WOTS and incorporating another algorithm to assist in testing attestation disambiguation. Moreover, there is an intrigue shown towards DASK, proposing a significant shift towards hybrid cryptography by suggesting that secp256k1 keys should not be deprecated but rather included alongside other signature types.

An inquiry about how nodes will validate signatures for block inclusion under the HBS model raises technical questions regarding the operational consistency between clients and nodes, especially considering the unique secrets held by clients. Appreciation is expressed for the research quality of an article, indicating its thoroughness and relevance.

Additionally, the dialogue introduces the latest iteration of BIP-360 available at [GitHub](https://github.com/cryptoquick/bips/blob/0ae69db70a4a28f202d441b7131cd5b2169e7afe/bip-0360.mediawiki), suggesting a potential collaboration in drafting a BIP for DASK. There's a contemplation on narrowing down BIP-360 to better align with DASK, highlighting a strategic consideration towards enhancing the proposal's focus and applicability. This exchange encapsulates a blend of technical deliberation, collaborative proposals, and a forward-thinking stance on cryptographic standards development.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T19:14:16.333000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
