<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:21.045500+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-02T19:30:47.726000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:21.045536+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>John Law's innovative approach to payment channel constructions introduces a nuanced method of employing two distinct relative timelocks utilizing separate Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), as detailed in his [GitHub repository](https://github.com/JohnLaw2/ln-hierarchical-channels). This technique is illustrated through Figures 14 and 15, which depict the implementation of these timelocks in the context of a payment channel network. The use of separate timelocks facilitates dual "lanes" for managing timeouts: one lane is dedicated to the revocation of commitment transactions, while the other addresses Hash Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs), potentially also linked to revocation processes. This dual-lane system ensures that once the conditions of both relative timelocks are met, HTLC-payment transactions can proceed without the risk of either lane resetting the timelines of the other. 

Furthermore, the construction includes an output that is considered a dust output, serving purely for control purposes within the transaction structure. This aspect highlights the strategic use of transaction outputs to manipulate and secure the payment channel's operational integrity. John Law’s methodology exemplifies a straightforward yet effective application of transaction ID (txid) stability within the domain of cryptocurrency payment channels, offering insights into the practical enhancements of security and efficiency in blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T19:30:47.726000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
