<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>End of 2024 site statistics</title>
  <updated>2025-01-03T02:23:28.468874+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.541000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-02T23:23:07.541000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>End of 2024 site statistics</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T02:23:28.468907+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/end-of-2024-site-statistics/1356" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The data provided highlights the trajectory of daily logged-in user visits to the delving website over a two-year period, specifically from January 2023 to December 2024. The figures show a progressive increase in site traffic, starting with 22 visits in January 2023 and experiencing significant growth to reach 1315 visits by December 2024. This upward trend in user engagement is particularly notable from August 2023 onwards, where the number of visits escalated from 148 to a peak of 1671 in March 2024. 

In mid-2024, the site implemented an upgrade designed to improve how it handles automated traffic that is not indicative of genuine user interest. This enhancement, discussed in more detail on a [Discourse community forum](https://meta.discourse.org/t/better-pageview-metrics-with-the-new-site-traffic-report/324068/10), aimed at providing more accurate and relevant statistics regarding site visits. Despite the introduction of this new system, the analysis presented here relies on data collected via the legacy version of the site traffic report tool due to its ability to offer consistent historical data extending back over the previous months.

Additionally, visual data concerning the number of new posts per month was shared, although specific numerical details were not provided. The graphical representation indicates fluctuations in content generation over the same period, which could correlate with or have influenced changes in user visitation patterns. This aspect of the report underscores the dynamic nature of online platform engagement, suggesting that content output may play a role in attracting or retaining site visitors.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T23:23:07.541000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
