<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Transitory Soft Forks for Consensus Cleanup Forks</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:20:12.808825+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-03T10:17:02.651000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Transitory Soft Forks for Consensus Cleanup Forks</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:20:12.808857+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/transitory-soft-forks-for-consensus-cleanup-forks/1333/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Feature forks within the cryptocurrency ecosystem offer a unique approach to introducing new functionalities. These can often be emulated by a trusted third party who adheres to the proposed rules of the feature, bypassing the need for direct changes to the core protocol. This method allows for modifications either directly on platforms like Bitcoin or through additional layers such as sidechains, which provide flexibility in implementation.

Despite the theoretical feasibility of this emulation technique, its practical application seems limited, with few known examples of widespread adoption. The "covenant-less Ark" serves as a notable instance of utilizing such an approach. The Ark protocol aims to facilitate these kinds of feature additions without requiring significant alterations to the underlying blockchain structure. For further details on this methodology and its implications, references are provided to explore the concept further: [introduction to covenant-less Ark](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/clark/index.html) and [Ark release v0.2 covenant-less ark](https://arkdev.info/blog/ark-release-v0.2covenant-less-ark). These sources elaborate on how the emulation of feature forks can be achieved, showcasing the potential for adopting new features in a less invasive manner.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T10:17:02.651000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
