<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:17:28.777977+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors.617000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-03T12:41:43.617000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:17:28.778009+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the strategic considerations and technical nuances influencing the behavior of miners within the Bitcoin network, particularly in the context of artificially manipulating block rates to affect fee rates and the overall stability of the network. The concentration of mining power raises plausible concerns about the potential for a 51% attack, which could enable miners to speed up the block rate by 10% after sustaining control for 59 difficulty periods. This scenario, while not deemed dangerous at the discussed scale, underscores the delicate balance between incentivizing miner behavior and maintaining network integrity.

A pivotal aspect of the debate centers on the impact of software bugs within mining pool software, exemplified by two incidents where bugs led to the generation of invalid blocks due to reliance on the system clock rather than the block template `nTime`. This issue is further complicated by the minimum median time past (MTP) rule, which has already rendered such software susceptible to producing invalid blocks under certain conditions. The discourse suggests that the existence of these vulnerabilities does not justify loosening the constraints around block timing, especially given that no miners have yet exploited this flaw due to the hash power required to manipulate MTP relative to wall clock time.

The introduction of a timewarp rule aims to mitigate griefing attacks that exploit the time setting in block generation, contrasting two types of attacks: one relying on significant hash power and another on luck. A recent [bug fix in Bitcoin Core](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30681) addresses one such vulnerability by adjusting the mining code to prevent excessive backward time adjustments at difficulty retarget periods, thereby also addressing a second form of griefing attack.

The proposal to use a 150-minute threshold for time adjustments instead of the tighter 600-second limit is advocated as a means to accommodate existing mining software that might be inadvertently non-compliant with stricter time checks. This broader threshold aims to reduce the necessity for comprehensive software audits and updates by miners, focusing instead on requiring a simple node upgrade. This approach implicitly acknowledges the potential for unknown software issues that could arise from stricter time rules, as highlighted by examples of mining software failing to adhere correctly to the `nTime` parameter in the block template, thus risking invalid block creation under the new timewarp rule.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T12:41:43.617000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
