<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:18:40.657789+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-03T12:59:20.523000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:18:40.657826+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Nb/Nc Dynamic Adjustment Algorithm (DAA) demonstrates resilience against variations in latency topology, effectively maintaining network consensus even when a minority of miners experience significantly higher latencies. Specifically, the algorithm's stability is not compromised by up to 5% of miners facing latency that is up to 20 times higher than average. This robust performance is attributed to the DAA's method of referencing a broader spectrum of blocks—extending beyond immediate parents to include grandparents and great-grandparents within its scope of consideration. Such an approach ensures that the difficulty level remains appropriately high, aligning closely with the optimal Nb/Nc ratio of 2.42 per block for parents, as opposed to the 1.44/block ratio seen with parent-only referencing methods.

Despite the introduction of higher latency among a small fraction of miners, the grandparent method's impact on the difficulty adjustment does not significantly diverge from that observed with the parent method. This observation underscores the limited influence of a 5% hashrate contribution operating under elevated latency conditions on the overall difficulty adjustment mechanism. The maintained difficulty level, as illustrated in the referenced chart, highlights the algorithm's capacity to sustain a near-ideal difficulty setting across varying network conditions, thereby ensuring consistent block generation times and reinforcing the network's consensus mechanism.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T12:59:20.523000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
