<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:18:33.407763+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-03T13:52:30.984000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:18:33.407797+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with skepticism towards relying solely on a graph structure and the Difficulty Adjustment Algorithm (DAA) to address high latency issues in a blockchain network. It points out that high latency is already considered within the Nc/Nb method, which identifies large cohorts as a result of high latency. The concern here is that adjusting the difficulty based on these occurrences could unfairly bias the algorithm, given that large cohorts can naturally arise without indicating systemic problems or attacks.

An alternative approach proposed involves not compensating for beads (a term used here to describe units or elements within the network's structure) that exhibit abnormally high latency. To implement this, it is suggested that Braidpool, presumably a part of the network infrastructure, includes millisecond resolution timestamps in its metadata. A calculation method for determining bead latency is introduced, focusing on the median timestamps of a bead's children and parents rather than the miner's timestamp. This method aims to be resistant to manipulation by miners, who cannot predict their own latency until after their bead has been added to the network. By using external timestamps, the system intends to ensure fairness and discourage gaming.

The proposal specifies a hard cutoff for bead latency at 5 seconds, beyond which a bead would not receive a reward. This measure seeks to maintain incentive alignment for miners to name all known tips without penalizing them for natural variations in latency that can occur due to statistical distributions or network issues like extended splits. The overall aim is to ensure that rewards are distributed fairly, focusing on contributions close to the main path of highest work, while preventing high-latency beads from negatively impacting other miners' rewards.

Lastly, the message mentions ongoing simulations by a contributor named @zawy, promising further results post-holidays. It concludes with an invitation to join the [Braidpool Discord](https://discord.gg/pZYUDwkpPv) for real-time discussions, suggesting a collaborative effort to refine and improve the network's handling of latency and reward distribution.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T13:52:30.984000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
