<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:21:46.814657+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida.608000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-03T22:02:29.608000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:21:46.814689+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks/1353/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The current situation, where each party submits what it considers the newest update, poses a challenge due to the inherent risks and inefficiencies this method introduces. This approach can lead to discrepancies and conflicts regarding the authenticity and recency of the submitted updates. Such a scenario complicates the process of determining the most current and accurate state, potentially leading to delays and errors in the system's operation.

The primary vulnerability that the CLRT (Chain-Linked Resolution Technique) aims to mitigate revolves around the issue of parties intentionally or unintentionally submitting outdated states. This is particularly problematic as it could either be a tactical move to gain an undue advantage or a genuine mistake. However, the outcome remains the same: it jeopardizes the integrity and reliability of the system. The concern is not just theoretical; the possibility of both parties publishing an outdated state, whether as a strategy or an oversight, underscores the need for robust mechanisms to prevent such occurrences.

A critical analysis of the situation reveals that the delay could extend beyond twice the expected time under specific circumstances, especially if there is a strategic submission of known outdated states by both parties. This tactic would indeed be counterproductive but is a conceivable strategy that parties might employ, highlighting the complexity of ensuring timely and accurate state resolutions within such systems. This scenario further illustrates the necessity for stringent safeguards and verification protocols within the CLRT framework to address and preempt these challenges effectively.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T22:02:29.608000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
