<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-05T02:25:33.853562+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.927000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-04T08:10:18.927000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-05T02:25:33.853593+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around a mining algorithm designed to distribute rewards fairly among miners without penalizing them for latency unless it becomes excessive. This approach is critical in avoiding the creation of Bitcoin orphans and ensuring the profitability of the mining pool. The algorithm's tolerance for latency is highlighted by its proportional payment system, where miners are rewarded based on their work as long as they do not exceed a certain latency threshold. This mechanism is particularly relevant when considering the algorithm's application in different scenarios, such as a standalone consensus system versus its use in coordinating reward sharing for Bitcoin mining.

In the context of Bitcoin mining, the concept of forming independent braidpools is introduced as a solution to manage hashrate distribution and latency variations across different geographic locations. The example given illustrates a situation where a significant portion of the hashrate operates from a single data center with minimal latency, while the majority is distributed globally with higher latency. This setup suggests that having separate braidpools could be an effective way to accommodate varying latencies without compromising the overall efficiency and fairness of the mining process.

Furthermore, the discussion delves into Bitcoin’s orphan rate, comparing theoretical estimates with real-world observations provided by [fork.observer](https://fork.observer/). The analysis of orphan rates due to network latency offers insights into the implications of latency on block propagation and the potential impact on the blockchain's integrity. By examining different orphan rates under various latency conditions, the conversation sheds light on the relationship between latency, block difficulty, and the stability of mining pools.

The email also explores the response of different algorithms to changes in hashrate and latency, emphasizing the importance of a dynamic difficulty adjustment algorithm (DAA) that considers recent blocks for faster consensus. This look-back mechanism is crucial for adapting to shifts in mining power and latency, ensuring that the blockchain remains secure and functional even as network conditions change. The idea challenges a previous suggestion by Zawy to orphan high-latency beads, proposing instead an inclusive approach that does not outright penalize delays but seeks to integrate them into the consensus process without rewarding them directly. This strategy, however, raises concerns about potential exploitation by delaying the inclusion of competing beads, highlighting the need for a balance between inclusivity and fairness in the reward distribution model.

In summary, the email addresses the complexities of managing latency in Bitcoin mining, proposing solutions for fair reward distribution and discussing the technical and ethical considerations involved in maintaining a decentralized consensus system. The analysis provides valuable insights into the challenges of designing algorithms that can adapt to varying network conditions while ensuring the stability and security of the blockchain.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T08:10:18.927000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
