<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:18:32.939562+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-01-04 20:43:29.758000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:18:32.939593+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The primary concern addressed by the Cross-Layer Reflective Transactions (CLRT) revolves around reducing the duration for which liquidity remains locked within protocols. This mechanism aims to alleviate the extended periods that can arise under certain conditions, particularly when both parties involved in a transaction knowingly publish an outdated state. Such a scenario is deemed unlikely since it would be counterintuitive for both participants. The conventional method entails a potential doubling of the delay period due to the inherent structure of transactions and state updates in blockchain networks. For instance, when a new Hashed Time-Locked Contract (HTLC) is introduced to a channel that has been inactive, the process for claiming this HTLC necessitates a waiting period that could effectively double, factoring in the time required for both parties to update and acknowledge the new state.

Moreover, the introduction of CLRT seeks to streamline this process by consolidating the required delay into a single timeframe, thus enhancing the efficiency of ln-symmetry transactions. However, it's important to note that the adoption of CLRT does not inherently diminish the risks associated with liquidity locking. Participants are still advised to meticulously select their `shared_delay` parameter, which serves as a crucial safeguard against potential threats such as HTLC theft. This parameter represents a pivotal security measure, ensuring the liveliness and integrity of the transactions amidst attempts by adversaries to compromise the funds by outbidding during the delay period.

Despite these considerations, CLRT does not extensively address the theoretical vulnerabilities that may arise from its implementation. An adversary with the capacity to consistently outbid another party during the `shared_delay` interval poses a significant risk, suggesting that the security model of CLRT requires careful scrutiny and potential adjustment. Furthermore, the discussion hints at the possibility of future enhancements or modifications to existing protocols like eltoo, which could introduce mechanisms to limit the number of updates thereby potentially mitigating some of the concerns raised. The discourse surrounding CLRT underscores its nascent stage of development and the ongoing dialogue within the community to refine and adapt this concept to practical use cases. The conversation reflects a proactive approach towards exploring innovative solutions to longstanding challenges in blockchain transaction efficiency and security, highlighting the dynamic nature of technological advancement in the field.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T20:43:29.758000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
