<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
  <updated>2025-01-05T02:27:53.958744+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ademan.202000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-04T22:35:51.202000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
    <updated>2025-01-05T02:27:53.958773+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multi-party-eltoo-with-bounded-settlement/1364" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The introduction of a multi-party eltoo scheme aims to address some inherent vulnerabilities in the naive eltoo protocol by incorporating mechanisms that penalize dishonest behavior and ensure a bounded settlement time for channel states. At the core of this proposal is a method that restricts each party to a single state update opportunity on-chain, significantly reducing the potential for malicious parties to delay honest settlement. This approach relies on innovative constructs like "multi-transaction-signatures" and "floating transactions," underpinned by the anticipated LNHANCE soft fork which would introduce several new opcodes facilitating these functionalities.

Acknowledgments in the proposal highlight contributions from individuals and the broader Bitcoin development community, underscoring the collaborative effort driving the current LNHANCE efforts and the exploration of new technical solutions to enhance blockchain protocols. The scheme operates within a structured framework where state updates are controlled through a generational model. Each generation defines a set of eligible parties that can submit updates, with the complexity and number of possible update transactions increasing exponentially with the addition of more parties. Despite this, the scheme employs a technique to compress the required signatures per party, potentially making it more practical and efficient than existing methods.

The practical considerations of implementing this scheme reveal significant computational demands, attributing to the exponential growth in the number of update transactions as more parties are added. However, the analysis suggests that maintaining a practical limit on the number of participants could keep the scheme within feasible operational parameters. Future explorations might focus on improving efficiency, integrating additional security features such as watchtower compatibility, and adapting the scheme to accommodate offline users or reduce witness sizes for uncooperative closes.

Further discussions and investigations into this multi-party eltoo scheme could pave the way for more robust, efficient, and secure multi-party channels in the Bitcoin network. While acknowledging the potential overlap with existing literature and the need for further optimization, this proposal invites feedback and collaboration to refine and possibly implement the scheme, marking a step forward in the ongoing evolution of blockchain technologies. 

For those interested in delving deeper or contributing to the proof of concept, the initial implementation and its performance benchmarks have been shared [here](https://github.com/Ademan/multi-party-eltoo-with-bounded-settlement), offering a basis for further development and testing within the community.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T22:35:51.202000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
