<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[BROKEN] Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:59.132201+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ademan</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-08T00:15:37.712000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[BROKEN] Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:59.132234+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/broken-multi-party-eltoo-with-bounded-settlement/1364" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The introduction of a novel multi-party eltoo scheme aims to address the vulnerabilities inherent in naive eltoo implementations, specifically the potential for dishonest parties to delay settlement by submitting outdated transactions. This new proposal focuses on penalizing such behavior while ensuring a bounded settlement time, crucial for maintaining the integrity and efficiency of multi-party channels. By limiting each party to a single state update opportunity, the scheme significantly reduces the chance of malicious interference, thereby facilitating more honest and straightforward settlements.

The proposed system relies on an innovative construct referred to as "multi-transaction-signatures," which allows for a more streamlined and efficient process by enabling the signing of vector commitments that authorize multiple transactions. This approach, coupled with the utilization of "floating transactions" enabled by the LNHANCE soft fork through a combination of opcodes, represents a significant technical advancement in the management of multi-party channels. Notably, the scheme also considers the possibility of adapting to ANYPREVOUT(APO)+CSFS+PC, indicating flexibility and a broad potential application base.

Acknowledgements within the proposal highlight contributions from various individuals and groups, demonstrating a collaborative effort in the development and review process. The practicality of the scheme is discussed, with an emphasis on the computational complexity tied to the number of participating parties. Despite the exponential increase in required computations with each additional party, the proposal suggests a practical upper limit of approximately 10 participants, balancing efficiency and inclusivity.

Further considerations are given to potential improvements and adaptations, such as the integration with watchtower services, truncating the number of generations to reduce complexity, accommodating offline users, and optimizing communication through musig to minimize witness size. These areas of further work suggest ongoing development and refinement of the scheme, aiming at greater efficiency and applicability.

In summary, the multi-party eltoo scheme presents a sophisticated solution to the challenges faced in managing multi-party channels within blockchain networks. Its emphasis on penalizing dishonest behavior, bounded settlement times, and reduced communication overhead highlights a commitment to improving transactional integrity and efficiency. As the proposal undergoes further review and practical testing, its adaptability and potential integration with existing technologies signify a promising advancement in blockchain channel management.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:15:37.712000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
