<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:18:09.871451+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-05T09:34:34.931000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:18:09.871482+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation highlights a novel concept introduced by @rijndael, focusing on a [token standard using CAT called CatNip](https://x.com/rot13maxi/status/1833667750469804315) that paves the way for a unique implementation strategy in blockchain technology. This concept revolves around the idea of creating a "singleton," which emerges from stripping down the token elements of the CatNip standard, aiming to achieve constant-size proof of ancestry. The innovative use of CAT is showcased in two significant ways: firstly, through carrying state with additional outputs by leveraging introspection combined with the Schnorr trick, and secondly, by introspecting a parent's Script via its transaction ID (txid). 

The discussion points out the potential limitations and complexities involved in these approaches, such as the challenges associated with reading 'inside' a txid. However, it also suggests that alternative methods for creating singletons that do not rely on txid might exist, although these alternatives are not elaborated upon.

Furthermore, the dialogue touches upon the possibility of employing an opcode like OP_CHECKCONTRACTERIFY to simplify the process of carrying state without resorting to the Schnorr trick, albeit acknowledging the inherent difficulties in this method. The singleton primitive is lauded for its potential to generalize the concept of 'connector outputs,' which serve as a zero-depth proof of ancestry and are exemplified in protocols like Ark. This advancement could significantly benefit the integration of state-carrying Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) with Ark and other shared UTXO constructions, indicating a promising avenue for future blockchain development and applications.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-05T09:34:34.931000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
