<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:23:16.072459+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-07 04:06:21.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:23:16.072489+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept revolves around the necessity for transactions (txs) to be transmitted and validated rapidly, potentially every 250 milliseconds, within a share-chain block context. This process is crucial for enabling transactions to be mined outside of standard policy frameworks, such as the recovery transactions proposed by RSK, and for facilitating off-chain transaction acceleration without the need for a centralized coordinator. The introduction of [recovery txs](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/26348) and support for [off-chain tx acceleration](https://mempool.space/accelerator) exemplifies efforts to enhance transaction processing efficiency and flexibility.

Braidpool, an initiative mentioned, highlights the evolution of transaction acceptance rules that blend characteristics from Bitcoin’s peer-to-peer (P2P) rules and block rules. This hybrid approach aims to optimize transaction processing by establishing a unique set of criteria specific to Braidpool’s operations. The success of Braidpool, speculated to be significant if it achieves over 30% hashrate, could influence Bitcoin core's relay policy to align more closely with Braidpool’s practices. Such alignment would help minimize discrepancies between the blocks that are expected and those actually produced, thereby improving the predictability and consistency of transaction validation and inclusion in the blockchain. The reference to a potential modification in Bitcoin core's relay policy based on Braidpool's operational success underscores the dynamic interplay between emerging technologies and established protocols, suggesting a future where novel approaches could lead to broader changes within the blockchain ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T04:06:21.514000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
