<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:23:03.335252+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-01-07 06:20:49.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:23:03.335281+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with a focus on the necessity for RSK's recovery transactions to adhere to the `isstandard()` criteria to ensure they can be mined. This raises an initial concern about why these transactions do not already meet this standard, highlighting a potential oversight in their design or implementation.

Further exploration suggests considering off-chain transaction acceleration as a viable solution. Specifically, the proposal involves Braidpool mining such transactions within its deterministic mempool and giving them priority. However, this introduces the challenge of directing an out-of-band fee to the pool without the risk of it being diverted by competing pools through high-fee unrelated transactions. This points to a broader issue within the system that requires addressing.

The conversation then shifts towards the inherent problems associated with paying for mining outside the standard transaction fees. It is argued that such practices are indicative of a systemic flaw rather than a beneficial feature. The ability to increase transaction fees, known as fee-bumping, is presented as a more appropriate mechanism within Bitcoin's framework. This would allow users to adjust their fee offerings in response to network congestion or delays, aligning with the protocol's intended functionality.

Finally, there is agreement on the problematic nature of deviating from the peer-to-peer relay policy that underpins Bitcoin's design philosophy. This consensus underscores a shared recognition of the importance of adhering to established protocols and mechanisms for maintaining the integrity and efficiency of the network.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T06:20:49.574000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
