<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:22:51.903306+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-07 10:34:33.860000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:22:51.903342+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of blockchain and cryptocurrency, the structure of transactions (txs) within the RSK network has undergone significant changes due to identified issues in its initial setup. The original configuration of RSK's transactions presented challenges that were not detected during the testing phase, leading to problems once the system went live. This situation underscores the critical importance of comprehensive testing in identifying potential flaws before deployment in such complex systems.

The ability to directly contact miners emerged as a crucial workaround for the issues encountered with RSK's transactions. This direct line of communication allowed for immediate remediation measures, bypassing the typical constraints faced within the network's operational framework. This approach has proven beneficial not only for addressing the specific issue at hand but also in other instances where direct intervention was necessary to maintain system integrity and performance.

Furthermore, the dynamics of hashpower within the network play a pivotal role in the resolution of specialized cases. The existence of entities or individuals with significant hashpower willing to address and rectify special cases mitigates the impact of issues that might arise from the lack of support or cooperation from a single pool or even the majority of hashpower holders. This flexibility within the network’s operational paradigm ensures a level of resilience and adaptability in managing and resolving unforeseen challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T10:34:33.860000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
