<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:19:56.000553+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-07T15:24:23.147000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:19:56.000580+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/64" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussions within a [private forum](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/worst-block-validation-time-inquiry/711?u=antoinep) have culminated in a significant proposal aimed at enhancing the worst-case validation time for blocks. Initially, the discourse revolved around mitigating strategies that had been previously suggested in 2019, accessible via a [GitHub proposal](https://github.com/TheBlueMatt/bips/blob/7f9670b643b7c943a0cc6d2197d3eabe661050c2/bip-XXXX.mediawikispecification). However, a realization emerged that an adaptation could effectively sidestep these earlier mitigations, spurring a detailed discussion spanning nearly a year. The dialogue engaged numerous participants, with notable contributions from Anthony Towns, who provided valuable insights, corrections, and fostered constructive debate.

The deliberation scrutinized various mitigation options, carefully weighing their impact, complexity, and the potential for confiscatory consequences. After thorough analysis, a consensus formed around the introduction of a specific rule: imposing a limit of 2,500 sigops for legacy inputs (encompassing both bare and P2SH formats) per transaction. This measure is anticipated to yield a fortyfold reduction in the worst-case validation time, representing a significant efficiency gain. It was selected for its simplicity, effectiveness, and minimal confiscatory implications. Although further enhancements were considered through the implementation of an additional rule, which promised to amplify the decrease in validation time by sevenfold, this option was ultimately deemed less favorable due to its greater confiscatory risk.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T15:24:23.147000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
