<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2025-01-08T02:24:59.862253+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vnprc</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-07T22:29:36.074000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T02:24:59.862288+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/32" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The person has been focused on developing a novel concept in isolation, which addresses various issues previously discussed within the community. Their project, showcased on [GitHub](https://github.com/vnprc/hashpool), introduces a unique approach to handling eCash tokens and mining shares, proposing that eCash tokens should only be redeemable once to preserve privacy and enhance value for all shareowners within a specific window. This method emulates Fixed Pay Per Share (FPPS) payouts without introducing trust assumptions and paves the way for an efficient futures market in the mining sphere.

In their detailed exploration, they highlight the application of Calle's Proof of Liabilities (PoL) protocol, which imposes a time arrow on mint operations to facilitate payout calculations and token issuance within designated ecash epochs. This system effectively segments shares into time windows, aiding in the accurate calculation of payouts and establishing a self-auditing mechanism for eCash mints by comparing proofs of collateral against liabilities. The discussion further delves into the auditing aspects of eCash mints, likening them to banks where assets and liabilities must be transparently audited. The proposal suggests a method to verify the validity of mining shares through a combination of block template, header, nonce data, and a merkle sum tree, aiming to address the industry-wide challenge of validating share contributions without compromising privacy.

Moreover, the correspondence outlines three primary goals: decentralizing block template production, creating a new Free Open Source Software (FOSS) and Know Your Customer (KYC)-free Bitcoin onramp, and lowering the threshold for mining withdrawals to enable more individual participation. An insightful revelation led to recognizing the benefits of Pseudonymous Pay Per Last N Shares (PPLNS) payouts in fostering a layered bitcoin mining ecosystem. This model allows smaller pools to operate under larger ones, circumventing the initial hurdle of achieving sufficient hash rates independently. It emphasizes economic efficiency over the traditional Fixed Pay Per Share (FPPS) model, which assumes the role of pricing hashrate risk onto the miners, thereby fostering a more decentralized and scalable mining infrastructure. This setup encourages experimentation with payout mechanisms, authentication processes, block template production, and more, potentially revolutionizing how mining pools function and contributing to a broader distribution of block rewards.

The enthusiasm for a decentralized approach is evident as it hints at the transformative potential of enabling numerous small mining pools to innovate in areas like coinbase and block template selection, which could drastically alter the landscape of Bitcoin mining and its associated privacy and transaction capabilities. The vision shared is one of resilience and innovation, challenging the status quo and inviting further exploration and development in this promising area.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T22:29:36.074000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
