<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2025-01-09T02:50:28.578952+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-08T19:26:22.934000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2025-01-09T02:50:28.578989+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/35" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the process of validating individual shares within a cryptocurrency mining framework, a method is proposed that involves utilizing a lookup table containing block template, header, and nonce data. By combining these elements into a complete bitcoin block, which likely exhibits insufficient proof of work, one can hash the header and subsequently provide a merkle proof for that specific header. The integrity and sum of difficulty of accepted shares are verified through a merkle sum tree of block header hashes.

The concept extends to the valuation of eHash tokens, which are assessed based on the difficulty level. This valuation is then directly compared against the sum of liabilities, as detailed in the Proof of Liabilities report. The liabilities are calculated by subtracting burn proofs from mint proofs, excluding any ecash redemptions, thereby providing a transparent and verifiable account of the network's obligations versus its assets.

The exploration of an appropriate payout formula for miners who contribute their computational power raises the question of whether to adopt a Basic Pay-Per-Last-N-Shares (PPLNS), TIDES, or an alternative modified PPLNS algorithm. The discussion suggests a potential alignment with the PPLNS with Job Declaration (PPLN-JD) accounting schema, which is explored further in the [PPLN-JD post](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/pplns-with-job-declaration/1099). This schema is highlighted for its complementary approach to share accounting and auditing, suggesting it could be effectively integrated into the eHash framework to ensure fairness and transparency in miner rewards.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-08T19:26:22.934000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
