<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-14T02:15:51.841848+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida.780000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-13T19:42:38.780000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T02:15:51.841884+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a recent discussion, the intricacies of Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLC) settlements on the Lightning Network (LN) were explored. The primary focus was on the maximum duration an HTLC could take to settle, which is identified as twice the `shared_delay` period. This timeframe is critical for ensuring that transactions are completed successfully without undue delay or vulnerability to malicious activities.

The conversation also touched upon the potential for abuse by a channel partner who might attempt to broadcast new update transactions beyond the established 2x `shared_delay` window. To counteract this, it was suggested that Symmetry HTLCs should have longer expiration times than Penalty HTLCs. This strategy aims not only to safeguard against possible attacks but also to enhance the efficiency of capital utilization within the LN framework.

Furthermore, it was clarified that the implementation of CLRT (Commitment-Lightning Round Trip) protocols is not specifically designed to address any direct attack vectors. Instead, CLRT's primary purpose is to optimize the use of capital within the Lightning Network by ensuring timely and secure transaction settlements. This approach underscores the ongoing efforts to refine and improve the operational efficiency of LN, making it a more robust and reliable platform for users.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-13T19:42:38.780000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
