<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
  <updated>2025-01-18T02:11:44.550298+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jaonoctus</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-17T19:46:09.699000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Unspendable keys in descriptors</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T02:11:44.550336+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/unspendable-keys-in-descriptors/304/32" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The creation of a NUMS key generator and validator is an innovative approach to cryptographic keys, closely following the guidelines set out in BIP-0341. This method, characterized by the equation `H + r*G`, stands out for producing keys that, while not appearing to be Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve (NUMS) at first glance, can indeed be verified as such by revealing the variable `r`. This technique offers a compelling blend of secrecy and verifiability, making it a significant development in the field of cryptography.

Further exploration into this domain involves the ambitious goal of generating a valid signature without the need to disclose `r`, as hinted at by cryptographer Pieter Wuille (@sipa). Such advancements could potentially redefine secure communication protocols, enhancing privacy and security in digital transactions. 

For those interested in delving deeper into this subject, additional resources and examples of this technology in action can be found through detailed documentation and transaction records available online. Notably, the practical application of this method has been illustrated via a specific key path and transaction, accessible at [Jaonoctus's NUMS-secp256k1](https://nums-secp256k1.jaonoctus.dev/?pk=2575ac0d328639136911eb82d6164b64908fef69f2c7df59314bdcae29653c26&amp;input=jaonoctus+unspendable+key-path) and [Mempool's Signet transaction detail page](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/080af3e3b86e10f1455719281f2727c4410f2480a8541d50583cbe11e6cb56d0), respectively. These resources serve as practical demonstrations of the theoretical concepts discussed, offering valuable insights into the real-world applications of such cryptographic innovations.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-17T19:46:09.699000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
