<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-01-24T02:16:01.411838+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-23T22:37:29.313000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T02:16:01.411872+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation revolves around the concept of the "extra pool" in compact block reconstruction, a technique aimed at optimizing the efficiency of block transmission in blockchain networks. This method particularly addresses issues related to bandwidth constraints and seeks to improve the speed and reliability of block propagation.

Compact block reconstruction involves creating a smaller version of a block by using information that is already available at the receiving node, thus minimizing the amount of data that needs to be transmitted. The "extra pool" functions as a supplementary storage area that holds transactions not yet included in the main blockchain but are candidates for inclusion in the next block. This approach significantly reduces the redundancy of transaction data transmission, enhancing the overall network performance.

Moreover, the mechanism supports the rapid dissemination of new transactions across the network, ensuring that nodes have up-to-date information for constructing complete blocks. By leveraging the "extra pool," nodes can more efficiently manage their bandwidth and storage resources, contributing to a leaner and more scalable blockchain infrastructure. This technique not only optimizes data exchange among nodes but also strengthens the resilience of the network against various types of disruptions and attacks, thereby bolstering the security and integrity of the blockchain.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-23T22:37:29.313000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
