<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Full Disclosure: Replacement Cycling Attacks on Bitcoin Miners Block Templates</title>
  <updated>2025-01-28T02:15:35.981622+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2025-01-27 15:38:22.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Full Disclosure: Replacement Cycling Attacks on Bitcoin Miners Block Templates</title>
    <updated>2025-01-28T02:15:35.981660+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/full-disclosure-replacement-cycling-attacks-on-bitcoin-miners-block-templates/1405" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In recent developments within the cryptocurrency security domain, a significant vulnerability was identified and tested against Bitcoin Core's 26.0 branch, highlighting concerns regarding the replace-by-fee mechanism and its implications for the security integrity of Lightning channels. This vulnerability, initially disclosed on October 16, 2023, has sparked considerable attention among cryptocurrency experts and analysts, including Peter Todd, who have noted that replacement cycling attacks pose a real threat to the stability and reliability of miners' block templates.

The essence of these attacks lies in their ability to manipulate transaction replacements in a way that compromises the miners' ability to create valid and secure block templates, a critical component in the blockchain's operation. This vulnerability was not only demonstrated on the traditional mempool associated with Bitcoin Core's 26.0 version but was also evident in subsequent tests conducted on the cluster mempool system present in the Bitcoin Core 29.0 branch. Such findings underscore the adaptability and persistence of this attack vector across different versions of the Bitcoin Core, pointing to a systemic issue that requires immediate and thorough resolution.

To facilitate a broader understanding and foster collaborative efforts towards addressing this critical security flaw, a comprehensive disclosure detailing the attack mechanism, its implications, and potential mitigation strategies was shared with the bitcoin development community. Interested individuals and parties are encouraged to review the detailed documentation available at [this link](https://ariard.github.io/minerjamming.html), which provides an extensive overview of the attack methodology and its impact on Bitcoin's infrastructure. Additionally, for those seeking a more technical deep dive into the nuances of this security challenge, a scholarly paper has been published and can be accessed [here](https://github.com/ariard/mempool-research/blob/6de7d8bb15f28b7444328335231e6b6d33f2a0af/rca-bmbt.pdf), offering an in-depth discussion on the novel attack vectors targeting Bitcoin miners and proposing avenues for future research and potential solutions to enhance the resilience of Bitcoin's network against such vulnerabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-27T15:38:22.861000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
