<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-01-29T02:15:04.774050+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sanket1729.644000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-28T22:28:00.644000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T02:15:04.774080+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email primarily addresses concerns and queries regarding the interaction of a specific code implementation with lightning channel closures within the context of blockchain technology and payment routing. The sender expresses commendation for the progress made on a particular issue that has been a subject of brainstorming for some time. An interest is shown in understanding how the newly implemented code deals with the intricacies of lightning channel closures, especially concerning the maintenance of an effective payment routing system.

A significant concern raised is about the necessity of updating the payment routing graph to reflect closed channels accurately. This update is crucial for the network's integrity and efficiency, ensuring that payments are not routed through non-existent or closed channels. The query delves into the technicalities of whether this process involves direct observation of the blockchain by nodes or if it utilizes lightning routing messages specifically designed for channel closure events.

Another point of inquiry pertains to the potential privacy implications of channel closures. The sender is curious about whether the zero-knowledge (ZK) benefits, presumably associated with maintaining anonymity or privacy within transactions, would be compromised upon the leakage of the `channel_id` during the channel closing process. This aspect touches on the broader theme of balancing transparency and privacy in blockchain applications, particularly in the context of decentralized payment networks.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-28T22:28:00.644000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
