<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
  <updated>2025-01-30T02:19:09.169722+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>olkurbatov.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-29T11:17:08.789000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T02:19:09.169754+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/emulating-op-rand/1409" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposed method introduces a novel way to emulate randomness within Bitcoin transactions through a trustless interactive game, circumventing the limitations of the Bitcoin script which inherently lacks direct support for randomness and inspection of blockchain elements. This emulation strategy does not necessitate any updates to the Bitcoin protocol nor the introduction of special scripts, making it indiscernible to external observers. The essence of this approach is illustrated through the implementation of a simple Thimbles Game, where participants engage in a probabilistic protocol that ensures fairness without allowing any party an undue advantage at any stage.

Bitcoin's scripting capabilities are currently unable to accommodate operations based on randomness due to several constraints. These include the inability to derive randomness at the point of transaction confirmation, inspect blocks or other transactions, ensure uniform state sharing among parties post-operation, and control over the determinism of ECDSA or Schnorr signatures. Additionally, Bitcoin does not support an OP_RAND opcode, limiting the creation of trustless systems that leverage randomness directly within the Bitcoin protocol.

To address these challenges, the proposal outlines a two-party interactive protocol that enables the emulation of randomness. This is achieved by employing cryptographic techniques and commitments, ensuring that neither party can manipulate the outcome to their benefit. The process involves the creation and commitment to random values, verification through cryptographic proofs, and a conditional transaction mechanism whereby the outcome dictates the ability of each party to claim funds.

The protocol's application is demonstrated through the Thimbles Game, where players lock in funds and engage in a series of steps involving the generation, selection, and revelation of values associated with thimbles. The game's structure ensures that neither participant knows the other's chosen value until the reveal phase, at which point the correct guess allows a player to claim the locked funds. This example illustrates the protocol's potential to facilitate fair and secure games or applications requiring randomness, without reliance on external oracles or updates to the underlying Bitcoin protocol.

Through this innovative approach, the proposal offers a practical solution to introducing randomness into Bitcoin transactions in a manner that is both trustless and transparent. The methodology promises broad applicability for developing decentralized applications that require fair and unpredictable outcomes without departing from the existing Bitcoin infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-29T11:17:08.789000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
