<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-01T02:23:06.963022+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-31T13:25:10.101000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T02:23:06.963052+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussed implementation explores the efficiency of utilizing Utreexo, a method for handling Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), in comparison to generating a fresh UTXO snapshot every six hours. The initial approach taken involved creating a Merkle tree from a complete UTXO set dump, a process that required approximately ten minutes without any optimization. The significance of Utreexo lies in its ability to create proofs without necessitating the storage of the full UTXO set, thereby offering compatibility with light clients. This aspect is crucial as it facilitates the revelation of keys (or node IDs) utilized in forming an aggregated key, enhancing the utility of this method in specific scenarios.

Moreover, the conversation brings up the potential of employing ring signatures as a means to achieve similar outcomes, indicating an interest in further exploration of this technique. An innovative suggestion raised during the discussion involves dividing the UTXO snapshot into separate trees based on different amount ranges. This would allow for proving transactions against a singular amount range, potentially streamlining the verification process and improving overall efficiency. The positive reception to this idea reflects a commitment to exploring various methodologies to enhance the effectiveness of handling UTXOs within blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T13:25:10.101000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
