<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
  <updated>2025-02-01T02:23:42.163149+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard.355000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-31T18:00:52.355000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T02:23:42.163180+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/which-ephemeral-anchor-script-should-lightning-use/1412/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the optimal approach for handling transactions in a manner that minimizes risks such as transaction hijacking by miners. A key recommendation against employing unkeyed anchors is emphasized due to the associated vulnerabilities highlighted in a detailed analysis found in a [Bitcoin development forum post](https://groups.google.com/g/bitcoindev/c/ZspZzO4sBys), specifically within section 6.4 titled "transaction traffic hijack and policy exposure surface." This cautionary stance points towards the potential dangers of this method, underlining the need for more secure alternatives.

A viable alternative presented involves allowing each counterparty to manage its own commitment transaction along with a Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) strategy without interference from others. This approach is favored over a straightforward replacement at the root of the Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) set, suggesting a more nuanced method of transaction management that respects the autonomy of each party involved. Additionally, while other keyed options are deemed somewhat acceptable, there remains a preference for solutions that offer greater security and control.

In terms of fee-bumping delegation, the usage of pre-signed transactions marked with `ANYONECANPAY` is advocated. This setup permits the delegate and the delegatee to engage in transactions securely, ensuring that the delegator cannot pin or otherwise manipulate the transaction. This recommendation supports a framework where transactions can be conducted with flexibility and safety, emphasizing the importance of carefully considering transaction methods to protect against vulnerabilities such as miner-led hijacking.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T18:00:52.355000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
