<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Erlay: Filter fanout candidates based on transaction knowledge</title>
  <updated>2025-02-01T02:25:55.565727+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sr-gi.159000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-01-31T21:19:46.159000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Erlay: Filter fanout candidates based on transaction knowledge</title>
    <updated>2025-02-01T02:25:55.565760+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/erlay-filter-fanout-candidates-based-on-transaction-knowledge/1416" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of the Erlay protocol's implementation and its impact on Bitcoin network efficiency reveals several key insights into peer selection strategies for transaction propagation. The primary concern is whether or not to include peers already aware of a transaction in the dissemination process. The intuitive approach might suggest excluding these peers to maintain a high fanout rate, especially during the initial phases of transaction propagation when fewer nodes are aware of it. This methodology posits that as the transaction becomes more widely known, the selection pool would naturally shrink, thereby reducing the fanout rate in a controlled manner.

However, the empirical data from simulations conducted with a network model comprising 110,000 nodes (with 10,000 reachable and 100,000 unreachable nodes) challenges this assumption. It was anticipated that filtering out peers with prior knowledge of the transaction would significantly impact the propagation dynamics. Surprisingly, the results indicated no notable difference between employing a filtering strategy and opting not to filter based on transaction awareness.

This unexpected outcome prompts a deeper investigation into the mechanics of transaction propagation within the Bitcoin network. Specifically, the role of unreachable nodes emerges as a crucial factor in understanding the observed phenomena. Unreachable nodes, which predominantly announce transactions via outbound connections, exhibit almost exclusive reliance on direct announcements for transaction knowledge. This contrasts sharply with reachable nodes, which demonstrate a broader distribution of transaction awareness due to their higher connectivity.

Further experimentation with the delay parameters of `GETDATA` requests sheds additional light on the situation. Adjustments to these parameters influence the spread of transaction information across the network, highlighting the significance of communication latency in the overall propagation process. In essence, the delay before a node receives a transaction and schedules its announcement plays a pivotal role in determining the spread of knowledge about that transaction.

In conclusion, the findings elucidate the complex interplay between network topology, node behavior, and propagation strategies within the Bitcoin ecosystem. Despite initial hypotheses, the decision to filter peers based on their existing knowledge of transactions proves largely inconsequential for overall propagation efficiency. This revelation underscores the importance of considering the unique characteristics of the Bitcoin network when devising optimization strategies for transaction dissemination.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T21:19:46.159000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
