<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-03T02:21:42.668760+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-01-02 19:16:14.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-01-02 17:18:06.007000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-01-02 16:04:00.283000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-01-02 14:47:10.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-01 01:21:03.301000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-31 04:30:09.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3923_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3921_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3920_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3917_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3909_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3903_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T02:21:42.668835+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an exploration of optimizing the Bitcoin orphan rate through a novel approach that combines elements of graph theory and difficulty adjustment algorithms. The proposed method focuses on targeting a specific ratio of parent blocks to reduce the percentage of blocks that would have been orphaned, aiming for a balance that minimizes latency without incentivizing geographic centralization. This approach is distinguished by its use of the average width of the Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG), measured by the ratio of share-chain blocks (beads) to total-ordered consensus points (cuts). The innovative aspect of this strategy lies in its clock-free mechanism for difficulty retargeting, which seeks to maximize global consensus points, thereby enhancing network security and efficiency while curbing manipulation tactics prevalent in traditional difficulty adjustment algorithms.

Further analysis unveils a significant challenge in maintaining consensus within blockchain networks, particularly in scenarios involving high-latency miners. By introducing a method that considers grandparents and possibly great-grandparents in the difficulty adjustment algorithm (DAA), the system aims to accurately account for variations in miner latency. This nuanced approach allows for an adaptive difficulty that favors the network's overall latency distribution, thus encouraging lower latency without disproportionately benefiting those who achieve it. The concept draws inspiration from prior research suggesting adjustments not based on hashrate but on the percentage of blocks not included in the main chain. Such mechanisms aim to deter collusion and optimize block rates within acceptable limits of orphaned blocks, although they might inadvertently promote miner colocation.

A comprehensive evaluation of various algorithms underlines the importance of adaptability to changes in network conditions such as hashrate and latency. Among the methods examined, the Simple Moving Average (SMA) algorithm stands out for its proficiency in adjusting to hashrate fluctuations, albeit with noted limitations in responding to latency shifts. Alternative approaches, like the Nb/Nc method and the "parent method," offer varying degrees of responsiveness and stability, emphasizing the trade-offs between computational demand and adjustment accuracy. These discussions highlight the intricate balance required to refine blockchain algorithms for enhanced performance and fairness.

The conversation extends into theoretical considerations surrounding the impact of constant latency values in competitive environments, such as cryptocurrency mining. The critique addresses the potential for strategic optimization through resource colocation, raising questions about the fairness and scalability of difficulty adjustment mechanisms in face of significant geographic and operational diversity among miners. This segues into speculative scenarios involving interplanetary mining operations, illustrating the complex dynamics at play when extending blockchain technology beyond Earth's confines.

The Braid Consensus algorithm represents a forward-thinking approach to achieving consensus in decentralized networks. By intertwining multiple blockchain strands, this model promises improvements in scalability and security. The documentation emphasizes the role of community involvement and open-source development in refining this consensus model, suggesting a collaborative path toward overcoming existing limitations in blockchain architectures.

Lastly, the correspondence touches upon a theoretical result poised to influence future blockchain developments, despite its current lack of practical application. This reflects a broader theme within the programming and research community, where theoretical innovation continues to drive dialogue and exploration, even in the absence of immediate real-world implementation.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T19:16:14.403000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
