<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-04-09T02:38:17.622913+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2025-04-08 16:43:45.487000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-04-08 16:06:52.816000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2025-04-08 13:50:16.397000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-03-24 19:26:58.876000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-05 04:51:21.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-02-04 14:03:58.047000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-04 07:44:49.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-02-03 14:16:02.273000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-02 03:30:20.192000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-31 20:45:26.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-01-31 13:31:01.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-24 00:42:29.140000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-23 22:37:29.313000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-23 21:00:49.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2025-01-23 17:14:31.157000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-23 14:46:08.743000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2025-01-23 08:49:12.690000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-20 14:43:27.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-01-20 10:51:08.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2025-01-19 15:21:50.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-19 13:26:01.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-01-19 11:03:42.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-08 10:17:20.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-08-06 13:41:52.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-04 15:45:21.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-02 12:08:52.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4731_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4730_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4726_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4596_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4180_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4167_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4163_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4152_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4146_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4129_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4121_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4094_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4093_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4092_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4090_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4088_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4087_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4080_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4079_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4078_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4077_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4076_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2928_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2920_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2913_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2911_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-04-09T02:38:17.623080+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an exploration of Bitcoin network optimization, particularly during periods of elevated mempool activity, various node adjustments reveal insights into improving transaction handling and block reconstruction efficiency. One notable adjustment involved setting the `blockreconstructionextratxn` parameter to `10000` on a node named `alice`, resulting in noticeable performance enhancements. This setting adjustment underscores the potential benefits of managing extra transactions more effectively. Further advancements were made through updates to nodes `charlie` and `erin`, implementing a novel approach for resolving orphan transactions as detailed in a GitHub pull request. However, these updates did not yield immediate performance improvements. A software upgrade on node `ian` from Bitcoin Core `v26.1` to `v29.0rc1` addressed previous shortcomings and highlighted the importance of default support for `mempoolfullrbf` for optimal node performance. The limitations faced by nodes like `mike`, which do not accept inbound connections, contrast with the superior performance of nodes that do, underscoring the value of connectivity in network health. Initiatives to enhance compact block announcements through strategic prefilling aim to reduce propagation time and bandwidth wastage, with ongoing work reflected in the branch [2025-03-prefill-compactblocks](https://github.com/0xB10C/bitcoin/commits/2025-03-prefill-compactblocks/).

The selection of transmission protocols plays a critical role in decentralized network communications, with a focus on minimizing latency issues inherent to TCP by utilizing UDP, as demonstrated by FIBRE. This protocol choice emphasizes the need for speed and efficiency in network performance. Consideration of TCP's characteristics suggests potential impacts on system responsiveness and efficiency.

Investigations into the prefilled transactions' efficacy in blockchain networks highlight the assumption that not all transactions within a block are known to all peers. By sending certain transactions immediately, network performance may be optimized. Empirical evidence is sought through analysis of `getblocktxn` messages, with experimental adjustments aiming to assess the impact of enhanced transaction pre-filling during full mempool conditions.

The integration of FIBRE code into the Bitcoin network raises questions regarding licensing compatibility and the feasibility of implementation strategies. An offline discussion concluded that updating the FIBRE patch set and reinstating public servers would be beneficial, despite development challenges. This decision reflects a prioritization of impactful enhancements over alternative improvements.

Transaction handling and data propagation optimization discussions suggest refining the process by evaluating different types of transactions for inclusion in the `vExtraTxnForCompact` buffer. The effectiveness of including orphans directly into blocks is questioned, with a focus on identifying transactions that peers are likely unaware of to improve efficiency. The exploration into the handling of orphanage blocks reveals technical challenges related to short ID computation, necessitating an exhaustive search through the orphanage to maintain blockchain integrity.

The management of transactions within systems such as libbitcoin, which retains all received transactions indefinitely, poses significant security and operational risks, particularly concerning DoS attacks. An alternative proposition involves backing the mempool with a database store to manage ejected transactions more effectively, drawing inspiration from libbitcoin's approach to transaction storage.

A significant update merged into the Bitcoin repository aims to optimize orphan transaction handling by requesting parental data directly from peers. This strategy seeks to streamline transaction verification and integration into the blockchain, reflecting broader efforts to tackle scalability and efficiency challenges within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.

A programmer's examination of a specific patch highlights the need for a methodical approach to understand discrepancies in transaction recognition by nodes. The investigation considers factors such as fee rates, transaction age, and standardness, proposing strategies to improve node reliability and efficiency in transaction handling.

An analytical approach to identifying non-standard transactions within low-numbered blocks provides insights into potential influences on network behavior, suggesting areas for improvement in transaction processing systems. Additionally, the exploration of compact block reconstructions underlines the efficiency differences between low-bandwidth and high-bandwidth modes, highlighting opportunities for optimization, especially in the context of the upcoming Bitcoin Core v28.0 release.

Overall, these discussions and investigations underscore the complexity of optimizing transaction handling and block reconstruction processes within the Bitcoin network. They highlight the importance of connectivity, protocol selection, and strategic management of transactions to enhance network performance and resilience.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-08T16:43:45.487000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
