<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-01-03T02:19:17.206562+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2025-01-02 19:14:16.333000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-10-22 19:51:57.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-13 02:40:40.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick  . 2024-06-08 21:11:13.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3922_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2024/3397_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2708_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2670_Proposing-a-P2QRH-BIP-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T02:19:17.206613+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discourse within the cryptographic community, particularly among those developing Bitcoin's infrastructure, illustrates a proactive and cautious approach towards quantum resistance. The concern centers on the potential for quantum computing to disrupt current cryptographic standards, prompting discussions on the necessity of preparing for such advancements well in advance. Adam Back's caution against hastily integrating existing post-quantum signing algorithms into high-assurance products like Bitcoin is highlighted as a prudent stance. This reflects an understanding that the landscape of quantum computing and its impact on cryptography is likely to evolve significantly before posing a real threat to systems like Bitcoin.

An innovative strategy proposed involves leveraging hash-based signature algorithms (HBS) to transition Bitcoin users towards quantum-resistant keys without immediate consensus changes. This method suggests using a secret key derived from a seed value through HBS, thereby preparing for a future where quantum computing could invalidate existing cryptographic methods. By incorporating a fallback mechanism using Winternitz OTS, a one-time signature algorithm, this approach provides a safeguard without necessitating immediate modifications to Bitcoin's consensus or scalability structures. The anticipation of developing more scalable and secure post-quantum algorithms underscores a forward-thinking approach, aiming for client-side adaptations first, with consensus changes to follow as quantum threats become imminent.

Further, the dynamic nature of these discussions is demonstrated by the continuous revisions of the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), with the latest version accessible through a provided GitHub link. This evolving document represents the collaborative effort of the community to refine and update strategies in response to both emerging threats and technological advancements.

The initial BIP draft aims to introduce quantum resistance into the Bitcoin protocol deliberately and methodically. Recognizing the slow development and activation process within the network, early action is advocated to mitigate potential quantum vulnerabilities effectively. This represents an initial step in a series of proposals focusing on developing a "QuBit" soft fork, designed to protect Bitcoin against quantum computing threats. Open for public review, this BIP invites feedback and discussion from developers and stakeholders, marking it as a work in progress. Through this collaborative process, the proposal seeks to validate its approaches, adjust as necessary, and evaluate the significance of pursuing quantum resistance at this stage. Access to the most current iteration of the BIP is facilitated through another provided GitHub link, encouraging further contributions from the broader community.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T19:14:16.333000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
