<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-07T02:26:01.852985+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode 2025-01-06 15:18:45.813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rijndael 2025-01-06 14:40:49.671000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-01-06 13:48:25.298000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-06 06:55:17.757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3982_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3979_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3978_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3972_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-07T02:26:01.853045+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Ademan's proposal for multi-party penalty optional rebindable channels introduces a mechanism that limits the number of updates to the number of channel participants. This unique approach allows each update to be identifiable by its sequence, enabling a reduction in settlement delay with each subsequent update. Notably, for two-party channels, this implies that only one settlement delay needs to be tolerated, potentially allowing for immediate settlement on the final permissible update.

In another innovative development within the realm of Bitcoin scripting and smart contracts, the utilization of the Schnorr signature algorithm in conjunction with CAT (Concatenate All Transactions) operations facilitates the retrieval of various transaction elements onto the stack. This technique enables the enforcement of transactions returning to the same taproot address by ensuring a match between an input's scriptpubkey and an output scriptpubkey. This capability serves as the foundation for creating state machines where different contract states are represented by distinct tapleafs, which validate state transitions. An in-depth exploration of this method, including the underlying Schnorr mathematics, was presented at Bitcoin++, details of which can be found [here](https://t.co/tQJQoWepcK).

The concept of "state caboose," as it has come to be known, involves passing state information from one transaction to the next. By embedding a state commitment in an output of one transaction and then verifying this commitment in a subsequent transaction, it is possible to create a continuous chain of state that is verified against the transaction ID (TXID) of previous transactions. This approach not only allows for the seamless transition of state across transactions but also supports the implementation of complex contract validity rules, such as signature verification, amount validation, and timelock enforcement. Moreover, this technique enables a constant-sized inductive proof of contract validity, significantly reducing the blockchain space required for contract execution.

Further advancements in this area include the possibility of delegating contract validity rules to external scripts through commitments made in the state caboose. This delegation mechanism can serve as a basis for contract upgrades or extensions, offering a flexible and efficient means of evolving contract logic over time. The exploration of additional opcodes, such as CCV or TAPTWEAK, alongside specialized introspection opcodes, promises to further refine and simplify the implementation of these concepts, enhancing their utility and accessibility within the blockchain ecosystem.

An interesting aspect of contract identity management emerges from the discussion on singleton tokens, which aims to streamline the proof of ancestry within contracts. By treating the contract's identity as an NFT (Non-Fungible Token), it is possible to limit introspection to a single step, thereby optimizing the process of verifying contract updates and settlements. This approach introduces a novel method of managing contract updates, where the update submission incurs overhead costs, shifting the financial burden away from honest participants during settlement. This strategy not only ensures the efficiency and security of contract execution but also aligns with the principles of relay and consensus safety within the blockchain network.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-06T15:18:45.813000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
