<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-02-02T02:19:19.033655+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-01 23:32:56.872000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-01 18:27:06.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-01 18:23:23.796000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-01 18:23:07.915000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-01 18:06:59.299000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-01 18:06:05.384000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-01 07:35:35.235000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-01 07:33:33.885000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-31 21:10:38.510000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-31 21:03:05.366000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo  . 2025-01-29 14:35:08.640000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-29 14:05:48.215000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo  . 2025-01-29 13:09:02.447000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>lorbax  . 2025-01-07 12:37:16.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-06 20:12:46.073000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>lorbax  . 2025-01-06 18:59:43.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-06 17:37:34.243000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>lorbax  . 2025-01-06 17:30:02.016000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2024-02-22 10:29:02.906000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto  . 2024-02-22 10:22:58.404000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2023-12-20 03:59:33.881000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4145_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4142_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4141_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4140_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4139_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4138_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4135_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4136_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4131_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4132_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4110_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4109_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4106_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4002_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3992_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3991_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3987_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3985_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1667_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1665_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2023/788_How-to-linearize-your-cluster.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-02-02T02:19:19.033792+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an analysis of the inherent challenges in optimizing transaction processing within cryptocurrency networks, focusing on the need for efficient algorithms that can handle large clusters of transactions. The primary goal is to sort these transactions based not only on their fee rates but also while maintaining a topological order that respects the dependencies among transactions. This task involves not just a straightforward linearization based on fee rates but also potentially complex post-processing to achieve optimal results. For smaller and more common clusters, advanced techniques beyond simple sorting methods are necessary to optimize the processing efficiently.

The conversation then shifts to the exploration of advanced linearization strategies, particularly those that address the connectivity within transaction clusters. By identifying and optimizing connected components within a cluster, the process becomes more manageable, allowing for individual groups within the larger cluster to be processed separately. One highlighted approach is bottleneck splitting, which targets transactions that are central to the cluster's structure, thus enabling the remainder of the cluster to be processed in a piecemeal fashion. However, the core challenge in this optimization process remains the identification of the highest-feerate subsets within a cluster, a problem that is recognized as NP-hard. Iterative search approaches aim to solve this by evaluating potential subsets and refining them through branching paths, with efficiency gains achieved by bounding the evaluation of subsets and employing techniques like 'jump ahead' to expedite the inclusion of certain transactions based on their ancestry.

Further, the dialogue delves into the specifics of improving the efficiency of these algorithms. Strategies such as using conservative upper bounds to limit the evaluation of subsets, employing a Last-In-First-Out stack approach for processing work items, and caching strategies to minimize recalculations are discussed. Early comparisons between the potential set's feerate and the current best subset help prevent unnecessary computations, streamlining the overall process. The initial setup of the algorithm with the best ancestor set ensures that the performance is at least equal to simpler linearization methods, setting a foundation for further optimizations.

The [current implementation](https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/blob/wip_memepool_fuzz/src/cluster_linearize.h) of this selection algorithm, while diverging slightly from its theoretical underpinning by not universally implementing connected-component splitting, still incorporates many of the proposed ideas. It benefits from managing work items across multiple LIFO stacks and strategically selecting transactions to minimize the search space, highlighting the ongoing efforts to refine and enhance the efficiency of transaction processing within the blockchain framework. This discourse underscores the complexity and dynamism involved in optimizing cryptocurrency transaction processing, illustrating both the challenges and innovative approaches being explored to improve scalability and efficiency in network operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-01T23:32:56.872000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
