<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Minimal signing flow changes for TRUC channels</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T02:24:04.229915+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.383000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  ..859000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..713000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  ..106000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..829000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  ..535000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4166_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4162_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4154_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4147_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4133_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4130_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4128_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4126_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Minimal signing flow changes for TRUC channels</title>
    <updated>2025-02-05T02:24:04.229983+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-truc-channels/1414" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the technical aspects of managing commitment transactions within blockchain technology, focusing specifically on the Lightning Network and its use of Hashed Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs) and Point Time-Locked Contracts (PTLCs). This discussion is pivotal for understanding the intricacies involved in ensuring secure and efficient transactions between parties. The scenario presented involves a transaction between two entities, Alice and Bob, where the structure and security of commitment transactions come under scrutiny. The methodology discussed aims to resolve potential vulnerabilities that could arise when one party withholds actions that could compromise the transaction's completion. This issue is of particular concern in situations where Alice might not follow through with her part of the transaction after Bob has met his obligations, highlighting a critical area for improvement in the design and execution of such contracts.

An innovative approach to enhancing the efficiency and security of conditional payments is outlined, emphasizing the modification of the commitment transaction structure. This solution involves a restructured commitment that accommodates new HTLCs while maintaining the integrity of the agreement between Alice and Bob. By adjusting balances and integrating new HTLCs without compromising existing contractual conditions, this method addresses potential issues arising from concurrent updates. The [option-simplified-update](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/867) facilitates these adjustments, crucial for the seamless operation of instant, low-fee transactions on the Lightning Network. Further insights into this discussion are accessible through an archived communication from October 2021, offering a comprehensive overview of the proposed enhancements to the Lightning Network's protocol.

The dialogue further explores operational concerns specific to the Lightning Network, particularly regarding the management of local and remote commitment preimage claims. The focus is on the need to presign these transactions to accommodate advancements like Taproot's scriptless scripts, or TRUC. A consensus emerges on the necessity of presigning both local and remote commitment preimage claims as version 3 transactions, introducing a protocol modification that adds a half round-trip to the commitment update flow. This adjustment aims to streamline the signature exchange process, ensuring that transactions proceed smoothly and securely. However, the complexity of this process is noted, especially concerning the potential for race conditions during the signing flow. An alternative suggestion involves attaching HTLC-Remote-Success signatures directly to the `revoke_and_ack` message, simplifying the process while safeguarding the integrity of the transaction.

This comprehensive examination underscores the continuous efforts within the cryptocurrency community to refine and secure transaction protocols on platforms like the Lightning Network. Through collaborative problem-solving and innovative approaches to managing commitment transactions, developers aim to enhance the reliability and efficiency of decentralized financial technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T13:01:14.095000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
