<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks</title>
  <updated>2025-01-05T02:27:41.214081+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-01-04 20:43:29.758000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-01-04 19:45:53.869000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2025-01-03 22:02:29.608000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2025-01-03 17:32:57.946000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-02 19:35:31.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-02 19:30:47.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3964_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3963_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3953_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3949_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3919_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3924_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks</title>
    <updated>2025-01-05T02:27:41.214140+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks/1353/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Chain-Linked Resolution Technique (CLRT) focuses on addressing the challenge of liquidity lock-up times in protocols, particularly aiming to reduce the delays that arise when parties submit outdated states, intentionally or unintentionally. This situation creates a vulnerability where the integrity and reliability of the system are at risk due to the potential for undue advantage or genuine errors in state submission. The complexity of ensuring timely resolutions is highlighted by the possibility of delays extending beyond twice the expected time if both parties engage in submitting known outdated states as a strategy. Such complexities necessitate robust mechanisms within the CLRT framework to effectively prevent and manage these challenges.

A detailed examination of the MUON mechanism within transaction processes reveals its crucial role in maintaining the integrity and non-malleability of transactions. The structure of transactions, including Tx Open, Tx Kickoff, Tx Update[i], Tx Ratchet i, and Tx Exit, outlines a comprehensive sequence designed to safeguard the transaction process from unauthorized modifications. The employment of MUON within this sequence ensures that each transaction adheres to a secure and verifiable pattern, preventing maligned changes through a setup of programmable conditions and inputs/outputs. Jeremy Rubin provides further insights into the significance of MUON in transactional integrity through his work, which can be explored for a deeper understanding of its application in transaction processes.

The introduction of Contract-level Relative Timelock (CLRT) UTXO presents a solution to the specific issue of extended fund lockup times in eltoo constructs, such as ln-symmetry. By incorporating a static utxo until the conclusion of a challenge period, the approach aims to streamline the `funding-&gt;kickoff-&gt;update-&gt;settle` sequence, thereby reducing the relative timelock's resetting impact on fund liquidity. However, this method introduces challenges related to TXID stability, transaction cost implications, and technical complexities, especially in scenarios lacking TXID stability. Despite potential simplifications suggested by leveraging Chia's coinid system, concerns remain regarding the consensus changes required to support proof construction and the feasibility of maintaining concise and enforceable proofs.

John Law's implementation of dual relative timelocks in payment channel constructions offers an example of utilizing TXID stability to enhance the operation and security of these channels. By creating separate "lanes" for managing timeouts and employing a dust output for system control, this method demonstrates the utility of txid stability in improving the functionality and reliability of payment channels. Further exploration of these concepts is available through John Law's work on GitHub, providing insight into innovative approaches to transaction management and contractual obligations within networks.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T20:43:29.758000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
