<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-01-21T02:16:03.182573+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-20 14:43:27.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-01-20 10:51:08.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2025-01-19 15:21:50.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-19 13:26:01.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-01-19 11:03:42.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-08 10:17:20.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-08-06 13:41:52.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-04 15:45:21.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-02 12:08:52.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4080_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4079_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4078_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4077_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4076_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2928_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2920_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2913_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2911_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-01-21T02:16:03.182669+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussions and analyses surrounding Bitcoin transaction processing have shed light on multiple facets of the blockchain's operational intricacies, focusing particularly on the management of orphan transactions and the optimization of block reconstructions. A pivotal development in this area is the modification suggested by a recent pull request, as seen in [Bitcoin's GitHub repository](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/31397), which aims to enhance the process of requesting parents for orphan transactions from peers. This improvement is further exemplified by the implementation of a specific patch ([see patch](https://github.com/0xB10C/bitcoin/commit/90181a45651fdebc7cc5dc5262416f0f83fa4c48)), which has been actively tested across various nodes to monitor its efficacy.

The logs from these tests, as illustrated in an example log ([view log](https://gist.github.com/0xB10C/bc24f1406443faf92fe30efd16555327)), indicate a need for a detailed analysis into why certain transactions were not known or were evicted from a node's memory pool, potentially due to factors like low fee rates, expiration, or non-standard characteristics. These observations have led to suggestions such as increasing the `-blockreconstructionextratxn` parameter beyond its default setting to improve transaction processing performance and examining the orphan pool for missing transactions.

In a broader context, the examination of blocks with low numbers of transactions reveals insights into the prevalence of non-standard transactions and their impact on network efficiency. Such analysis highlights how prioritization mechanisms outside of standard queues, possibly through inconsistent eviction policies or external transaction relaying, can influence network dynamics. This inquiry underlines the importance of understanding the underlying causes of observed phenomena to enhance the fairness, efficiency, and transparency of the blockchain transaction processing system.

Furthermore, the discussion extends to the technical aspects of Bitcoin Core, specifically its maintenance of a specialized pool for compact block reconstructions. The `-blockreconstructionextratxn` parameter plays a significant role in this mechanism by specifying the number of additional transactions retained to assist in reconstructing compact blocks. This feature underscores the efforts to optimize blockchain efficiency, distinguishing between the impacts of mempool size variations and the strategic management of internal transaction pools.

Exploration into the efficiency of block reconstructions in different bandwidth modes reveals that high-bandwidth mode, which accounts for the majority of compact block deliveries, generally requires fewer requests for transactions compared to low-bandwidth mode. This observation suggests avenues for optimizing low-bandwidth delivery by pre-filling transactions, a potential improvement noted but not yet implemented in Bitcoin Core’s codebase. The upcoming release of Bitcoin Core v28.0, introducing full-RBF, presents an opportunity to reassess and potentially enhance the efficiency of compact block delivery and reconstruction across both bandwidth modes.

Lastly, the analysis facilitated by `debug=cmpctblock` logging offers valuable insights into the frequency and conditions under which additional transaction requests are made during block reconstructions. Variations in node configurations and their impact on block reconstruction efficiency highlight the importance of tailored settings, such as the adjustment of maximum connections and the adoption of `mempoolfullrbf=1`, in improving network performance. This comprehensive review of block reconstruction practices and the associated challenges underscores the ongoing efforts to refine Bitcoin transaction processing and the critical role of community contributions and technical advancements in achieving these objectives.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-20T14:43:27.958000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
