<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2025-01-07T02:21:45.979231+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-01-06 18:36:22.950000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-04 07:56:50.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-05-09 15:43:20.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-05-09 15:16:43.719000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Fi  . 2024-05-06 10:00:29.691000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-05-04 21:22:17.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>evoskuil  . 2024-04-29 13:45:50.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-04-29 12:26:28.811000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3990_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3957_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2397_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2396_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2376_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2368_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2348_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2347_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2025-01-07T02:21:45.979300+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into a comprehensive analysis of the challenges and proposals associated with transaction selection and block space allocation within cryptocurrency mining pools, specifically focusing on a scenario where miners are required to process transactions previously included in shares before selecting their transactions. It introduces the concept of using a deterministic algorithm to prioritize transactions based on fee rates, allowing for immediate inclusion in blocks, and suggests reserving a portion of block space for miners’ discretionary transaction inclusion. This approach faces significant technical hurdles, especially regarding the enforcement of new policies or updates and the efficient handling of transaction data influx.

A strategic shift towards empowering individual miners with the responsibility of transaction selection is proposed as a means to further decentralize the process and enhance network security against state-level attacks. However, this decentralization could increase revenue variance for miners with less than 1% of the network's hashrate, exposing them to higher financial uncertainty. The discussion also touches upon Braidpool’s use of a "full proportional" payout scheme, which aims to distribute transaction fees across the pool, thereby preventing any single miner from exclusively claiming high-fee transactions. This raises questions about economic incentives and game theory within pool design, as well as concerns over potential censorship through the inclusion of nonsensical transactions.

The critique extends to the broader blockchain technology, highlighting the lack of a technical solution to address the raised concerns but suggesting that the varied legal responsibilities of miners across jurisdictions might offer some mitigation. The potential for government intervention in mining activities, particularly through mandates requiring miners to use specific pools, underscores the difficulty of achieving true autonomy and resistance to censorship within the Bitcoin network.

Centralization in transaction selection among decentralized mining pools is critiqued for potentially exacerbating centralization issues, with a hypothetical scenario suggesting a near-monopoly situation in transaction selection. This could limit transaction diversity and undermine the democratic decision-making process inherent in blockchain networks. The discussion calls for maintaining a balance between combating censorship through fee mechanisms and preserving the decentralized nature of transaction selection processes.

Finally, the conversation acknowledges the challenges faced by the concept of pool hopping and its implications for the blockchain mining ecosystem. The introduction of braids at scaling HK represents a new direction worth investing in, potentially addressing these challenges. Concerns about the future of transaction selection in Bitcoin, particularly the risk of full centralization around block template providers, are highlighted. A proposed shift towards a more deterministic and consensus-based approach aims to enhance decentralization and resist censorship, though it does not completely solve the problem of censorship but rather shifts it to the share chain level. This proposal necessitates complex technical adjustments and a rethinking of transaction pooling and validation processes to preserve Bitcoin's foundational principles while navigating its practical operation and governance challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-06T18:36:22.950000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
