<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-07T02:24:47.480475+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson 2025-02-06 17:11:33.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-06 13:44:44.539000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-06 11:42:05.040000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-05 23:33:28.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-05 16:48:23.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-05 16:46:45.483000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson  . 2025-02-05 00:35:23.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-04 15:03:32.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-04 14:47:45.351000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-04 14:45:08.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 21:19:50.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 17:01:05.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:24:44.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:13:28.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:03:57.645000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-02 17:00:25.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 23:00:58.162000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-02-01 19:18:18.695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 17:06:17.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-31 13:25:10.101000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-30 23:11:20.253000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-30 13:34:13.143000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-29 15:25:42.441000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-29 11:22:02.630000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2025-01-28 23:44:14.837000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-01-28 22:28:00.644000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-28 13:10:04.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4203_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4196_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4195_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4189_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4186_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4185_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4179_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4174_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4173_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4172_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4157_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4158_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4153_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4151_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4150_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4149_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4144_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4143_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4137_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4120_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4115_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4114_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4111_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4108_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4104_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4103_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4102_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:24:47.480657+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with an acknowledgment of the efficiency gains afforded by Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC) in programming environments, noting specifically its impact on performance relative to other factors such as code bottlenecks. The conversation then shifts towards the potential of algebraic hash functions within the context of proof generation, as facilitated by the `rustreexo` project. This inclusion allows for customization of hash functions, with algebraic hashes significantly reducing computational load, especially noted within proving environments. The exploration into algebraic hash functions is motivated by a curiosity regarding their effect on proving times, particularly in relation to utreexo proofs, which are implicated in the broader profiling of key aggregation times in Musig signature verification processes.

Further deliberations touch upon Rusty Russell's model for channel management within the Bitcoin Lightning Network, emphasizing a strategic shift away from direct blockchain engagement for anti-DOS measures and the maintenance of vagueness in capacity claims. This model, contrasting with Zero-Knowledge Proof (ZKP) applications, suggests efficiencies in non-ZKP scenarios through the allowance of alternative UTXO commitments, thereby not necessitating direct channel UTXO revelation. The discourse extends into the mechanics of channel creation, highlighting scalability challenges posed by dual-funder requirements versus single-funder channels, where the latter could potentially leverage ZKPs to initiate channels without revealing specific UTXOs. Russell's proposal hints at evolving thoughts around channel claims and funding dynamics, encapsulated within the `channel_update_v2` messages, demonstrating a nuanced approach towards managing channel operations and ownership claims within the Lightning Network.

The dialogue intricately weaves through the technical intricacies of zk prover technologies, spotlighting Halseth's contributions and the introduction of customizable hash functions in `rustreexo`, aiming at efficiency improvements within proof generation. The employment of algebraic hashes underlines a collaborative effort towards optimizing proving times, underpinned by a shared interest in leveraging advancements like Poseidon 2 for data conversion to facilitate Bitcoin zk prover development. This cooperative narrative underscores the iterative nature of software development, particularly within cryptographic optimizations aimed at enhancing privacy and efficiency in blockchain networks.

In delving into privacy enhancement strategies within the Lightning Network, the conversation evaluates the transition towards utilizing ZKP for UTXO possession, proposing a paradigm shift from explicit UTXO disclosure towards a more privacy-preserving mechanism. This approach, while fostering user privacy, navigates the economic implications tied to M*N channel value propositions, advocating for a balanced integration of MuSig2 within ZKP frameworks to reconcile economic viability with privacy concerns. The dialogue reflects ongoing efforts to harmonize technological innovation with practical utility, marking a critical juncture in the evolution of privacy-centric protocols within blockchain networks.

The discussion further explores the application of cryptographic schemes, emphasizing the role of distinctness in preventing UTXO reuse through mechanisms akin to nullifiers or key images. This technical discourse extends into the realm of Curve Trees and zk-STARKs, showcasing a collective endeavor towards identifying efficient cryptographic solutions that address key operational challenges within Bitcoin coding and the Lightning Network. The narrative encapsulates a vibrant exploration of cryptographic advancements, underscoring a concerted push towards enhancing transaction privacy, verification efficiency, and the overall robustness of cryptographic protocols in blockchain technology.

Lastly, the conversation pivots towards the implementation considerations surrounding Utreexo and Groth16 within a blockchain context, juxtaposed against simpler methods like UTXO snapshots and log-scale ring signatures. This comprehensive examination highlights the trade-offs between complexity and efficiency in advancing blockchain systems, underscoring the imperative of optimizing network operations without imposing undue burdens on participants. Through a detailed exposition of technical strategies and potential future adaptations, the dialogue enriches the discourse on balancing scalability, privacy, and usability within the burgeoning landscape of blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T17:11:33.635000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
