<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-02-10T02:25:14.347304+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-02-09 16:48:47.248000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-06 16:45:01.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pmn  . 2025-01-05 11:36:35.625000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-04 23:43:19.353000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-04 08:10:18.927000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 17:05:07.824000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-01-03 15:27:10.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 13:52:30.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 12:59:20.523000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 11:51:32.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 19:16:14.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-02 17:18:06.007000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 16:04:00.283000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-02 14:47:10.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-01 01:21:03.301000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-31 04:30:09.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4236_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3984_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3971_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3967_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3959_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3947_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3943_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3942_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3940_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3931_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3923_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3921_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3920_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3917_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3909_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3903_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T02:25:14.347429+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The simulator developed by the programmer, available on [GitHub](https://github.com/mcelrath/braidpool/tree/main/tests), introduces a refined approach to simulating blockchain network behavior, specifically focusing on latency and cohort calculation improvements over previous models. The simulator's capability to distribute nodes randomly and compute distances accurately on a spherical surface allows for a more precise simulation of propagation latencies between nodes, a key factor in blockchain operations. By adopting a suggestion to target two parents per bead, the simulator achieves an improved balance (Nb/Nc ratio) that closely aligns with theoretical optimums, enhancing the understanding of network dynamics under various conditions.

In another facet of blockchain research, the discussion around the application of Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs) and Byzantine fault tolerance presents innovative methods for securing and streamlining digital currency transactions. Through leveraging moderately-hard puzzles, this approach seeks to maintain transaction integrity and participant anonymity without compromising on security. Such advancements underscore the ongoing efforts to address the inherent challenges within decentralized financial systems, particularly in balancing computational demands with network efficiency and security.

The email correspondence sheds light on the intricate considerations surrounding difficulty adjustment algorithms (DAAs) within blockchain networks, especially Braidpool. It explores the impact of latency on orphan rates and consensus, suggesting adjustments to the DAA to better accommodate variations in node latency across the network. This nuanced approach aims to ensure fairness in miner rewards while maintaining network integrity against potential latency-induced disparities. Furthermore, it introduces methods like the "great grandparent method" to mitigate high-latency transactions' effects, advocating for a balanced and statistically informed approach to difficulty adjustment.

On the topic of managing transaction data within blockchain pools, the implementation of deterministic block templates emerges as a solution to streamline transaction selection and block creation processes. This method simplifies the integration of transactions into blocks by negating the need for extensive data sharing among nodes, potentially enhancing the efficiency and reliability of blockchain operations. Additionally, the exploration of UTreeXO and libbitcoin methodologies for UTXO management reflects a broader strategy to optimize data handling and storage within the blockchain architecture, illustrating a commitment to leveraging advanced techniques for system improvement.

Lastly, the theoretical discussions and proposals outlined in the emails highlight the constant innovation within blockchain technology, from DAG-based difficulty adjustments to strategies for managing orphan rates and latency effects. These contributions not only demonstrate a deep engagement with the technical challenges of blockchain operation but also suggest a forward-looking perspective aimed at refining consensus mechanisms and network performance. Through collaborative efforts and open-source development, such advancements reflect the dynamic interplay between theory and practice in the pursuit of more efficient, secure, and equitable blockchain systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-09T16:48:47.248000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
