<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Minimal signing flow changes for TRUC channels</title>
  <updated>2025-02-04T02:19:37.422098+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-02-03 14:33:13.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-02 04:36:56.859000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-31 21:04:27.713000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2025-01-31 20:49:25.106000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-31 20:25:38.829000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2025-01-31 19:19:09.535000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4154_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4147_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4133_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4130_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4128_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4126_Minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-TRUC-channels.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Minimal signing flow changes for TRUC channels</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T02:19:37.422213+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/minimal-signing-flow-changes-for-truc-channels/1414" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion in the realm of blockchain technology and cryptocurrency transactions, especially focusing on the Lightning Network, delves into the management and optimization of Hashed Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs) to improve the efficiency and security of conditional payments. A novel method is proposed that involves modifying the structure of commitment transactions to include additional HTLCs without compromising the contractual balance or integrity between the involved parties, Alice and Bob. This mechanism, facilitated by an update method known as [option-simplified-update](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/867), aims to prevent potential issues that could arise from concurrent updates, ensuring that HTLCs remain claimable despite timing discrepancies between commitment closures and HTLC resolutions. Further insights into this approach are documented in an archived communication from October 2021, accessible at [Oct 2021](https://web.archive.org/web/20231114193842/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2021-October/003278.html), which provides valuable information on the ongoing developments aimed at enhancing the Lightning Network's protocol.

Moreover, the conversation acknowledges a necessary correction pointed out by a participant, underlining the significance of accurate communication and collaborative feedback in addressing complex technical challenges. It also mentions a specific operational concern related to the security and reliability of channel-based transactions within the Lightning Network. This issue pertains to the vulnerability where Alice might exploit the system by withholding a `revoke_and_ack` after a `commitment_signed` message from Bob, potentially reclaiming an HTLC that Bob has forwarded. Such vulnerabilities underscore the continuous need for scrutiny and adaptation in the network's protocols to ensure transaction security and reliability. For a deeper understanding of these concerns, a [Gist](https://gist.github.com/instagibbs/1d02d0251640c250ceea1c66665ec163rationale) provides detailed rationale behind these operational challenges.

In addition, discussions extend to optimizing the handling of both local and remote commitment preimage claims through presigning transactions, particularly to accommodate advancements like Taproot's scriptless scripts, or TRUC. The adaptation involves updating HTLC-Success transactions to version 3 and introducing a half round-trip in the communication sequence for exchanging signatures during commitment updates. This process entails a `commitment_proposed` message initiating the update, followed by a `commitment_signed` message with necessary signatures, and a `revoke_and_ack` message to revoke the previous commitment. However, this adjustment faces potential complexities due to race conditions in the signing flow, necessitating a robust mechanism for verifying and incorporating correct HTLC transactions into the new commitment transaction. An alternative simpler method was also discussed, suggesting attaching HTLC-Remote-Success signatures directly to the `revoke_and_ack` message to reduce complexity while maintaining the security of the transactions. These nuanced approaches highlight the evolving nature of cryptographic protocols in the Lightning Network, emphasizing the importance of managed state transitions to ensure the integrity and security of transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T14:33:13.287000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
