<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T02:21:37.855285+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson 2025-02-05 00:35:23.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-02-04 15:03:32.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-04 14:47:45.351000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-04 14:45:08.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 21:19:50.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 17:01:05.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:24:44.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:13:28.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:03:57.645000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-02 17:00:25.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 23:00:58.162000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-02-01 19:18:18.695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 17:06:17.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-31 13:25:10.101000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-30 23:11:20.253000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-30 13:34:13.143000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-29 15:25:42.441000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-29 11:22:02.630000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2025-01-28 23:44:14.837000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-01-28 22:28:00.644000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-28 13:10:04.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4179_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4174_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4173_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4172_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4157_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4158_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4153_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4151_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4150_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4149_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4144_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4143_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4137_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4120_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4115_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4114_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4111_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4108_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4104_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4103_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4102_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-05T02:21:37.855444+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation initiates with a focus on the implementation and performance implications of utilizing algebraic hash functions within zk provers, specifically addressing the integration with `rustreexo` for custom hash function selection. The discussion highlights the efficiency gains from employing algebraic hashes within provers, particularly noting their lightweight nature when running inside a prover compared to traditional hash functions. The mention of `rustreexo`'s flexibility since a recent update allows for a nuanced approach to hash function implementation, fostering an environment conducive to experimentation and optimization in proof generation processes. This exploration is further enriched by the incorporation of Poseidon 2 as a hash function, which is supported through a specific bridge node feature, enhancing the format and utility of json outputs for provers.

The discourse advances into the intricacies of replacing direct possession proofs with Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs) of possession within the Lightning Network (LN) protocol for enhanced privacy. The rationale behind this pivot stems from the desire to mitigate spamming costs without compromising the logical structure of channel-related UTXOs. This examination delves into the economic and privacy considerations surrounding the use of channel UTXOs versus alternative UTXOs for generating proofs. The dialogue encapsulates the strategic decisions involved in optimizing privacy without imposing undue liquidity costs on LN operators, advocating for a balance between economic rationality and privacy preservation through potential support for MuSig2 negotiation.

Further, the discussion explores the conceptual shift towards proof creation by channel parties, emphasizing the operational and privacy implications of selecting non-channel UTXOs for proof generation. This perspective introduces a critical analysis of liquidity costs associated with channel operations, presenting a compelling argument for the necessity of supporting two-party output mechanisms within ZKP schemes. The narrative underscores the complexity of achieving privacy and efficiency in LN operations, pointing towards a nuanced understanding of the trade-offs involved in proof creation methodologies.

Technical considerations surrounding the viability of certain cryptographic operations within the LN context are scrutinized, with particular attention to the practical limits of proving times on hardware capabilities. The conversation acknowledges the potential for hardware acceleration and optimization techniques to mitigate the concerns over extended proving durations. This segment of the discussion juxtaposes the theoretical and practical aspects of implementing cryptographic solutions, such as the usage of `pk_hash` for generating key images in multisignature setups, against conventional practices. The critique extends to the exploration of Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) as a method for enhancing transaction privacy through unique key image generation, highlighting the ongoing efforts to refine cryptographic protocols for improved security and privacy in blockchain transactions.

The dialogue transitions into a comprehensive analysis of various cryptographic schemes, including STARKs, SNARKs, Curve Trees, and ring signatures, with a focus on their respective impacts on verification time, proof size, and cryptographic maturity. This exploration reflects a collective endeavor to identify and implement efficient, scalable cryptographic solutions tailored to the requirements of the Lightning Network and similar systems. The emphasis on collaborative insight and potential advancements encapsulates the dynamic nature of cryptographic research and its implications for future developments in blockchain technology and privacy-preserving digital transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-05T00:35:23.038000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
