<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - [BROKEN] Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:20:43.585517+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ademan</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cdecker  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cdecker  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3966_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4006_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4001_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4000_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3998_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3995_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3989_-BROKEN-Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - [BROKEN] Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:20:43.585580+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/broken-multi-party-eltoo-with-bounded-settlement/1364/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around blockchain security, specifically within the context of channel finalization delays and potential attacks, sheds light on several sophisticated strategies employed by attackers and the countermeasures that can be implemented to mitigate these threats. A notable concern highlighted is the vulnerability to attacks where an attacker deliberately publishes outdated state updates to disrupt the settlement process. This strategy, however, appears to have limited effectiveness due to mechanisms that allow victims to respond promptly, thereby neutralizing the threat posed by such attacks. The economic viability of these attacks is further questioned, with emphasis on the cost dynamics that could render the expected value negative for the attacker, thus acting as a deterrent.

In exploring the practicality of channel finalization in a multi-party setting, the discussion introduces the concept of "punishable Eltoo" and references prior research that has delved into similar territories. The challenges associated with implementing a secure, trustless multi-party construction without a coordinator or quorum are acknowledged, highlighting the technical and economic complexities involved. Additionally, the potential integration of watchtower services is proposed as a means to enhance security against hidden transaction attacks, suggesting that the presence of external monitoring could significantly reduce the likelihood of successful deceit by attackers.

The proposal put forth for a multi-party eltoo scheme aims to address these concerns through a novel approach that restricts each party to a single update, potentially reducing the risk of dishonest behavior and ensuring bounded settlement time. This is achieved via a complex system of signed vector commitments and floating transactions, supported by the implementation of specific opcodes provided by a hypothetical soft fork named LNHANCE. The scheme's reliance on exponential computation, however, poses practical limitations on the number of participants, projecting a feasible range within 10-20 parties. This limitation underscores the challenge of scaling such a system while maintaining efficient and secure operations.

Further exploration into the feasibility of integrating watchtowers and adapting the scheme to accommodate offline users suggests ongoing efforts to refine and enhance the protocol's robustness and practicality. The acknowledgment of exponential computational complexity and the exploration of potential improvements reflect a nuanced understanding of the trade-offs involved in designing secure, scalable multi-party channels within the blockchain ecosystem. The dialogue surrounding these developments emphasizes the importance of continual research and collaboration within the community to address the evolving landscape of blockchain security and functionality.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:15:37.712000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
