<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:43.300561+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ademan  ..196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..616000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..780000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..683000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  ..453000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  ..813000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>rijndael  ..671000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  ..298000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  ..757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi.931000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.630000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.758000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler.869000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida.608000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin.946000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4056_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4051_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4050_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4049_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4048_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3982_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3979_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3919_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3978_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3972_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3970_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3969_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3964_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3963_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3953_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3949_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3924_Contract-level-Relative-Timelocks-or-let-s-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Contract-level Relative Timelocks (or, let's talk about ancestry proofs and singletons)</title>
    <updated>2025-01-22T02:19:43.300676+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/contract-level-relative-timelocks-or-lets-talk-about-ancestry-proofs-and-singletons/1353/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion encompasses various technical strategies aimed at enhancing the efficiency and security of blockchain transactions, particularly within Bitcoin's framework and related protocols. A significant focus is placed on optimizing transaction settlement times and introducing mechanisms to enforce contract conditions and state continuity across transactions.

One proposal suggests integrating the settlement transaction directly into the last allowed update in a channel, specifically for scenarios involving two parties. This method could significantly reduce settlement delays by streamlining the final steps of the transaction process. The idea draws inspiration from Daric and aims to optimize the process by decreasing the delay to `(N - 1) * shared_delay`, ensuring that each party can still make an update in the worst-case scenario. This approach is poised to enhance settlement times within channels by making the transaction process more efficient.

Another part of the discussion delves into the challenges and critiques surrounding Moon's scenario, emphasizing the importance of precise communication in technical discussions. The critique underscores the necessity of clear engagement with presented scenarios or arguments, particularly in specialized fields where clarity is vital. It highlights the need to explicitly state the relevance of any new example or argument introduced to avoid misinterpretation or confusion, promoting productive and meaningful exchanges.

Exploring Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLC) settlements on the Lightning Network, the conversation identifies the maximum duration an HTLC could take to settle and discusses potential abuse by channel partners. The suggestion to differentiate expiration times for Symmetry HTLCs and Penalty HTLCs aims to prevent malicious activities while improving capital utilization within the network. The implementation of Commitment-Lightning Round Trip (CLRT) protocols is discussed not as a direct attack mitigation strategy but as a means to optimize capital use and ensure secure transaction settlements.

Further, the dialogue shifts to Bitcoin programming specifics, focusing on implementing contract-level relative timelocks, ancestry proofs, and singletons. These technical elements are highlighted for their potential to advance smart contract functionality on the Bitcoin network, allowing for time-based conditions enforcement and unique contract states to prevent fraud. This advancement signifies Bitcoin's evolution towards supporting a broader array of decentralized applications and financial instruments, reflecting ongoing innovation in blockchain technology.

Ademan's multi-party penalty-optional rebindable channels proposal is examined for its potential to limit update numbers equal to participant numbers, aiming to achieve immediate settlements in final updates and improve operational efficiency in blockchain transactions. Additionally, the Schnorr trick combined with CAT operation in Bitcoin scripting is proposed as a method to maintain transaction element integrity and facilitate complex contract operations, including state machines within contracts and seamless continuation of state across transactions.

The concept of Contract-level Relative Timelock (CLRT) UTXO for Eltoo is introduced to address liquidity lockup issues in protocols, proposing a dedicated utxo to mitigate extended delays in transaction settlements. This approach includes modifications to eltoo structure for enforcing concurrent spending of a state output and CLRT output during settlements. The discussion also covers challenges related to transaction ID stability and the complexity of integrating such mechanisms within Bitcoin's current framework.

Lastly, the potential of utilizing a singleton for representing contract identity is explored, offering a pathway to constant size proof of ancestry and simplifying contract validation. This method aligns with innovative approaches like Chia's coinid for managing update history and ensuring contract integrity. The overall discourse reflects a deep dive into the technical intricacies of blockchain technology, aiming to refine transaction processing, enhance security, and expand the functional capabilities of Bitcoin and related platforms.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T14:38:30.196000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
