<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Transitory Soft Forks for Consensus Cleanup Forks</title>
  <updated>2025-01-02T02:17:52.652807+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin 2025-01-02 01:05:17.836000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-30 19:22:07.692000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2024-12-29 19:47:59.835000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-12-24 20:33:01.708000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-24 17:47:34.308000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2024-12-23 22:53:02.859000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3915_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3897_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3868_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3857_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3856_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3851_Transitory-Soft-Forks-for-Consensus-Cleanup-Forks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Transitory Soft Forks for Consensus Cleanup Forks</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T02:17:52.652867+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/transitory-soft-forks-for-consensus-cleanup-forks/1333" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion delves into various facets of implementing transitory soft forks within the Bitcoin network, contrasting cleanup efforts with the introduction of new features. Highlighted is a nuanced evaluation of applying such forks, especially in scenarios involving potential risks and the need for evolving consensus rules without permanent commitment to specific protocols. This evaluation underscores the strategy of initially applying consensus rules to relay/mining policy as a risk mitigation measure, suggesting that if no complaints or rule-violating transactions emerge over a significant period, the perceived risk of these "anti-features" diminishes.

A notable point of discussion centers around the utility of soft forks for feature additions versus cleanup operations. It's acknowledged that while almost any proposed feature can be emulated through third-party intervention, either directly on Bitcoin or via a sidechain, the absence of widespread adoption for this capability reflects a user base divided by trust preferences. This dichotomy suggests a limited demand for new features among users comfortable with third-party trust and those desiring features that ensure trustlessness. The text advocates for the use of transitory soft forks to introduce new features that meet technical standards and have community support but face opposition due to unresolved uncertainties or concerns. This approach offers a compromise by allowing features to be used trustlessly without a permanent commitment, although it acknowledges the current lack of enthusiasm for adopting this method for existing proposals.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the challenges developers face in proposing and activating soft forks, particularly those aimed at transaction restriction for security reasons. The concept of auto-repeal is discussed as a means to address DoS vulnerabilities, providing a streamlined process for managing patches over time. This approach is contrasted with a UNIX-like model for consensus change management, emphasizing versioned, modular changes that allow for more focused and manageable activation processes.

The feasibility and considerations surrounding the implementation of transitory soft forks, akin to [BIP50](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/665712c727ee898f0e6a31eee6f1a0ecab8bae4e/bip-0050.mediawiki), are further explored, acknowledging the technical viability and potential benefits of such mechanisms in response to emergent risks. However, a reluctance within the community, particularly among developers, to invest substantial effort in forks that may require re-implementation without clear additional benefits is highlighted. This discussion reflects broader concerns regarding resource allocation, consensus building, and the challenges of governance within decentralized systems.

Lastly, the concept of introducing soft forks with an expiration term, proposed by @harding, is revisited with an emphasis on consensus cleanups rather than feature implementations. This approach, which aims to avoid long-term commitment to potentially flawed solutions, is presented as offering flexibility and a safeguard against unforeseen consequences. The distinction between cleanup and feature forks is clarified, advocating for expiration terms for the former to address specific risks without disrupting network operations or user trust. This adaptive protocol management strategy represents a balance between innovation, security, and practicality, highlighting cautious optimism in integrating changes into complex systems like blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T01:05:17.836000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
