<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CTV++ OP_TEMPLATEHASH and OP_INPUTAMOUNTS</title>
  <updated>2025-01-01T02:26:43.436770+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-01-01 00:19:49.539000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-12-31 20:04:34.026000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-12-30 22:16:52.664000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:52:24.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2024-12-30 12:34:21.017000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3908_CTV-OP-TEMPLATEHASH-and-OP-INPUTAMOUNTS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3907_CTV-OP-TEMPLATEHASH-and-OP-INPUTAMOUNTS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3900_CTV-OP-TEMPLATEHASH-and-OP-INPUTAMOUNTS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3899_CTV-OP-TEMPLATEHASH-and-OP-INPUTAMOUNTS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3894_CTV-OP-TEMPLATEHASH-and-OP-INPUTAMOUNTS.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CTV++ OP_TEMPLATEHASH and OP_INPUTAMOUNTS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-01T02:26:43.436825+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-op-templatehash-and-op-inputamounts/1344" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the intricacies and potential of `OP_INPUTAMOUNTS` and `OP_TEMPLATEHASH`, two proposed opcodes designed to enhance flexibility and functionality within the realm of blockchain programming, particularly concerning CheckTemplateVerify (CTV). The `OP_INPUTAMOUNTS` opcode is capable of returning sums of input amounts based on specified conditions, providing a nuanced approach to handling transactions below or above certain thresholds, such as the 42 BTC transaction size. This opcode's design decision, whether to return values in a compact form or padded with zeroes to 64 bits, presents an open question that balances efficiency with utility.

Similarly, `OP_TEMPLATEHASH` extends the range of acceptable inputs to include amounts up to 64 bits and offers compatibility with all numeric inputs in compact integer form. These enhancements are positioned against the backdrop of ongoing debates regarding the optimal balance between introspection capabilities and programmable flexibility. By leveraging these opcodes, developers can potentially craft more sophisticated contracts, such as those necessary for operations like Vault withdrawals to staging addresses, which necessitate a more granular control over transaction amounts and conditions.

The broader conversation encapsulates the tension between achieving maximum specificity through CTV and the generality afforded by TXHASH. It questions the necessity of introducing intermediate points along this spectrum, suggesting that the current range sufficiently addresses user-defined spending conditions without complicating the activation process. This discourse underscores the challenges developers face, especially when engaging with complex mechanisms like Vaults, prompting the exploration of alternatives that eschew extensive introspection or state-carrying covenants while still delivering tangible benefits.

A notable development in this context is the introduction of a method that utilizes a specialized hash function to increase amount flexibility within CTV, circumventing the creation of new template types akin to TXHASH. This innovative approach, detailed in a [shared gist](https://gist.github.com/moonsettler/d2369e043473c42ff7fa52878dd064a5), draws from the collective insights of several contributors, including Jeremy Rubin, James O'Beirne, and Salvatore Ingala. Their collaborative efforts aim to solve the prevalent issues encountered with `CTV`, proposing a solution that maintains the advantages of existing methods while expanding upon their capabilities. Furthermore, the dialogue incorporates an edit directing readers to a resource on optimistic zk-verification at [Delving into Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/optimistic-zk-verification-using-matt/1050/1), offering an avenue for deeper investigation into the technological discussions presented.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-01T00:19:49.539000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
