<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-01-04T02:19:06.542807+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-01-03 17:05:07.824000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-01-03 15:27:10.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2025-01-03 13:52:30.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-01-03 12:59:20.523000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-01-03 11:51:32.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 19:16:14.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-02 17:18:06.007000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 16:04:00.283000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-02 14:47:10.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-01 01:21:03.301000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-31 04:30:09.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3947_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3943_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3942_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3940_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3931_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3923_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3921_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3920_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3917_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3909_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3903_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T02:19:06.542909+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation elaborates on a distinctive approach to blockchain consensus and difficulty adjustment by leveraging Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs) and innovative algorithms. This methodology diverges from traditional techniques by focusing on graph theory principles and the dynamic adjustment of blockchain difficulties based on network conditions, such as latency and hashrate variations. A critical aspect of this strategy is the introduction of a novel consensus mechanism that aims to improve scalability and security within decentralized networks. By intertwining multiple blockchain strands, the Braid Consensus algorithm enhances transaction throughput and resistance against attacks, addressing key challenges in conventional blockchain frameworks.

In achieving consensus without standard metrics like timestamps or latency, the development emphasizes direct targeting of DAG width for setting difficulty levels. This approach facilitates quicker consensus by ensuring a block becomes a unique link between generations, simplifying the measurement process and aiming for an optimal number of block parents. The discovery that targeting two parents per block leads to efficient consensus, reflecting in the difficulty adjustment algorithm's design to maintain network behavior, represents a significant advancement. Simulation results underscore the algorithm's efficacy, aligning closely with theoretical projections and demonstrating its potential as a more streamlined alternative to existing protocols.

Furthermore, the dialogue touches upon practical concerns regarding latency's impact on network integrity and consensus speed, especially in adversarial environments like cryptocurrency mining. It critically examines the implications of geographic location on latency and explores hypothetical scenarios involving interplanetary mining to highlight the complexities of managing latency in diverse operational contexts. This exploration underscores the challenges and adaptability required in designing blockchain systems capable of accommodating significant variations in network conditions.

Additionally, the discussion features a critique of current methodologies and proposes adjustments to counteract latency disparities among miners, aiming to preserve fairness and efficiency. The emphasis on avoiding incentives for geographical centralization and acknowledging physical constraints imposed by communication delays reflects a thoughtful consideration of the broader implications of blockchain technology deployment.

The exchange also includes references to ongoing research and theoretical work, indicating a vibrant community dialogue focused on refining and documenting advancements in blockchain algorithms and consensus mechanisms. This continuous exchange of ideas and findings is pivotal in advancing the understanding and application of blockchain technology, highlighting the importance of both theoretical explorations and practical implementations in shaping the future of decentralized networks.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T17:05:07.824000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
