<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - What happens after we "run out" of script flags?</title>
  <updated>2025-01-13T02:24:21.030929+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-01-13 00:00:36.709000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-01-12 23:32:51.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-01-12 23:08:56.517000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-01-12 19:29:48.433000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4041_What-happens-after-we-run-out-of-script-flags-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4040_What-happens-after-we-run-out-of-script-flags-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4039_What-happens-after-we-run-out-of-script-flags-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4038_What-happens-after-we-run-out-of-script-flags-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - What happens after we "run out" of script flags?</title>
    <updated>2025-01-13T02:24:21.030978+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/what-happens-after-we-run-out-of-script-flags/1382" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical nuances of implementing changes within Bitcoin Core's scripting mechanism, particularly concerning script flags. These flags are integral to instructing the script interpreter on the validation checks to be performed but are not deemed consensus critical. This means their modification or extension is not expected to directly impact the broader consensus rules that underpin the network's operation.

A current point of contention is the limitation imposed by the existing data structure used for script flags, which is a 32-bit unsigned integer. The dialogue highlights a hypothetical scenario where adding an additional 11 script flags would exhaust the available space within this structure. Such an expansion raises questions about the future scalability of script flags and the potential need to transition to a larger data structure, such as a 64-bit integer, to accommodate more flags.

Furthermore, there's an ongoing debate regarding the best approach to handle concurrent overlapping activations, with specific reference to LNHANCE, which currently utilizes three flag bits, and C3PO, which is gaining preference among developers. This situation underscores the challenges faced in balancing technical feasibility with community preferences and the need for forward-thinking solutions in Bitcoin Core's development.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-13T00:00:36.709000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
