<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
  <updated>2025-01-07T02:25:09.364991+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ademan  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3995_Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3989_Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3966_Multi-Party-Eltoo-with-bounded-settlement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Multi-Party Eltoo with bounded settlement</title>
    <updated>2025-01-07T02:25:09.365052+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multi-party-eltoo-with-bounded-settlement/1364" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of a "punishable Eltoo" in multi-party settings has been previously explored by Lloyd Fournier and others, focusing on enhancing the Eltoo protocol with mechanisms that penalize dishonest behavior while aiming for a trustless design. This approach attempts to tackle the challenges inherent in multi-party constructions across the Bitcoin network, regardless of the security model employed. Notably, these explorations include innovative solutions such as using Per-Update Credentials to enable Eltoo-Penalty and creating Witness Asymmetric Channels, both aimed at improving the security and efficiency of multi-party channels. Additionally, the discussions around solving high interactivity issues in payment pools and channel factories highlight the ongoing effort to make multi-party channels more viable and user-friendly.

A significant aspect of this research is the target of enabling scalable multi-party channels capable of supporting thousands of participants without requiring consensus changes in the Bitcoin blockchain. The ambition is to accommodate the entire global population with individual pool balances within these channels, underlining the scale at which these solutions aim to operate. However, the challenge of assigning blame among non-trusted counterparties and managing the exponential growth in vector commitments as more parties join the off-chain construction remains a critical hurdle.

The proposal introduces a structured framework for multi-party eltoo schemes that emphasizes limiting each participant to a single opportunity for state update on-chain. This limitation is crucial for mitigating the risks posed by malicious actors who might seek to delay honest settlement. The methodology relies on advanced concepts like multi-transaction-signatures and floating transactions, which are expected to be supported by future soft forks introducing new opcodes. These technical innovations are designed to streamline the process of state updates and enhance the overall security and efficiency of the blockchain protocols involved.

Despite the potential benefits, there are practical considerations concerning the computational demands of implementing such a scheme. As the number of participants increases, so does the complexity and number of required update transactions, leading to an exponential rise in computational requirements. However, keeping the number of participants within a practical limit could help manage these demands, making the scheme more feasible. Future directions for this research could involve optimizing efficiency, integrating additional security features, and adapting the scheme to support offline users or reduce witness sizes for uncooperative closes.

The proposal encourages feedback and collaboration from the broader Bitcoin development community to refine and possibly implement this multi-party eltoo scheme. It represents a step forward in the evolution of blockchain technologies, aiming to provide more robust, efficient, and secure multi-party channels. For those interested in contributing to this endeavor, the initial implementation and its performance benchmarks have been shared, offering a foundation for further development and testing.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-07T01:07:20.278000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
