<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-04-06T01:51:00.532041+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-05T03:26:53.160000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T01:51:00.532066+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin development, a notable discussion has emerged regarding the SIGHASH_SINGLE bug first reported in 2012. The conversation revolves around the strategic use of this bug for managing low-value or dust Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). By exploiting the SIGHASH_SINGLE signature hash type in conjunction with a specific R-value (half of the generator point G's order), developers can create transactions that allow for the efficient spending of these UTXOs as miner fees. This method is particularly advantageous because it employs a shorter encoding for the signature's R-value, thereby enabling the clearance of more dust within a given byte limit.

The technique involves assembling a transaction with multiple inputs and a single output, applying the SIGHASH_SINGLE option to all inputs beyond the first. This approach not only facilitates cheaper hashing but also intentionally exposes the private key of the UTXOs involved. Given that these UTXOs are considered insecure, the revelation of their private keys is deemed acceptable. Furthermore, the reuse of signatures for other UTXOs sharing the same public key is seen as a beneficial side effect due to the non-concern over privacy for these particular assets.

Despite the unconventional nature of leveraging a known bug, the opinion expressed suggests that addressing this issue may not be necessary. Instead, the recommendation is put forth to adopt more secure transaction types like Pay to Witness Public Key Hash (p2wpkh), Pay to Witness Script Hash (p2wsh), or Pay to Taproot (p2tr) as alternatives. These methods are advocated as preferable solutions for those seeking to avoid the peculiarities associated with the SIGHASH_SINGLE bug, thus steering the community towards more robust practices in handling Bitcoin transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T03:26:53.160000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
