<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-04-06T01:50:10.678702+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>recent798.536000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-05T16:17:19.536000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T01:50:10.678732+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical specifics of handling reorganizations (reorgs) in blockchain technology, particularly concerning Bitcoin's block 490,897. It explores the proposal of hardcoding a check against a specific coinbase transaction to prevent potential issues arising from deep reorgs. Deep reorganizations, while considered problematic due to their potential to significantly disrupt the blockchain's stability, are acknowledged as not entirely unfeasible scenarios. They can occur under various circumstances, such as intentional actions by users or unintentional mishaps, illustrating the complexity and variability in managing blockchain integrity.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the mechanisms designed to safeguard against low-work reorganizations during the Initial Block Download (IBD) phase, specifically through the Proof of Work (PoW) Denial of Service (DoS) protection implemented in the headers-first download strategy. Despite these protections, there remains a concern regarding the effectiveness of these safeguards when blocks are submitted through Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) rather than over Peer-to-Peer (P2P) networks. This distinction highlights a potential vulnerability in the system, suggesting that while current defenses may mitigate certain risks, they might not fully encompass all vectors through which a blockchain could be compromised, especially in the context of block submissions outside the standard P2P announcements.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T16:17:19.536000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
