<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Constellation - a high performance Lightning-based L3. Feedback wanted</title>
  <updated>2024-04-07T01:57:12.307731+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>azz.976000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-06T16:31:23.976000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Constellation - a high performance Lightning-based L3. Feedback wanted</title>
    <updated>2024-04-07T01:57:12.307764+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/constellation-a-high-performance-lightning-based-l3-feedback-wanted/775" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The project in discussion, named Constellation, is designed as an L3 protocol that aims to address several user experience (UX) issues present at the first two layers of blockchain technology. These issues include but are not limited to non-instant transaction confirmations, rising transaction fees, liquidity problems in channels, and throughput challenges. By integrating various protocols and technologies, Constellation ensures that all funds at the L3 level are backed 1:1 by funds held in L2 channels.

Constellation introduces a novel federated security model reinforced through a ROAST wrapper around the FROST protocol, enabling the creation of BIP 340 compatible Schnorr signatures. This design sets Constellation apart from other federated networks by facilitating a network of multiple, interoperable federations, termed guilds, which resolve disputes via Lightning. The flexibility of the trust model within Constellation allows entities to choose between running their nodes for full sovereignty or joining a guild that best fits their trust requirements.

At its core, Constellation employs a unique ledger system based on UTXO, diverging from the traditional account-based ledgers. Each operator manages 2^16 distinct partitions, allowing transactions to be processed across multiple partitions and leading to an efficient consensus mechanism. This setup enables high transactional throughput while maintaining near-instant confirmation times, surpassing even those of Lightning.

The protocol handles deposits and withdrawals through a process involving eCash, effectively breaking the link between deposited funds and the coins created on L3. This mechanism also facilitates seamless transactions across operators and guilds, with liquidity managed autonomously to address any balance issues.

For developers, Constellation promises a congenial environment with the ability to build L3 wallets akin to L1 wallets, leveraging Bitcoin's UTXO model and scripting language. This compatibility extends to hardware wallets and includes features such as offline sending and support for light client protocols for standardized communication with operators.

Despite its complex architecture, Constellation presents a solution that balances advanced financial interconnectivity with the option for users to maintain full sovereignty over their operations, provided they can afford the on-chain fees associated with Lightning channel operations. This approach acknowledges the trade-offs involved but offers a path forward for addressing critical limitations in current blockchain infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-06T16:31:23.976000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
