<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
  <updated>2024-04-10T01:55:46.216886+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>shesek.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-09T22:47:42.178000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
    <updated>2024-04-10T01:55:46.216916+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dsl-for-experimenting-with-contracts/748/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Minsc is a programming language with unique features that cater to specific needs in script writing, particularly useful within contexts requiring declarative syntax alongside functional constructs. It offers a distinct approach to looping, evident through its `repeat` and `unrollLoop` functions, which allow for repetitive script execution either a fixed number of times or based on a condition met up to a maximum iteration count. The language’s utility is showcased through examples like the `rollFromAltStack` function, which demonstrates how to employ `repeat` for executing a script fragment precisely N times, thereby facilitating operations like stack manipulation with ease.

Further extending its capabilities, Minsc introduces conditional looping with `unrollLoop`, allowing scripts to execute as long as a specified condition is satisfied, up to a set limit. This feature is adeptly illustrated with a countdown example, highlighting the language’s versatility in handling dynamic conditions within scripts. Such functionality underscores Minsc's potential in creating efficient and compact code for complex looping scenarios.

Despite its powerful features, Minsc faces challenges in documentation and accessibility, with the main website lagging in updates and the absence of comprehensive documentation on non-Miniscript Script features. However, efforts to bridge this gap are evident through the provision of an updated playground linked to the latest codebase on GitHub and the sharing of advanced examples via social media platforms. These initiatives signal an ongoing development process aimed at enhancing user experience and widening the application scope of Minsc in script-level spending conditions, possibly complementing other domain-specific languages like Bitcoin DSL.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-09T22:47:42.178000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
