<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
  <updated>2024-04-12T01:54:18.794040+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv 2024-04-11 21:52:09.564000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T01:54:18.794072+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/basic-vault-prototype-using-op-cat/576/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses a vulnerability in a specific transaction mechanism involving a vault that can be exploited by miners or sabotaged by non-miners. Specifically, it outlines how a miner is capable of draining the vault during the 'trigger withdrawal' transaction. This is achieved by positioning their input as the first input and the covenant-locked input as the second. The transaction is constructed in such a way that the output directed back to the miner equals the amount they initially contributed (satisfying the `input_0=output_0` condition), while the remaining portion of the covenant's funds are split. A minimal amount, referred to as the "dust" amount of 546 satoshis for non-SegWit transactions, is allocated to one output, and the rest is taken as a fee by the miner, effectively allowing them to capture all the value from the vault.

Additionally, the email highlights a potential risk posed by non-miners who, although unable to directly benefit in the same manner, can nonetheless initiate transactions that result in the vault's funds being inadvertently directed to a random miner, thereby sabotaging the vault. This aspect underscores a broader security concern within the system - the lack of a safeguard against malicious interventions aimed at depleting the vault's assets without direct financial gain to the aggressor.

The author also notes a discrepancy in the minimum dust threshold between non-SegWit and SegWit transactions, with the latter having a lower threshold as determined by the `IsDust()` function. This detail suggests further complexity in managing and securing transactions across different Bitcoin transaction formats. 

However, the email concludes without offering a solution to this vulnerability, indicating an ongoing uncertainty or challenge in addressing this specific security flaw within the described transaction system.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T21:52:09.564000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
