<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
  <updated>2024-04-12T01:55:21.803337+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt.668000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-11T22:14:30.668000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T01:55:21.803369+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dsl-for-experimenting-with-contracts/748/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the development of a TypeScript embedded domain-specific language (eDSL) known as sCrypt, specifically designed for Bitcoin's layer 1 smart contract framework. This innovative approach is detailed in [a comprehensive article on Medium](https://medium.com/@scryptplatform/introduce-scrypt-a-layer-1-smart-contract-framework-for-btc-b8b39c125c1a), which outlines its functionalities and potential applications. 

The core of sCrypt's functionality is illustrated through the example of a NAND gate commitment within BitVM, a virtual machine constructed to operate with Bitcoin Script. The code snippet provided showcases how sCrypt can be utilized to define and execute smart contracts directly on the Bitcoin network. It includes the definition of a smart contract class `BitVM` that encapsulates properties and methods for handling hash pairs and demonstrating the open gate commitment logic based on NAND operations.

The `BitVM` class leverages several key data structures and functions from the `scrypt-ts-btc` package, including types like `ByteString`, `Ripemd160`, and utilities such as `hash160`, demonstrating the seamless integration of cryptographic primitives essential for blockchain operations. By defining properties to store hash pairs and implementing methods for opening gate commitments and bit commitments, the example effectively demonstrates how to enforce complex logical conditions in smart contracts using basic cryptographic constructs.

This example is vital in understanding the practical application of sCrypt in creating sophisticated smart contract functionalities on the Bitcoin blockchain. Through this, developers can leverage TypeScript's familiar syntax to write contracts that compile down to Bitcoin Script, offering a robust framework for building decentralized applications on Bitcoin's secure and immutable ledger.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T22:14:30.668000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
