<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
  <updated>2024-04-12T01:53:54.678171+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rijndael</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-11T22:23:13.754000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Basic vault prototype using OP_CAT</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T01:53:54.678203+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/basic-vault-prototype-using-op-cat/576/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In addressing the challenges and potential vulnerabilities associated with using input/output ordering for covenant identification without an enforcement mechanism, the discussion highlights a particular case involving a vault. A suggested mitigation strategy involves introducing a requirement for a signature check to complement the existing script. This approach stems from recognizing the conceptual value of incorporating a "trigger key" as part of the solution, an idea initially overlooked but now acknowledged as beneficial and slated for future implementation.

Further consideration extends to the broader applicability of safeguarding mechanisms within such systems. Specifically, the conversation references the practice of covering the [index of the input](https://github.com/taproot-wizards/purrfect_vault/blob/ee7ee57ba9b5ed8fee7382334625bacbe27f8c36/src/vault/signature_building.rsL266) in the signature message, an approach detailed within the [full specification in bip341](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/b3701faef2bdb98a0d7ace4eedbeefa2da4c89ed/bip-0341.mediawikicommon-signature-message). This method suggests a viable means of enforcing that the covenant input occupies a specific index, thereby enhancing the security and predictability of transactions.

The issue of determining a reasonable threshold for what constitutes 'dust' or negligible output values in transactions was also addressed. The choice of considering outputs valued at 546 as 'dust' was mentioned, indicating a practical approach to defining minimal transaction output values based on observed data, albeit acknowledging this as an area of subjective judgment.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T22:23:13.754000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
