<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
  <updated>2024-04-15T03:51:47.239787+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>yonson.859000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-14T22:05:16.859000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP324 Proxy: easy integration of v2 transport protocol for light clients (PoC)</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T03:51:47.239819+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip324-proxy-easy-integration-of-v2-transport-protocol-for-light-clients-poc/678/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent collaboration between the developers has led to significant progress in the BIP324 project, particularly in the development of a Rust-based version 2 proxy. This new proxy draws inspiration from an existing Python implementation and leverages the asynchronous programming capabilities of the Tokio runtime. The source code for this advancement can be found on GitHub at [rustaceanrob/bip324](https://github.com/rustaceanrob/bip324/blob/fae064c22f77c62e3541cceea33690ef3efad52b/proxy/src/bin/async.rs). 

In addition to the asynchronous proxy, there is an ongoing effort to develop a threaded version. This initiative serves not only as a practical exercise but also as a means to refine the design of the bip324 protocol library's interface. A key aspect of this development process is the adoption of a "sans I/O" approach. This strategy is aimed at making the library independent of any specific runtime environment, thereby enhancing its flexibility and usability across different programming contexts. The team acknowledges that further improvements and iterations are necessary, but the current direction indicates a strong commitment to creating a versatile and efficient solution for the BIP324 protocol.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T22:05:16.859000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
