<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>CISA and Privacy</title>
  <updated>2024-04-23T01:55:29.249391+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-22T21:24:52.155000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>CISA and Privacy</title>
    <updated>2024-04-23T01:55:29.249422+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cisa-and-privacy/824" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA) is a technique that amalgamates multiple signatures into a single one, leading to lighter transactions and reduced fees. This method has been explored and developed with resources available for further insight and experimentation provided through links to [BlockstreamResearch on GitHub](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/cross-input-aggregation) and a [playground for CISA](https://github.com/fjahr/cisa-playground). The effectiveness of CISA can be quantified, showing savings in transaction weight and fees ranging from 7.6% for half aggregation up to 15.2% for maximum aggregation.

An illustrative scenario featuring Alice demonstrates the impact of CISA on transaction processes. Without CISA, Alice would conduct separate transactions to pay Bob, Carol, and Dave using different Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), potentially resulting in change but maintaining distinct inputs. Conversely, with CISA, Alice could combine these inputs into a single transaction to make these payments, illustrating the potential for both weight and fee reductions.

However, despite its benefits, CISA introduces significant privacy concerns and complexity for what may be considered marginal savings in transaction fees. This complexity and the trade-off with privacy might outweigh the financial benefits it offers. Moreover, this discussion contributes to the broader conversation around blockchain technology and its optimization, which is of interest not only to current researchers but also to future investigations, such as the research fellowship announced by the Human Rights Foundation ([HRF](https://hrf.org/hrf-announces-cisa-research-fellowship/)). This examination of CISA's implications serves not only as an analysis of its technical aspects but also as a reflection on the balance between innovation, privacy, and user experience in the development of blockchain technologies.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-22T21:24:52.155000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
