<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 25.2</title>
  <updated>2024-04-28T01:59:59.769862+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-27T02:51:43.188000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 25.2</title>
    <updated>2024-04-28T01:59:59.769900+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-inquisition-25-2/838" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest version of Bitcoin Inquisition, 25.2, is now accessible for download at [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/releases/tag/v25.2-inq). This release introduces support for several proposed consensus changes aimed at enhancing the functionality and security of Bitcoin transactions. Among these updates are support for BIP 119 OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY ([PR33](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/33)), BIP 118 SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT ([PR34](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/34)), and BIN-2024-1, also known as BIP 347 OP_CAT ([PR39](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/39)). These innovative proposals are designed to improve transaction efficiency, flexibility, and reliability within the Bitcoin network.

The implementation of these changes is based on Bitcoin Core 25.2, available from [Bitcoin Core's official website](https://bitcoincore.org/en/releases/25.2/). Notably, BIP 119 and BIP 118 have been active on the default signet since September 6, 2022, starting from block 106704. The activation of BIN-2024-1 (BIP 347) is anticipated shortly, expected at block 193536. It is important for users to understand that transactions utilizing these new features will not be relayed by nodes that do not support these enhancements. To ensure transactions reach a miner, it is recommended to connect with other inquisition nodes. A straightforward method to establish such connections is by specifying `addnode=inquisition.bitcoin-signet.net` when interacting with the network.

Additionally, Bitcoin Inquisition nodes make their presence known through the subversion string, which can be identified using the command `bitcoin-cli -netinfo 3`. This approach allows for greater visibility and integration within the network, ensuring that nodes supporting these updates can efficiently communicate and transact. Further details regarding these updates and their implications can be found in the announcement for version 23.0, hosted on the [Linux Foundation's mailing list](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2022-December/021275.html). This release marks a significant step forward in the ongoing development and refinement of the Bitcoin protocol, highlighting the community's commitment to optimizing and securing the network.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-27T02:51:43.188000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
