<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>[WITHDRAWN] Alternate script design for LNHANCE-Symmetry</title>
  <updated>2024-04-28T02:00:12.599259+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.084000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-04-28T01:02:42.084000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>[WITHDRAWN] Alternate script design for LNHANCE-Symmetry</title>
    <updated>2024-04-28T02:00:12.599293+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/withdrawn-alternate-script-design-for-lnhance-symmetry/839/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email in question delves into the complexities and challenges encountered while attempting to enhance ln-symmetry, expressing frustration over the difficulty of making theoretical improvements work in practice. This struggle is not unique to this instance, as evidenced by previous experiences and discussions logged in IRC chats, specifically pointing to a date where similar sentiments were shared.

The technical portion of the email addresses the structure and components essential for transaction handling within a specific protocol, outlining the sizes of different elements such as the annex, control block, script, signature, and ctv hash, cumulatively forming a total of 210 bytes. A critical analysis follows regarding the handling of the settlement transaction hash through an annex. It points out a potential oversight in ensuring that any update transaction includes the annex from its preceding transactions to maintain the integrity and continuity of the transaction chain. This inclusion is vital for verifying the capability to spend from one update transaction to the next within the network.

Moreover, the discussion suggests a modification to the protocol concerning two-party channels, which could simplify the process. By altering the protocol so that one party spends from the funding transaction to an update transaction, and the other spends from this update transaction to another, omitting the need for an annex in the second party's spend, it proposes a streamlined approach for managing transactions. However, this adjustment would necessitate restricting the protocol to only two-party channels, indicating a trade-off between complexity and flexibility in the system's design.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-28T01:02:42.084000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
