<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
  <updated>2024-04-03T01:53:26.166091+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2024-04-02 14:34:40.402000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-04-02 00:43:13.940000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  . 2024-04-01 21:19:31.406000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-04-01 20:35:50.495000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-25 08:36:40.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-22 23:41:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:40:39.031000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:38:27.559000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2024-03-21 20:55:55.854000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-21 17:33:00.972000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-21 16:27:09.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2133_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2126_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2125_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2124_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2022_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1991_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1989_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1990_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1985_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1982_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1980_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
    <updated>2024-04-03T01:53:26.166183+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-based-fee-estimation-on-bitcoin-core/703/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on blockchain transaction fee estimation addresses the challenges in accurately determining fee rates, especially during network congestion. It highlights that inaccuracies in fee rate estimates often occur when the time to discover a new block exceeds 10 minutes. Using the 50th percentile as a benchmark for estimating fees has been shown to be effective, though there are risks of subsequent higher-fee transactions displacing earlier ones in the mempool. To improve understanding and accuracy of fee estimations, a revised methodology incorporating both linear and logarithmic scales has been introduced, aiming to inform users about potential overpayments.

The discussion also explores the Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanism, which balances economic benefits with the convenience of not adjusting fees post-submission. A more nuanced fee estimation format, backed by comprehensive datasets and visual aids accessible via Colab and GitHub links, promises improved accuracy. Concerns are raised about current methods' vulnerability to manipulation tactics similar to those used in selfish mining. Solutions include adopting a mempool-based estimation method to reduce overestimation risks and provide verbose options for better decision-making on fee adjustments.

Miner strategies that might artificially influence fee rates through mempool manipulation are scrutinized, emphasizing the need for algorithmic adjustments in fee estimation processes. The objective is to avoid aggressive overbidding or overly conservative underbidding. Integrating confirmed and mempool-based estimates, alongside proactive network stability measures during protocol updates, is suggested to enhance estimation accuracy. Additional insights are provided through a linked spreadsheet detailing the performance of proposed solutions.

The conversation acknowledges the intricacies within the Bitcoin network, including the displacement of transactions from the mempool. The integration of direct blockchain data into estimation processes is recommended for real-time adjustments reflecting current network conditions. In cases of significant discrepancies, reverting to established methods like the `CBlockPolicyEstimator` is advised. The approach of utilizing mempool and block information for estimation could outperform existing strategies, despite potential stability issues due to the dynamic nature of block formation.

Kalle Alm's presentation at Scaling Bitcoin 2017 offers insights into optimizing fee estimation through mempool state analysis, advocating for a balanced use of RBF and combining confirmed and real-time mempool estimates. Alm's work, accessible through slides, a transcript, and a video, also discusses the non-financial implications of RBF, such as privacy concerns. Bitcoin Core's exploration of mempool-based fee estimation is highlighted, noting its potential for generating accurate fee rates despite challenges related to discrepancies between nodes' mempools and technical hurdles in building block templates efficiently. This ongoing research aims to refine mempool-based fee estimation methods, supported by contributions from various developers.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-02T14:34:40.402000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
