<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
  <updated>2024-04-12T01:56:29.324051+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sCrypt 2024-04-11 22:14:30.668000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>shesek  . 2024-04-09 22:47:42.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-04-09 09:08:16.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>dgpv  . 2024-04-06 20:43:12.923000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-04-06 20:25:08.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-04-02 10:56:33.502000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Luckylee  . 2024-04-02 08:42:43.055000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-31 19:04:06.072000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-31 17:31:14.749000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-31 16:42:27.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-03-31 10:20:06.175000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-30 21:52:17.324000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-30 18:44:58.745000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2024-03-29 16:50:26.252000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2206_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2189_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2185_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2179_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2178_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2131_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2129_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2109_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2108_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2106_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2105_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2101_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2100_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2086_DSL-for-experimenting-with-contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - DSL for experimenting with contracts</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T01:56:29.324157+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dsl-for-experimenting-with-contracts/748/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of sCrypt, a TypeScript embedded domain-specific language (eDSL) for the Bitcoin network, marks a significant advancement in blockchain and smart contract programming. sCrypt compiles down to Bitcoin Script, enabling the execution of complex logic such as NAND gate commitments within BitVM, enhancing Bitcoin's functionality through smart contracts. This technology facilitates the implementation of cryptographic commitments and logical operations.

Minsc, a programming language designed for Bitcoin DSL, offers declarative syntax and functional constructs ideal for scenarios that require looping constructs. Despite its powerful features, challenges in documentation and accessibility have hindered Minsc's widespread adoption, with ongoing efforts to improve accessibility and usefulness for developers.

Temporal Logic of Actions (TLA+) plays a crucial role in verifying system states and transitions, ensuring the reliability of concurrent protocols in blockchain technologies. Efforts to extend TLA+'s utility include simplifying contract development through module decomposition and a library of TLA+ modules. The potential integration of DSL with TLA+ aims to automate the verification process of Bitcoin contracts, combining technological advancements to enhance cryptocurrency agreement integrity and reliability.

Rust Bitcoin's Script development benefits from the use of macros, as demonstrated in BitVM's GitHub repository, allowing for dynamic scripting possibilities. The introduction of a `reorg_chain` command and tooling enhancements, such as a Jupyter notebook for DSL script construction and execution, indicate progress towards more interactive and collaborative development processes.

BitVM seeks collaboration with projects to leverage commonalities and bolster DSL development for improved scripting clarity and efficiency. An innovative address suggestion mechanism and the development of `features.py` using DSL exemplify the language's expressiveness, facilitating rapid prototyping and clearer communication among developers. The `reorg_chain` concept suggests an alternative for resetting system states, emphasizing the need for clear contract and transition descriptions.

Further exploration into `reorg_chain` indicates efforts to streamline blockchain reorganization processes, aiming to replace existing commands and enhance code readability. The discussion also highlights the DSL's role in simplifying bitcoin transactions and contract management by providing a declarative syntax for automatic witness program management and flexible contract execution. Documentation and examples are available ([documentation site](https://opdup.com/bitcoin-dsl/index.html), [repository](https://github.com/pool2win/bitcoin-dsl)), showcasing the DSL's practical application in easing complexities associated with bitcoin transactions and contracts.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T22:14:30.668000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
