<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Second Look at Weak Blocks</title>
  <updated>2024-04-18T01:55:07.387676+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-04-17 15:56:26.759000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-04-17 15:28:21.297000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-04-16 17:45:35.589000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2255_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2254_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2242_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Second Look at Weak Blocks</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T01:55:07.387718+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/second-look-at-weak-blocks/805/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of enhancing blockchain efficiency emphasizes the utilization of weak blocks within the infrastructure established for compact blocks. This proposal aims to reduce delays and unnecessary communications in block propagation, potentially benefiting mining fairness and decentralization. By mitigating disparities in mempool policies and their effects, the introduction of "weak compact blocks" could streamline the final block relay process. The adaptation from compact to weak compact blocks doesn't necessitate a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) or additional consensus beyond validation, allowing these messages to serve as a robust broadcast layer for miners' efforts. Despite this innovative approach, questions regarding the extent of necessary validation, strategies for omitting weak blocks from storage, and handling untraceable transactions persist.

A Proof of Concept (PoC) has been developed to demonstrate the practicality of integrating weak blocks into the mempool and further disseminating them, indicating a need for further dialogue on several technical aspects. These include the Proof of Work (PoW) multiplier adjustment, the optimal number of blocks to buffer, and the management of transactions already present in the mempool. The possibility of employing both high and low bandwidth solutions for the propagation of weak blocks suggests a flexible approach to maintaining efficiency while considering bandwidth limitations.

Moreover, the proposal opens up discussions on broader implications for network performance, such as improved fee estimation for upcoming blocks, thereby influencing miner strategies. Future steps involve gathering input from the developer community and evaluating miner interest in using Remote Procedure Calls (RPCs) for block submission or supporting direct non-compact version submissions for initial spread. Market research is critical to ascertain the practicality and inclination among miners, especially smaller entities, towards adopting this system for enhanced network convergence.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T15:56:26.759000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
