<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
  <updated>2024-04-16T01:58:57.731732+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2024-04-15 19:58:05.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2024-04-15 05:14:32.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek  . 2024-04-13 17:18:42.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2237_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2228_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2222_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T01:58:57.731783+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/can-game-theory-secure-scaling/797/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation around off-chain deferred settlement protocols like lightning networks brings to light the complexities and challenges inherent in their operation. These protocols necessitate constant vigilance for breaches of contract and require interactivity, demanding a persistent agent's presence to manage these tasks on behalf of the user. This requirement complicates the use of such protocols due to the need for uninterrupted liveness to ensure transactions are completed and to guard against potential breaches. The introduction of additional deferral mechanisms, as suggested in some proposals, may further complicate matters by increasing the demands on users to maintain such vigilant oversight without significantly addressing the core issues that push individuals towards considering custodial solutions.

To alleviate these concerns, two primary solutions emerge: simplifying the process of initiating an agent that can autonomously handle these responsibilities or devising protocols that eliminate the need for continuous monitoring altogether. Products like [Start9](https://marketplace.start9.com/lnd) exemplify attempts to simplify the user's role in managing these processes. Meanwhile, the integrity of lightning networks relies heavily on the disincentive for dishonesty, given the high stakes of losing all channel funds through misconduct. However, ensuring this deterrent works in practice requires users to have the capability to promptly address any breaches, a factor that extends to funding transactions as well.

The discussion then shifts to the concept of sidechains and the innovative ways they can potentially support the cryptocurrency ecosystem without undermining security or autonomy. By employing a model where transactions are prepared off-chain and only finalized on-chain in response to specific triggers, a framework is established that allows for efficient test networks and potentially broader applications. This model hinges on the ability to obscure complex multi-signature arrangements behind simpler interfaces, enhancing both usability and security. The envisioned system would balance flexibility and control, enabling transactions to proceed under clearly defined conditions while guarding against misuse through standardization and encryption measures. Such a setup could also benefit from networked nodes acting as global watchtowers, further securing the system against unauthorized alterations.

Lastly, the "Last Mile" proposal introduces a novel approach aimed at making self-custody more appealing and economically feasible without compromising transaction speed or reliability. By capitalizing on traditional Bitcoin transactions in a way that delays their broadcast until necessary, this method aims to incentivize honesty and reduce the allure of custodial options. Despite its preliminary nature, this proposal invites community engagement to refine and develop the concept further, with the ultimate goal of fostering a digital asset environment that values autonomy, efficiency, and security. The sharing of foundational documents and ideas on platforms like GitHub underscores a collaborative effort to address these challenges head-on.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-15T19:58:05.995000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
