<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2024-04-30T01:55:21.715072+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>evoskuil 2024-04-29 13:45:50.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-04-29 12:26:28.811000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2348_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2347_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T01:55:21.715111+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with a reflection on the challenges faced by the concept of pool hopping in the context of state threats, highlighting how such threats might have delayed investments in potential solutions or improvements for decentralized mining. There's an expression of hope that small-scale miners operating independently and competitively could be an ideal solution, especially with the introduction and subsequent investment in braids technology since the Scaling Hong Kong conference.

The conversation shifts to concerns over the risks and liabilities associated with transaction selection potentially leading to full centralization around block template providers. This issue is exacerbated by the reduction in the diversity of transaction sets used by pools and the limited number of pools available, contradicting the aim of achieving decentralization through pool hopping. The problem of transaction selection is framed as having more downsides than upsides, given every jurisdiction has entities they oppose, which could range from political to criminal. This poses a significant challenge to Bitcoin's goal of being censorship-resistant.

An alternative proposed to address these challenges involves adopting a deterministic algorithm for transaction selection, contingent upon achieving consensus on the mempool's contents. This approach would necessitate a committed mempool with consensus, achievable in decentralized mining pools like P2Pool or Braidpool by incorporating a metadata block containing transactions into the weak blocks used by the pool. This system allows for a self-consistent block with no size restriction, defined by the highest work-weighted path to the previous Bitcoin block within the share chain.

The advantages of this method include eliminating the need to communicate block templates to sharechain nodes, thereby speeding up validation processes and reducing communication bandwidth requirements. However, it doesn't completely solve the issue of transaction censorship but rather transfers it to the share chain. Preventing a transaction from being mined in the main chain now requires preventing it from being mined in the share chain, although in a DAG, conflicts can still arise through diamond-type graphs, and in P2Pool-like chains, through orphaning a share chain block. This nuanced perspective underscores the complexity of achieving true decentralization and censorship resistance in blockchain networks.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-29T13:45:50.660000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
