<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
  <updated>2024-04-02T01:56:29.989929+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cryptoquick 2024-04-01 06:02:32.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-25 17:46:17.413000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-03-25 13:30:21.075000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-03-24 01:10:48.966000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-21 14:10:49.825000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-03-21 00:19:14.595000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-19 00:48:28.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roconnorblockstream  . 2024-03-15 22:53:08.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roconnorblockstream  . 2024-03-15 21:59:44.349000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen  . 2024-03-14 23:44:37.805000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>prozacchiwawa  . 2024-03-14 23:03:34.690000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-03-14 22:25:27.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>prozacchiwawa  . 2024-03-14 22:23:35.310000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj  . 2024-03-14 22:19:45.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-03-14 12:51:49.490000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2111_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2040_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2030_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1993_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1978_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1977_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1930_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1910_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1909_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1901_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1900_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1899_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1897_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1898_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1886_BTC-Lisp-as-an-alternative-to-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BTC Lisp as an alternative to Script</title>
    <updated>2024-04-02T01:56:29.990037+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/btc-lisp-as-an-alternative-to-script/682/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The correspondence presents a detailed discussion on programming constructs, particularly focusing on blockchain technology, including Bitcoin scripts, Chialisp, and the integration of Lisp. It begins with a playful naming suggestion for a programming construct, "Thcript," before delving into more complex topics such as the differentiation between consensus code and supplementary infrastructure in software development. A significant portion of code differences, potentially over 80%, is attributed to supporting structures like COQ proofs, which are crucial for validation but do not contribute directly to the core consensus code. This distinction is essential for developers and stakeholders to make informed decisions.

One primary concern discussed is the challenge posed by using Simplicity as a consensus language due to its complexity and extensive code requirements. The Elements1219 pull request is highlighted as an example of this complexity, suggesting a focus on formal specifications and tooling for code generation as a more manageable approach. The discourse emphasizes the importance of balancing review efficiency with code integrity and security, likening the deletion of mechanical proofs for simplicity to cutting brake lines for speed, thus underlining the risks involved.

The conversation introduces a simplified syntax approach, `!curly-infix` notation, and a unique shorthand involving "O," "I," and "H" to enhance readability and ease of implementation in languages like Simplicity. Furthermore, it discusses the implementation of Scheme interpreters as compilers for stack virtual machines to facilitate efficient environment lookups and simplify variable access, contrasting with Bitcoin SCRIPT's limitations. A concept of softfork semantics through an `OP_EVALINSOFTFORK` operation is proposed for adding new opcodes to Bitcoin, enabling backward compatibility and the potential for arbitrary looping within scripts.

The dialogue explores the nuances of various programming languages within blockchain development, touching upon the practical implications of these languages in terms of reviewability, predictability, and bug prevention. Concerns about the complexity and accessibility of Simplicity are raised, alongside discussions on integrating just-in-time (JIT) compilation to enhance performance without sacrificing safety.

Finally, the email compares Chia Lisp, Simplicity, and Bitcoin Script regarding computational methods, data handling, readability, and typing systems. While acknowledging broad similarities, distinct characteristics, and trade-offs involved in designing languages optimized for blockchain applications are pointed out. The sender, involved with Chia and working on the chialisp compiler, shares insights and resources including an [overview of modern chialisp efforts](https://chialisp.com/modern-chialisp/), a [Rust code repository](https://github.com/Chia-Network/clvm_tools_rs/tree/base/src/compiler), and an [introductory document on a gradual type system](https://github.com/Chia-Network/clvm_tools_rs/blob/7aa40d44fb3310c6dde14af181d40f9dd4029fef/types.md) being developed for chialisp. The communication also advocates against using one-character names in programming for better readability and easier debugging, explores the benefits of Lisp's quasiquotation syntax, and suggests Haskell's strategy of lazy evaluation as a solution for compiler design challenges. The proposal to integrate Lisp as an alternative scripting language within Bitcoin's blockchain aims to enhance transaction mechanisms without altering the UTXO database structure, reflecting the adaptability of functional programming languages in blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-01T06:02:32.125000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
