<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
  <updated>2024-04-02T02:00:00.535925+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2024-04-02 00:43:13.940000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2024-04-01 21:19:31.406000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq 2024-04-01 20:35:50.495000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-25 08:36:40.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-22 23:41:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:40:39.031000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-22 11:38:27.559000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2024-03-21 20:55:55.854000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-03-21 17:33:00.972000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2024-03-21 16:27:09.262000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2126_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2125_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2124_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/2022_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1991_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1989_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1990_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1985_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1982_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1980_Mempool-Based-Fee-Estimation-on-Bitcoin-Core.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Mempool Based Fee Estimation on Bitcoin Core</title>
    <updated>2024-04-02T02:00:00.536009+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-based-fee-estimation-on-bitcoin-core/703/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation underscores the significance of enhancing fee estimation for blockchain transactions, highlighting adjustments in data representation and the introduction of log scale on the y-axis to better depict discrepancies in fee payments. It appreciates ClaraSh's contribution towards bridging gaps in fee rate data from the 5th to the 75th percentile, suggesting improvements in visual data representation could aid users in avoiding excessive fees.

The discussion transitions to addressing challenges in fee estimation, particularly in relation to selfish mining attacks. It introduces a technical strategy that leverages the `CBlockPolicyEstimator` threshold for refining fee estimation accuracy and suggests the possibility of employing fee bumping techniques to mitigate underestimation risks. This segment emphasizes enhancing security against manipulation tactics by offering users access to verbose mempool state information.

Challenges in accurately estimating transaction fees due to the dynamic nature of blockchain transactions are further explored, with special attention to the risks posed by mempool surges. The dialogue recommends incorporating direct blockchain data into analyses for real-time adjustments, ensuring fee estimations align more closely with current network conditions and miner behaviors. It also points out discrepancies between user and miner mempools, advocating for comprehensive blockchain analytics to improve estimation processes.

Kalle Alm's research at Scaling Bitcoin 2017 is referenced, presenting insights into optimizing fee estimation through mempool state analysis. Alm suggests the use of Replace By Fee (RBF) mechanisms and choosing the minimum between confirmed and mempool estimates to efficiently adjust fee rates. His research also touches on the practical considerations of using RBF, including potential financial strategy revelations. Resources for further exploration include [Slides](https://scalingbitcoin.org/stanford2017/Day2/Scaling-2017-Optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state.pdf), [Transcript](https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/), and [Video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QkYXPJMqBNk&amp;t=2052s).

Lastly, the conversation delves into the intricacies of mempool-based fee estimation utilized by Bitcoin Core, detailing its reliance on analyzing node mempool transactions to recommend optimal fee rates. Despite its advantages in adjusting to network conditions, limitations arise from disparities between individual node mempools and those of network miners. Anticipated future advancements such as Cluster Mempool aim to streamline block template construction, although concerns about block propagation speeds remain. An experimental RPC version of this estimator has been launched, indicating ongoing efforts to refine and evaluate mempool-based fee estimation strategies, showcased in an experimental phase without full sanity checks available at [mempool-based fee estimator without any sanity check](https://github.com/ismaelsadeeq/bitcoin/tree/02-2024-fee-estimation-with-mempool-without-s-check).</summary>
    <published>2024-04-02T00:43:13.940000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
