<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
  <updated>2024-04-18T01:54:34.730174+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2024-04-17 15:13:15.924000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek 2024-04-17 13:01:37.414000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-04-16 20:15:20.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek  . 2024-04-16 19:50:43.067000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-04-15 19:58:05.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2024-04-15 05:14:32.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek  . 2024-04-13 17:18:42.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2253_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2248_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2244_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2243_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2237_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2228_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2222_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T01:54:34.730243+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/can-game-theory-secure-scaling/797/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the comparison of LN-Symmetry (eltoo) protocol and a proposed system highlights significant differences in the risk profiles for participants involved in blockchain transactions. In eltoo, the financial risk to an honest party is limited to transaction fees, which can be minimal, especially in high-value channels. This low risk facilitates a market environment where neither party feels compelled to demand a premium or discount based on the perceived risk of loss. Conversely, the proposed system suggests that an honest party may incur a substantial fraction of their funds to penalize a dishonest participant. This introduces a scenario where the receiver might only accept transactions at a discount, and the spender might seek a risk premium, potentially hindering market match due to divergent cost expectations from both parties.

The increasing trend towards custodial lightning wallets within the cryptocurrency community raises concerns about cost-effectiveness versus sovereignty. While custodial services offer lower costs, they compromise users' control over their assets. The ambition to grow the number of sovereign users faces challenges in balancing accessibility with maintaining the integrity of the blockchain's foundational principles. The ease of use provided by custodial solutions contrasts with the ideal of user sovereignty, underscoring a fundamental tension in advancing network health without compromising its core values.

Further examination reveals that managing Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) presents nuanced capabilities and limitations, especially regarding Alice's theoretical ability to manipulate UTXOs on-chain with comprehensive condition awareness. Concealing N-of-N multisig arrangements behind a single public key could streamline transactions without preliminary blockchain actions, suggesting nodes could serve as global watchtowers. This approach addresses privacy and security concerns by limiting information broadcast. The exploration into enhancing non-custodial lightning networks’ usability through autonomous agents and protocols for reducing the need for continuous online presence points towards solutions like [Start9](https://marketplace.start9.com/lnd). These innovations aim to democratize access while safeguarding the blockchain's underlying structure, emphasizing the importance of inclusivity without sacrificing network integrity.

The complexity of operating off-chain deferred settlement protocols like Lightning is underscored by the requirement for ongoing blockchain monitoring and interactivity for transfer completions. Proposals aiming to further defer these processes inadvertently increase the operational burden, necessitating more sophisticated solutions. The introduction of entities like [Start9](https://marketplace.start9.com/lnd) simplifies deploying autonomous agents, reducing barriers to non-custodial lightning network operations. However, the sustainability of such systems relies on active breach response capabilities, highlighting a preference for custodial solutions amidst challenges in maintaining non-custodial operations.

Discussing sidechains unveils potential uses and implementations, notably in creating test networks for off-chain transaction management. This approach allows for flexibility in transactions without moving actual coins, offering privacy and security enhancements through obscured multi-signature transactions behind single public keys. Proposed standardness rules aim to ensure seamless operation across the network, emphasizing trust and openness with additional client interaction verifications. Incorporating storing penalty transactions into Bitcoin nodes proposes a novel security layer, transforming nodes into global watchtowers to deter unauthorized broadcasts. Despite the inherent risks of attack by malicious actors, community consensus and software adoption play crucial roles in ensuring transaction integrity and network security.

The "Last Mile" concept emerges as a novel proposal addressing the balance between cost-efficiency and sovereignty in self-custody versus custodial services. By leveraging traditional Bitcoin transactions in dispute scenarios, it aims to make honesty economically favorable, presenting a counter-narrative to the prevailing custodial trend. The availability of foundational details on GitHub invites community engagement to refine and enhance the proposition, striving for a solution that embodies autonomy and efficiency in digital transactions, accessible via [this link](https://github.com/hynek-jina/Hynek/blob/0301c90015f9d66fb22e347f21924dc9d04f0bc8/blog/Last%20mile%20transactions.md).</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T15:13:15.924000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
