<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
  <updated>2024-04-17T01:57:13.276641+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags 2024-04-16 20:15:20.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek 2024-04-16 19:50:43.067000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-04-15 19:58:05.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2024-04-15 05:14:32.096000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hynek  . 2024-04-13 17:18:42.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2244_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2243_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2237_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2228_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2222_Can-Game-Theory-Secure-Scaling-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Can Game Theory Secure Scaling?</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T01:57:13.276694+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/can-game-theory-secure-scaling/797/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discourse surrounding the use of custodial lightning wallets within the cryptocurrency community sheds light on a pressing dilemma: the trade-off between cost efficiency and user sovereignty. The inclination towards custodial solutions is largely attributed to their reduced operational costs. However, this convenience arguably comes at the significant cost of relinquishing control over one's digital assets. Contrary to this prevailing trend, there exists a compelling argument that championing self-custody can still be economically feasible, without necessarily compromising transaction speed or convenience. In the midst of this debate, a pioneering proposal known as "Last Mile" emerges, aspiring to reconcile these conflicting interests. This proposition ingeniously suggests a novel application of traditional Bitcoin transactions, where transactions are withheld from being broadcasted unless a dispute necessitates it. This mechanism ingeniously incentivizes honesty, positing a scenario where the potential costs associated with deceitful actions outweigh any perceived benefits. By doing so, "Last Mile" endeavors to render self-custody an attractive option by ensuring its affordability and efficiency, thereby challenging the current predilection for custodial services. For those intrigued by the underpinnings of the "Last Mile" concept, further elucidation is accessible through a document available on GitHub, which can be explored [here](https://github.com/hynek-jina/Hynek/blob/0301c90015f9d66fb22e347f21924dc9d04f0bc8/blog/Last%20mile%20transactions.md). While the proposal modestly acknowledges its preliminary nature, it actively solicits the community's engagement for critique and refinement, aiming to evolve the idea into a robust solution that harmoniously balances autonomy with transactional efficiency.

The underlying challenges of implementing off-chain deferred settlement protocols, such as the Lightning Network, are underscored by the indispensable need for ongoing blockchain surveillance to detect and mitigate any contractual breaches, coupled with the requisite interactivity for completing transfers. These operational demands highlight the paramount importance of having a dedicated agent to undertake these tasks on behalf of the user, thereby complicating the protocol’s usability. The complexity inherent in these protocols extends beyond the mere act of signing transactions; it encompasses the continuous maintenance and active management essential for preserving the integrity and finality of transactions. Proposals aiming to defer these processes further exacerbate these challenges, necessitating more intricate solutions or mechanisms to address the added layers of deferral. Within this context, solutions like [Start9](https://marketplace.start9.com/lnd) gain prominence by offering simplified means to deploy agents capable of autonomously managing these responsibilities, thus lowering the barriers to non-custodial operation of Lightning networks. Moreover, the inherent game theory of the Lightning Network discourages dishonest behavior by imposing severe penalties for broadcasting outdated states, potentially leading to the loss of all channel funds. Nonetheless, this theoretical safeguard relies heavily on users' capacity to actively counter breaches, underscoring the critical need for innovative protocols or solutions that minimize or eliminate the necessity for such active involvement.

Exploring the utilization of sidechains reveals intriguing insights into their potential application, particularly in the realm of test networks and transaction management. The core premise suggests that transactions could be executed off-chain without the actual movement of coins, enabling the creation of a test network where coins materialize only upon being signed for and vanish once transferred on-chain. Although not deemed a definitive resolution, this concept unveils the versatility and potential inherent in managing transactions outside the main blockchain. A significant revelation from this exploration is the feasibility of concealing complex multi-signature transactions behind a singular public key, which opens up promising avenues for enhancing both privacy and security in transaction management. The proposed framework for establishing such a network revolves around on-chain coin signing to facilitate peg-ins, coupled with on-chain movements to execute peg-outs, all while maintaining minimal restrictions on verifying transaction histories. To curtail abuse, the implementation of standardness rules is recommended, ensuring seamless peg-in and peg-out operations across the network under basic conditions like OP_TRUE. Although the network fundamentally relies on a degree of trust and transparency, certain client interactions might require additional verification steps, such as proving ownership of specific on-chain UTXOs with designated multi-signature arrangements. Further discussions delve into bolstering network security and integrity, notably through the innovative notion of embedding features like "storing penalty transactions" within Bitcoin nodes. These enhanced nodes could serve as global watchtowers, preventing unauthorized broadcasts by encrypting penalty transactions and decrypting them solely in response to recognized disputes. This strategy introduces an added security layer, ensuring transactions remain confidential until their disclosure becomes necessary. Yet, the effectiveness of such measures heavily depends on the collective honesty and cooperation among miners and participants in disseminating and adopting software endowed with these new capabilities. This acknowledgment brings to the fore the perpetual risk posed by malicious entities within any second-layer solution, while simultaneously highlighting the crucial role of community consensus and integrity in countering such threats.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-16T20:15:20.354000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
