<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Second Look at Weak Blocks</title>
  <updated>2024-04-19T01:56:21.144775+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-04-18 17:14:04.476000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-04-18 15:47:09.925000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath 2024-04-18 13:36:59.726000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2024-04-18 12:46:56.542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2024-04-18 11:16:26.881000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2024-04-18 07:16:55.801000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-04-17 15:56:26.759000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-04-17 15:28:21.297000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-04-16 17:45:35.589000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2275_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2274_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2271_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2270_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2268_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2262_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2255_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2254_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2242_Second-Look-at-Weak-Blocks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Second Look at Weak Blocks</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T01:56:21.144877+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/second-look-at-weak-blocks/805/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the limitations and potential of weak block propagation in blockchain networks, specifically addressing the inefficacy of weak blocks in achieving mempool synchronization in a fragmented mempool environment. The primary issue highlighted is that miners engaged in out-of-band fee arrangements are unlikely to share transactions they are paid for out-of-band through weak blocks, as this could enable other miners to usurp these fees. This practice not only undermines the goal of mempool synchronization but also exacerbates the challenge of block validation times due to the necessity of retrieving missing transactions. Moreover, the approach conflicts with the "first seen" rule employed by mempools for accepting transactions, thereby impacting transaction censorship resistance and failing to establish a consensus on transaction order, considering the manipulability of timestamps.

A proposed solution to these challenges involves the implementation of Braidpool, which aims to incentivize miners to participate in a decentralized mining pool, offering benefits such as reduced variance and outsourced transaction selection. This model relies on extending Nakamoto consensus to a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) structure to achieve time ordering and conflict resolution among transactions within weak blocks. However, it is acknowledged that while a decentralized mining pool can encourage adherence to transaction broadcast norms, it cannot entirely prevent centralized pools from engaging in out-of-band transaction acceptance. Economic disincentives are suggested as a means to deter such practices. The discourse includes references to further reading on Braidpool's ambitions and specifications.

Additionally, there's a consideration of employing a variant of compact block messages to facilitate the propagation of "weak compact blocks," aiming to streamline the process without necessitating a consensus on these messages. This approach focuses on ensuring efficient transmission and validation of weak blocks, potentially reducing the overhead associated with filling gaps in transaction history. This concept aligns with Braidpool’s strategy of referencing the last confirmed bitcoin block to simplify the validation of weak blocks, thus avoiding the sequential validation typically required.

The exploration also extends to optimizing bandwidth usage through selective transmission of weak blocks and prioritizing `weakheaders` to mitigate additional data transfer loads. It contemplates the frequency of weak block discovery and its implications on network data volume, suggesting a need for strategic filtering to manage redundancy effectively. The proposal theorizes on maintaining a manageable weak block cache size, anticipating a high occurrence rate of weak blocks between actual block confirmations, which necessitates efficient processing capabilities for rapid proof of work validation and transaction caching.

Furthermore, the narrative touches upon the evolution of mining shares propagation and the potential integration of existing compact block infrastructure to support weak block transmission. This adaptation seeks to improve compact block relay efficiency and contribute to mining fairness by alleviating discrepancies arising from divergent mempool policies. The proposal underscores several unresolved questions related to the validation and management of weak blocks, advocating for community feedback and further experimentation to refine the approach. Possible applications and the broader impacts of this system on network performance and mining strategies, including fee estimation for subsequent blocks, are also discussed, indicating areas for future research and development.</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T17:14:04.476000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
