<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - DNS seeds returning gone peers</title>
  <updated>2023-05-15T18:57:18.340843+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-08-03 15:32:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-08-03 14:48:33</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-08-03 11:38:19</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000285_DNS-seeds-returning-gone-peers.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000283_DNS-seeds-returning-gone-peers.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000272_DNS-seeds-returning-gone-peers.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - DNS seeds returning gone peers</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T18:57:18.340843+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-August/000285.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In this email thread, Gregory Maxwell and Mike Hearn discuss the issue of a starved p2p network for connectable slots. Hearn suggests massively increasing all the anti-DoS limits in 0.4 to solve the problem, but Maxwell counters that it's not possible to increase the number of available connection slots significantly without risking memory issues for nodes on lower memory systems. They both agree that 125 slots should be enough and the focus should be on finding out why it isn't. Hearn also talks about how bad nodes are appearing in DNS seeds and slowing down peer bringup for Android apps. He runs a test using nmap and finds that only 19 out of 48 IPs returned are usable. Maxwell points out that the actual number is much less as filtered IPs are also worthless and nmap can't tell if a node has its connection slots full without making an actual connection. Finally, Hearn mentions that he's hoping a friend would take on DNS seeding as a project and suggests a custom DNS server that watches the network to find long-lived peers running the latest version, which could help resolve the issue. Maxwell points him to a GitHub repository for DNS seeding and suggests using a different DNS server that pulls directly from the database for a more dynamic solution.</summary>
    <published>2011-08-03T15:32:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
