<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Change to multiple executables?</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:54:21.979708+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-08-11 13:50:54</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-08-11 13:08:45</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Pieter Wuille 2011-08-10 10:43:36</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Matt Corallo 2011-08-10 10:14:49</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000358_Change-to-multiple-executables-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000357_Change-to-multiple-executables-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000331_Change-to-multiple-executables-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000329_Change-to-multiple-executables-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Change to multiple executables?</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:54:21.979708+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-August/000358.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In August 2011, there was a discussion on the Bitcoin development mailing list about the organization of the client. John Smith proposed splitting the client into three separate executables: bitcoind for the daemon, bitcoin-qt or bitcoin-gui for the GUI executable, and bitcoincl for the RPC command line. Pieter and Matt Corallo expressed their opinions on the proposal. Pieter initially misunderstood the proposal, but after clarification, he supported it. He also suggested a script or symlink that detects whether RPC commands are present on the command line to invoke either bitcoin-server/bitcoin-gui or bitcoin-client. Matt agreed with the split of the source into separate library components but disagreed with splitting into more executables. He argued that adding more executables would complicate things for users with little clear advantage. Instead, he suggested making RPC optional for GUI users. They also discussed the possibility of merging bitcoin-qt into the mainline codebase. Finally, they discussed the issue of backward-incompatible changes to the protocol and the need for a dev branch to deal with internal changes.</summary>
    <published>2011-08-11T13:50:54+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
