<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T04:47:00.289057+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-08-04 20:35:53</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell 2011-07-23 23:39:13</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Aug_2011/000298_Discussion-related-to-pull-349-and-pull-319-escrow-transactions-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="July_2011/000217_Discussion-related-to-pull-349-and-pull-319-escrow-transactions-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Discussion related to pull 349 and pull 319 (escrow transactions)</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T04:47:00.289057+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2011-August/000298.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an email conversation dated August 3, 2011, it was discussed that with Eligius mining IsStandard transactions and other pools open to the idea, it could be possible to quickly get 30% or more of mining power to upgrade. However, it was also noted that propagation is a crucial factor in addition to mining power. The focus on maturity/bugfixes was predicted to delay the full patch, but the IsStandard part was seen as uncontroversial and could go in quickly. The suggestion was made to split pull request 319 into two separate ones: one for the IsStandard change and the other for the full escrow feature set. Pull request 349 was also mentioned as an implementation of multiple signature escrowed transactions that needs further testing and discussion before being added to the client. It was noted that the patch exposes an issue with multisig validation due to redundancy in the script length coding opcodes, and one candidate fix for this is to exclude the length opcodes from the comparison. However, this fix carries a risk of creating differences in how nodes validate transactions leading to lasting forks. Another way of fixing it would be to define that OP_PUSHDATA* cannot be used to push the smaller lengths which could be more efficiently encoded with the direct length opcodes, but this may not solve the problem entirely. Lastly, changing how the templating code works to ensure it codes the template the same way the original was coded was suggested as another potential solution.</summary>
    <published>2011-08-04T20:35:53+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
