<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2024-07-24T02:05:19.536051+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-07-23T09:01:14.255000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T02:05:19.536076+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the technical specifics and implications of implementing changes to Bitcoin's consensus rules, particularly focusing on the witness commitment in coinbase transactions and potential alternatives for incorporating additional commitments. The initial point highlights a hypothetical scenario regarding pre-Segwit coinbase transactions and their inability to carry a specific witness commitment format, which includes a commitment marker followed by a sequence of zeroes. This format is crucial for ensuring the functionality of the witness commitment, especially in empty blocks where the coinbase witness consists entirely of zeroes.

Further examination delves into the challenges associated with adding more than one commitment to the blockchain in a way that remains compatible with existing soft-fork mechanisms. The text outlines the difficulties in achieving this without either causing a hard fork or necessitating the direct inclusion of all commitment values in each block, which would significantly alter the current operation of the blockchain.

An alternative solution proposed involves the use of the `nLockTime` field within transactions as a more straightforward method for introducing future commitments. This approach is favored due to its simplicity and the lower likelihood of disrupting existing processes. The discussion also contemplates the timing for activating such a change, with suggestions ranging from immediate implementation to deferring the activation by up to two decades. The consensus leans towards a shorter notice period before enforcement, arguing that a delay of many years could lead to non-compliance and potentially significant issues for future stakeholders, drawing parallels to the Y2K problem. This perspective emphasizes the importance of timely updates to the Bitcoin protocol to ensure its continued relevance and functionality.

For further details, refer to the original discussion on [DelvingBitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/6?u=ajtowns).</summary>
    <published>2024-07-23T09:01:14.255000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
