<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2024-07-30T02:06:57.459259+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kravens 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T02:06:57.459348+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent advancements and challenges in the realm of cryptocurrency privacy have led to significant developments, particularly in how transactions are managed and executed to enhance user anonymity. A pivotal method for conducting private transactions, CoinJoin, has seen innovative adaptations, notably with Trezor Suite enabling CoinJoin again through alternative coordinators. This was achieved by starting the Trezor Suite app with a debug argument setting a custom coordinator server, as detailed in a guide provided at [Change Coordinator (kravens.nl)](https://wasabi.kravens.nl/trezor), which includes an example for connecting to the Noderunners Coordinator.

The dynamic involvement of volunteers in projects has been crucial, especially in initiatives aimed at developing systems that operate independently of hardcoded directory nodes or reliance on specific individuals. This approach is designed to create a more sustainable and autonomous infrastructure, addressing the challenges posed by a changing roster of volunteers. The discussion extends to the architecture of decentralized networks, emphasizing the unresolved issue of peer discovery, which transitions the responsibility to directory nodes, underscoring the need for a reliable entity to manage these nodes effectively.

The JoinMarket messaging protocol stands out as a significant contribution to the security and operation of decentralized Bitcoin transactions. It highlights the use of encrypted communication channels and specifies mechanisms for transaction creation and management, ensuring user anonymity and efficient coinjoin transactions. This protocol facilitates peer-to-peer transactions without central authority, contributing to a robust financial system. Detailed documentation on this protocol is available at [GitHub](https://github.com/JoinMarket-Org/JoinMarket-Docs/blob/d098c022b2fa4d148337aa45e995083e3416a3c2/Joinmarket-messaging-protocol.md), providing insights into its implementation and promoting wider adoption.

Communication infrastructure within decentralized systems utilizes directory nodes, Internet Relay Chat (IRC), and Onion services, with specific configuration requirements for onion-based messaging channels. These configurations address the setup for directory nodes and the importance of correctly specifying parameters for operational integrity. Additionally, the documentation outlines IRC server configurations for maintaining anonymity over traditional IP networks and Tor.

JoinMarket with Jam offers an alternative wallet interface operating without a central coordinator, promising enhanced privacy and security despite a complex setup process. However, the absence of detailed technical insight on its decentralization methodology leaves gaps in understanding its operation. Meanwhile, the joinstr protocol presents a decentralized coordination mechanism utilizing nostr relays for peer communication, diverging from traditional coinjoin methods by facilitating public pool information dissemination and encrypted PSBT exchange. Further technical details and philosophies behind joinstr are explored in its Network Improvement Proposal (NIP) at [GitLab](https://gitlab.com/1440000bytes/joinstr/-/blob/main/NIP.md).

Recent crackdowns on non-custodial privacy tools have reshaped the Bitcoin privacy service landscape, leading to the closure of coordinator servers such as Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet. In response, alternatives like JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin have emerged, highlighting adaptations to maintain transaction privacy. The BTCPay plugin, leveraging the WabiSabi protocol, enables users to host their own coordinator services, discoverable via Nostr relay, integrating with wallets supporting WabiSabi. This development, along with tools designed to locate active coordinators, hints at a potential decentralized network of BTCPay Coordinators and the evolving strategies to enhance Bitcoin transaction privacy in response to regulatory pressures.</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T18:46:11.526000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
