<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
  <updated>2025-09-06T02:21:13.010099+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>kravens 2025-09-05 11:25:31.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-06-24 00:46:03.504000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-06-04 22:57:12.634000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-23 18:48:34.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-23 12:50:43.605000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-23 12:49:42.885000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-21 15:17:30.948000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-09-21 01:44:52.889000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 22:46:58.079000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-20 15:23:05.543000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-09-20 14:03:45.676000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Gibson  . 2024-09-19 16:21:53.074000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-08-28 17:15:28.379000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-07-29 18:46:11.526000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-19 02:09:07.214000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-18 12:45:46.196000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:32:55.911000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-17 19:27:30.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>realorrandom  . 2024-06-11 06:59:48.377000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>everythingSats  . 2024-06-04 16:00:23.138000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-03 06:20:10.278000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>conduition  . 2024-06-02 22:18:52.919000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-06-02 15:23:09.812000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kravens  . 2024-06-02 10:01:26.166000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2025/5837_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5337_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5215_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3252_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3250_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3249_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3244_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3242_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3241_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3238_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3237_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3234_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/3076_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2903_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2747_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2738_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2728_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2727_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2682_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2632_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2608_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2605_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2602_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2598_Who-will-run-the-CoinJoin-coordinators-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Who will run the CoinJoin coordinators?</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T02:21:13.010288+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/who-will-run-the-coinjoin-coordinators/934" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent updates in the Wasabi Wallet, as detailed in their [latest release](https://github.com/WalletWasabi/WalletWasabi/releases/tag/v2.7.0), highlight a significant advancement towards enhancing privacy within the Bitcoin ecosystem. This version introduces an easier method for users to run their own anonymous coordinator as an onion service, accessible only via the Tor network. This development comes at a crucial time when public and clearnet coordinators face increased scrutiny and potential shutdowns, such as the case with [coinjoin.nl](https://coinjoin.nl). The necessity of switching from BTCPay Server's Coinjoin plugin to Wasabi Wallet for better reliability and support is emphasized, despite the plugin's discontinuation of active maintenance. The encouragement for community involvement in maintaining this plugin reflects a proactive stance towards sustaining privacy tools within the cryptocurrency realm.

Discussions around new whirlpool coordinators raise substantial concerns regarding security vulnerabilities and user trust within the community. A detailed thread on BitcoinTalk ([here](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5547639.0)) sheds light on these issues, proposing collective efforts to enhance the security framework and maintain the integrity of cryptocurrency transactions. Meanwhile, the U.S. Secret Service's alert on cryptocurrency mixing activities, specifically mentioning @kruw's coordinator, underscores the challenges law enforcement faces in tracing illicitly obtained digital currencies. This situation highlights the delicate balance between innovation in cryptocurrency services and preventing illegal use cases.

Technical discussions also delve into Bitcoin's `ALL|ANYONECANPAY` signature feature, exploring its potential applications and limitations. The complexities and nuances surrounding Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT) and wallets underline the ongoing need for developer attention to detail and innovation in addressing these challenges. Moreover, the conversation extends to privacy features in blockchain transactions, examining the limitations and seeking solutions for more flexible and private transaction mechanisms.

Joinstr's development represents a noteworthy effort in decentralizing coordination for cryptocurrency transactions, aiming to overcome communication coordination centralization issues encountered by Joinmarket. This protocol utilizes the SIGHASH ALL | SIGHASH ANYONECANPAY signature hash type, highlighting a forward-thinking approach to transaction signing and the potential for incorporating covenants for enhanced security and functionality. JoinMarket's evolution, from relying on a single IRC server to introducing directory nodes for peer-to-peer encrypted messaging, illustrates the continuous pursuit of decentralization within the coinjoin transaction space.

CoinShuffle and its improved version, CoinShuffle++, offer advancements in transaction privacy but still face the challenge of centralization in communication coordination. This persistent issue underscores the intricacies of developing truly decentralized and uncensored communication methods within privacy-enhancing technologies. The discussion about the feasibility of using the blockchain or alternative, unconventional methods like ham radio for uncensored communication reflects the innovative thinking within the cryptocurrency community.

Furthermore, the closure of Samourai Wallet and Wasabi Wallet's coordinator servers due to legal actions signifies a pivotal moment in the Bitcoin privacy service landscape. The emergence of alternatives like JoinMarket with Jam and the BTCPay Server CoinJoin plugin suggests a shift towards more decentralized solutions that could potentially shape the future of privacy-enhanced cryptocurrency transactions. These developments indicate a crossroads in the evolution of Bitcoin privacy techniques, where the community's response and adaptation to regulatory pressures may lead to novel and resilient solutions.</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T11:25:31.138000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
