<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
  <updated>2024-07-16T02:09:18.932527+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2024-07-15 12:24:02.981000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-02-20 13:16:12.153000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-02-19 18:46:49.691000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-31 19:13:07.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-24 22:44:23.190000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-01-24 22:04:54.478000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-24 12:19:55.474000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-24 05:20:08.136000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-23 17:15:37.327000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-01-20 04:52:15.672000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2024-01-19 16:56:04.789000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2879_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1645_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1618_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1398_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1331_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1329_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1320_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1319_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1315_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1240_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1224_Ephemeral-Anchors-and-MEVil.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ephemeral Anchors and MEVil</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T02:09:18.932661+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ephemeral-anchors-and-mevil/383/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with an acknowledgment of the complexities surrounding the Lightning Network (LN) specifications, particularly focusing on the issues caused by the ability of counterparties to inflate transaction fees at another user's expense. A shift towards a simpler implementation of Pay To Anchors (P2A) without additional logic to counteract these issues is proposed, as detailed in a [GitHub pull request](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30352). The proposition includes a hybrid approach for managing transactions depending on the trimmed output value, suggesting different strategies for when there are no trimmed outputs or their value is low versus when the trimmed value is high.

Further analysis delves into the economic incentives behind choosing specific transaction fee structures within blockchain networks, emphasizing how parties may opt for cost-effective methods that influence the overall transactional landscape. A nuanced strategy involving zero-value outputs with an 'anyone-can-spend' clause and timelocked far into the future is highlighted, aiming to ensure these outputs do not disrupt mempool operations while keeping commitment transaction fees at zero.

The conversation evolves to examine the technical aspects of mempool transaction replacement and the associated incentives for inflating transaction values. Through illustrative scenarios using mermaid flowchart syntax, the dialogue explores how conflicting inputs in transactions are managed, proposing solutions like implementing checks during execution phases and leveraging Replace-by-Fee (RBF) logic post-clustering in the mempool to simulate conflicts more accurately.

Addressing the potential manipulation of ephemeral anchor values, the discussion underscores the risk of third parties influencing transaction fees and the subsequent need for channel parties to possibly resort to RBF to expedite transaction confirmation. This highlights a vulnerability in the fee structure and transaction confirmation process, necessitating robust mechanisms to prevent unwarranted cost escalations caused by external manipulations.

Technical scrutiny continues with a comparison of combined transaction fee rates and the implications of incorporating ephemeral anchors into transaction fees calculation. Concerns about how existing mempool transactions might affect the effectiveness of a proposed "diagram check" lead to suggestions for adjusting byte counts to optimize transaction fees.

Exploring the conditional logic related to transaction fees and ephemeral anchors, an optimization is suggested if an ephemeral anchor is added as an input to an existing transaction, reflecting on the efficiency of consolidating inputs to maintain adequate fee rates.

Lastly, the email addresses the strategic considerations involved in crafting transactions attractive to miners within a competitive blockchain space. An example elucidates the strategic financial structuring required for a transaction to remain competitive without relying on direct conflict with other transactions, thereby illuminating the intricate dynamics of transaction fee economics in the blockchain environment.</summary>
    <published>2024-07-15T12:24:02.981000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
