<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
  <updated>2024-08-08T02:09:22.278097+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding 2024-08-07 14:12:45.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-08-07 10:28:25.289000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-05 20:53:19.731000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-07-30 15:12:09.428000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2926_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2925_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2917_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2905_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T02:09:22.278197+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bolt-12-trusted-contacts/1046/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on enhancing the security and trustworthiness of payment notes in financial transactions between individuals, specifically addressing concerns about phishing attacks. The proposed solution involves a user interface workflow where the recipient can add a sender's contact key to their wallet, which would then label future payments from this contact with the sender's name. This process aims to establish a trusted connection between parties, reducing the risk of fraudulent transactions. However, concerns are raised about the potential for malicious actors to exploit this system by tricking users into associating their contact key with another person’s name, thus facilitating unauthorized transactions under false pretenses.

The conversation also touches on the practicality and risks of implementing a mutual authentication process through cryptographic means, suggesting the addition of a simple text field within encrypted messages to identify the sender. While recognizing the potential security risks of impersonation, the proposal sees value in instances where payments are made on behalf of others, emphasizing the need for a balance between convenience and security in digital transactions. This reflects a consideration for scenarios where specifying the actual payer could improve the transaction experience without compromising integrity.

Furthermore, the integration of Bolt 12 offers into lightning wallets is discussed as a means to streamline transactions while maintaining privacy and mutual authentication between contacts. The post outlines two methods for distributing contact keys: adding a new TLV field in Bolt 12 offers and using an optional query parameter in BIP21 URIs. Each method has its advantages and drawbacks, such as redundancy and the need for larger QR codes, respectively. The options for achieving mutual authentication include utilizing the `invreq_payer_id` field, deriving a per-contact `invreq_payer_id`, and employing bLIP-31 for message authentication. The post concludes with a call for feedback on these methods to refine [bLIP 42](https://github.com/lightning/blips/pull/42), aiming to enhance the user experience in Bolt 12 payments without sacrificing privacy or security.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-07T14:12:45.195000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
