<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
  <updated>2024-09-07T02:10:47.919355+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2024-09-06 11:35:02.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Vincenzo Palazzo  . 2024-09-02 15:06:10.533000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-08-09 07:01:37.418000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-07 14:12:45.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-08-07 10:28:25.289000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>David Harding  . 2024-08-05 20:53:19.731000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2024-07-30 15:12:09.428000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3113_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3089_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2930_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2926_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2925_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2917_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2905_Bolt-12-Trusted-Contacts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bolt 12 Trusted Contacts</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T02:10:47.919419+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bolt-12-trusted-contacts/1046/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing the C-Lightning framework's payment transactions delves into several key areas concerning user privacy, security, and functionality. A proposal is made for an optional text field to indicate the sender's identity in a payment transaction, drawing parallels with Ocean's Bolt12 methods which use descriptive tags to verify payer identity without complex processes. This approach aims at balancing transparency with privacy by allowing users to selectively reveal their identities to recipients they trust, thus maintaining domain separation and mitigating security risks associated with using common keys across different nodes.

The conversation further explores vulnerabilities and design considerations in cryptocurrency wallets, particularly focusing on the association of contact information with payment codes. It highlights the potential for deception where a user could mistakenly associate a malicious key with a trusted contact, leading to security breaches. The dialogue underscores the implications of compromised contact keys, especially for organizations, emphasizing the need for clear communication in such events. It also critiques the reliance on 'payer_note' fields for conveying security-related information, suggesting that it may inadvertently lead users to overlook important security practices.

Concerns about phishing attacks within payment systems are raised, illustrating how attackers might exploit the process of adding contacts to manipulate trust. This section discusses the risks associated with simplifying user interfaces to the extent that they might inadvertently enable attackers to forge transactions or deceive users into misattributing payments. The conversation questions the safety and efficiency of proposed systems, advocating for a cautious approach where users are educated to trust only the payment amount as a reliable piece of information.

The potential for employing cryptographic methods to facilitate mutual authentication during transactions is examined. The discussion points out the dual necessity of ensuring security while accommodating scenarios where flexibility in identifying the payment originator is beneficial. This balance is crucial for creating payment systems that are both secure and user-friendly, acknowledging the diverse needs for authentication and representation in digital transactions.

Finally, the email touches upon technical proposals for distributing contact keys in lightning wallets, specifically through Bolt 12 offers. It evaluates different methods for integrating mutual authentication into payment processes, weighing the simplicity against potential privacy and security trade-offs. The conversation calls for community feedback on enhancing Bolt 12 payments to support selective identity revelation, aiming to refine standards like bLIP 42 based on developer input. This dialogue reflects a broader consideration of how to best combine convenience, privacy, and security in digital payment solutions, highlighting ongoing efforts to improve user experience without compromising fundamental principles.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T11:35:02.270000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
