<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
  <updated>2025-05-09T02:46:06.825823+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen.682000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-08T06:38:16.682000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T02:46:06.825853+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines/1655/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the specifics of implementing an opcode in the context of Bitcoin transactions, particularly with respect to Pay-to-Witness-Script-Hash (P2WSH) transactions. The primary suggestion made is that this new opcode should enforce the requirement that a transaction includes a P2WSH output. This enforcement would involve specifying a SHA-256 hash of a script, thereby integrating a higher level of specificity and security within the transaction process.

This proposal implies a nuanced understanding of Bitcoin's scripting and transaction validation mechanisms. By mandating the presence of a P2WSH, the opcode would inherently ensure that transactions adhere to a certain structure, potentially streamlining verification processes and enhancing the network's ability to handle complex scripts efficiently. Such an approach could offer benefits in terms of both security and functionality, as it directly ties the execution of a script to the transaction's validity.

Overall, the suggestion to link the opcode's function with the existence of a P2WSH output represents a technical strategy aimed at refining Bitcoin's scripting capabilities. It suggests a path forward for developing more sophisticated and secure transaction types, which could have implications for how transactions are constructed and verified within the network.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-08T06:38:16.682000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
