<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
  <updated>2025-05-09T02:44:04.281464+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-08T14:09:29.385000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T02:44:04.281495+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the integration of amount opcodes with covenant opcodes presents potential synergies but also introduces significant challenges, particularly when separating the amount semantic from `CCV` or `VAULT`. One major issue arises in scenarios where transaction structures cannot be predetermined, such as in ergonomic vaults. In these cases, the inability to know which and how many vault UTXOs will be spent at the time of script definition necessitates a complex cross-input logic to ensure compatibility among input selections. This complexity underscores the nuanced yet critical role of amount logic within `CCV`, drawing inspiration from `VAULT` rather than its initial applications.

Moreover, achieving an efficient aggregation of inputs under a unified bitmap presents its own set of difficulties. The straightforward approach of replicating the bitmap across all inputs incurs an impractical $O(n^2)$ cost in both computational and space requirements. This contrasts sharply with the theoretical possibility of optimizing such operations to an $O(n)$ cost, suggesting that without embedded cross-input logic, efficiency gains are limited. A proposed solution involves designating a special input to perform all amount checks, thereby simplifying the verification process for other inputs. However, this approach may not be the most user-friendly.

The discussion further extends to the inherent limitations of covenant opcodes that do not incorporate amount logic, either directly or through supplementary mechanisms. The absence of such integration could render the covenant opcode ineffectual, as demonstrated by various examples and discussions within the community. The utility of `OP_OUT_AMOUNT` in conjunction with `OP_CCV`, especially in the `DEDUCT` mode, illustrates a promising avenue for bypassing complex arithmetic in scripts managing withdrawals from shared UTXOs. Conversely, the potential application of `OP_IN_AMOUNT` and 64-bit arithmetic for velocity-limited constructions highlights the diverse requirements across different use cases.

In conclusion, the separation of amount logic from covenant opcodes may compromise the efficacy and ergonomics of resulting scripts. Despite the challenges, integrating specific opcodes to facilitate direct checks on output amounts offers a pathway towards more efficient and simpler scripting solutions. The ongoing discourse, including insights from various implementations and theoretical frameworks, emphasizes the need for a balanced approach that accommodates the dynamic and multifaceted nature of blockchain transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-08T14:09:29.385000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
