<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
  <updated>2025-05-09T02:43:35.857797+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-05-08 19:41:45.428000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Op_inout_amount</title>
    <updated>2025-05-09T02:43:35.857835+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation revolves around the implementation and testing of a separate amount logic using opcodes, specifically `OP_{IN,OUT}_AMOUNT`, within the context of Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) 345. The person inquiring is trying to understand the security implications or concerns that might have been overlooked in their approach. They reference the BIP345 case study available at [BIP345](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549/4) to clarify their point. Moreover, they mention successful testing outcomes for both `test_batch_unvault` and `test_batch_recovery` as demonstrated in the provided GitHub repository links, which are part of an effort to implement feature vaults in Bitcoin.

The discussion further delves into a specific scenario involving Vault Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). In this scenario, two Vault UTXOs, labeled A and B each containing 1 Bitcoin (₿), are considered. The concern is about ensuring that when these UTXOs are spent towards a staging or "unvaulting" output (U), the script enforces that U contains at least 2 Bitcoins. The intricacy arises in preventing potential fraudulent activities where the input indices could be misrepresented in the witness stack during transactions. This misrepresentation could theoretically allow for an invalid transaction to appear valid, thereby risking the theft of 1 Bitcoin.

The key issue highlighted is the necessity for a mechanism or form of "synchronization" among different input scripts. This synchronization would ensure the integrity of input indices across all related inputs, safeguarding against the possibility of such theft. The discussion points toward a deeper technical exploration of how Bitcoin's scripting and transaction verification processes can be fortified through opcode modifications and enhancements to address specific security challenges.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-08T19:41:45.428000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
