<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-05-12T02:47:36.800562+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>blockchainhao</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-11T12:11:09.694000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-05-12T02:47:36.800593+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/77" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses a realization regarding the process of adding transactions to INCnew and its implications for POTnew. The sender acknowledges an oversight in understanding how additional ancestors (anc(p)) of a transaction (p) that belongs to POTnew could also be eligible for inclusion in INCnew. This indicates a complex relationship between transactions and their dependencies, underlining the importance of accurately tracking which transactions are newly includable based on their ancestral links.

Furthermore, the email queries about the integration of GGT and SFL into the codebase, wondering whether these components are already implemented or if they are planned for future integration. This suggests ongoing development efforts aimed at enhancing or modifying the functionality of the system, with GGT and SFL being potential additions or modifications that could impact how transactions are processed or managed within the system. The mention of GGT and SFL implies that there are specific functionalities or improvements anticipated from their inclusion, although the exact nature of these expectations is not detailed in the extracted summary. 

Overall, the communication reflects a technical dialogue focused on the intricacies of transaction handling and system updates, highlighting the sender's engagement with the technical aspects of the system's operation and their interest in its continuous improvement.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-11T12:11:09.694000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
