<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
  <updated>2025-05-13T02:50:36.463520+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-12T16:22:22.312000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T02:50:36.463557+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/anecdotal-kode-code-for-humans/1441/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the integration of SHA256 hashes into Bitcoin transactions, an interesting concept emerges regarding the use of these hashes within the locktime component of a transaction. This technique does not affect the overall size of the raw transaction, demonstrating a seamless way to embed additional information without altering its footprint. By incorporating a SHA256 hash composed of two octets into the locktime, one can leverage this aspect for various applications while maintaining the transaction's integrity.

The method employs both a header and footer line surrounding the plaintext in a preformatted block, facilitating an easy optical verification process to confirm that the plaintext has not been tampered with or altered. This approach ensures that the content is secure and authentic, safeguarding against potential collision attacks. The use of `sha256sum` on the command line to generate the hash from the plaintext serves as a practical example of how to apply this technique effectively.

Furthermore, the discussion includes a practical example with a link to a Testnet4 transaction ([Testnet4 Transaction Example](https://mempool.space/testnet4/tx/6a955b1e60ab64473f38b6dbc8355e7eb42c32bcf0c45e8d4c14f6a490167bab?mode=details)), which showcases the real-world application of embedding a SHA256 hash within a Bitcoin transaction's locktime. This example underlines the feasibility and utility of the method in live blockchain environments. 

The explanation also references the use of `signify`, as detailed at [OpenBSD signify](https://man.openbsd.org/signify.1), highlighting the importance of secure cryptographic signatures in verifying the authenticity of data encapsulated within transactions. This suggests a broader context in which cryptographic techniques ensure the integrity and trustworthiness of embedded information in blockchain transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:22:22.312000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
