<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
  <updated>2025-05-14T02:44:23.338449+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jb55 2025-05-13 17:43:50.573000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
    <updated>2025-05-14T02:44:23.338481+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-usdt-tracepoints/1694" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The tool shared, named bitcointap, is a significant advancement in the realm of Bitcoin development, stemming from inspiration by @0xB10C's peer_observer project. It leverages the robustness of Rust programming language to provide a library and command-line interface (CLI) tool that facilitates tapping into bitcoin-core's enhanced Berkeley Packet Filter (eBPF) User Space, Statically Defined Tracing (USDT) tracepoints. This capability is crucial for developers looking to gain deeper insights into Bitcoin Core's runtime behavior without impacting its operational performance.

To demonstrate the utility and functionality of bitcointap, a demonstration video has been made available, showcasing how it operates in real-world scenarios ([demo video](https://cdn.jb55.com/s/bitcointap-demo.mp4)). Furthermore, the source code and additional resources are accessible on GitHub, providing an open platform for developers to contribute, experiment, and enhance their understanding and usage of tracing within Bitcoin Core ([bitcointap on GitHub](https://github.com/jb55/bitcointap)).

For those unfamiliar with the concept of tracing in the context of Bitcoin Core, the project strongly recommends reviewing the official tracing documentation. This document serves as a comprehensive guide, detailing the methodologies, applications, and benefits of implementing tracing within Bitcoin Core environments ([Bitcoin Core tracing documentation](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/8309a9747a8df96517970841b3648937d05939a3/doc/tracing.md)). The creators of bitcointap are actively seeking feedback on the traces community members find most beneficial, signaling an ongoing commitment to evolving the tool's capabilities in line with user needs and technological advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-13T17:43:50.573000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
