<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
  <updated>2025-05-15T02:45:52.325860+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-15 01:51:04.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T02:45:52.325893+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-spam-problem-of-bitcoin-and-unpermissioned-broadcast-networks-in-general/1692/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of spam in the Bitcoin ecosystem diverges significantly from its traditional understanding related to email. In the realm of Bitcoin, what is often labeled as spam constitutes transactions between consenting parties, including the miners who process these transactions for a fee. This presents a stark contrast to the negligible costs associated with sending spam emails. The discussion highlights that, historically, inserting data into the Bitcoin blockchain was incredibly cheap, leading to potential abuse. However, the current state of Bitcoin's economy has rendered such practices prohibitively expensive, akin to storing data on commercial services like Amazon S3.

The narrative further explores why, despite high costs, there are still instances of what can be perceived as spam on the Bitcoin network. It suggests that the scarcity of space on the Bitcoin blockchain can be exploited for seigniorage, turning it into a valuable asset beyond its intended purpose. This utilization of blockchain space responds differently to cost increases or resource restrictions compared to traditional spam, showing resilience or even preference for such constraints.

Additionally, the text delves into historical responses to the misuse of Bitcoin's blockchain for purposes other than financial transactions. It recounts efforts within the community to mitigate the proliferation of altcoins, which often leveraged the Bitcoin codebase for alternative yet not always legitimate ends. A notable response was the creation of a service allowing users to easily create altcoins, which was ultimately acquired and shut down by an altcoin producer, aiming to curb the abuse and reduce the clutter of copycat cryptocurrencies.

Finally, the email touches upon "dusting" as an analog to email spam within the Bitcoin universe, albeit less frequently discussed. It outlines potential countermeasures to minimize the impact of dusting, such as wallets concealing minuscule transactions or avoiding the display of sending addresses to enhance user privacy and security. These solutions aim to address the unique challenges posed by spam-like activities on the blockchain, demonstrating the evolving nature of spam mitigation in the context of decentralized digital currencies.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T01:51:04.951000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
