<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
  <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:05.161812+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon.493000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-15T05:58:29.493000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:05.161847+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-spam-problem-of-bitcoin-and-unpermissioned-broadcast-networks-in-general/1692/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of Layer Zero within blockchain technology represents an innovative approach to structuring and processing transactions, which stands in contrast to the more commonly discussed layers above it, such as sidechains (Layer Two) and enhancements like the Lightning Network (regarded as "Layer One and a Half"). This foundational layer proposes a network architecture where the Bitcoin mainchain, among others, could function as a subnetwork. This hierarchical inversion allows for a reduction in the volume of transactions that need to be processed directly by any single node, suggesting a streamlined method for handling data across the network.

At the heart of the Layer Zero proposition is the idea of efficiency and simplification in transaction processing. By establishing a network where Layer One transactions are committed to a more fundamental layer that contains fewer transactions, it becomes possible to reduce the overall data processing requirements for participants. This reimagined structure views the current Bitcoin Core code as a composite of Layer Zero foundational elements combined with additional Layer One functionalities. The outcome of this reconfiguration is a network that can process less data while maintaining its integrity and functionality for users.

The motivation behind exploring and potentially developing Layer Zero stems from the challenge of managing spam within the network. The proposed solution emphasizes compression and simplification of transactions to mitigate the impact of spam activities. In this scenario, while spammers may continue to operate on Layer One, pushing substantial amounts of data, users have the option to transition to Layer Zero. Here, they can engage with a network designed for greater utility and efficiency, free from the direct burden of spam transactions. However, despite the apparent benefits, the realization of Layer Zero has been hindered by a lack of initiative and the inherent human tendency towards inertia, with no pressing necessity driving its development up to this point.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T05:58:29.493000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
