<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
  <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:40.584794+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>willcl-ark 2025-05-15 16:23:11.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:40.584837+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-usdt-tracepoints/1694/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of a similar tool for peer-observer by another programmer demonstrates the ongoing interest and efforts within the community to enhance tooling capabilities. The mentioned project, accessible on GitHub at [this link](https://github.com/willcl-ark/peer-observer/tree/tui), showcases an attempt to create a text-based user interface (TUI) tool aimed at improving peer observation. To get the tool running, a specific command involving `cargo run` is provided, indicating the steps to initiate the tool with options for specifying the NATS address. This process is illustrated through an example available at [asciinema](https://asciinema.org/a/eMHaUhfX537iXR2IZBlulXHBx), which visually represents how the tool operates once launched.

However, the project encountered significant performance issues attributed to the underlying library, ratatui, which negatively impacted the tool's efficiency in long-running operations. These challenges are exemplified by a referenced issue on the ratatui GitHub repository, found at [ratatui issue #1338](https://github.com/ratatui/ratatui/issues/1338), highlighting the technical difficulties faced during development. Despite these obstacles, the communication expresses enthusiasm for testing new tools that serve similar purposes, emphasizing the importance of tracepoint-oriented tools in the programming community. The sharing of experiences and projects among programmers not only fosters collaboration but also contributes to the collective search for more efficient and effective software development tools.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T16:23:11.245000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
