<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-05-21T02:46:03.784419+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidgumberg 2025-05-21 00:47:41.040000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T02:46:03.784458+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring innovative approaches to enhance blockchain efficiency and privacy, recent discussions have focused on optimizing compact block transmissions and addressing privacy concerns related to mempool policies. A proposed method for testing improvements involves running a secondary node configured to exclusively process `CMPCTBLOCK` announcements from select peers. This setup aims to evaluate the effectiveness of a specific patch available on [0xB10C/2025-03-prefill-compactblocks](https://github.com/0xB10C/bitcoin/commits/2025-03-prefill-compactblocks/) without widespread deployment. Further exploration is being conducted through a dedicated branch, [davidgumberg/5-20-25-cmpct-manual-only](https://github.com/davidgumberg/bitcoin/tree/5-20-25-cmpct-manual-only), which signifies an ongoing effort to refine this approach.

Privacy issues emerge as a significant concern within these discussions, particularly regarding how nodes might inadvertently expose details about their transaction policies through compact block announcements. Two primary vulnerabilities are identified: the potential for a node to reveal its unique mempool policy, and the risk of disclosing non-standard transactions by omitting them from prefill data. The latter is deemed more critical, suggesting a need for broader solutions beyond compact block optimization. One innovative suggestion involves segregating a node's transactions in a separate mempool instance, termed `m_user_pool`, to mitigate the risks associated with mempool policy fingerprinting. This concept seeks to balance the inclusion of transactions in compact blocks more judiciously, aiming to align prefills with an ideal set that neither over-represents nor under-represents the node's actual transaction activity.

Further technical considerations relate to TCP/IP protocol nuances, specifically managing data transmission within constrained network conditions as outlined in [RFC 5681](https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc5681). Understanding the interplay between the congestion window (cwnd) and the receiver-advertised message window (rwnd) is crucial for optimizing data flow across networks. Practical implementation suggestions include leveraging the `tcp_info` structure to dynamically adjust transmission strategies based on real-time network feedback, thereby enhancing efficiency and reliability of blockchain communications.

These discussions highlight the complex balance between improving blockchain transaction efficiency and safeguarding user privacy. By experimenting with novel configurations and leveraging detailed protocol insights, there is a clear pathway toward more sophisticated and privacy-aware blockchain operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-21T00:47:41.040000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
