<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
  <updated>2025-05-24T02:40:59.437132+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-23 15:45:07.582000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
    <updated>2025-05-24T02:40:59.437157+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email touches on the origins and applications of CheckLockTimeVerify (CLTV) within blockchain technology, highlighting its significance before the advent of Lightning Network. CLTV, a feature that predates the Lightning Network, demonstrated its utility through the implementation of nLocktime, showcasing its value in earlier forms. The message also addresses concerns regarding the suitability of CLTV for specific applications, suggesting an openness to explaining or clarifying these limitations rather than viewing them as detrimental.

Additionally, the email contains advice regarding interpersonal communication within the community, specifically addressing the recipient's approach to discussions about vaults. It suggests that persistently steering conversations towards this topic has negatively impacted the individual's reputation and contributed to creating an unwelcoming atmosphere. The sender encourages the recipient to reconsider their approach to discussions, implying that a more constructive and less confrontational stance could be beneficial for both the individual and the broader community. This advice underscores the importance of maintaining a positive and respectful discourse, even when exploring contentious or complex topics.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-23T15:45:07.582000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
