<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-05-26T02:50:10.460298+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-05-25 11:41:49.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-05-26T02:50:10.460329+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the topic of recursive secret splitting, acknowledging it as an intriguing and feasible method. The sender appreciates the recipient's work on this innovative approach, highlighting its potential to generalize existing schemes. Specifically, the traditional model involves a subset of participants, who also contribute their extended public keys (xpubs), being able to decode a backup. However, the recipient's method introduces a more versatile framework. This new approach allows for setting thresholds and creating complex subsets of participants that align with certain spending conditions outlined by miniscript rules.

Despite recognizing the technical advancements and flexibility offered by this new scheme, the sender expresses a belief in the superiority of simpler choices for most users. They argue that simplicity often leads to higher adoption rates due to lower barriers related to implementation complexity. Moreover, the email points out a significant challenge in developing user experiences for wallets that require multi-party cooperation for recovery from backups. The complexity of crafting such an interface is underscored as a notable obstacle, suggesting that while the recipient's method adds valuable options for security and access control, practical application and widespread acceptance may be hindered by these usability concerns.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-25T11:41:49.381000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
