<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-05-28T02:48:54.768332+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>tnull</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-27T10:09:24.579000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T02:48:54.768365+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue emphasizes the nuanced trade-offs involved in implementing forwarding delays within a network, specifically referencing the Lightning Network's handling of HTLCs (Hash Time-Locked Contracts). It highlights that while adding forwarding delays might initially seem contrary to the incentives of forwarding nodes, these nodes already engage in similar practices by batching HTLCs. This batching process, despite introducing latency, offers benefits such as reduced input/output and network latency overheads. The potential for greater efficiency through batching could become even more significant with the implementation of an `option_simplified_update`, suggesting a future direction for improving network performance.

The conversation also touches upon the delicate balance between privacy and security within network transactions. The introduction of random delays by individual nodes seeking enhanced privacy protection is discussed. While this approach aims to obscure transaction patterns from potential on-path adversaries, it might inadvertently make these nodes more conspicuous in other scenarios. This paradox underlines the complexity of designing privacy measures that do not compromise the node's security or draw undue attention. The recommendation for documenting best practices around sender/receiver side delays in the [BOLT 7 "Recommendations for Routing"](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/blob/011bf84d74d130c2972becca97c87f297b9d4a92/07-routing-gossip.mdrecommendations-for-routing) section suggests a collective move towards standardized privacy protections which can reconcile these concerns.

Furthermore, the discussion explores how evolving standards, specifically the transition from BOLT11 to a post-BOLT12/blinded path model, impact privacy and anonymity within the network. In a BOLT11 framework, the sender’s knowledge of the receiver's identity along the payment path compromises receiver anonymity. However, the blinded path capabilities introduced in BOLT12 offer a significant enhancement to privacy by concealing the receiver's identity from the sender. This advance raises new considerations regarding the reporting of hold times at intermediate hops, which could potentially enable a sender, now acting as an on-path adversary, to deduce the receiver's identity, thus undermining the privacy gains achieved through BOLT12. Addressing these concerns necessitates a careful reevaluation of how information is shared across the network and the development of additional safeguards for the onion message components of the protocol. The acknowledgment that receiver/sender-side delays could be beneficial, provided they are formalized as best practices for network implementations, reflects a cautious optimism towards balancing operational efficiency with privacy and security needs, subject to further refinement to protect against emerging threats to blinded path privacy.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-27T10:09:24.579000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
