<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-05-28T02:47:52.866794+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>carla 2025-05-27 19:25:31.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-05-28T02:47:52.866824+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The debate on implementing forwarding delays in the context of Lightning Network transactions touches upon the balance between node incentives and the efficiency gains from batching HTLCs (Hashed Time-Locked Contracts). It is acknowledged that while adding delays may seem counterintuitive to the forwarding nodes' interests, this practice can actually lead to improved performance due to reduced input/output and network latency overheads associated with batching. The consensus seems to lean towards the flexibility of adjusting these delays, allowing nodes to manage their own trade-offs between immediacy and operational efficiency. Notably, the Lightning Network Daemon (LND) already supports such configurations, indicating a move towards customizable delay settings could be broadly feasible.

Furthermore, the discussion highlights the importance of establishing best practices for managing receiver-side delays. This approach is suggested not only as a means to optimize the network's functioning but also as a potential default setting to enhance privacy protections without compromising sender metrics. The integration of timing-based scoring mechanisms, which are already under consideration for Multi-Part Payments (MPP), appears to accommodate these adjustments with minimal additional complexity. 

Privacy concerns related to BOLT 12, specifically the fear that privacy might be compromised by attributing data through latency measurements, are addressed with an understanding that proper implementation would remove such data at the introduction point. This ensures that subsequent nodes cannot misuse latency metrics for attribution, thereby preserving privacy across the network. The clarification requests concerning BOLT 12's handling of attribution data suggest a nuanced approach to privacy, where added delays by receiving nodes—including those through fabricated hops—would be reported without compromising the anonymized nature of transactions. This conversation underscores the ongoing efforts to refine Lightning Network protocols to achieve a balance between efficiency, privacy, and user autonomy in configuring their network participation.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-27T19:25:31.933000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
