<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:16:48.164820+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-05-29 13:02:49.588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin and Quantum Computing</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:16:48.164853+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-and-quantum-computing/1730/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email provides feedback on a comprehensive document, pointing out a minor typo where "Jan 2025" is mistakenly written as "Jan 2015" on page 30. The sender acknowledges the depth of the analysis within the document, specifically appreciating the discussion on BIP32 implications, which underscores the attention to detail by the author. This level of detail surpasses expectations and indicates a nuanced understanding of the subject matter.

Despite the thoroughness of the document, the sender expresses skepticism regarding the timelines presented at the outset. There's a sense of resignation about the complexity and the near impossibility of resolving the situation cleanly, suggesting that the document, while informative, does not instill confidence in a favorable outcome. The comparison with fusion technology, humorously noted to have been "10 years away" since 1985, reflects the sender's doubt about the realistic threat of the situation worsening in the next decade. This doubt is tempered by an acknowledgment of the opinions of some experts who believe the threat is imminent, contrasting with the sender's more skeptical viewpoint. This exchange highlights the intricate balance between detailed technical analysis and the broader, often uncertain, predictive aspects of technological advancement and its implications.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-29T13:02:49.588000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
