<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:18:47.167459+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell.030000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-30T01:07:45.030000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:18:47.167492+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-confiscatory-transaction-weight-limit/1732/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of enhancing blockchain technology, a notable approach discussed involves leveraging the height of inputs at validation time. This method proposes an innovative way to mitigate risks by setting a condition that only transactions with all inputs below a certain height are accepted. This strategy aims at minimizing potential disruptions by filtering out transactions that might introduce complexities or inconsistencies into the system.

Furthermore, the proposal introduces a dynamic element through the implementation of a rule that would periodically expire and require renewal. Specifically, it suggests having such a rule sunset after a predetermined number of years, necessitating its reactivation every half of the set period. This periodic review and renewal process is designed to address concerns about future risks and uncertainties. However, it's acknowledged that this approach carries political risks due to the necessity for repeated consensus changes among stakeholders.

The efficiency of setting a threshold, such as accepting only 1/10th of transactions based on their input height, remains debatable. There's an openness to arguments supporting the sufficient impact of this ratio on making block construction more sensible. Yet, there's a clear stance that significantly lowering this threshold could be impractical. This impracticality is not just rooted in historical precedents but also in the recognition that large transactions, which could potentially be excluded by too stringent a threshold, are a common aspect of regular blockchain operations.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T01:07:45.030000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
