<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:14:01.684128+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast.601000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-05-30T15:06:54.601000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:14:01.684164+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The decision to utilize onion packets of 1300 bytes is strategically aimed at ensuring they fit within the 1500 bytes Maximum Transmission Unit (MTU), catering specifically to the inclusion of `update_add_htlc` messages. This alignment with the MTU is critical in avoiding packet fragmentation, which can introduce complexity and inefficiency in data transmission. The curiosity now extends towards understanding the ramifications of transmitting larger lightning packets, specifically those sized at 65kB. Such sizes would undeniably necessitate significant reassembly processes due to exceeding the standard MTU limits.

Exploring the impact of these larger packet sizes could be effectively approached through simulations or practical experiments. Tools like SimLN offer a simulation environment that could provide valuable insights into the behavior and performance implications of using 65kB packets within the lighting network. Alternatively, conducting A/B testing on the mainnet presents a more empirical method of assessing the real-world effects of such adjustments. This hands-on approach would allow for direct observation and analysis of how larger packets interact within the existing infrastructure and what potential challenges or benefits they might introduce.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T15:06:54.601000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
