<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T13:49:46.506337+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:49:46.506377+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the challenges and potential solutions regarding security for transactions, particularly in the context of blockchain technology. It outlines a comparison between the revocation capabilities of TLS certificates and the inherent risks associated with co-signing keys once they are integrated into numerous Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). The conversation suggests that, unlike TLS certificates, which can be easily revoked if compromised, co-signing keys do not offer this flexibility once they become part of the blockchain infrastructure.

To address these concerns, the concept of using CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS is introduced as a means to construct an infrastructure bearing similarities to TLS, complete with certificate authorities. This approach proposes the use of a connector output to block spending via the path with the compromised key, thereby directing transactions through an alternative path secured by a backup key held offline by the government until necessary. This method allows for the preparation of multiple secure paths within the emulated covenant tapscript, enhancing the system's resilience against unauthorized access.

Furthermore, the strategy includes provisions for immediate action upon detection of a compromise. It involves alerting users to transition their funds into a new covenant equipped with fresh co-signer keys, thereby safeguarding against potential theft or unauthorized access. This proactive measure underscores the importance of end-user key security, in addition to the cosigner key, to ensure comprehensive protection.

Despite acknowledging the ease of management facilitated by new opcodes, the argument acknowledges existing limitations but refutes the notion that these pose critical barriers to misuse by authoritarian entities. Instead, it points towards [credible alternatives](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703) that may serve effectively even if the co-signing approach is deemed overly burdensome. This nuanced discussion highlights the ongoing efforts and considerations in enhancing transaction security within blockchain systems, aiming to balance efficiency, user autonomy, and protective measures against malicious actors.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
