<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-14T21:44:45.985005+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-14T21:44:45.985042+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the complexities and potential security issues related to co-signing keys in blockchain transactions, contrasting them with the more flexible and secure mechanisms provided by TLS (Transport Layer Security) certificates. Unlike TLS certificates, which can be easily revoked if compromised, co-signing keys are permanently embedded into millions of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), making their revocation or replacement challenging. However, the introduction of concepts such as CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS offers a framework that resembles the TLS infrastructure, including the possibility of creating certificate authorities.

One proposed solution for enhancing security involves using a government-operated connector output to redirect transactions through alternative paths in case a key is compromised. This method relies on creating multiple backup paths that remain inactive until needed, thereby ensuring that transactions can still proceed securely without the compromised key. Nevertheless, an attacker would need to compromise both the cosigner key and the end user's key, adding an additional layer of security. In response to a detected compromise, the government could then instruct users to transfer their funds into a new covenant with fresh cosigner keys, further mitigating the risk.

Despite these advancements and proposals for increased security, the argument is made that current limitations might not pose significant barriers to malicious actors, given the existence of [credible alternatives](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703). These alternatives suggest that even with potential challenges in managing co-signing keys and implementing new opcodes for enhanced transaction security, there are viable paths forward that do not critically hinder the system's overall security posture against threats.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
