<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-15T00:52:20.255071+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:52:20.255110+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In addressing the challenges of securing transactions against unauthorized access or theft, it's highlighted that while TLS certificates offer a manageable level of security through their ability to be revoked if compromised, the situation with co-signing keys used in millions of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) presents a more complex problem due to the inability to revoke these keys easily. However, advancements in cryptographic techniques such as CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS provide a framework that can emulate the infrastructure of TLS, including the implementation of certificate authorities, thereby enhancing the security of transactions.

A proposed solution involves the use of connector outputs within an emulated covenant tapscript to redirect transactions through alternative paths secured by backup keys maintained offline by governmental bodies until required. This approach allows for the preparation of numerous secure paths in anticipation of key compromise incidents. Furthermore, this system necessitates attackers to compromise both the end-user key and the cosigner key to access funds, significantly increasing the security barrier. Upon detection of a compromise, authorities could immediately notify users to transfer their assets into new covenants safeguarded by freshly issued cosigner keys.

Despite the potential complexity and limitations associated with current technologies and methods, the argument is made that these barriers are not insurmountable for malicious entities. Nonetheless, the existence of [credible alternatives](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703) suggests that even if the co-signing approach encounters critical challenges, there are other viable options available to ensure the security of digital transactions. This discourse underscores the importance of continuous innovation and adaptation in cryptographic practices to mitigate the evolving threats to transaction security.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
