<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-21T20:00:23.250878+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T20:00:23.250917+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the inherent vulnerabilities and solutions in securing digital transactions, particularly focusing on the challenges of protecting large sums from unauthorized access. It contrasts the robustness of traditional TLS (Transport Layer Security) mechanisms with the difficulties associated with safeguarding co-signing keys that are integral to millions of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). Unlike TLS certificates, which can be revoked if compromised, a co-signing key's compromise presents a significant challenge due to its embedded nature within numerous transactions.

The conversation introduces concepts like CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS as foundational elements for constructing a security infrastructure akin to TLS, suggesting the potential for creating certificate authorities and similar protective measures. An innovative approach discussed involves utilizing connector outputs within an emulated covenant tapscript to reroute transactions through secondary paths secured by backup keys held offline by government entities. This method allows for the preparation of multiple secure paths, enhancing the security posture against attackers who must now compromise both the end-user and cosigner keys. Upon detecting a compromise, governments could prompt users to transition their assets into new covenants with fresh cosigner keys, thereby mitigating the risk.

Furthermore, the dialogue acknowledges the evolving landscape of cryptographic security with the introduction of new opcodes that simplify system management. Despite these advancements, the current limitations are not seen as critical barriers for malicious actors. However, the existence of [credible alternatives](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703) offers a counterpoint to the argument, suggesting that even if the cosigning method proves cumbersome, there are viable solutions available to address these challenges. This underscores the ongoing dialogue within the cryptographic community regarding the balance between security, usability, and the need for innovative approaches to protect digital assets effectively.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
