<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-07-16T02:59:24.177837+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-31 16:14:28.359000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-07-16T02:59:24.177869+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/33" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of computer networking, it's essential to distinguish between the processes involved in IP and TCP transmissions. A common misconception arises when one conflates IP reassembly with TCP reassembly, which are distinct operations serving different purposes within the network communication protocol stack. 

IP fragmentation and reassembly are mechanisms that operate at the Internet Protocol (IP) layer. These processes are designed to handle situations where packets exceed the maximum transmission unit (MTU) size supported by a network path. Path MTU Discovery (PMTUD) is a technique used to prevent IP fragmentation by discovering the minimum MTU size along the path from the source to the destination, ensuring that packets are sized appropriately to avoid fragmentation.

On the other hand, TCP reassembly is a function of the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP), which operates at a higher layer than IP. TCP reassembly addresses the ordering and delivery of segments received from a TCP stream. Due to the nature of TCP's reliable delivery mechanism, packets may arrive out of order; TCP reassembly ensures these packets are reordered correctly before they are processed by the receiving application.

Understanding the distinction between IP reassembly and TCP reassembly clarifies the roles these mechanisms play in network communications. While IP fragmentation and reassembly deal with packet size and transmission efficiency across diverse network infrastructures, TCP reassembly focuses on the integrity and sequential organization of data transmissions within a TCP session. This clarification highlights the layered approach of network protocols in managing data flow efficiently and reliably across the internet.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-31T16:14:28.359000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
