<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
  <updated>2025-05-08T02:46:46.464122+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen 2025-05-07 04:32:30.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen  . 2025-05-02 23:23:13.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4952_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4924_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
    <updated>2025-05-08T02:46:46.464176+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines/1655" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The proposal to enhance Bitcoin Script involves the introduction of straightforward opcodes aimed at enabling recursive covenants efficiently. These new opcodes are designed to simplify the process by eliminating the need for concatenation typically used in quining processes, focusing instead on direct hashing. This method not only makes the creation of recursive covenants more streamlined but also addresses potential issues such as script bloat that could arise from using alternative opcodes like OP_CAT, which significantly increases script sizes.

A key application of this enhanced Bitcoin Script is the development of a vault mechanism that utilizes dual keys: one being a hot key with spending rate limits and the other a cold key free from such constraints. The script differentiates between transactions initiated by either key, applying specific conditions accordingly. For cold key transactions, it simply checks for a matching signature. However, for those initiated with the hot key, the script imposes additional requirements such as enforcing transaction output size limits, applying a relative timelock to regulate spending rates, and ensuring the transaction output reflects the new amount while also maintaining the original script's logic. This implementation showcases the practicality of incorporating advanced scripting functions like recursive covenants into the Bitcoin network without the need for complex scripting mechanisms.

Moreover, the discussion touches upon the potential benefits of introducing a loop construct within Bitcoin Script to further facilitate smart coin development. Nonetheless, it acknowledges that the proposed enhancements, which necessitate a UTXO spend with each iteration, effectively support loop-like functionalities in a more constrained manner. This approach aligns with the overall objective of maintaining simplicity within Bitcoin Script while expanding its capabilities to include more powerful functionalities that may be added in the future, particularly those not initially enabled by the current proposal. The focus remains on adding simple, immediately useful opcodes that adhere to the existing operational framework of Bitcoin Script, underscoring a cautious yet progressive strategy for evolving the scripting language's utility and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-07T04:32:30.503000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
