<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
  <updated>2025-05-21T02:51:35.354083+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-21 00:06:44.757000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2025-05-17 21:36:35.733000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5064_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5025_On-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - On the possibility of evil covenants and implications for soft fork proposals</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T02:51:35.354123+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/on-the-possibility-of-evil-covenants-and-implications-for-soft-fork-proposals/1703" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the introduction of "covenant" into Bitcoin's lexicon has evolved, marked by regret from the originator for how the term and its application have been misconstrued. The initial intent was to highlight misuse through exaggerated examples; however, this approach inadvertently led to the concept being weaponized in fearmongering tactics rather than fostering understanding. The dialogue underscores that the potential for abuse should not invalidate the broader freedoms the technology offers. It is acknowledged that Bitcoin's consensus rules inadvertently permit the creation of programmatic covenants, suggesting any attempt to entirely prevent them would severely limit the system's flexibility. Moreover, it is argued that malicious uses of covenants could be achieved via simpler means such as multisignature setups or threshold signatures, without significantly empowering bad actors beyond current capabilities.

The discourse also delves into the implications of enabling covenants within Bitcoin, particularly through soft fork additions like `OP_CTV`, `OP_CSFS`, `OP_CAT`, and `OP_EXPIRE`. This exploration raises a philosophical debate on whether the potential for restrictive applications—dubbed "evil covenants"—warrants outright rejection of such proposals. The argument against such dismissal hinges on two main points: the practicality of alternatives for oppressive regimes and the potential benefits covenants offer in making Bitcoin more private, scalable, and a stronger instrument for freedom. Examples provided include Perpetual One-Way Peg ([P1WP](https://medium.com/@RubenSomsen/21-million-bitcoins-to-rule-all-sidechains-the-perpetual-one-way-peg-96cb2f8ac302)) and co-signer arrangements like [AMP](https://docs.liquid.net/docs/blockstream-amp-overview)), which authoritarian entities might employ in the absence of covenant capabilities to exert control over cryptocurrency usage.

Furthermore, the narrative emphasizes the dual-use nature of technology, akin to firearms and the internet, which can serve both oppressive and liberatory ends. Bitcoin, with or without covenants, is positioned within this dual paradigm, highlighting the ethical responsibilities of users and the critical role of judicial systems in mitigating misuse. The conversation advocates for technological advancement within Bitcoin, promoting a balanced view that recognizes the potential for both harm and good. By focusing on leveraging the positive aspects of covenants, the community is encouraged to pursue avenues that ensure financial freedom and integrity, aligning with the overarching goal of enhancing the Bitcoin ecosystem's utility and security.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-21T00:06:44.757000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
