<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-08-01T03:18:26.294222+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-07-31 22:35:56.460000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-07-15 12:06:03.412000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pyth  . 2025-07-15 08:34:22.826000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>drorlovsky  . 2025-07-12 12:49:23.515000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jdlcdl  . 2025-06-22 10:33:44.879000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-06-02 09:44:03.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-06-01 09:54:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-06-01 07:08:14.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-31 22:24:07.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-31 18:45:36.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-25 23:34:10.338000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-25 11:41:49.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-24 18:41:51.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-21 09:45:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh  . 2025-05-21 06:34:14.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5602_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5480_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5478_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5445_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5326_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5186_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5185_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5183_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5182_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5180_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5118_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5117_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5113_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5072_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5070_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T03:18:26.294393+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation begins with a discussion on a cryptographic scheme designed for securing backups, specifically focusing on its application in scenarios involving inheritance and sharing access among designated individuals. The scheme is highlighted for not requiring the storage of additional secrets beyond an initial seed or mnemonic, integrating the encryption of the common secret directly into the backup. This setup facilitates controlled access through a policy that necessitates cooperation among heirs under specified conditions, incorporating concepts like Shamir's Secret Sharing to enforce decryption thresholds without overly complicating the system. References to related work underscore the potential for extending this approach, although concerns about increased complexity and its impact on user adoption are noted.

Further elaboration on fund recovery mechanisms introduces a nuanced debate between accessibility and privacy, recognizing the value of time-locked recovery partners while also considering the privacy implications of standalone decryption capabilities. A proposed policy model emphasizes collaborative consent for enhanced security, suggesting a preference for mechanisms that require multiple parties' cooperation for decryption. This section reflects on the adaptability of security protocols, advocating for customizable solutions that cater to specific needs while maintaining simplicity to encourage broader adoption.

A significant portion of the discussion delves into the innovative use of master extended public keys (xpubs) for managing access to cryptographic descriptors, proposing a shift towards a more decentralized method of backup encryption. This approach suggests eliminating the need for a shared secret in multisig operations, enhancing both autonomy and security. Further exploration into key management within digital wallets addresses the balance between security and convenience, particularly concerning the integration of the T component in Bitcoin operations and its implications for predictability and recoverability of xpubs.

The conversation then transitions to discussing strategies for handling account numbers in reused devices and the importance of error correction mechanisms for the longevity of data storage. It also touches upon the complexities involved in creating a user-friendly interface for multi-party wallet recovery processes, acknowledging both the technical and usability challenges.

An intriguing aspect of the discussion revolves around recursive secret splitting, presenting it as a versatile method that could generalize existing schemes to accommodate complex participant subsets and spending conditions. Despite recognizing the method's technical merits, the conversation points out the potential barriers to widespread acceptance due to its complexity.

The creation of the `descriptor-encrypt` Rust library introduces a novel solution for encrypting descriptors, ensuring that only authorized spenders can decrypt them. This development is lauded for its compatibility with various cryptographic scenarios and its emphasis on security, even allowing encrypted data to be stored publicly without compromising the underlying descriptor's security.

Lastly, the email shifts focus to the significance of backing up public keys and descriptors, marking a departure from traditional approaches centered on safeguarding secrets. It underscores the necessity for robust backup strategies for these elements, vital for operational continuity and security. The comparison with Superbacked highlights the tool's comprehensive features aimed at enhancing developers' productivity, emphasizing collaboration, security, and community support. This dialogue underscores a multifaceted approach to cryptographic security, balancing innovation with practical considerations to enhance the security and recoverability of digital assets.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-31T22:35:56.460000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
