<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
  <updated>2025-12-13T02:48:04.163054+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>vostrnad  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-28 19:01:24.876000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-29 13:23:38.249000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-29 18:03:45.531000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 01:07:45.030000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>vostrnad  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 07:38:02.854000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:40:29.150000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:47:03.686000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:48:59.786000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>AntoineP  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-06-06 17:50:58.354000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-11 23:37:47.100000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>murch</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-12 17:58:55.447000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>ajtowns</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-13 00:14:53.839000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5147_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5154_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5157_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5160_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5161_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5170_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5163_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5172_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5244_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6422_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6423_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6425_Non-confiscatory-Transaction-Weight-Limit.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Non-confiscatory Transaction Weight Limit</title>
    <updated>2025-12-13T02:48:04.164695+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/non-confiscatory-transaction-weight-limit/1732/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-05-28 19:01:24.876000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Several mining pools have united in a significant move to support the mining of non-standard transactions, specifically focusing on BitVM transactions that surpass the conventional 100 kvB weight limit. This collaboration aims at enhancing Bitcoin's DeFi capabilities through evolving transaction standards while addressing the challenges posed by quadratic hashing and the reliance on centralized template providers. The initiative is detailed in a [CoinDesk article](https://www.coindesk.com/business/2025/05/27/bitlayer-joins-forces-with-antpool-f2pool-and-spiderpool-to-supercharge-bitcoin-defi), which also mentions the Consensus Cleanup proposal aimed at mitigating these issues.
The discussion extends to the potential implementation of a soft fork in Bitcoin, aiming to align maximum transaction sizes with the relay size, a strategy in place for about 12 years. This proposal highlights the complexities involved in managing oversized transactions and suggests such transactions be disallowed for efficiency and security enhancements. The conversation further explores innovative cryptographic techniques and direct negotiations between miners and protocols as potential solutions to accommodate large transactions without undermining network principles.
An interesting aspect of the dialogue delves into leveraging transaction input heights and proposes a dynamic rule that would periodically expire, requiring renewal. This approach introduces a method to minimize disruptions and uncertainties in blockchain operations, albeit with recognized political and practical risks. Additionally, the complex nature of protocols requiring large transactions is acknowledged, indicating that these operations often necessitate substantial scripts for data processing, which cannot be easily replaced by splitting data across multiple smaller transactions.
The activation of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) is discussed as a pivotal change that could streamline transaction management, particularly for coinbase transactions. By potentially limiting the size of the coinbase transaction, CTV activation could facilitate a more decentralized and efficient framework for handling transactions. Moreover, the resilience of BitVM technology in managing transaction frequencies without compromising system performance is highlighted, affirming confidence in its design and operational efficiency.
The debate touches on the OP_RETURN function and its importance for specific protocols, like the watchtower light-client protocol, which requires embedding a certain amount of data within a transaction. This challenge underscores the limitations of current policies and the benefits of easing block template creation to reduce dependence on centralized services. However, the necessity and impact of proposed changes, including a soft fork to accommodate large transactions, remain subjects of scrutiny within the community.
Further discussions address the technical and economic complexities of including large transactions in blocks, emphasizing the need for software solutions and private agreements between users and miners. A hypothetical consensus limit for transaction sizes is proposed, alongside a mining strategy that categorizes large transactions to optimize fee collection and mempool management. This detailed mechanism seeks to balance efficiency with the health of the network by adjusting how transactions are weighted and included in blocks.
Lastly, a quick thought shared in the thread suggests a modification to the handling of pre-signed, low feerate large transactions by possibly allowing them to form a cluster of two transactions. This adjustment aims to facilitate the inclusion of such transactions without resorting to out-of-band payments or replacement-by-fee mechanisms, highlighting the ongoing efforts to refine transaction management strategies within the blockchain framework.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>