<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
  <updated>2025-05-02T02:41:46.395355+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-05-01 21:11:10.185000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-04-23 11:11:19.978000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-04-18 12:31:09.945000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-07 20:20:58.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-05 01:08:43.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4913_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4861_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4826_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4223_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4171_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T02:41:46.395409+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/spanning-forest-cluster-linearization/1419" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent exploration into optimizing data structures through algorithms has yielded significant insights, particularly in the realm of linearizing spanning forests. The post on delvingbitcoin.org provides a deep dive into three primary algorithms: the spanning-forest linearization algorithm (SFL), the exponential candidate-set search algorithm (CSS), and the minimum-cut based parametric breakpoints algorithm outlined in the GGT paper. Each serves distinct purposes in computational efficiency, with SFL offering streamlined processes for complex data structures, CSS presenting an older but sometimes useful methodology, and the GGT algorithm introducing graph theory principles for optimized data segmentation. These methods are crucial for enhancing computational tasks by simplifying the handling of nested or interconnected datasets. For further details, the original discussion can be found [here](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/73).

In comparing these algorithms, the analysis emphasizes the termination condition and complexity bound of the SFL algorithm. It's noted that while SFL guarantees optimal linearization upon termination, its ability to consistently reach this endpoint is uncertain. Fuzzing tests indicate that strategic merging might circumvent repetitive states, suggesting potential for consistent termination. Despite an inherent exponential complexity, considering active dependencies offers a more constrained perspective. A key challenge lies in managing equal-feerate chunk splitting without falling into infinite loops. The current SFL framework lacks mechanisms for ordering transactions within chunks, which affects block building and poses questions about the algorithm's granularity and efficiency.

Significant improvements have been made to Bitcoin Core's `Linearize()` function, as evidenced by substantial performance enhancements detailed in benchmarks from an updated version hosted on GitHub. This new approach dramatically reduces processing times for challenging clusters previously identified as "hard," showcasing both speed and robustness improvements. These enhancements highlight the general applicability and improved performance of the updated method over the existing one, across a broad spectrum of cases.

Furthermore, the discussion introduces a work in progress on the spanning-forest cluster linearization algorithm as a promising contender for solving real-life problems. The concept is framed as a Linear Programming (LP) problem, with the objective to find the highest-feerate, topologically-valid transaction subset. By leveraging LP solving algorithms, it's established the problem is not NP-hard, opening avenues for efficient solution techniques. The spanning forest linearization algorithm, derived from the simplex algorithm, aims for optimal cluster linearization through specific operations like merging and splitting chunks based on feerate comparisons. Despite lacking known complexity bounds, this approach is praised for its elegance, speed, and practicality, offering a pragmatic solution focused on achieving "good enough" linearization efficiently.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-01T21:11:10.185000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
