<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-15T03:04:02.623642+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk 2025-07-14 13:26:38.093000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-07-13 00:20:28.380000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-07-02 13:03:14.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-07-01 22:03:02.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-30 17:09:09.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-06-30 00:57:12.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-02 14:22:43.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-22 21:20:03.071000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-12 17:47:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:20:40.305000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:17:55.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-04-15 15:55:25.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5454_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5448_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5392_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5387_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5379_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5371_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5192_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5092_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4993_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4878_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4877_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4790_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T03:04:02.623757+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the economics and operational intricacies of Lightning Network nodes, particularly focusing on the costs, risks, and profit margins associated with routing payments. It begins by debunking the notion that one can expect to double their funds every two weeks by routing payments through these nodes without considering the expenses and risks involved. This misconception overlooks the operational reality where channels do not maintain 100% utilization rates, and thus, the expected returns are far less optimistic than presumed.

The email progresses to clarify the financial commitment required from routing nodes, emphasizing the collateral needed to cover potential hold fees. For instance, a routing node at the beginning of a transaction chain must lock in significantly more satoshis as a security against possible fees compared to nodes later in the sequence. This layered risk model introduces a realistic perspective on the profitability of operating a Lightning Network node, countering initial assumptions with a detailed cost-benefit analysis based on a cost of capital at 19% per annum.

Additionally, the conversation delves into the Fee-Based Spam Reduction Protocol, which proposes a structured fee system consisting of Upfront Fees, Hold Fees, and Success Fees across a 10-hop payment scenario. This system aims to comprehensively cover the operational costs and risks incurred by nodes while processing payments. The protocol suggests a novel approach to securing and incentivizing transactions across the network, introducing mechanisms like matching fund requirements for burn outputs to protect against griefing attacks. This nuanced fee structure is designed to ensure fair compensation for nodes, addressing the challenges posed by delayed or failed payments and offering solutions to mitigate spam and malicious activities within the network.

Furthermore, an update to the paper introduces a lower-latency bug fix, enhancing the protocol's efficiency in handling time-dependent Hold Fees for not-immediately-settled payments. This improvement focuses on reducing the added latency without compromising the integrity of Hold Fee calculations, showcasing a commitment to optimizing network performance.

Lastly, the correspondence touches upon the critical aspects of jamming attacks and the strategic requirement to lock collateral as a deterrent. It examines the complexities of channel closure and fund distribution, suggesting a numerical example to better understand the trade-offs involved. Through these discussions, the email outlines strategies for leveraging automated protocols to prevent exploitation during transactions, highlighting the importance of continuous adaptation and improvement in combating challenges within the Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T13:26:38.093000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
