<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T05:06:27.340018+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jdlcdl 2025-06-22 10:33:44.879000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-06-02 09:44:03.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-06-01 09:54:34.063000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-06-01 07:08:14.744000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-05-31 22:24:07.511000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-05-31 18:45:36.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-25 23:34:10.338000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-25 11:41:49.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-05-24 18:41:51.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-05-21 09:45:02.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>securitybrahh  . 2025-05-21 06:34:14.794000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5326_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5186_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5185_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5183_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5182_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5180_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5118_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5117_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5113_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5072_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5070_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T05:06:27.340182+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation begins with an exploration of how XOR operations on individual secrets, Ci, relate to the shared secret, S, in the context of decrypting a ciphertext payload within a cryptographic backup scheme. The discussion clarifies that for a descriptor with an even number of xpubs, the XOR result of all Ci values reveals the shared secret. This understanding leads to the consideration of various cryptographic and operational nuances, such as the impact of including timestamps (T) in key derivation paths on the predictability and recoverability of extended public keys (xpubs). It's highlighted that integrating T into the key affects the simplicity of recovering from a predictable xpub, suggesting instead that derivation paths, potentially including or excluding fingerprints, be kept in clear text within wallet backups. The dialogue also touches upon the limitations imposed by BIP32 regarding timestamp incorporation due to bit-size constraints, proposing a division by 3600 to accommodate this within the allowable range.

Further, the discussion delves into practical aspects of implementing these cryptographic concepts into real-world applications. A proposal for using timestamps or block height as part of the derivation path is examined for its user-friendly nature and potential to aid in rescanning blockchain data. The complexity of adopting new cryptographic schemes is acknowledged, with optimism expressed for easing adoption through packaging solutions into Rust crates combined with WebAssembly for broader compatibility with wallets.

A significant portion of the conversation pivates to the innovative 'descriptor-encrypt' Rust library, designed to encrypt descriptors so only authorized spenders can decrypt them, directly tying access control policies to spending policies. This development is notable for its adaptability across different types of descriptors and miniscript, offering a robust solution for enhancing data security. The library employs a tag-based and variable-length encoding scheme to efficiently reduce encrypted data size while ensuring full secrecy mode allows for public storage of encrypted data without compromising security.

The exchange then shifts focus toward the necessity of a comprehensive backup strategy for public keys and descriptors, underscoring the critical role these elements play in maintaining access and security in digital asset management. Despite the lack of extensive documentation on backing up these components, the need for robust methodologies is evident, highlighting an emerging area of interest within cryptographic security practices.

Comparatively, Superbacked is presented as a versatile tool for developers, emphasizing collaboration, version control, and security features that enhance productivity and protect sensitive data. The platform’s broad support for programming languages and frameworks, alongside intuitive interfaces and community resources, positions it as a valuable resource for developer teams.

The conversation concludes with a detailed examination of a proposed encryption scheme for multisig wallets, leveraging Shamir's Secret Sharing algorithm to split access secrets among participants. This method intricately balances security against unauthorized access with the practicality of fund recovery under adverse conditions. Additionally, recent updates to documentation aim to refine the clarity of information presented, ensuring accurate communication of intended messages and minimizing misunderstandings. 

In summary, the dialogue traverses a wide array of topics from cryptographic theories and their application challenges to practical tools and strategies for enhancing digital asset security. The emphasis on collaborative improvement and technical innovation underscores a collective effort towards advancing cryptographic practices in line with evolving digital infrastructure needs.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-22T10:33:44.879000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
