<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
  <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:56.105789+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jb55</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>willcl-ark</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jb  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5018_Bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-USDT-tracepoints.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5017_Bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-USDT-tracepoints.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5000_Bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-USDT-tracepoints.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcointap: an strace-like tool for bitcoin ebpf USDT tracepoints</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:56.105840+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcointap-an-strace-like-tool-for-bitcoin-ebpf-usdt-tracepoints/1694" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of bitcointap marks a significant leap forward for Bitcoin developers, offering a new tool that enables enhanced insights into Bitcoin Core's runtime behavior through the use of Rust programming language. Bitcointap is both a library and a command-line interface (CLI) tool designed to tap into bitcoin-core's Berkeley Packet Filter (eBPF) User Space, Statically Defined Tracing (USDT) tracepoints without affecting its operational performance. This innovative approach provides developers with a powerful resource for understanding and optimizing Bitcoin Core operations.

The inspiration behind bitcointap stems from the peer_observer project initiated by @0xB10C, highlighting the collaborative and iterative nature of development within the Bitcoin community. The project underscores the importance of tracing in Bitcoin Core, an aspect that allows developers to delve deeper into the system's runtime processes in a non-intrusive manner. For those keen on exploring this further, the official Bitcoin Core tracing documentation is recommended as a comprehensive resource. This guide elucidates the methodologies, applications, and significance of tracing within Bitcoin environments, serving as an essential read for developers looking to leverage these capabilities ([Bitcoin Core tracing documentation](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/8309a9747a8df96517970841b3648937d05939a3/doc/tracing.md)).

In a related development effort, another contributor shared their experience working on a similar tool aimed at enhancing peer observation capabilities. Despite achieving partial success, they encountered performance issues linked to the ratatui interface, particularly when running the tool over extended periods. This challenge ultimately led to the discontinuation of the project, yet the sharing of this experience, along with the provision of relevant links such as the project repository ([peer-observer](https://github.com/willcl-ark/peer-observer/tree/tui)) and a demonstration video ([asciinema recording](https://asciinema.org/a/eMHaUhfX537iXR2IZBlulXHBx)), enriches the collective knowledge and toolset available to the Bitcoin developer community. 

The narrative surrounding these developments emphasizes the ongoing need for tracepoint-oriented tools in Bitcoin development. It reflects a vibrant ecosystem where developers are encouraged to build upon each other's work, share insights, and seek feedback for continuous improvement. The creators of bitcointap are actively engaging with the community, inviting suggestions on traces that could enhance the tool's utility and effectiveness. This open invitation for feedback signals a commitment to evolving bitcointap in alignment with user needs and technological advancements, fostering a culture of innovation and collaboration within the Bitcoin development space.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T20:23:27.303000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
