<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-05-18T02:51:20.976184+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2025-05-17 21:49:58.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light 2025-05-17 20:50:31.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QcMrHyde  . 2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>juangalt  . 2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5026_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5024_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-05-18T02:51:20.976294+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion evaluates the efficacy and potential drawbacks of Know Your Customer (KYC) regulations within the context of Bitcoin transactions. It highlights concerns about the practicality of updating a whitelist only every two weeks, noting that such a delay could allow compromised addresses to be abused, undermining the goal of immediate action against fraud or theft. The conversation acknowledges that while KYC covenants aim to make stealing coins more difficult, history has shown that attackers can still find ways to circumvent these barriers through methods like money mules, account takeovers, and identity theft.

In exploring alternatives to traditional KYC mechanisms, the dialogue shifts towards the use of technologies like Railgun and Privacy Pools built on Bitcoin. These innovations are presented as trustless solutions that could enhance privacy and security without compromising the integrity of transactions. The mention of Optech Newsletters provides insights into ongoing discussions within the Bitcoin community regarding OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and recursive covenants, emphasizing the balance between innovation and maintaining censorship resistance.

The regulatory landscape is further dissected with references to European Union efforts captured in documents like [EUR-Lex](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32023R1114), which clarifies the stance on custodial versus non-custodial wallet services. This segmentation underscores a broader move towards regulated custody services, suggesting a nuanced approach to blockchain technology's governance and its implications for user autonomy and security.

Concerns over "evil covenants" and their implementation within the Bitcoin protocol are critically examined. The debate touches upon the technical challenges and ethical considerations of embedding such functionalities, which could potentially enforce stringent control over transactions. The discourse delves into the possibilities of achieving covenant-like behavior through alternative script operations, highlighting the creativity and resilience of Bitcoin’s development community in navigating these complex issues.

The conversation also scrutinizes the operational and regulatory nuances of integrating new financial institutions into the blockchain ecosystem. It debates the merits and limitations of using backend server code updates versus on-chain mechanisms like covenants or multisig for ensuring compliance and security. This aspect brings to light the ongoing tension between leveraging blockchain's innovative potential and adhering to evolving regulatory frameworks.

A detailed analysis of covenant versus multisig KYC pools reveals a preference for the structured and transparent nature of covenants. This structure is seen as offering greater reliability and accountability in managing KYC protocols, contrasting with the more flexible yet less publicly verifiable multisig arrangements.

Furthermore, the discussion navigates the procedural intricacies of incorporating new addresses for transaction purposes, particularly in relation to regulatory compliance and operational efficiency. The model of using extended public keys (xpubs) for registering multiple addresses en masse illustrates an attempt to reconcile privacy concerns with regulatory demands.

Lastly, the discourse addresses the theoretical and practical aspects of implementing perpetual KYC contracts using Bitcoin script opcodes. This exploration considers the implications of such contracts for regulatory compliance, user security, and the broader dynamics of control and autonomy within the Bitcoin network. The conversation culminates in pondering the permanence of government policies on Bitcoin transactions, questioning the long-term viability and ethical ramifications of perpetual oversight and control by regulatory authorities.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-17T21:49:58.786000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
