<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-05-27T02:46:41.398731+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-05-26 20:23:54.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-05-26 07:53:54.965000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>brh  . 2025-05-23 20:28:07.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>carla  . 2025-05-23 17:44:47.800000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5124_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5122_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5109_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5107_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T02:46:41.398780+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue concerning the implementation of forwarding delays within the Lightning network highlights a critical debate on balancing privacy enhancement with operational performance. Concerns were raised about the potential for these delays to interfere with the efficiency of payment processing, particularly given the trial-and-error nature of routing in the network. The increased time for resolving both successful and failed payment attempts could exacerbate issues related to liquidity locking and the availability of HTLC slots, essential for the fluid operation of the network. This situation underscores the challenge of incentivizing routing nodes to adopt practices that primarily benefit privacy without offering tangible benefits to their operational goals or the broader network's efficiency.

An alternative approach to implementing delays at every hop suggests introducing them only at the source and destination points, allowing users to opt-in based on their privacy preferences versus performance needs. This method avoids the complexities and resistance associated with network-wide protocol changes, offering a more user-centric and adaptable solution. For receivers, it ensures that payments are still processed successfully despite these added delays, striking a balance between enhancing privacy and maintaining acceptable performance levels.

During discussions on the privacy implications of disclosing HTLC hold times, the idea of encoding these times in block intervals rather than milliseconds was proposed to protect payment privacy better. This change aims to obscure the precise timing information that could be used to undermine the effectiveness of random forwarding delays. Furthermore, the conversation touched upon the strategic balance between ensuring fast payments for a positive user experience and the privacy advantages offered by such delays. The distinction between on-path and off-path attackers in the context of privacy attacks was also elaborated, highlighting the different methodologies employed by each to compromise transaction anonymity. The variability introduced by forwarding delays presents challenges for both types of attackers, though the current incentive structure within the Lightning Network does not strongly encourage the adoption of such privacy-preserving measures.

The discourse acknowledges the limited adoption of privacy-enhancing forwarding delays across significant portions of the network, operated predominantly by LND and Eclair nodes, which lack consistent implementation of such measures. This reality opens up a debate on whether enforcing forwarding delays through protocol amendments is the optimal strategy for enhancing privacy or if other recommended approaches should be pursued. These include imposing delays at the recipient's end, diversifying retry paths, and introducing cooldown periods between attempts for senders, all aimed at empowering users with greater control over their privacy without significantly detracting from the network's performance.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-26T20:23:54.347000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
