<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
  <updated>2025-05-15T02:43:50.019046+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-05-14 12:18:33.194000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-24 11:04:04.197000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-24 08:31:45.420000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>kloaec  . 2025-04-23 19:29:50.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:47:43.736000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:28:51.370000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi  . 2025-04-16 17:27:45.999000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2025-04-16 16:00:46.661000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-04-16 15:57:46.287000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode  . 2025-04-16 13:52:53.883000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5005_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4870_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4869_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4866_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4811_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4810_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4802_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4809_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4808_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4805_A-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple backup scheme for wallet accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T02:43:50.019125+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-backup-scheme-for-wallet-accounts/1607/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation begins by addressing the advantages of a backup scheme for Bitcoin wallets, particularly focusing on multisig configurations. This approach emphasizes secrecy for those without a specific descriptor while allowing for data recovery in case of loss through the use of signing devices and a Bitcoin Core node. It details a method involving SHA256 computation and XOR operations to decrypt backup payloads using public keys, suggesting BIP87's account level xpub as a plausible candidate for decryption attempts. The backup strategy benefits from its direct derivation from a descriptor, offering practical advantages such as data verification against corruption and adaptability for cloud synchronization. The backup's payload, potentially a JSON blob, would include essential information like the wallet descriptor or policy, with room for expansion to accommodate additional backup needs.

Further discussion points towards enhancing cryptographic systems' security through controlled access to encrypted backups, necessitating all devices involved to provide their key parts. This method contrasts simpler schemes by reducing recovery search paths, thus increasing security. However, it acknowledges limitations due to dependencies on hardware signers and considers incorporating error correction mechanisms to ensure backup file reliability. Various alternatives for creating and storing backup copies are suggested, highlighting the importance of balancing advanced error correction techniques with thoughtful backup strategies for data preservation.

The discourse transitions to exploring an encryption scheme designed to secure multisig wallets by conditioning access on specific extended public keys (xpubs). Utilizing Shamir's Secret Sharing algorithm, the scheme divides the necessary secret for accessing the multisig descriptor into several shares. Each share is encrypted with a unique xpub, requiring possession of a minimum number of specific xpubs for decryption. This method strategically increases security while maintaining manageability, albeit acknowledging limitations for more sophisticated wallet configurations.

Attention is drawn to the criticality of accurately documenting and conveying information, emphasizing the need for clarity in language to prevent misunderstandings. This segment underscores the importance of precision in communication materials, especially when dealing with complex topics such as cryptocurrency security.

The significance of backing up wallet descriptors is underscored, with a focus on the peril of losing access to multisig wallets if these descriptors are not properly secured. The text encourages differentiating between seeds and descriptors due to their varying levels of sensitivity and proposes a combination of symmetric and asymmetric encryption techniques for optimal backup security. The deterministic encryption approach discussed aims to foster further development toward a standardized backup standard that enhances the security and recoverability of digital assets stored in multisig configurations.

Lastly, the document includes a detailed examination of a proposed backup scheme for multisig wallets, addressing potential vulnerabilities associated with storing encrypted descriptors publicly. By utilizing shamir secret sharing within a $k$-of-$n$ multisig descriptor setup, this scheme enhances security by encrypting each share with one xpub, thereby obfuscating the multisig's complexity from attackers. Additionally, it suggests keeping derivation paths in plaintext to facilitate easy derivation of xpubs while securing critical information. Public resources, including a GitHub repository and a detailed post on Delving Bitcoin, are provided for collaborative enhancement and application of the backup scheme. The correspondence suggests a cooperative effort to integrate various methods for a comprehensive solution, highlighting the community's role in advancing cryptocurrency security practices.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-14T12:18:33.194000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
