<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-23T13:50:07.424618+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-26 05:12:52.072000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-25 00:16:13.204000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 21:49:58.786000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 20:50:31.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>harding  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>sanket  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>roasbeef  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>QcMrHyde  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>juangalt  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_18" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_19" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5171_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5120_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5114_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5026_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5024_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-23T13:50:07.428495+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The subject of blockchain security, particularly in the context of large transactions, highlights a noteworthy contrast between the revocability of TLS certificates and the permanence of co-signing keys embedded in UTXOs. The possibility of constructing a framework mirrored on TLS, utilizing technologies such as CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS, introduces a potential advancement in blockchain infrastructure. This approach could enable a dynamic management of security, akin to certificate authorities in traditional web security, suggesting a movement towards more adaptable and resilient systems against security breaches.
In parallel, discussions around KYC practices within digital currency systems underscore the challenges in preventing account misuse and the movement of illicit funds. Despite KYC's intent to secure transactions, its effectiveness appears limited without supplementary measures like transaction rate limiting. The experiences from traditional financial institutions reveal significant vulnerabilities, even with extensive KYC protocols, emphasizing the complexity of ensuring security within digital currencies. Moreover, the conversation extends into the realm of key management and the difficulties associated with maintaining operational security and efficiency, especially concerning hot keys. The exploration of CBDCs by governments ventures into uncharted territories, raising unanswered questions about the potential for authoritarian misuse of cryptocurrency technology for surveillance.
Further analysis delves into the KYC covenant mechanism and its potential manipulation risks. Despite the structured security promises, sophisticated fraud schemes prevalent in traditional banking highlight the potential for similar threats within digital currencies. The discussion also considers alternative trustless mechanisms, proposing a shift towards privacy-focused solutions like Railgun and Privacy Pools facilitated by `OP_CAT`. This suggests an evolving consideration of blockchain technology's capabilities to incorporate advanced security features without solely relying on conventional KYC measures.
The examination of Bitcoin’s development, specifically regarding OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and censorship resistance, reflects the community's cautious yet collaborative approach towards enhancing Bitcoin's functionality. The dialogue across platforms like the Linux Foundation's mailing list and Optech Newsletters reveals a deep engagement with the technical and philosophical aspects of Bitcoin's evolution. This ongoing discourse underscores the developer community's dedication to scrutinizing proposed changes, aiming to preserve Bitcoin's core values while exploring avenues for innovation.
The EU's regulatory efforts, as outlined in recent documents, emphasize a distinction between custodial and non-custodial wallet services, indicating a trend towards more regulated custody services. This shift implicates a broader strategy of enforcing KYC regulations more effectively, potentially increasing reliance on custodian services. The debate over covenants versus multisig mechanisms for regulatory compliance brings forth considerations about the balance between operational simplicity and the robustness of security protocols, highlighting the evolving intersection of blockchain technologies and financial regulation.
Discussions on covenant KYC pools versus multisig KYC pools suggest a preference for the former due to its structured, rule-bound nature, which may offer a more reliable and transparent framework for managing KYC protocols. This aligns with broader strategic considerations in digital finance, where the integration of regulatory compliance, privacy, and security remains paramount.
The narrative around generating new addresses for each transaction, enhanced by the use of extended public keys (xpub), illustrates an innovative approach to marrying privacy with regulatory compliance. This method, reflecting a blend of security consciousness and operational efficiency, exemplifies the nuanced strategies being employed to navigate the regulatory landscapes of digital currencies.
Lastly, the comparative analysis of whitelist and multisig approaches for government-related cryptocurrency transactions does not show a clear preference for either system in terms of flexibility or security. However, it underscores the complexities of implementing KYC procedures and managing secure transactions within the decentralized framework of cryptocurrencies, pointing towards an ongoing dialogue on finding optimal solutions within this dynamic field.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>