<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-05-24T02:43:23.175298+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>brh28 2025-05-23 20:28:07.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>carla 2025-05-23 17:44:47.800000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5109_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5107_Latency-and-Privacy-in-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Latency and Privacy in Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-05-24T02:43:23.175338+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/latency-and-privacy-in-lightning/1723" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the trade-off between enhancing privacy and the consequent performance issues within the Lightning Network, particularly regarding latency introduced by forwarding delays. These delays impact every hop of payment attempts, slowing down both successful payments and failing ones, which compounds the existing problems of locked liquidity and HTLC slots for routing nodes. Despite these concerns, the idea of applying delays at the source and destinations is favored for its flexibility, lack of protocol changes required, and enhanced safety for receivers.

A recent meeting highlighted concerns about the privacy impact of revealing granular HTLC hold times, which could lead nodes to prioritize speed over privacy, undermining efforts to introduce random forwarding delays as a privacy measure. A proposed solution involves changing the encoding of hold times to represent block time instead of milliseconds, making it impractical to communicate values below a certain threshold, thus preserving the efficacy of random delays.

The effectiveness of forwarding delays against two types of attackers - on-path and off-path adversaries - is analyzed. On-path attackers, who create channels and route payments to deanonymize transactions, can be thwarted by random delays that disrupt their ability to match observed times with their latency estimates. Off-path attackers, monitoring network messages, rely on deterministic pathfinding to reduce anonymity sets, but forwarding delays hinder their ability to construct partial paths, although other strategies like message padding may be more effective against them.

The incentive structure for forwarding nodes does not naturally align with privacy preservation, as they are motivated to clear payments quickly to utilize their capital efficiently. This misalignment suggests that relying on forwarding nodes for privacy might not be optimal. Instead, implementing delays at the recipient's end or giving senders control over routing algorithms could offer better-aligned incentives for privacy protection.

In conclusion, while current implementations in the Lightning Network do not sufficiently defend against privacy attacks, there's an acknowledgment of the need for better solutions, whether through the implementation of forwarding delays or exploring other suggested measures. The discussion reflects a consensus on the necessity of improving privacy protections without compromising on performance, urging collective action towards implementing more robust defenses.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-23T20:28:07.443000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
