<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
  <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:21.582321+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-05-15 05:58:29.493000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell  . 2025-05-15 01:51:04.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2025-05-13 13:24:31.629000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5014_The-Spam-problem-of-Bitcoin-and-Unpermissioned-Broadcast-Networks-in-general.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5013_The-Spam-problem-of-Bitcoin-and-Unpermissioned-Broadcast-Networks-in-general.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4998_The-Spam-problem-of-Bitcoin-and-Unpermissioned-Broadcast-Networks-in-general.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T02:46:21.582381+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-spam-problem-of-bitcoin-and-unpermissioned-broadcast-networks-in-general/1692" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of network layers within Bitcoin's architecture reveals a nuanced approach to handling spam. The concept of Layer Zero presents an innovative framework that positions the Bitcoin mainchain as a subnetwork, thereby enabling transactions to commit to a less congested layer. This structure suggests a method for users to experience a more efficient network by processing fewer transactions, essentially compressing and simplifying the data. Such an approach counters spam by encouraging spammers to remain on Layer One, where they can continue to push data without affecting the streamlined experience of users on Layer Zero. This idea underscores the potential for architectural changes within Bitcoin's network to address issues of spam without compromising the integrity or functionality of the system.

The narrative around spam in the Bitcoin ecosystem diverges from traditional understandings, particularly in how it relates to the blockchain. Unlike the minimal costs associated with email spam, transactions labeled as spam in Bitcoin involve consenting parties, including miners who process these transactions for a fee, making such activities expensive. This economic shift has made storing data on the Bitcoin blockchain as costly as using commercial services like Amazon S3, deterring misuse. Additionally, the blockchain's limited space has become a valuable asset, exploited for seigniorage rather than merely transmitting financial transactions. Historical efforts to mitigate the misuse of Bitcoin’s blockchain highlight the community's response to altcoins and the phenomenon of "dusting," suggesting evolving strategies to preserve the blockchain's intended purpose while enhancing user privacy and security.

Furthermore, the discussion emphasizes the challenges of mitigating spam in peer-to-peer (P2P) value transfers, especially within unpermissioned networks like Bitcoin and nostr. The analysis suggests that increasing transaction costs as a deterrent to spam may disproportionately benefit spammers over regular users. This is due to the higher value spammers derive from their activities compared to individuals engaging in P2P transactions. The inherent design of Bitcoin's layer-1, based on broadcast principles, poses limitations on adopting more efficient anti-spam measures that do not penalize legitimate users. The comparison with internet-wide strategies against spam, which focus on user identification and penalization for misbehavior, highlights a fundamental clash with Bitcoin’s principles of anonymity and censorship resistance. Consequently, this dilemma points to the need for alternative solutions that balance the network's utility with its foundational values, challenging the community to innovate while preserving privacy and resisting surveillance.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T05:58:29.493000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
