<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
  <updated>2025-05-10T02:37:35.504766+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen 2025-05-09 06:29:35.472000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen  . 2025-05-08 06:38:16.682000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-05-08 04:39:17.052000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen  . 2025-05-07 04:32:30.503000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bramcohen  . 2025-05-02 23:23:13.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4966_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4960_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4958_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4952_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4924_A-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - A simple approach to allowing recursive covenants by enabling quines</title>
    <updated>2025-05-10T02:37:35.504823+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/a-simple-approach-to-allowing-recursive-covenants-by-enabling-quines/1655" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email conversation explores the introduction of OP_ASSERT_OUTPUT as a simplified alternative to OP_CTV, focusing on enhancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities for more dynamic uses, such as state channel gaming. This new opcode allows specifying outcomes within Bitcoin transactions more flexibly by making claims about individual outputs rather than the entire transaction. The design draws inspiration from OP_CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY, emphasizing specificity in transaction conditions. The motivation behind this development is to enable games over state channels, with a proof of concept nearly completed after years of dedicated effort.

Further discussion delves into the technical intricacies of implementing an opcode that mandates the inclusion of a Pay-to-Witness-Script-Hash (P2WSH) output in transactions. This proposal aims to integrate a higher level of specificity and security by requiring a SHA-256 hash of a script for transaction validation, thus potentially refining Bitcoin's scripting and verification processes. Such a move could streamline network operations and enhance its capacity to support complex scripts more efficiently, aligning with goals to bolster both the security and functionality of Bitcoin transactions.

The conversation also touches upon the limitations faced in implementing recursive covenants due to the rigid structure of Bitcoin’s scripting language, particularly within the P2WSH framework. Recursive covenants, which allow for conditions controlling transactions over multiple stages, present a challenge due to the current scripting model's limitations. The discussion notes that extending script functionalities is largely constrained to replacing no operation codes with functional opcodes, a workaround that falls short of supporting the desired recursion for advanced scripting capabilities like recursive covenants.

A novel approach suggested includes introducing a 'reverse order' opcode to improve Bitcoin Script parsing and execution flexibility. This would facilitate easier implementation of complex scripts by allowing them to process script bytes in reverse order. Additionally, the proposal of opcodes capable of reversing byte order or enabling incremental hashing without concatenation points towards simplifying script processing, thereby laying groundwork for future enhancements, especially for recursive covenants.

Moreover, the proposal discusses the practical application of these scripting enhancements in creating a vault mechanism with dual keys: one hot key with spending limits and one cold key without such restrictions. It illustrates how different conditions can be applied to transactions based on which key is used, demonstrating the utility of the proposed changes in real-world scenarios. While acknowledging the potential benefits of loop constructs for smart coin development, the existing proposals emphasize efficiency and sufficiency in achieving similar outcomes through the proposed scripting additions.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-09T06:29:35.472000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
