<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-09-21T20:00:42.006312+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-26 05:12:52.072000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-25 00:16:13.204000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 21:49:58.786000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-05-17 20:50:31.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>harding  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>sanket  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>roasbeef  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>QcMrHyde  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>juangalt  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>recent  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_18" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>RobinLinus  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_19" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>light  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5171_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5120_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5114_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5026_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5024_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T20:00:42.010451+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-05-30 15:44:35.371000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The challenge of securing large sums against attackers in digital transactions is significant, with TLS certificates offering a robust security measure due to their revocability, a feature not present in co-signing keys once integrated into UTXOs. The introduction of CAT, EXPIRE, and CSFS technologies proposes an infrastructure that mirrors TLS, suggesting a move towards adaptable security infrastructures capable of managing emerging threats. This development indicates a shift towards more dynamic and resilient frameworks for data protection.
Concerns about the effectiveness of KYC protocols in cryptocurrency transactions highlight the limitations of relying solely on KYC to prevent misuse or abuse of accounts. The necessity of additional measures, such as rate limiting on transactions, is underscored by the practical challenges faced by traditional financial institutions, which demonstrate vulnerabilities despite comprehensive KYC protocols. This discussion brings to the forefront the complexities of ensuring security and efficiency within crypto networks, especially regarding key management and the deployment of Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs) by governments.
The potential for abuse of KYC covenants, despite their intended security measures, raises questions about their effectiveness in preventing theft. Sophisticated fraud schemes within traditional banking systems hint at possible vulnerabilities within KYC covenants in the cryptocurrency context. Alternatives such as Railgun and Privacy Pools suggest a move towards trustless mechanisms that do not rely on conventional KYC protocols, indicating a search for more secure and privacy-oriented solutions in blockchain technology.
Explorations into enhancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities through OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and concerns about losing censorship resistance reflect the community's careful consideration of technical implementations against Bitcoin's foundational goals. The discussions, covered in Optech Newsletters, reveal a commitment to maintaining security, decentralization, and resilience against undue control, showcasing the thoughtful and scrutinizing nature of Bitcoin's development community.
Recent EU regulations impacting cryptocurrency custodians highlight a shift towards regulated custody services, aiming to strike a balance between innovation and regulatory compliance. Discussions around the use of covenants and multisig mechanisms for enforcing KYC regulations indicate an evolving landscape of digital finance, where operational efficiency and security protocols are pivotal considerations for new and established financial institutions.
The efficiency of generating new addresses for each transaction, highlighted by the registration process using an extended public key (xpub), underscores a thoughtful integration of privacy and regulatory compliance. This approach, while accommodating regulatory oversight, suggests a path forward for financial institutions to navigate the challenges of digital financial transactions with enhanced security and privacy considerations.
The intricacies of employing Merkle roots and covenants in transaction processes raise concerns about user experience and operational efficiency. These discussions touch upon the balance between security requirements and practical usability, pointing towards continuous efforts to refine blockchain technology for optimal functionality within regulatory frameworks.
Lastly, the debate over perpetual KYC contracts within Bitcoin's protocol delves into the implications of government policies on cryptocurrency autonomy and liquidity. Questions about the permanence of such policies and the government's ability to relinquish control over BTC transactions probe into the long-term impacts of regulatory approaches on the decentralized nature of cryptocurrencies. This reflects ongoing dialogues about the balance between regulation, innovation, and the foundational principles of digital currencies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>