<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-05-27T02:44:42.439879+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus 2025-05-26 05:12:52.072000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2025-05-25 00:16:13.204000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2025-05-17 21:49:58.786000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2025-05-17 20:50:31.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-02-16 16:27:39.486000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-02-14 07:28:22.722000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2024-02-13 23:50:36.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2024-02-13 23:13:17.260000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>QcMrHyde  . 2024-02-13 22:17:35.211000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 20:35:41.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>juangalt  . 2024-02-13 20:15:48.223000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 20:05:17.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 18:59:47.064000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 18:27:42.245000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>recent  . 2024-02-13 17:47:20.804000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:10:40.381000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>RobinLinus  . 2024-02-13 17:09:04.329000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>light  . 2024-02-13 17:04:01.952000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5120_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5114_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5026_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5024_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1590_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1557_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1552_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1551_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1550_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1548_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1547_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1546_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1542_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1541_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1539_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1534_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1538_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1537_Perpetually-KYC-d-Coins-Using-Evil-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Perpetually KYC'd Coins Using Evil Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T02:44:42.439998+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/perpetually-kycd-coins-using-evil-covenants/556/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the effectiveness of Know Your Customer (KYC) protocols in digital currency systems reveals various challenges and considerations in preventing account misuse and the movement of illicit funds. Despite KYC processes, without additional measures like rate limiting or rapid blacklisting of compromised accounts, large unauthorized transactions can still occur. This points to inherent vulnerabilities within traditional financial institutions and the limitations of relying solely on KYC for security. The management of keys, especially hot keys, poses significant challenges in maintaining both system security and performance. The potential use of Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs) by authoritarian regimes for surveillance raises further concerns about digital currency management practices.

The conversation also delves into the intricacies of KYC covenant mechanisms and their manipulation risks. Despite assurances of security, attackers have found ways to circumvent existing banking systems' KYC measures, suggesting that similar schemes could undermine KYC covenants. Discussions around alternatives such as trustless systems indicate a search for more secure and privacy-preserving methods in blockchain technology.

The discourse on OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK and Bitcoin's censorship resistance within its development community highlights ongoing debates around the protocol's evolution. Insights from Optech Newsletters and Linux Foundation mailing list discussions reflect the community's cautious approach to introducing new opcodes and the broader implications of technical implementations on Bitcoin's foundational goals.

Recent EU regulations distinguish between custodial and non-custodial wallet providers, emphasizing a regulatory shift towards more controlled custody services while raising questions about the utility and regulation of covenants in blockchain technologies. Discussions suggest that governments might not need covenants for KYC enforcement, proposing multisignature setups as an alternative.

The debate on evil covenants within Bitcoin explores their risk mitigation and the technical feasibility of solutions like freeze keys, underscoring the balance between innovation and security. Meanwhile, discussions on transaction introspection and creating recursive covenants without OP_CAT showcase the technical creativity within the Bitcoin community, despite existing limitations.

The consideration of backend server code updates by financial institutions as an alternative to blockchain-based mechanisms like covenants or multisig highlights the trade-offs between implementation ease and security robustness. The analysis of covenant versus multisig KYC pools emphasizes the structured, transparent nature of covenants as potentially more reliable for managing KYC protocols.

Strategies to enhance digital payment security and compliance involve generating new addresses for each transaction and leveraging extended public keys for efficient registration with governmental entities. This model balances privacy, security, and regulatory compliance, highlighting the evolving dynamics of digital finance.

The discussion on using Merkle roots and covenant models for Bitcoin transactions contrasts their operational efficiency and user experience implications, pointing to challenges in achieving practical usability. Lastly, the exploration of perpetual KYC contracts and government control over Bitcoin transactions underlines the regulatory ambitions and potential impacts on the cryptocurrency's autonomy and liquidity, sparking inquiries into the permanence and reversibility of such policies.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-26T05:12:52.072000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
