<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
  <updated>2025-05-13T02:48:42.881121+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>blockchainhao</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>hebasto  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sdaftuar  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4986_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4985_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1668_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1664_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1654_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1652_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1599_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1598_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1490_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1489_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1485_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1461_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1450_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1447_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1442_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1441_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1429_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1097_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1096_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1095_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1090_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1089_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1087_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2024/1046_An-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - An overview of the cluster mempool proposal</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T02:48:42.881276+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/an-overview-of-the-cluster-mempool-proposal/393" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins by addressing a common question among newcomers regarding the potential for conflict between two transactions, referred to as C and C', in Bitcoin's mempool. The confusion arises when both transactions, despite having different parents (A and D, respectively), attempt to spend the same confirmed UTXO, thus leading to a conflict without an apparent direct dependency.

The conversation then shifts to the intricacies of Replace-By-Fee (RBF) transactions, emphasizing the need for setting limits to manage validation costs effectively. RBF transactions, distinguished by their requirement for re-clustering and re-linearization within affected clusters, pose significant computational challenges. The current RBF rules cap the number of transactions that can be evicted for a single replacement at 100, proposing a strategy to control validation costs by limiting conflicts and cluster sizes to manageable numbers. This approach aims to simplify the validation process while acknowledging the need for further benchmarking to refine these limitations.

Security concerns associated with RBF transactions are also highlighted, pointing out the potential for new attack vectors due to the substantial effort required to reject an RBF transaction. This underscores the importance of thorough analysis to ensure system security and integrity against various attacks, including those exploiting the RBF mechanism.

The practicalities of constructing RBF transactions are explored, noting the complexity of doing so without detailed mempool information. Despite theoretical guidelines provided in BIP 125, wallets typically rely on increasing fees until acceptance or confirmation, indicating a gap between theory and practice. Recent proposals suggest adjustments to RBF rules might align more closely with user expectations and real-world scenarios, as indicated by minimal changes needed in functional tests.

Furthermore, the dialogue covers alternative approaches to managing mempool efficiency, such as enforcing a validation rule that ensures replacements offer a "strictly better" condition for miners. This proposal seeks to eliminate ambiguity and optimize transaction replacement through precise feerate diagram checks, although the feasibility of wallets constructing compliant RBF transactions without explicit mempool ordering knowledge is questioned.

The concept of blockchain transaction limitations is introduced, particularly focusing on unconfirmed transactions and proposed cluster size limits. A scenario is described where transactions without ancestors and with outputs exceeding a cluster size limit face spending restrictions until the parent transaction's confirmation. This discussion extends to CoinJoin transactions, highlighting how cluster size limits could affect participant experiences based on the order of participation and the imposed cap on cluster size.

An exploration of mempool management strategies reveals a proposed algorithm aiming to select a superior subset of transactions from an overly large cluster, enhancing processing efficiency without necessitating transaction resubmission. This algorithm prioritizes high-fee transactions for inclusion, potentially allowing for the re-addition of previously evicted transactions if space permits, thus optimizing mempool composition.

The blog post transitions to discussing challenges in transaction eviction policies, emphasizing the balance between efficiency, security, and fairness in mempool management. It critiques current methodologies for their inefficiency and explores alternatives that might offer neater solutions without compromising system integrity. The concept of sibling eviction is revisited, suggesting its potential relevance in future network structures and mempool management strategies.

Lastly, the email touches upon proposed policy changes within the Bitcoin Core mempool, highlighting a shift towards cluster size limitations and updated RBF rules. This new design seeks to improve transaction organization and mining efficiency by ensuring a coherent order for eviction and selection processes, thereby aligning miner incentives with mempool management objectives.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-12T14:31:40.551000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
