<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
  <updated>2025-05-15T02:46:07.962155+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-05-15 01:51:04.951000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2025-05-13 13:24:31.629000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5013_The-Spam-problem-of-Bitcoin-and-Unpermissioned-Broadcast-Networks-in-general.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4998_The-Spam-problem-of-Bitcoin-and-Unpermissioned-Broadcast-Networks-in-general.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Spam problem of Bitcoin and Unpermissioned Broadcast Networks in general</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T02:46:07.962192+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-spam-problem-of-bitcoin-and-unpermissioned-broadcast-networks-in-general/1692" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the complexities of addressing spam within Bitcoin and similar decentralized networks, contrasting traditional anti-spam strategies with the unique challenges presented by these systems. Unlike conventional email spam, which can be combated by simply not viewing the unwanted messages, spam in the context of Bitcoin involves transactions between consenting parties that are verified and recorded on the blockchain at a significant cost to the sender. This high cost of transactions inherently limits the volume of spam but does not eliminate it entirely. The primary concern is the use of Bitcoin's blockchain for purposes other than direct monetary transfers, such as creating non-Bitcoin assets through seigniorage. This activity exploits the blockchain's scarce space without being deterred by rising costs, unlike most spam.

The discussion also highlights a shift among users who seek efficient peer-to-peer value transfers away from Bitcoin, due to its vulnerability to spam. Bitcoin's fundamental design, based on broadcasting transactions to all network participants, makes it difficult to adopt more effective anti-spam measures without compromising its core principles, such as anonymity and censorship resistance. This issue is not only specific to Bitcoin but extends to other decentralized networks like nostr, which face similar challenges in managing spam without resorting to user identification and the resulting privacy concerns.

In exploring potential solutions, the text references the early creation of altcoins as an attempt to address Bitcoin's limitations, including its susceptibility to spam. However, the effectiveness of such solutions remains questionable, particularly when the demand for these alternative tokens may be driven by illicit activities rather than genuine utility. Additionally, the phenomenon of "dusting" is mentioned as an analog to email spam in the Bitcoin ecosystem, suggesting that while countermeasures exist, they have yet to be widely discussed or implemented.

Ultimately, the conversation underscores the need for innovative approaches to reconcile the desire for open, decentralized networks with the imperative to protect against spam. It suggests rethinking current strategies in favor of methods that preserve the network’s utility and foundational values without succumbing to the drawbacks of increased surveillance and loss of privacy inherent in many of today's anti-spam techniques.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T01:51:04.951000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
