<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-03T02:19:44.674408+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-02-02 17:00:25.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T02:19:44.674434+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the enforcement of distinctness or uniqueness in a cryptographic scheme, specifically questioning whether it incorporates a mechanism like a nullifier or key image to prevent multiple uses of a UTXO (Unspent Transaction Output). The scheme under scrutiny allows a prover to demonstrate possession of a valid signature for any given message corresponding to a public key \(P\), where \(P\) equals \(x\) times \(G\), with \(G\) being a generator point in elliptic curve cryptography. In this process, the prover reveals both the message and \(hash(x)\) to the verifier. Additionally, it is shown that the public key \(P\) is included in a Utreexo set, a data structure designed for efficient representation of state, by providing the Utreexo root to the verifier.

The original query hints at a lack of direct mention of a mechanism ensuring uniqueness in the provided readme documentation, drawing a parallel with an "add-on" feature from another project (aut-ct) that integrates a key-image concept into the curvetree part to tackle this issue. However, it is speculated that the function of \(hash(x)\) might serve the purpose of ensuring uniqueness, acting similarly to a nullifier or key image by preventing the reuse of UTXOs through its unique association with each public key \(P\).

This conversation underscores the importance of explicitly addressing concerns related to the prevention of double-spending or replay attacks in cryptographic protocols. It highlights the need for clear documentation and the integration of mechanisms that ensure each transaction output can only be spent once, thereby maintaining the integrity and security of the system.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-02T17:00:25.514000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
