<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-04T02:17:57.921073+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-03T14:24:44.565000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T02:17:57.921110+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry touches on the critical aspect of ensuring distinctness or uniqueness within a cryptographic scheme, specifically questioning whether the proposed method outputs an identifier (like a nullifier or key image) that prevents the reuse of a transaction output (UTXO), either within channel operations or more broadly. The focus is on the application of this scheme to Musig2 for Lightning Network (LN) gossip, directing attention to resources that elaborate on the enforcement of uniqueness. The suggested approach involves hashing public keys prior to their aggregation into a taproot key, a process detailed in the provided documentation links. By doing so, individual Musig2 public keys remain off-chain, aiming to obscure any direct linkage between the hash and on-chain transactions or spends. This method's intent is to enhance privacy and security by preventing observers from associating the hashed identifiers with specific blockchain activities.

The linked documents, found on the musig2 branch and within the LN gossip document, offer detailed insights into the technical implementation and rationale behind using hashed public keys for maintaining transactional uniqueness without sacrificing privacy. By hashing the bitcoin keys together before forming a taproot key (`pk_hash = hash(bitcoin_keys[0] || bitcoin_keys[1])`), the scheme introduces a layer of obfuscation. This technique ensures that even though the Musig2 public keys contribute to network operations, they do not become publicly traceable through on-chain data, aligning with the overarching goal of enhancing the confidentiality and integrity of transactions within the Lightning Network ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T14:24:44.565000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
