<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T02:17:42.966941+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-02-04 15:05:35.701000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-02-05T02:17:42.966971+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/23" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of parametric min-cut problems reveals a significant characteristic that benefits the analysis and solution of these problems. Specifically, in a broad class of these problems, including the monotone source-sink variations, min-cuts exhibit a nested structure. This nesting implies that for any sequence of decreasing feerates ($\lambda$), the solution for a lower $\lambda$ always encompasses the solutions for all higher $\lambda$s. This not only simplifies the identification of optimal cuts but also ensures that the number of unique min-cuts required to solve the entire problem is linearly bounded by the number of nodes ($O(n)$). Additionally, this property enables solving for the entire set of optimal partitions within the same time complexity as finding a single min-cut, leveraging the continuity of solutions across different $\lambda$ values.

An effective method to enhance the efficiency of identifying the highest fee closure involves contracting the source side of the closure into a single source node, a technique previously mentioned in the GGT paper. This approach facilitates a quicker progression to subsequent solutions without necessitating repetitive calculations. The relevance of such algorithms extends to applications like evaluating the impact of Replace-By-Fee (RBF) transactions on cluster diagrams, where comparing feerates becomes straightforward due to the pre-known rates involved.

Implementation discussions reference a [2007 paper](https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~jonderry/maxflow.pdfpage14) that evaluates the practicality of the full GGT algorithm against its simplified version. The latter, which forgoes bidirectional flow computations for starting each maximum flow calculation anew and incorporates source contraction, consistently outperforms not only the comprehensive GGT algorithm but also another algorithm optimized for bipartite graphs. This evidence suggests that, especially for smaller graph instances, simpler min-cut/max-flow strategies might offer superior performance. These findings advocate for an applied research approach, focusing on actual implementation tests and possibly developing benchmarks to validate the algorithms' efficacy in real-world scenarios. Collaboration and further investigation into the available code and methodologies are encouraged to optimize the application of these algorithms in relevant contexts.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T15:05:35.701000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
