<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T02:19:16.999936+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-04T14:03:58.047000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-02-05T02:19:16.999964+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring improvements in the efficiency of populating prefilled transactions in blockchain networks presents a promising avenue for optimizing data transfer between peers. The concept revolves around the assumption that certain transactions within a block may not be known to all peers, suggesting a proactive approach by sending these transactions immediately could enhance network performance. An investigative effort has been initiated to gather empirical evidence on the matter, focusing on analyzing the contents of inbound and outbound `getblocktxn` messages. This analysis aims to uncover patterns regarding the commonality of missing transactions among peers and the feasibility of pre-filling transactions that were previously requested.

An experimental adjustment was made to one node, setting `blockreconstructionextratxn=10000`, alongside upgrading two nodes to incorporate changes from a significant update ([p2p: track and use all potential peers for orphan resolution 31397](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/31397)). This adjustment is part of a broader strategy to evaluate the impact of enhanced transaction pre-filling under conditions of a full mempool. The outcome of this experiment could provide valuable insights into potential optimizations for transaction dissemination protocols within the Bitcoin network, thereby contributing to the overall efficiency and robustness of blockchain technology. The anticipation of observing the effects of these modifications requires a period of increased mempool activity, during which the effectiveness of the newly implemented strategies will be assessed.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T14:03:58.047000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
