<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T02:22:26.739357+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-04T14:24:16.572000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
    <updated>2025-02-05T02:22:26.739382+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/which-ephemeral-anchor-script-should-lightning-use/1412/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion focuses on the nuances of reorg safety within the context of Lightning Network transactions, particularly highlighting a scenario where a counterparty collaborates with a miner to allocate the full value of a keyed anchor directly to their wallet. This action effectively leaves both the commitment transaction and the Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) transaction as zero fee within a block. Despite the initial oversight of this potential vulnerability, it is deemed manageable due to the protocols Lightning nodes employ to ensure transaction confirmation security. Lightning nodes delay considering transactions as irrevocably confirmed for a period long enough to mitigate the risks associated with blockchain reorganizations. This built-in delay ensures that honest nodes have ample opportunity to rebroadcast their anchor-spend transactions along with their commitments, expecting that sincere miners will include these in the blockchain.

Additionally, the conversation touches on concerns regarding targeted attacks, specifically the risk posed by adversaries guessing when a node might be offline for short periods, such as approximately ten minutes. Although acknowledging this threat, the argument presented suggests its limited applicability mainly to smaller nodes, which are not considered significant targets due to their lesser scale and impact. For more substantial and serious nodes, which rarely experience downtime, especially not as brief as ten minutes, this type of attack is less of a concern. Furthermore, the dialogue explores the value of being able to reclaim small amounts from dust HTLCs (Hashed Time-Locked Contracts). While it may not always be possible to recover these funds fully, the ability to do so occasionally still presents a beneficial option rather than surrendering them entirely to fees. This aspect underscores a pragmatic approach to managing the efficiencies and risks associated with Lightning Network operations, emphasizing the trade-offs between optimal security measures and operational flexibility.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T14:24:16.572000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
