<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2025-02-06T02:17:46.493660+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding.026000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-05T13:39:47.026000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T02:17:46.493692+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/67" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Introducing a per-transaction limit of 2,500 on the number of legacy input signature operations (sigops) represents a nuanced approach to managing blockchain transactions. This limit encompasses both bare and Pay to Script Hash (P2SH) inputs, proposing a standardized accounting method for sigops across various types of transactions. Specifically, the method for calculating the number of sigops for `OP_CHECKMULTISIG` (CMS) varies depending on the context. For bare scripts, traditionally only applied to output scripts, each CMS is counted as 20 sigops. However, when it comes to P2SH redeem scripts, the number of sigops is determined by the CMS parameter that specifies the number of public keys to be checked. For example, a script like `2 3 OP_CMS` would count as three sigops.

Additionally, there's clarification sought on whether the 2,500 input limit applies to CHECK*SIG operations specified in a bare previous output script. This would mean, for instance, that spending a Pay to Public Key (P2PK) output would contribute one sigop towards the transaction's overall limit. This delineation emphasizes the broader effort to standardize and streamline transaction processing rules within the blockchain ecosystem, ensuring a balanced and efficient transaction throughput.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-05T13:39:47.026000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
