<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-06T02:22:49.027949+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth.483000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-05T16:46:45.483000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T02:22:49.027980+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of utilizing a different Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) than the channel output as a means to mitigate spam in the context of channels, particularly focusing on scenarios outside of Zero-Knowledge (ZK) proofs. The initial analysis questions the practicality and necessity of this approach given that the creation of a multisignature (multisig) output is already a requirement for opening a channel between parties. This existing requirement implies that a UTXO is inherently available for use, which would negate the need for an additional UTXO for anti-spam purposes unless channels not backed by a real UTXO were considered.

Moreover, the dynamics of channel creation among non-trusted parties are highlighted as a complicating factor for the proposition of using an alternative UTXO as an anti-spam measure. In situations where channels are established between individuals or entities without mutual trust, the responsibility for providing a UTXO could become contentious. If both parties were required to contribute a UTXO, this could potentially reduce the scalability of the system by adding an additional layer of complexity and resource requirement for channel establishment. This consideration emphasizes the importance of scalability and trust in the design and operation of channels, underscoring the challenges faced in creating efficient and secure mechanisms for mitigating spam without compromising the system's usability and accessibility.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-05T16:46:45.483000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
