<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-06T02:22:31.135065+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-02-05 23:33:28.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T02:22:31.135098+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/24" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the dynamics of channel creation within the Bitcoin Lightning Network, particularly between parties that may not entirely trust one another, the question arises regarding who should commit a UTXO (Unspent Transaction Output) to establish such channels. This inquiry delves into the scalability challenges that could emerge if both parties are required to contribute UTXOs, potentially hindering the network's efficiency and expansion.

Referencing Rusty Russell's proposal on a second version of gossip for the Lightning Network, found [here](https://diyhpl.us/~bryan/irc/bitcoin/bitcoin-dev/linuxfoundation-pipermail/lightning-dev/2022-February/003470.txt), sheds light on an evolving mental model concerning UTXOs and channel management. According to Russell's insights, the existence of a channel is affirmed through `channel_update_v2` messages from both involved peers. Furthermore, Russell introduces the notion of claiming a channel upon its opening, adding another layer to the conceptual framework surrounding channel operations and ownership.

The discussion also touches upon the nuances of channel funding, contrasting single-funder channels with dual-funder scenarios. In single-funder channels, a zero-knowledge proof (zkp) could ostensibly serve as a means to initiate the channel, whereas in dual-funder arrangements, the initial channel balance might reflect the asymmetrical burden of one party providing a singular proof. This perspective, while admittedly speculative, suggests a potential method to accommodate the disparate costs associated with channel establishment, albeit in a manner that leaves room for further clarification and debate.

Rusty's approach to decoupling anti-DOS measures from the blockchain itself and embracing ambiguity in capacity claims presents an intriguing viewpoint. It seemingly offers a more logical foundation by distancing operational security concerns from the blockchain, thereby aiming to enhance the overall scalability and functionality of the Lightning Network without overly complicating the underpinning economic transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-05T23:33:28.574000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
