<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
  <updated>2025-02-07T02:25:41.460868+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-02-06 06:19:44.430000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:25:41.460899+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/which-ephemeral-anchor-script-should-lightning-use/1412/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of channel counterparty transactions, the issue of fee griefing and replacement cycling presents a nuanced challenge. The peculiar position of a channel counterparty allows them to engage in fee griefing practices with a potentially profitable outcome, differentiating them significantly from other participants in the network. Unlike random individuals or miners who engage in similar activities, channel counterparties are in a unique position where their actions can lead directly to financial gain. This gain is primarily through the mechanism of claiming htlc payments via the timeout path, which provides a clear incentive for such behavior.

The risks associated with fee griefing by random individuals or miners are notably higher, accompanied by little to no benefit. For these participants, engaging in fee griefing could result in substantial losses without any guaranteed advantage. Miners, for instance, face a particular dilemma. By attempting to replace transactions, they might either end up mining the original transaction, which only leads to minor delays, or risk significant funds with no assured return. This stark contrast underscores the unique threat posed by channel counterparties in the context of fee griefing and replacement cycling, highlighting the potential for profit-driven exploitation within these interactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T06:19:44.430000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
