<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-07T02:24:03.302739+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>halseth</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-06T13:44:44.539000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:24:03.302769+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407/26" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Exploring the efficiency of hash functions within cryptographic protocols, particularly in the context of `rustreexo`, reveals a significant focus on optimizing proving times. Since October of the previous year, `rustreexo` has introduced the capability for users to implement custom hash functions into their systems. This development paves the way for the adoption of algebraic hash functions, which are notably more efficient—especially in scenarios involving a prover—than their traditional counterparts. The question arises regarding the extent to which utreexo proofs contribute to overall proving time, prompting an investigation into alternative hashing methods that could potentially enhance performance.

A closer examination into the performance metrics of using algebraic hash functions over standard ones indicates that the majority of proving time is not predominantly consumed by utreexo verification or SHA-256 computations. Instead, it appears that key aggregation, particularly for verifying Musig signatures, occupies the largest portion of the computational workload. This insight suggests that while utreexo verification and SHA-256 hashing play roles in the process, they do not represent the primary bottlenecks in proving efficiency. Consequently, the exploration of algebraic hash functions as a means to improve proving times could be valuable, yet it should be considered alongside other optimization strategies for signature verification processes.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T13:44:44.539000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
