<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-02-07T02:18:16.938851+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lagrang3.498000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-06T20:47:07.498000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T02:18:16.938884+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/28" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the GGT algorithm's approach to optimizing a specific subset selection, initially described as seeking to maximize the difference between the fee associated with a subset (xxx) and a scaled version of its size, denoted as $\mathrm{fee}_x - \lambda \mathrm{size}_x$. However, this description is clarified by explaining that for a given value of $\lambda$, the problem essentially becomes one of finding a "maximum weight closure" in a graph, which is a well-understood challenge that can be addressed with any algorithm designed to find a minimum cut in such graphs.

The GGT algorithm stands out due to its novel approach in handling the "maximum feerate closure" problem. Unlike traditional methods that might require iterative bisection techniques to pinpoint the optimal solution, GGT maintains the computational complexity on par with solving a single instance of the "max weight closure" issue. This efficiency sidesteps the need for potentially time-consuming bisection, streamlining the process of solving the more complex "maximum feerate closure" problem without escalating the computational demands. This innovation marks a significant departure from how such optimization problems are typically approached, highlighting the uniqueness and potential utility of the GGT algorithm in relevant applications.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T20:47:07.498000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
