<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
  <updated>2025-02-08T02:15:01.023268+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik.771000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-07T07:39:38.771000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Which ephemeral anchor script should lightning use?</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T02:15:01.023299+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/which-ephemeral-anchor-script-should-lightning-use/1412/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent discussion around the term "miners" in the context of blockchain and cryptocurrency transactions necessitates a deeper exploration into a specific transaction that has been making rounds in the community. This particular transaction, identified on the mempool.space platform, highlights an intriguing aspect of the mainnet P2A (Pay to Address) transactions, especially concerning fee structures and transaction replacements. The transaction in question aimed to send 330 sats (the smallest unit of bitcoin) to a specific address. However, due to its disappearance from the replacement history on mempool.space, it signifies the dynamic and competitive nature of transaction processing within the Bitcoin network.

Further investigation into this matter led to an experimental approach to prioritize a transaction within the mempools of three pruned nodes operated from a single IPv4 address but on different ports. This experiment proved successful, showcasing the flexibility and potential for manipulation within the network's transaction processing mechanisms. The detailed process and outcome of this experiment have been documented and made available through a commit in a GitHub repository, providing a tangible example of how network participants can influence transaction prioritization.

This scenario sheds light on the operational aspects of miners and their interaction with transaction relay services such as Peter Todd's LibreRelay. Notably, LibreRelay's requirement for a minimal additional fee (merely one-fourth of a satoshi more than what is required by Bitcoin Core for transaction replacements) exemplifies the nuanced strategies that can be employed to ensure transaction inclusion in a mined block. This insight into the mechanics of transaction fees and miner operations underscores the intricate balance between user-initiated transactions and miner preferences within the broader ecosystem.

In summary, the exploration of this P2A transaction not only illuminates the technical intricacies involved in transaction propagation and replacement but also highlights the evolving strategies employed by users to navigate the competitive landscape of Bitcoin transaction processing. Furthermore, the documentation of this experiment via a GitHub commit serves as a valuable resource for understanding the practical applications of these strategies in real-world scenarios. For more information, visit the [transaction details on mempool.space](https://mempool.space/tx/ad1507f186ccdd448cc58a5ed68367249de6ad55d7f4b70bb3fcc5c88a85c626?mode=details) and the [GitHub commit](https://github.com/carnhofdaki/anchor/commit/86a4983b4f0947e2858795e90faa3c71d09fa290).</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T07:39:38.771000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
