<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
  <updated>2025-02-08T02:16:52.358129+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-07T08:26:07.472000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T02:16:52.358160+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multisigbackup-com-backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds/1430/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The practice of using a 2-of-2 multisig setup for securing Bitcoin has been highlighted as not only a method to safeguard against personal error but also as a strategy for secure backup. This approach requires the cooperation of another party, referred to as a real human counterpart, who is involved in the security and backup processes without having independent spending capabilities. This system ensures that the secured sats (satoshis, the smallest unit of Bitcoin) are protected from unilateral actions by either party while both are alive, fostering a mutual trust and security framework.

The implementation of multisig, as described, offers several benefits, including the absence of monthly fees associated with Bitcoin's network operations. This aspect underlines the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of utilizing Bitcoin’s infrastructure, which operates independently of the user's geographic location. Moreover, the approach provides plausible deniability regarding the ownership of assets, as neither party in the multisig arrangement can claim sole possession of the sats. This feature is particularly noted for its potential to reduce financial contributions to war efforts and centrally managed social programs, showcasing a philosophical and practical stance on the use of decentralized financial systems like Bitcoin.

The experience shared also touches upon the dissolution of multisig arrangements with students, indicating that such setups can be concluded peacefully and cooperatively. This aspect emphasizes the flexibility and voluntary nature of these agreements. Additionally, the practice of regularly rehearsing mnemonic phrases, which are critical for accessing Bitcoin wallets, reflects a disciplined and security-conscious approach to cryptocurrency management. This habit ensures continued familiarity and readiness to access secured funds, further solidifying the personal investment in the security and integrity of one's digital assets.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T08:26:07.472000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
