<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
  <updated>2025-02-10T02:26:05.889502+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-02-09 16:20:45.895000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T02:26:05.889528+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/emulating-op-rand/1409/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email involves a detailed discussion on modifications to Algorithm 2, focusing on cryptographic procedures and key management in a transaction process. The proposed method starts with Alice providing an unsigned transaction template for TX1, where the output address is a taproot key denoted as $X$. She also provides a series of proofs and notations, notably $\pi_a$, which proves that $X$ equals either $(a_1 + x_a)T$ OR $(a_2 + x_a)T$, and it includes proving knowledge of the discrete logarithm (DL) of $T$.

This approach integrates the use of MuSig, a simpler model being MuSig1, for aggregating signatures from multiple participants into a single signature. The process elaborates on how both Alice and Bob, the transaction participants, share hashes of their nonces followed by their actual nonces. This leads to the calculation of $P_{agg}$, the aggregated public key. Bob then provides his partial signature on the TX1 message, while Alice gives an adaptor on her partial signature. This step includes the verification by Bob to ensure the adaptor reveals the secret $t$, affirming the correctness of Alice's behavior.

Further, the email outlines Bob's actions, which involve choosing a hash and constructing $\textrm{addr}_b$ with a structure that needs to be hidden from Alice but verified through a zero-knowledge proof (ZKP). This ZKP essentially proves that the address has the given structure without revealing specific details to Alice, other than the confirmation that the structure is correct. The ZKP is crucial for maintaining privacy and security while ensuring both parties are informed of the necessary details to proceed with the transaction.

The discussion also touches upon the potential application of "native" ZKPs for improved performance, suggesting the use of bulletproofs or generalized Schnorr proofs due to their efficiency in small circuits. This aspect highlights the ongoing exploration and innovation in cryptographic techniques to enhance security, privacy, and efficiency in transactions.

The modifications and methods described aim to refine the transaction process, making it more secure and efficient by leveraging advanced cryptographic proofs and signature aggregation models. The focus on ZKPs and adaptors underscores the importance of privacy and security in digital transactions, offering insights into the complexity and sophistication of modern cryptographic solutions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-09T16:20:45.895000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
