<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
  <updated>2025-02-11T02:25:12.548178+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-02-10 20:10:35.564000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T02:25:12.548210+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multisigbackup-com-backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds/1430/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of a novel tool aimed at enhancing the process of making inscriptions on the Bitcoin blockchain has been detailed, focusing on efficiency and sustainability. This tool is designed with a unique approach to manage transactions, specifically by not generating new Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). Instead, it cleverly generates an address that can be used to reveal inscriptions once funds are spent from it. This method not only simplifies the inscription process but also opens it up for anyone to use, as the generated address does not restrict spending.

To facilitate real-time tracking of transactions to this address, the tool integrates with the [mempool.space](https://mempool.space) webhook. This allows for the immediate creation of a transaction containing a single `OP_RETURN` output upon the receipt of funds. To ensure the transaction adheres to standard size requirements, four dummy bytes are added. One of the significant benefits of this approach is the direct forwarding of the entire payment amount to the miner as a transaction fee, thereby negating the creation of new UTXOs. This method is instrumental in reducing the costs associated with making inscriptions and plays a crucial role in preventing UTXO bloat within the Bitcoin network.

For those interested in exploring this tool further or understanding its technical workings in detail, the creator has provided a comprehensive guide and code repository available at [https://github.com/joshdoman/btc-scribe](https://github.com/joshdoman/btc-scribe). This resource offers an in-depth look at the tool's functionality and its application in the broader context of blockchain technology and digital currency transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T20:10:35.564000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
