<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
  <updated>2025-02-11T02:24:06.091052+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-10T16:12:31.477000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Emulating OP_RAND</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T02:24:06.091085+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/emulating-op-rand/1409/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the technical and economic considerations in using randomized Hashed Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs) within blockchain technology, particularly focusing on Bitcoin's Lightning Network. The primary concern revolves around the potential high costs in terms of CPU usage and bandwidth required to rerun the protocol for every randomized-HTLC whenever a commitment transaction is updated. This could lead to significant resource consumption as each channel might operate similarly to running over Tor, indicating an increase in latency and resource usage.

Furthermore, there's a perspective that such protocols could become a "hot path" issue, necessitating their execution before any payment forwarding can occur. This suggests an operational bottleneck that could impede the efficiency of payment channels, especially in scenarios involving frequent updates.

Contrary to initial assumptions, the conversation also explores the viability of probabilistic HTLCs for transactions larger than minimal or "dusty" outputs. Through a hypothetical scenario featuring Alice and Bob as channel partners within a channel factory, it questions the practicality of applying traditional on-chain solutions for relaying a $100 HTLC when faced with $1,000 in transaction fees. This exemplifies the disproportionate cost of on-chain transaction fees relative to the value being transacted, especially at high Bitcoin price points.

The dialogue then shifts towards the potential efficiencies of leveraging Merkle trees for reducing witness data size in a channel factory with a vast number of participants, thereby significantly lowering the associated transaction fees. This approach underscores the importance of technological advancements such as improving fan-out technology to mitigate the financial and computational overheads of executing large numbers of microtransactions on the blockchain.

Finally, the conversation includes a recommendation to focus on enhancing fan-out technology, as detailed in an external resource ([improving the fan out technology](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/flexible-coin-earmarks/1275)). This suggests a strategic pivot towards refining existing technologies to support scalable and cost-effective implementation of HTLCs, rather than solely relying on probabilistic approaches for managing small-value transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T16:12:31.477000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
