<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-02-11T02:20:54.558892+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-10 18:01:14.393000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T02:20:54.558926+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In discussing the implications of Layer 2 (L2) solutions on Bitcoin's network security, a significant concern arises regarding the potential vulnerability of Level 1 (L1) Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). The core of this issue lies in the ability of L1 UTXOs to maintain their value in hypothetical future scenarios where they might be susceptible to theft. This vulnerability raises questions about the overall security and value retention of the currency, irrespective of the introduction of technologies designed to represent tokens pegged to Bitcoin.

The addition of L2 solutions is critiqued for possibly diluting the robustness of Bitcoin's security framework. By introducing another layer—on top of the existing L1 protocol stack—the complexity and potential attack vectors within the system increase. This complexity does not necessarily translate into enhanced security; rather, it introduces additional risks. The existence of two distinct protocol stacks, both of which could be compromised, amplifies the threat landscape, potentially endangering the security of the entire system.

Moreover, the discussion highlights the ongoing challenges in cryptographic security, particularly in the realm of post-quantum cryptography. Despite advancements, cryptographic algorithms remain susceptible to being broken, a reality underscored by recent incidents where post-quantum cryptography candidates were cracked. This vulnerability, demonstrated through a specific [instance](https://cacm.acm.org/news/nist-post-quantum-cryptography-candidate-cracked/), emphasizes the precarious nature of relying on such algorithms for securing blockchain networks. It suggests that even with the adoption of ostensibly more secure, future-proof cryptographic methods, the fundamental issues of security and vulnerability persist, warranting careful consideration and continuous scrutiny.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T18:01:14.393000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
