<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
  <updated>2025-02-13T02:19:53.380007+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager.878000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-12T09:27:45.878000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T02:19:53.380039+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/highly-available-lightning-channels-revisited-route-or-out/1438/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse highlights the current nuances and challenges within the realm of pathfinding in network systems. It acknowledges that while pathfinding may not present a significant hurdle for many, it remains a considerable challenge for specific groups. The practice of probing or downloading probe data as a means to navigate these challenges is discussed, with a preference expressed for minimizing such practices if feasible.

There's a critical examination of the behavior of senders within the system, suggesting that some may opt for simpler, albeit less ideal, strategies such as downloading lists of high-quality nodes to prioritize their connections. This approach, however, is critiqued for potentially exacerbating accessibility issues for nodes not already on these lists, making it harder for them to achieve visibility or recognition through merit-based mechanisms like earning an "HA" (High Availability) badge.

Furthermore, the idea of nodes appending an "(HA)" tag to their alias is deliberated upon. The discussion suggests that while there might be concerns about the social implications of this practice, it is important to confront and understand these potential impacts sooner rather than later. This proactive approach aims at addressing any societal consequences that could arise from the differentiation created by the HA badge, emphasizing the need for timely investigation into the matter.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-12T09:27:45.878000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
