<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
  <updated>2025-02-13T02:20:50.255361+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-02-12 14:55:49.628000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T02:20:50.255392+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/anecdotal-kode-code-for-humans/1441" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest innovation in block hash shortening presents a practical application for naming time-sensitive entries, introducing two distinct codes: the "shortened kode" (sk) and the "anecdotal kode" (ak). These codes are designed to offer an efficient way of managing block hashes, with a live demonstration available at [anyone.eu.org/niceblack.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/niceblack.txt). Although moving forward, only the anecdotal kode will be provided through this platform. The methodology behind these codes, including their creation process, is thoroughly explained at [anyone.eu.org/skm.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/skm.txt), showcasing an example that incorporates both the shortened and anecdotal kodes.

The conceptual foundation of the anecdotal kode lies in the XOR operation applied to certain double octets, which generates the final `ak` value. This approach was inspired by an initial idea explored years ago, documented within the context of Bitcoin at [anyone.eu.org/bitcoin.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/bitcoin.txt), where it is referred to as "shortform."

For practical application examples, the document references an older implementation using the `sk` code, with details and live examples accessible via [http://anyone.eu.org/ws](http://anyone.eu.org/ws) and [https://anyone.eu.org/ws/883417-c1a4a4.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/ws/883417-c1a4a4.txt). In contrast, the newer `ak` code usage is exemplified through links [https://anyone.eu.org/as/](https://anyone.eu.org/as/) and [https://anyone.eu.org/as/883438-53c655.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/as/883438-53c655.txt), illustrating its adoption for current applications.

The initiative seeks feedback on this novel method, noting that there have been no complaints so far, except for the mention that the number `16777215` (`0xFFFFFF`) might be considered too small for some applications. This feedback request underscores the developer's openness to improvement and engagement with the user community to refine the technique further.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-12T14:55:49.628000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
