<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
  <updated>2025-02-13T02:19:41.899820+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2025-02-12 15:17:46.597000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T02:19:41.899858+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/highly-available-lightning-channels-revisited-route-or-out/1438/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the current state and considerations of pathfinding within a network, highlighting the perspective that pathfinding is not seen as a significant obstacle for many, though it acknowledges that certain groups might find it challenging. The preference expressed is towards bearing the social costs associated with heuristic-based (HA) pathfinding until such time that these challenges become more pronounced. This stance is rooted in the desire to minimize reliance on probing or the downloading of probe data due to its less than ideal nature, despite acknowledging that these methods are not as problematic as once thought. Particularly, the act of probing by individuals does not contribute significantly to network traffic, a situation improved by the decrease in stuck Hashed Timelock Contracts (HTLCs).

Furthermore, the acquisition of probe data is considered relatively harmless, especially when such data is sourced from a Lightning Service Provider (LSP), which would have visibility over one's payments regardless. The primary concern lies with the impact on privacy for those operating full lightning nodes independently of an LSP and without engaging in frequent payments or probing activities. These individuals may experience diminished privacy, though the number of such nodes is reportedly declining. This shift is viewed positively in terms of overall payment success across the network.

In essence, while there are reservations about the current mechanisms employed for pathfinding, particularly regarding their implications for user privacy and network efficiency, the prevailing opinion is that these issues are manageable. The focus remains on navigating these challenges with an eye towards future adjustments as the landscape evolves, suggesting a pragmatic approach to dealing with the complexities inherent in maintaining a robust and efficient network.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-12T15:17:46.597000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
