<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
  <updated>2025-02-14T02:19:29.158122+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xfffffffa</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-13T08:39:33.912000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposing a P2QRH BIP towards a quantum resistant soft fork</title>
    <updated>2025-02-14T02:19:29.158153+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposing-a-p2qrh-bip-towards-a-quantum-resistant-soft-fork/956/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around an innovative solution designed to ensure the security and longevity of Bitcoin in the face of potential quantum computing threats. This solution, initially functioning as a Layer 2 (L2) system, operates parallel to the existing Bitcoin blockchain. Its design is reminiscent of the Lightning Network, providing additional capabilities while working alongside the main Bitcoin network. The primary purpose of this L2 system is to act as a safeguard, preparing for a scenario where quantum computers become powerful enough to compromise Bitcoin’s security. Should such a technological advancement occur, making Bitcoin vulnerable to attacks such as block rearrangement, this L2 system is poised to transition into a new Layer 1 (L1) blockchain. This shift would only happen if the integrity of the original Bitcoin blockchain is irrevocably compromised, indicating that it can no longer be trusted due to the potential of quantum attacks.

The envisioned transformation of this backup system into the new foundational layer of Bitcoin signifies its readiness to take over all essential functions, including consensus and transaction validation, on its own independent blockchain. The concept emphasizes the system's role as a reliable backup - continuously operational and ready to replace the original blockchain if necessary. This ensures that Bitcoin users have a secure alternative to migrate to, which they can already interact with on testnets and, following its official launch, on the mainnet by "quantum wrapping" their BTC.

Furthermore, the system incorporates FIPS240 ML-DSA for its cryptographic operations, a protocol that has received approval from the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). This choice underlines the commitment to adhering to recognized security standards and benefiting from NIST's rigorous verification processes to safeguard against quantum vulnerabilities. The adoption of such advanced cryptographic measures reflects a proactive approach to maintaining Bitcoin's security in an era approaching quantum computing capabilities.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-13T08:39:33.912000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
