<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-02-14T02:17:57.943710+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa.852000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-13T13:27:24.852000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-02-14T02:17:57.943747+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/48" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the significant progress and shifts in focus regarding algorithms intended for use in Bitcoin Core, highlighting the development and integration of various algorithmic solutions aimed at optimizing different aspects of Bitcoin's underlying technology. The initial point of interest is an older exponential algorithm, which has been successfully merged into Bitcoin Core's master branch. This merger is not just limited to the algorithm itself but extends to a range of related enhancements including postlinearizing, merging, LIMO, and ancestor sorting among others. The current emphasis of work is on creating a more sophisticated abstraction layer above this merged code to better manage clusters. This involves its integration within the mempool and validation code, a task that is described as consuming the majority of the developer's time, underscored by a [tracking issue](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/30289) dedicated to monitoring progress.

In addition, there is mention of a simplex-derived spanning forest algorithm, another novel approach that was also developed and shared by the same individual. Although now shifted away from active development, this algorithm represents an important step towards improving the system’s efficiency and is available for review [here](https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/spanning_tree_linearization). The reason for moving away from this algorithm lies in the promising discussions surrounding min-cut based linearization approaches, which are considered to offer a better balance of implementation complexity and performance.

Lastly, the exploration of min-cut based linearization techniques is highlighted as the next significant phase of research and development. The focus here is on experimenting with a from-scratch implementation of the GGT algorithm, utilizing either FIFO or max-label strategies. This direction is chosen due to its potential in achieving an optimal mix of ease of implementation and efficient worst-case performance. While still in the preliminary stages without any concrete code developed, there is an optimistic outlook that this line of work will culminate in a superior cluster linearization algorithm. This new algorithm is expected to serve as a direct replacement for the currently merged code, albeit its realization is anticipated to be a more long-term project than making the existing code fully operational.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-13T13:27:24.852000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
