<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 28.1</title>
  <updated>2025-02-15T02:18:06.981526+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-02-14 07:38:36.290000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 28.1</title>
    <updated>2025-02-15T02:18:06.981559+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-inquisition-28-1/1445" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Bitcoin Inquisition 28.1, a new release integrating features from [Bitcoin Core 28.1](https://bitcoincore.org/en/releases/28.1/), is now available for download at [this GitHub link](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/releases/tag/v28.1-inq). This version not only continues to support TRUC, anchor relay, and full replace by fee behavior as established in Bitcoin Core 28.0 but also introduces backported support for ephemeral dust. This specific feature facilitates the relay of transactions with low or zero-valued outputs that are immediately spent, exemplified by pre-signed transactions where fees are covered by a subsequently signed child transaction. Notable examples of these transactions include [7c1b4d](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/7c1b4d9c5c7bb411bc9c8742c7dda1d06c68655ef47585c8b58a8a314fcdd6efvout=1) and [5107bb](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/5107bb639ce389234e1da21a0a60d7c05ca1cf0d9a904e98c83ee0e50a597c8dvin=0).

The release also encompasses support for several proposed consensus changes which have been activated on the default signet. These include [BIP 119](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/584f4a732ba94199fc097fbb9b4660db868dd712/bip-0119.mediawiki) OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY, [BIP 118](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/584f4a732ba94199fc097fbb9b4660db868dd712/bip-0118.mediawiki) SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT, and [BIN-2024-1](https://github.com/ajtowns/binana/blob/8264328e6c7fd9e9f30efb8273fb94700f001454/2024/BIN-2024-0001.md) also known as [BIP 347](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/740e826c19391a7a290933f514c15518e00780f0/bip-0347.mediawiki) OP_CAT. These features have been active since specific blocks on the signet, enhancing the flexibility and capabilities of Bitcoin transactions. However, it's important to note that transactions utilizing these new features will not be relayed by nodes lacking support for them. To ensure transactions reach a miner, peering with other inquisition nodes is necessary, achievable by specifying `addnode=inquisition.bitcoin-signet.net`.

For users interested in verifying the presence and advertisement of these nodes, the command `bitcoin-cli -netinfo 3` provides the necessary information through the subversion string. Further details about these implementations can be found in the [23.0 announcement](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2022-December/021275.html). This release signifies a significant step towards enhancing the operational framework and consensus mechanisms within the Bitcoin network, demonstrating the continuous efforts to improve and evolve the cryptocurrency's underlying technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-14T07:38:36.290000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
