<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
  <updated>2025-02-19T02:20:02.292842+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-02-18 14:54:25.455000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
    <updated>2025-02-19T02:20:02.292870+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets/1453/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Lightning Network transactions, particularly those involving Hash Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs), the dynamics of fee payments have nuanced implications for both channel openers and HTLC transaction owners. Traditionally, it might be assumed that the channel opener bears the financial brunt of transaction fees. However, the structure is more favorably designed such that the owner of the HTLC transaction, often a mobile wallet user, is responsible for the fees. This arrangement does not impose additional costs on the peer, making it an efficient mechanism to facilitate transactions.

The deduction of fees from the output of the HTLC transaction underscores a critical aspect of maintaining balance in the Lightning Network ecosystem. It ensures that while facilitating seamless transactions, the integrity and financial equity of the network are preserved. Nonetheless, this system opens a potential vulnerability to exploitation by malicious actors. An attack vector is identified wherein a mobile wallet receives a batch of HTLCs with pre-signed transactions that allocate a disproportionate amount of the HTLC value towards fees. The wallet fulfills these HTLCs and later publishes a revoked commitment containing all HTLCs. Since the majority of the value is allocated to mining fees, the peer cannot claim these as penalty transactions. This scenario illustrates a sophisticated method by which individuals could undermine the network's financial stability.

To combat such vulnerabilities, the implementation of zero fees for HTLC transactions through anchor outputs has been proposed and adopted. This measure effectively shields against potential miner attacks targeting lightning peers, ensuring that the network remains robust against external threats. Furthermore, Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) play a pivotal role in mitigating risks associated with high feerate overshoots. By carefully managing feerates and scrutinizing transactions for patterns indicative of risky behavior, LSPs can refuse to relay HTLCs that pose a significant risk. Although this requires a detailed understanding and vigilant monitoring of transaction behaviors, confidence remains high that effective strategies can be developed. These measures collectively aim to safeguard honest users and the network at large, ensuring that the ecosystem remains secure, efficient, and resilient against malicious exploits.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-18T14:54:25.455000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
