<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
  <updated>2025-02-22T02:15:18.187926+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik.372000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-21T13:25:12.372000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>How to linearize your cluster</title>
    <updated>2025-02-22T02:15:18.187955+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303/49" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an effort to assist with testing, a programmer has shared details regarding the data from their version 28.1 node's memory pool (mempool). This data is crucial for those looking to populate the mainnet mempool of a Bitcoin Core node that has been freshly started and is currently empty. To facilitate this, several files have been made available for download. These include transaction identifiers (txid's) in a text file, a binary file generated using the `savemempool` command, and a log file. The respective files can be accessed through provided links: txid's are available at [https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool.txt), the binary file can be found at [https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool.dat](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool.dat), and the log file is located at [https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/mymempool-log.txt).

The programmer suggests downloading these files to a `tmpfs`-mounted directory, such as `/dev/shm`, to ensure optimal performance. Once downloaded, the `importmempool` RPC command can be used to import the mempool data into the node. This process is designed to be efficient and is updated every five minutes, providing a window twice this duration to complete the download. This approach ensures that users can quickly and effectively fill the mempool of their Bitcoin Core node with current transaction data, enabling accurate testing environments or simulations based on real-world mempool conditions.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T13:25:12.372000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
