<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-22T02:20:04.207111+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-02-21 16:47:25.808000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-22T02:20:04.207143+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>AntoineP has penned three insightful blog posts focusing on various aspects of Bitcoin Core's development and direction. In the first post, found at [antoinep.com/posts/core_project_direction/](https://antoinep.com/posts/core_project_direction/), AntoineP highlights a growing concern within the Bitcoin Core project. The decentralized nature of the project leads to fragmented efforts, with contributors working in isolation without a unified vision for the project's future. This situation results in an accumulation of code, features, and RPCs without proportionate review capabilities, posing a threat to the software's quality due to the dilution of focus.

In the second post titled "Stating the Obvious," available at [antoinep.com/posts/stating_the_obvious/](https://antoinep.com/posts/stating_the_obvious/), the discussion shifts towards the prioritization of development within Bitcoin Core. Given that the user base of Bitcoin Core indirectly includes all Bitcoin users, the post argues for a development focus that ensures the software acts as a stable foundation for the Bitcoin network. The balance between securing the software and adding new features is emphasized as critical for the strengthening and improvement of the Bitcoin network.

The third post elaborates on a potential structural evolution for Bitcoin Core, suggested through the multiprocess project initiative. This post, accessible at [antoinep.com/posts/bitcoin_core_scope/](https://antoinep.com/posts/bitcoin_core_scope/), proposes the division of the current project into three separate binaries: `bitcoin-node`, `bitcoin-wallet`, and `bitcoin-gui`. Each binary would be developed by different sets of contributors, focusing on specific functionalities while communicating through well-defined interfaces. This separation aims to streamline the development process, allowing for more focused contributions across the three main aspects of the Bitcoin Core software. Such a reorganization could enhance efficiency and clarity in the project's development, ensuring each component receives the attention it requires from a dedicated team. Through this restructuring, the project could potentially address the issues of dispersed focus and insufficient review resources highlighted in the earlier posts.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T16:47:25.808000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
