<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-22T02:19:50.163970+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP.840000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-21T18:10:50.840000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-22T02:19:50.164003+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the complexities of managing shared code and configuration in a project setup that involves integrating a wallet as a subtree to a node, and similarly, integrating a GUI with the wallet. It highlights the challenge of deciding how to handle common code sections. Specifically, it points out that while some parts of the code, such as `src/crypto`, could be relatively easily split between the projects, other areas like `src/util` and `src/common` present a more significant challenge. These might either need to be duplicated across projects or require the establishment of another interface to facilitate their integration.

Furthermore, the message touches upon the concerns related to copying configurations, particularly for Continuous Integration (CI) processes, but suggests that these are less worrisome compared to the broader issue of organizing the build system. This latter point is identified as a critical area needing attention, indicating the sender's uncertainty about how best to approach the structuring of the build environment to support this integrated project setup. A call for input is made to @fanquake, seeking expertise or advice on organizing the build system effectively, underscoring the importance of collaborative problem-solving in addressing complex technical challenges within the project.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T18:10:50.840000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
