<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-22T02:19:27.660462+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2025-02-22 00:14:24.712000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-22T02:19:27.660495+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initiates with the recognition of Bitcoin Core's extensive user base, implicitly encompassing all Bitcoin users, and this broad audience significantly influences the prioritization of development efforts within the Bitcoin Core ecosystem. The excerpt, sourced from a detailed post ([read more here](https://antoinep.com/posts/stating_the_obvious/)), sets the stage for a deeper exploration into who constitutes the average user of Bitcoin Core. This inquiry is not trivial, as understanding the user is critical to tailoring development processes, features, and support to meet their needs effectively.

The conversation continues by questioning the average Bitcoin Core user's profile, aiming to demystify the characteristics and technical acumen required to operate `bitcoind`, the core daemon powering the Bitcoin network. This exploration delves into the operating systems preferred by these users, pondering whether they lean more towards Windows ("Windaube") or various Unix-like systems (*NIX), which could influence the design and accessibility of Bitcoin Core software.

Moreover, the narrative probes the motivations driving individuals to run `bitcoind`. It contrasts users who engage with the software out of a cypherpunk ethos—valuing verification of transactions and blockchains for ideological reasons—with those who might be more fascinated by its technical intricacies or simply the utility it provides without deeper engagement in its philosophical underpinnings. This segment also touches on the user interface preferences, distinguishing between users who favor a browser-like experience and those who are comfortable, if not preferential, towards command-line interfaces (CLIs).

Lastly, the discussion shifts to examining the level of engagement and interaction users have with Bitcoin and `bitcoind`, from participation in local community events discussing consensus changes and developments to considerations of Bitcoin's value relative to traditional fiat currencies. It questions how frequently users access their `bitcoin-wallet`, suggesting variability in engagement—from daily use to more sporadic interactions. This portion aims to highlight the diversity within the Bitcoin Core user base regarding their engagement levels, interests, and how these factors might inform the ongoing development and support strategies of Bitcoin Core.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-22T00:14:24.712000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
