<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-24T02:22:43.513011+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-02-23 08:37:34.438000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-24T02:22:43.513050+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The narrative shared revolves around an individual deeply engrossed in the intricacies of Bitcoin Core, demonstrating a profound commitment to understanding and experimenting within this domain. This person regularly revisits Satoshi's whitepaper to stay aligned with the foundational principles of Bitcoin while actively running Bitcoin Core nodes. Their engagement is not limited to theoretical knowledge; they apply their insights practically by creating scripts that interact with Bitcoin Core releases without necessitating alterations to the core code itself. This approach has led to the development of projects such as the one showcased on [alt.signetfaucet.com](https://alt.signetfaucet.com), which embodies the culmination of ideas since 2017, marking the transition from a Linux-only nocoiner.

Despite not frequently attending meetups, the individual values insights from friends who do, highlighting a preference for indirect engagement with the broader community. The curiosity about the technical functionalities and limitations of Bitcoin Core is evident in the experimental approach taken to answer complex questions. For instance, there was an experiment to determine whether a hand-crafted transaction, prioritized in the mempools of personal nodes, would get mined despite not offering additional fees to outbid a competing transaction in the memory pool. The successful mining of this transaction on the mainnet, as seen on [mempool.space](https://mempool.space/tx/ad1507f186ccdd448cc58a5ed68367249de6ad55d7f4b70bb3fcc5c88a85c626?mode=details), provided empirical evidence in favor of the query. Further exploration into the Replace-by-Fee (RBF) protocol on signet demonstrated its capability to work multiple times, adding another layer of understanding to Bitcoin's transaction dynamics, verified through [mempool.space/signet](https://mempool.space/signet/tx/6283defdc43b1fead93c851a8d11d7d79d796d8d1596216bae7b213e9f49f5aa?mode=details).

This detailed exploration underscores a dedicated and methodical approach to dissecting and enhancing the functionalities associated with Bitcoin Core, driven by a blend of theoretical revisitation and practical experimentation. Through this journey, the individual contributes to the broader discourse around Bitcoin's operational capabilities, while also expanding their personal toolkit of scripts and solutions tailored around the existing framework of Bitcoin Core releases.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T08:37:34.438000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
