<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-26T02:22:29.495136+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>bruno</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-25T13:20:23.639000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T02:22:29.495169+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The rapid evolution of BDK (Bitcoin Development Kit) compared to Bitcoin Core can be attributed to several factors that influence both developer engagement and project management. One significant aspect is the programming language used; Rust appears to attract more interest from developers, especially newcomers, than the older C++ language used by Bitcoin Core. This preference for Rust over C++ is not only because Rust offers modern language features and safety guarantees but also due to a larger trend where new programmers are more inclined to contribute to projects using languages they perceive as more current or innovative.

Furthermore, the organizational structure and community engagement strategies employed by BDK play a crucial role in its fast-paced development. The project's use of communication platforms such as Discord for discussions and meetings fosters a more inclusive and collaborative environment. Such approaches enhance project management and coordination among contributors, making it easier for new ideas and improvements to be integrated swiftly.

In summary, the accelerated development of BDK compared to Bitcoin Core is a multifaceted phenomenon. It encompasses both the technological allure of the Rust programming language and the effective project management and community-building practices. These elements together create a conducive ecosystem for rapid innovation and development, attracting a wide range of contributors keen on advancing the project.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-25T13:20:23.639000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
