<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-02-26T02:22:15.906452+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-25T14:40:45.694000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T02:22:15.906486+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The rapid evolution of BDK compared to Bitcoin Core can be attributed to several factors, each contributing to its dynamic progress. One significant aspect is the programming language used by BDK, which presumably offers advantages in development speed and flexibility. While the impact of project organization tools like Discord and meetings remains uncertain, these could potentially facilitate better communication and collaboration among contributors.

Another noteworthy point is the appeal of starting a new project or rewriting existing components from scratch. This approach contrasts with the daunting task of navigating and modifying legacy code, which is prevalent in projects like Bitcoin Core. The excitement and novelty associated with developing something new can significantly boost motivation and engagement among developers.

A clear vision and well-defined objectives are crucial for maintaining focus and ensuring concerted efforts towards common goals. This clarity not only aids in solving coordination challenges but also enhances the project's ability to make tangible progress. It parallels the concept of working groups in Bitcoin Core, where the feasibility and potential inclusion of contributions are considered upfront, thereby making the development process more rewarding.

Furthermore, the criteria for incorporating changes into BDK are generally perceived to be less stringent than those for Bitcoin Core's wallet. This lower barrier to entry, coupled with a fun and goal-oriented development environment, naturally attracts and retains more contributors. Proposals such as segregating the wallet into a separate repository and temporarily easing review standards could further streamline progress by aligning with the current reality of contributor availability. By allowing developers to concentrate solely on the wallet, and possibly leveraging additional factors highlighted in the provided [link](https://lclhost.org), there exists an opportunity to foster a more focused and efficient advancement towards the project's aspirations.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-25T14:40:45.694000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
