<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>AssumeUTXO and Bitcoin snapshots</title>
  <updated>2025-02-27T02:26:11.567946+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jaonoctus 2025-02-26 22:52:11.492000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>AssumeUTXO and Bitcoin snapshots</title>
    <updated>2025-02-27T02:26:11.567979+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/assumeutxo-and-bitcoin-snapshots/1482" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The availability of AssumeUTXO files and Bitcoin blockchain snapshots is now provided via a dedicated website, taking inspiration from the "prunednode.today" project initiated by stepansnigirev/Specter. This initiative aims to facilitate access to these resources for those interested in Bitcoin's technical intricacies or requiring this data for development and research purposes. The website hosting these files can be found at [https://bitcoin-snapshots.jaonoctus.dev](https://bitcoin-snapshots.jaonoctus.dev), serving as a valuable tool for the Bitcoin community.

For users seeking to verify the authenticity and accuracy of the data provided, the website includes detailed technical information. This encompasses results from the `gettxoutsetinfo` command and specific AssumeUTXO parameters which are essential for understanding the state of the Bitcoin blockchain without downloading the entire chain. These details are critical for developers and researchers working with Bitcoin, providing a foundation for trust and reliability in the snapshots offered. The relevant technical parameters and further elaboration on the AssumeUTXO feature can be accessed through the link to the Bitcoin GitHub repository, available at [https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/32efe850438ef22e2de39e562af557872a402c31/src/kernel/chainparams.cppL497-L504](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/32efe850438ef22e2de39e562af557872a402c31/src/kernel/chainparams.cppL497-L504).

This effort underscores the importance of community-driven projects in supporting the infrastructure of cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin. By providing vital resources such as these snapshots, the initiative not only aids in the practical aspects of Bitcoin operations but also contributes to the broader goal of decentralization and accessibility within the ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-26T22:52:11.492000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
