<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2025-02-28T02:23:03.497954+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-27T17:32:51.613000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T02:23:03.497985+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/76" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an effort to analyze Bitcoin's Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs), certain filters were applied to exclude specific types of UTXOs from consideration. Notably, UTXOs with a zero value were omitted from the analysis, as were any UTXOs that involve a check signature operation, as outlined in BIP66. Additionally, UTXOs associated with syntactically invalid scripts—particularly those containing OP_IF operations without the corresponding OP_ENDIF—were also excluded. This approach was aimed at refining the dataset to ensure the reliability and relevance of the analysis.

The source code utilized for this examination is hosted on GitHub, providing transparency and access to the methodologies used in the analysis. The exact location of the source code can be found at [GitHub](https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin-s-core/blob/dfcd59eddc7ac2d5c622136fa100e6a448d20021/app/scripts/src/main/scala/org/bitcoins/scripts/ScanBitcoind.scalaL225). This level of accessibility allows for independent verification and potential replication of the findings, fostering an environment of open collaboration and scrutiny within the community.

Furthermore, the analysis has not yet been tested against various interpreter flags such as `CLEANSTACK`, `PUSHONLY`, `MINIMALDATA`, etc., which could potentially influence the interpretation of the results. Acknowledging this limitation opens up avenues for further investigation, suggesting that the current findings may be subject to change upon the application of these additional parameters. The request for a link to further discussions highlights an ongoing engagement with the broader community, seeking to deepen the understanding of the implications of these findings and perhaps refine the methodology based on collective insights.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-27T17:32:51.613000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
