<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-03-01T02:26:41.727760+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-02-28T16:06:05.748000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-03-01T02:26:41.727791+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse highlights the flexibility and advancements in Bitcoin Core usage and development, emphasizing the non-necessity for a direct connection between the user's wallet and node. It outlines the concept behind `multiprocess`, which allows for the separation of the node and wallet into different memory spaces, enhancing security and efficiency by potentially allowing them to be hosted on separate entities. This approach is lauded for its contribution towards a more decentralized and robust Bitcoin network.

Furthermore, the conversation addresses the potential for Bitcoin Core to accommodate alternative clients without necessitating a hard or soft fork. This possibility is significantly facilitated by the development of `[libbitcoinkernel](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/24303)`, a standalone library that encapsulates all bitcoin consensus rules. The library lowers the barriers significantly for developers who wish to build upon or modify the Bitcoin protocol, provided they adhere to these consensus rules. The ease with which one can now contribute to or extend the Bitcoin ecosystem underscores a pivotal shift towards greater openness and collaboration within the community.

The importance of community vigilance and responsibility is also underscored, particularly in the context of identifying and reporting any consensus bugs or DDoS vulnerabilities discovered while working with `libbitcoinkernel`. This call to action reinforces the collective duty of participants to safeguard the network's integrity and ensure its ongoing resilience against threats.

Overall, the communication elucidates a vision of a more accessible, secure, and decentralized future for Bitcoin, inviting broader participation and innovation within its ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-28T16:06:05.748000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
