<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
  <updated>2025-02-21T02:21:50.089724+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-02-20 08:43:54.342000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2025-02-19 18:28:29.521000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-19 16:18:32.286000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse  . 2025-02-19 16:11:27.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-02-19 15:14:08.326000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-19 14:46:22.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-02-19 14:21:01.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-19 09:44:53.454000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-18 14:54:25.455000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-02-18 14:31:14.930000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-18 13:06:24.718000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4337_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4333_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4332_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4331_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4330_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4329_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4328_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4325_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4319_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4317_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4316_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T02:21:50.089809+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets/1453" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights a nuanced approach to improving the management of HTLC (Hashed Time-Locked Contracts) transactions within the Lightning Network, specifically targeting the optimization of fee rates. A key proposal involves allowing peers to sign two versions of HTLC transactions: a standard version without a transaction fee and another with a high feerate enclosed in a custom TLV within `commitment_signed`, tailored to current network conditions. This dual-signing strategy aims to enhance transaction efficiency by ensuring fees are sufficient for prompt processing while considering the economic implications for mobile wallet users and their peers. The inclusion of a high feerate is financially borne by the channel opener, usually a mobile wallet user, encouraging its use only when necessary, such as for security reasons or to recover liquidity from inactive channels. This method cleverly integrates economic incentives with technical solutions to address both efficiency and safety concerns in transaction handling.

Further technical discussions delve into the integrity and security of blockchain transactions, emphasizing the importance of employing `SIGHASH_ALL` for pre-signed transactions to ensure their reliability. This approach is contrasted with the existing practice of using `SIGHASH_SINGLE | SIGHASH_ANYONECANPAY`, which, although offering flexibility for adjusting transaction fees, potentially allows users to claim excess mining fees. The proposed shift towards `SIGHASH_ALL` seeks to mitigate the risk of exploiting transaction structures for undue gain, highlighting ongoing efforts to refine blockchain transactional security and trustworthiness.

Moreover, the dialogue addresses a notable vulnerability within the Lightning Network related to the exploitation of pre-signed HTLC transactions by malicious actors. It outlines strategies that could be employed by a malicious wallet to shift on-chain fee burdens to peers, undermining the network's financial stability. Despite this vulnerability, several mitigating factors are identified, suggesting that the overall risk is manageable. The conversation underscores the delicate balance between operational efficiency, security, and economic dynamics within digital currency transactions and the continuous search for optimal solutions.

In addition, the proposal to incorporate zero-fee commitments into lightning channels represents a significant advancement towards enhancing mobile wallet functionality and security. This initiative aims to simplify the handling of revoked commitments and improve the resilience of mobile wallets against specific adversarial conditions. By enabling peers to sign two versions of HTLC transactions, one with no fee for standard operations and another with a higher feerate for unilateral close situations, mobile wallets are better equipped to manage uncooperative peers. This development not only simplifies operational requirements but also potentially increases the adoption and utility of mobile wallets for cryptocurrency transactions.

Collectively, these discussions reflect the complex interplay between technical innovation, operational efficiency, security considerations, and economic incentives in the evolution of blockchain technology and digital currencies. The ongoing efforts to refine and enhance the Lightning Network through such proposals underscore the community's commitment to addressing challenges and improving the ecosystem for all participants.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-20T08:43:54.342000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
