<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
  <updated>2025-02-11T02:26:21.258359+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cguida 2025-02-10 19:04:45.378000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager 2025-02-10 17:01:20.154000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4273_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4269_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T02:26:21.258422+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/highly-available-lightning-channels-revisited-route-or-out/1438" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue within the Lightning Network (LN) community highlights a pivotal concern regarding the balance between privacy and the need for a fast, cheap, and reliable payment system. A suggestion has been made for allowing users to choose their preference—prioritizing either privacy or efficiency in transactions. This flexibility would mean that different routes on the network could be optimized for specific functions, catering to diverse user needs.

A notable proposal aims to enhance the LN by striving for a zero payment failure rate, a significant leap from the current reliance on complex probabilistic scoring models that are challenging to design and validate. The suggested approach involves excluding nodes from transaction paths for an extended duration after just one failure, adopting a “ROUTE OR OUT” strategy. This paradigm shift suggests that senders may favor connections that exhibit high availability signals, potentially accepting higher fees for these more reliable channels. Such a move towards high availability (HA) signaling is seen as a way to increase overall network reliability and efficiency.

However, there are concerns and counterpoints regarding this approach within the development community. The impact of HA signaling is still uncertain, and debate continues on whether it should be formalized through standardization rather than relying on ad hoc modifications by routing node operators. Interestingly, routing nodes have the capability to signal HA today, using existing mechanisms such as modifying the `htlc_maximum_msat` channel update parameter. For example, no current node sets this parameter to a value ending in 555, which could be utilized as a unique identifier for channels offering high availability for certain transaction amounts. This discussion underscores the community's ongoing efforts to refine and improve the LN's functionality and user experience. Further input and exploration into the concept of HA signaling and its implementation are encouraged, as highlighted in the shared [discussion](https://www.mail-archive.com/lightning-dev@lists.linuxfoundation.org/msg03094.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T19:04:45.378000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
