<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
  <updated>2025-02-13T02:20:27.252603+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4291_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4287_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4283_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4282_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4273_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4269_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T02:20:27.252663+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/highly-available-lightning-channels-revisited-route-or-out/1438" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse surrounding the Lightning Network (LN) delves into the intricacies of pathfinding, probing practices, and the concept of High Availability (HA) nodes, underscoring the network's pursuit of optimal reliability in payment success rates. It emerges that while pathfinding is not currently seen as a significant hindrance to payment success, it presents challenges for specific sender groups. The practice of probing or downloading probe data, although not ideal due to potential privacy concerns and its impact on network traffic, is considered preferable over the implications associated with HA signaling. This preference stems from a desire to minimize social costs and maintain privacy, especially for those running full lightning nodes independently of a Lightning Service Provider (LSP).

Further discussion reveals an acknowledgment of the efforts made to improve pathfinding through technological advancements, such as the development of new channel types and enhancements like trampoline routing. These improvements have led to a high rate of payment success on the first attempt, contingent on the payer's willingness to pay necessary fees. However, issues such as insufficient liquidity and the lack of regular probing by some nodes are identified as more prevalent causes of payment failures. Amidst these operational challenges, the proposal of labeling nodes with an "(HA)" suffix to indicate high availability sparks debate. Critics argue that this approach might discourage nodes from enhancing their own pathfinding solutions, potentially leading to a binary choice that could disadvantage average node operators and centralize control among large custodial operators.

In parallel, conversations among routing node operators explore strategies for managing HA nodes, including the dynamic management of liquidity and the use of aliases to signal HA status without necessitating code changes. These discussions also touch on the tactical handling of depleted channels and the strategic cessation of routing during periods of high chain fees to manage financial risks effectively. Additionally, the significance of inbound liquidity for HA node designation is highlighted, alongside the challenges of maintaining efficiency and reputation amidst performance issues, particularly with nodes operating over Tor.

A novel proposition within the LN discourse introduces the concept of allowing users to prioritize either transaction efficiency or privacy, suggesting the development of separate routing options to accommodate these preferences. This concept challenges the prevailing notion that efficiency and privacy are mutually exclusive, proposing a flexible infrastructure capable of adapting to user requirements.

Lastly, the "ROUTE OR OUT" approach proposes a shift away from probabilistic scoring models towards a system where nodes experiencing a single failure may be bypassed indefinitely, emphasizing the value of HA signaling for ensuring transaction success. This initiative raises discussions about the practicality and potential impacts of such a strategy on the network's dynamics, with some developers expressing concerns about its implementation. The debate extends to whether formalizing HA signaling methods would be beneficial, highlighting an ongoing dialogue aimed at enhancing the Lightning Network's infrastructure for more reliable and efficient payment processing. Further insights into these discussions can be found [here](https://www.mail-archive.com/lightning-dev@lists.linuxfoundation.org/msg03094.html), offering a comprehensive view of the varying perspectives and considerations within the developer community.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-12T15:17:46.597000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
