<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
  <updated>2025-05-13T02:50:46.139765+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4981_Anecdotal-kode-code-for-humans.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4288_Anecdotal-kode-code-for-humans.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Anecdotal kode (code) for humans</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T02:50:46.139804+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/anecdotal-kode-code-for-humans/1441" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The innovative approach to block hash shortening is demonstrated through the introduction of two key concepts: the "shortened kode" (sk) and the "anecdotal kode" (ak). These concepts are critical for efficiently managing block hashes, with a focus on the anecdotal kode moving forward. The methodology behind generating these kodes involves an XOR operation on specific double octets to produce the final `ak` value. This technique is rooted in an idea initially explored within the Bitcoin context, described as "shortform." For individuals interested in the practical application and creation process of these codes, detailed explanations and examples are available online. Resources include a live demonstration at [anyone.eu.org/niceblack.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/niceblack.txt) and a comprehensive explanation at [anyone.eu.org/skm.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/skm.txt), which illustrates the usage of both shortened and anecdotal kodes.

Further exploration into the application of these concepts can be found through various documented examples. Previous implementations utilizing the `sk` code are detailed at [http://anyone.eu.org/ws](http://anyone.eu.org/ws) and [https://anyone.eu.org/ws/883417-c1a4a4.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/ws/883417-c1a4a4.txt). In contrast, current applications employing the newer `ak` code are showcased at [https://anyone.eu.org/as/](https://anyone.eu.org/as/) and [https://anyone.eu.org/as/883438-53c655.txt](https://anyone.eu.org/as/883438-53c655.txt), highlighting its adoption in contemporary settings. The initiative is open to feedback, reflecting the developer's commitment to continuous improvement and engagement with the user community. Despite the positive reception, there has been a mention that the maximum number `16777215` (`0xFFFFFF`) might be considered too small for certain applications, indicating an area for potential refinement based on user feedback.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:22:22.312000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
