<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Forking Guide</title>
  <updated>2025-02-17T02:21:20.461317+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2025-02-16 21:49:14.334000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-14 14:40:05.232000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4314_Bitcoin-Forking-Guide.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4311_Bitcoin-Forking-Guide.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Bitcoin Forking Guide</title>
    <updated>2025-02-17T02:21:20.461356+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-forking-guide/1451" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on achieving consensus within the Bitcoin community highlights a critical challenge: fostering agreement on covenant and contract primitives. This issue is notably compounded by the diverse approaches to designing these primitives, driven by specific use-cases. The recurring debates over similar ideas year after year have led to concerns about the "memoryless" nature of the consensus process, underscoring a need for a comprehensive technical archive. Such an archive would serve as a common reference point for researchers and developers, enabling them to build on a shared foundation of knowledge, ideas, and frameworks. The current state of documentation, including efforts like the listing of opinions on soft forks in the Bitcoin wiki, tends to be more people-focused rather than idea-centric. This approach misses the opportunity to critically evaluate the trade-offs and potential enabled by different proposals.

Efforts to document and discuss Bitcoin's contracting primitives have been made in the past, such as the Bitcoin Contracting Primitives Working Group and a documentation attempt by Optech. These initiatives aimed at creating a platform for comprehensive discourse on proposals, yet they fell short of providing a sustainable solution for archiving and building a consensus. The [Bitcoin Contracting Primitives WG](https://github.com/ariard/bitcoin-contracting-primitives-wg) and a [similar attempt](https://github.com/bitcoinops/bitcoinops.github.io/pull/806) by Optech are noteworthy, despite their discontinuation, for their aim to facilitate understanding and discussion of proposals within the community.

The [bcap project](https://github.com/bitcoin-cap/bcap) sheds light on the importance of social consensus in implementing consensus changes within Bitcoin. It argues for the necessity of broad-based agreement before any code modifications, highlighting that successful integration and acceptance of changes depend on this widespread support. A guide ([link](https://ajtowns.github.io/bfg/)) further elaborates on this concept, offering insights into the complexities of making consensus changes. While not exhaustive, the guide serves as an advisory document, stressing the non-enforceability of its suggestions beyond moral persuasion or community support. It champions a cooperative ethos, advocating for changes that benefit the entire ecosystem and cautioning against proposals that might advantage the majority at the minority's expense, as these are less likely to achieve consensus.

The guide underscores the intricate work required to navigate consensus changes, emphasizing that it's not a means to manipulate the system but a roadmap for constructive dialogue and thoughtful decision-making. It aims to promote a methodical process that considers the collective well-being of the Bitcoin community, encouraging proposals that are universally seen as beneficial for facilitating smoother consensus-building. Through fostering an inclusive and constructive dialogue, the guide seeks to advance a thoughtful approach to consensus changes within the decentralized framework of Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T21:49:14.334000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
