<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
  <updated>2025-03-25T02:27:58.790606+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>0xB10C 2025-03-24 19:26:58.876000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-05 04:51:21.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-02-04 14:03:58.047000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-04 07:44:49.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-02-03 14:16:02.273000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-02 03:30:20.192000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-31 20:45:26.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>glozow  . 2025-01-31 13:31:01.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-24 00:42:29.140000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-23 22:37:29.313000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-23 21:00:49.186000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2025-01-23 17:14:31.157000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-01-23 14:46:08.743000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jungly  . 2025-01-23 08:49:12.690000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-20 14:43:27.958000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-01-20 10:51:08.698000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ismaelsadeeq  . 2025-01-19 15:21:50.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-19 13:26:01.385000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2025-01-19 11:03:42.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-08 10:17:20.354000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>CryptiQ  . 2024-08-06 13:41:52.443000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-04 15:45:21.037000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>xBC  . 2024-08-02 12:08:52.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4596_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4180_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4167_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4163_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4152_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4146_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4129_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4121_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4094_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4093_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4092_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4090_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4088_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4087_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4080_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4079_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4078_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4077_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4076_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2928_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2920_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2913_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2911_Stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stats on compact block reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T02:27:58.790782+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stats-on-compact-block-reconstructions/1052" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an extensive exploration of Bitcoin's network performance, particularly in terms of transaction handling and block reconstruction efficiency, several key modifications and findings have been highlighted. The adjustment to one node's configuration to run with `blockreconstructionextratxn=10000` and the update of two nodes to include a significant patch ([p2p: track and use all potential peers for orphan resolution 31397](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/31397)) are central to this analysis. These changes aim at enhancing the system's capacity to manage transactions effectively, especially during periods of increased mempool activity. The observed impact of these adjustments provides insight into potential optimizations for transaction dissemination protocols within the Bitcoin network.

An investigative effort has commenced, focusing on the efficiency of populating prefilled transactions in blockchain networks. This approach suggests a proactive strategy by sending certain transactions immediately to improve network performance. The initiation of recording the contents of inbound and outbound `getblocktxn` messages marks a step towards gathering empirical evidence on transaction management practices. The anticipation of evaluating the effects of these modifications during heightened mempool activity underscores a broader strategy to optimize the overall efficiency and robustness of blockchain technology.

The integration of FIBRE code into the Bitcoin peer-to-peer network is discussed, emphasizing the licensing challenges and the potential need for either a complete rewrite or a relicense of the code due to compatibility issues between AGPL and Bitcoin's licensing requirements. Moreover, the discussion touches upon the possibility of allowing users to select specific peers for ultra-high-bandwidth compact block relay, highlighting considerations around access and security measures in the decentralized nature of Bitcoin.

Further, the conversation shifts towards prioritizing updates and maintaining the FIBRE patch set, suggesting a renewed focus on straightforward, impactful enhancements. The suggestion to explore a peer-to-peer version of FIBRE indicates an interest in innovative approaches to optimization and efficiency within the project's scope. Additionally, the importance of managing "orphans" or transactions without a readily identifiable parent transaction within a block is underscored. A strategic approach to enhance transaction processing through the iteration of an "orphanage" alongside the existing "vextra buffer" is proposed.

The handling of orphanage blocks and the necessity to iterate through the entire collection due to technical constraints related to short IDs are discussed. This exhaustive search ensures no potential connections are missed, which is vital for maintaining the continuity of the blockchain. The dialogue also covers the evaluation of the `-blockreconstructionextratxn` parameter and its potential impact on block reconstruction efficiency.

The discussion further delves into the "extra pool" in compact block reconstruction, aiming to optimize bandwidth usage and improve the speed of block propagation. By leveraging the "extra pool," nodes can more efficiently manage their resources, contributing to a more scalable blockchain infrastructure. Additionally, strategies to mitigate denial-of-service (DoS) attacks, focusing on optimizing data management and minimizing unnecessary resource usage, are proposed.

Libbitcoin's approach to transaction handling raises concerns regarding its vulnerability to DoS attacks, emphasizing the need for robust data management and security measures. The proposition of backing the mempool with a database store for improved transaction handling introduces a novel approach to managing transactions more efficiently while addressing spam concerns.

Lastly, the recent merge of a significant update into the Bitcoin repository ([GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/31397)) showcases an enhanced mechanism for handling orphan transactions. This development, along with an extensive examination of node behavior and block reconstruction statistics, underscores ongoing efforts to bolster the reliability and efficiency of Bitcoin nodes. Through targeted adjustments and further research, these initiatives aim to enhance the performance of the Bitcoin network, reflecting a methodical examination of transaction management and block reconstruction processes.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T19:26:58.876000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
