<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
  <updated>2025-02-08T02:17:09.764205+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-02-07 17:55:37.798000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-07 14:32:39.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-02-07 08:26:07.472000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-02-06 19:56:35.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4222_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4218_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4216_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4209_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T02:17:09.764254+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multisigbackup-com-backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds/1430" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion opens with skepticism towards the efficiency of using a globally replicated database for personal information storage due to its potential inconvenience and impracticality in the long term. The argument suggests that conventional backup methods should suffice for such data, emphasizing the need for plausibly deniable backups alongside traditional ones. It transitions into the specifics of single-signature (single-sig) use cases, where backing up a seed phrase is deemed adequate for most users. This method is compared to remembering a password, highlighting its simplicity and the feasibility of physically recording the information through means such as writing or engraving on steel.

The conversation then shifts to the application of this concept to multi-signature (multisig) setups, providing users with an additional backup option by inscribing wallet descriptors on the blockchain. Despite concerns over the use of Bitcoin for this purpose, the narrative defends the practice by pointing out the relative cost-effectiveness and user autonomy in deciding the value of such an insurance policy against multisig transaction costs. It also outlines strategies for minimizing inscription costs, such as opting for low fee rates and leveraging miners' incentives to include transactions in blocks when economically viable, thus offering flexibility irrespective of prevailing fee environments.

Personal experiences shared highlight the use of 2-of-2 multisig configurations for self-protection against improvident spending and ensuring security through mutual backup without sole control over funds. This anecdote illustrates both the practical benefits of multisig arrangements for safeguarding assets and the emotional peace derived from such secure financial management practices.

Finally, the dialogue introduces [multisigbackup.com](http://multisigbackup.com/), a project addressing the critical need for accessible, reliable recovery methods for 2-of-3 multisig wallets, which hinges on the availability of output descriptors along with seed phrases. It critiques traditional descriptor backup methods for their vulnerability to loss, damage, or privacy breaches and proposes a durable, privacy-preserving alternative involving steel engraving. The project promises several advantages: cost-efficiency, robustness against physical loss or damage, enhanced privacy, simplified recovery processes conducive to inheritance planning, and improved user experience through possible integration into wallet setup workflows. Future enhancements include support for advanced Bitcoin features and optimization for diverse wallet types, with ongoing development documented at [https://github.com/joshdoman/multisig-backup](https://github.com/joshdoman/multisig-backup).</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T17:55:37.798000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
