<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
  <updated>2025-02-08T02:16:24.115019+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-02-07 20:20:58.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-05 01:08:43.125000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4223_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4171_Spanning-forest-cluster-linearization.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Spanning-forest cluster linearization</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T02:16:24.115057+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/spanning-forest-cluster-linearization/1419" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent advancements in cluster linearization algorithms have led to the development of a new approach known as the spanning-forest cluster linearization algorithm. This method is being considered for integration into Bitcoin Core as it shows potential in providing more efficient transaction processing by optimizing the way transactions are ordered. The core idea behind this technique lies in solving a Linear Programming (LP) problem, aiming to select the highest-feerate, topologically-valid subset of transactions within a given cluster. By treating each transaction as a variable and applying constraints that ensure the topology remains valid, the problem is shown to be solvable in polynomial time using LP solving techniques like the Interior Point Methods. This revelation is significant as it demonstrates that the issue is not NP-hard, thus allowing for more straightforward solutions through linear programming.

The simplex algorithm, traditionally used in LP problems, has been adapted to better suit the needs of transaction ordering. It operates by partitioning the transaction graph into interconnected “chunks” or groups of transactions. Each chunk is internally connected by a spanning tree of transactions considered free variables. Through iterative optimization of these chunks, the algorithm aims to find an optimal arrangement of transactions that adhere to the network's constraints. Simplifications to the traditional simplex process have been made to enhance efficiency, focusing on optimizing the transaction inclusion within each chunk implicitly.

Building upon the simplex method, the spanning forest algorithm introduces modifications that tailor it more closely to transaction linearization. It employs a boolean marker for each dependency in the transaction graph to indicate its activity status, enabling the algorithm to perform merges and splits of chunks based on feerate comparisons. This process strives to arrange the entire cluster of transactions into an optimal linear order, where no higher-feerate chunk depends on a lower-feerate one. The algorithm achieves this by selectively activating or deactivating dependencies, guided by the goal of maximizing feerate differences among the chunks.

Significant efforts have also been put into refining the algorithm's execution, including preferring merges over splits and designing specific functions to prevent state repetitions. This ensures progress towards an optimal solution without backtracking. Notably, starting the process with an existing linearization provides a baseline that the algorithm seeks to improve upon, ensuring that the outcome is at least as favorable as the initial input.

The practical application and performance of the new algorithm were evaluated through benchmarks against existing examples of challenging transaction clusters found within the Bitcoin network. These benchmarks revealed substantial improvements in processing times, suggesting that despite theoretical concerns about worst-case complexity, the algorithm performs exceptionally well under real-world conditions. The focus on achieving a "good enough" linearization quickly, rather than finding the absolute optimal solution, represents a pragmatic approach to enhancing transaction processing efficiency. This work, documented and shared on GitHub ([view code](https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/spanning_tree_linearization)), marks a significant step forward in the ongoing effort to optimize blockchain technology and highlights the potential of applying advanced mathematical frameworks to solve complex problems in cryptocurrency systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T20:20:58.258000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
