<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
  <updated>2025-02-28T02:28:21.057020+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>zawy 2025-02-27 19:57:52.004000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-02-09 16:48:47.248000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-06 16:45:01.124000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>pmn  . 2025-01-05 11:36:35.625000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-04 23:43:19.353000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-01-04 08:10:18.927000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 17:05:07.824000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sjors  . 2025-01-03 15:27:10.650000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-03 13:52:30.984000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 12:59:20.523000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-03 11:51:32.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 19:16:14.403000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2025-01-02 17:18:06.007000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-02 16:04:00.283000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-01-02 14:47:10.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2025-01-01 01:21:03.301000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2024-12-31 04:30:09.270000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-12-31 01:39:41.910000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ProofOfKeags  . 2024-12-30 21:35:01.198000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>zawy  . 2024-12-22 15:14:50.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4394_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4236_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3984_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3971_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3967_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3959_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3947_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3943_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3942_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3940_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3931_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3923_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3921_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3920_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3917_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3909_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3903_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3901_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3898_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2024/3844_Fastest-possible-PoW-via-Simple-DAG.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fastest-possible PoW via Simple DAG</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T02:28:21.057245+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fastest-possible-pow-via-simple-dag/1331" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initially focuses on the limitations of the "parent method" used in a Proof of Work (PoW) Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) chain, particularly how its effectiveness diminishes with significant changes in the network's topology. This method inadvertently favors larger miners due to their ability to maintain low latency connections amongst themselves, potentially marginalizing smaller miners by increasing the number of blocks they can claim. An alternative approach, referred to as the "Nc/Nb" method, is introduced for its resilience against such topological changes. It aims to regulate the DAG's width without relying on time or timestamps, instead adjusting difficulty based on the proportion of recent ancestors within the DAG, offering a more stable solution amidst varying network conditions.

Further elaboration is provided on a simulator hosted on [GitHub](https://github.com/mcelrath/braidpool/tree/main/tests), which showcases an advanced algorithm for simulating global node distribution and accurately calculating propagation latencies. This tool marks a significant step forward in testing blockchain resilience against latency and represents a collaborative effort, as indicated by discussions on platforms like [OpTech recaps](https://x.com/bitcoinoptech/status/1887827549209645090) and a dedicated [Discord community](https://discord.gg/pZYUDwkpPv). The simulator incorporates suggestions from the community, including targeting two parents per bead to achieve a desired balance in the Nb/Nc ratio, showcasing the iterative nature of this research.

The significance of community-driven discussions merging with academic research is highlighted through references to a notable [bitcointalk post](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=98314.msg1075701msg1075701) and its influence on the NC-Max paper ([link](https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1101.pdf)). This interplay between informal forums and formal research underscores the value of diverse contributions to the field's advancement. Similarly, the work by Miller and LaViola Jr. introduces a Byzantine fault tolerance model utilizing moderately-hard puzzles to secure transactions in digital currencies like Bitcoin, accessible via the Nakamoto Institute ([link](http://nakamotoinstitute.org/research/anonymous-byzantine-consensus)).

The intricacies of managing latency within blockchain networks are further discussed, emphasizing the need for a nuanced approach to incorporate high-latency transactions without compromising system integrity. Various strategies, including the "great grandparent method," are proposed to ensure fairness and efficiency in reward distribution among miners, addressing potential biases introduced by network latency. This dialogue extends into the realm of Braidpool, exploring innovative solutions for difficulty adjustment and orphan rate management within a decentralized mining context. The conversation also delves into deterministic block templates and UTXO set management challenges in validating a DAG chain, highlighting initiatives like Utreexo for compacting the UTXO set and maintaining system efficiency.

Lastly, the discourse explores theoretical advancements in blockchain consensus mechanisms, specifically focusing on the development of the Braid Consensus algorithm. This novel approach aims to enhance scalability and security by intertwining multiple blockchain strands, fostering a collaborative ecosystem for continuous improvement. The conversation also touches on the broader implications of these developments for achieving efficient, secure, and decentralized consensus across blockchain networks, inviting further exploration and community engagement through platforms like GitHub and Discord.

In summary, the exchange encapsulates a broad spectrum of topics from the technical challenges and innovations within blockchain technology to the collaborative efforts bridging community ideas with academic research. Each aspect contributes to a deeper understanding of the complexities involved in developing resilient, fair, and scalable blockchain systems.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-27T19:57:52.004000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
