<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
  <updated>2025-02-10T02:27:13.580869+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-02-09 07:55:29.492000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-02-07 17:55:37.798000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sipa  . 2025-02-07 14:32:39.832000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik  . 2025-02-07 08:26:07.472000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-02-06 19:56:35.929000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4227_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4222_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4218_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4216_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4209_MultisigBackup-com-Backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - MultisigBackup.com: Backup and recover a k-of-n descriptor using only n seeds</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T02:27:13.580921+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/multisigbackup-com-backup-and-recover-a-k-of-n-descriptor-using-only-n-seeds/1430" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the usage of blockchain technology for individual data storage raises concerns over its efficiency and sustainability. It is argued that while globally replicated databases might offer convenience in the short term, their long-term viability for personal data storage remains questionable. The text emphasizes the importance of traditional backup methods, pointing out that integrating specific, small data amounts into backups should be both simple and secure, maintaining plausible deniability. This highlights the broader necessity of planning for data security and longevity beyond the immediate allure of blockchain solutions.

The conversation also delves into the specifics of using 2-of-2 multisig setups for Bitcoin security, portraying it as a method that not only guards against personal error but also serves as a secure backup strategy. This setup involves the cooperation of another party without granting them independent spending abilities, thereby ensuring mutual trust and protection of assets. The benefits of such an arrangement include the absence of monthly fees, potential for plausible deniability regarding asset ownership, and a philosophical stance on decentralization’s role in reducing financial contributions to war efforts and centrally managed programs. Furthermore, the practice of regularly rehearsing mnemonic phrases for wallet access is emphasized, underlining a disciplined approach to digital asset management.

The project [multisigbackup.com](http://multisigbackup.com/) is presented as addressing a critical misunderstanding among users concerning the recovery of 2-of-3 multisig wallets. It clarifies that recovery requires not just two seed phrases but also an output descriptor with essential information like derivation paths and extended public keys (xpubs). Highlighting the risks associated with traditional descriptor backup methods, the text suggests engraving descriptors onto steel as a more durable solution. This method offers numerous advantages, including cost-effectiveness, strong data availability, privacy preservation, simplified recovery processes conducive to inheritance planning, and an enhanced user experience through features like payment links or direct inscriptions during wallet setup. Future developments aim to support advanced features like Taproot multisig and Miniscript, alongside optimizations and software wallet integrations, with more information available at [https://github.com/joshdoman/multisig-backup](https://github.com/joshdoman/multisig-backup).

Lastly, the issue of txouts space pollution is addressed, highlighting a concern over the inefficiency of leaving unspent transaction outputs (UTXOs) on the blockchain, which may seem minor in amount but contribute to chainstate size. A report on the current state of the Bitcoin Core node illustrates this concern, showing fluctuations in the chainstate's size over time, emphasizing the need for mindful practices in blockchain space utilization.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-09T07:55:29.492000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
