<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
  <updated>2025-02-12T02:21:04.176615+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2025-02-11 18:03:23.763000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager 2025-02-11 17:30:44.052000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cguida  . 2025-02-10 19:04:45.378000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>joostjager  . 2025-02-10 17:01:20.154000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4283_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4282_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4273_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4269_Highly-Available-Lightning-Channels-Revisited-ROUTE-OR-OUT.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Highly Available Lightning Channels Revisited – ROUTE OR OUT</title>
    <updated>2025-02-12T02:21:04.176663+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/highly-available-lightning-channels-revisited-route-or-out/1438" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing the Lightning Network's (LN) transaction efficiency while balancing privacy concerns introduces a nuanced perspective on the network's development. The LN aims to scale blockchain transactions in terms of speed, cost, and reliability, yet this objective often clashes with the need for increased privacy within the network. A proposed solution to this dichotomy is the implementation of functionality that allows users to prioritize either transaction efficiency or privacy based on their immediate needs. This would entail offering distinct routing options tailored to either speed and cost-efficiency or privacy, suggesting a flexible infrastructure capable of adapting to user preferences. This concept challenges the prevailing assumption that transaction efficiency and privacy are mutually exclusive, proposing a compromise that necessitates technical innovation and careful consideration of its impact on network usability and security.

Further discussions on improving LN's transaction success rate introduce a "ROUTE OR OUT" approach, which advocates for an operational shift where nodes failing to process transactions could be bypassed for a significant period, potentially leading to a preference among senders for channels signaling high availability (HA). This signifies a move towards prioritizing connections known for reliability, possibly at the cost of higher fees, to ensure transaction success. Such a shift could reshape the network's topology and payment routing strategies. However, concerns have been raised about the practicality and potential consequences of this approach, sparking debate among developers regarding its efficacy and implications.

The possibility of signaling HA through existing protocols is highlighted, particularly by utilizing unused bits in the `htlc_maximum_msat` parameter in channel updates. By adjusting this value to end in 555, nodes can indicate their HA status for transactions up to a specified amount, prompting a broader discussion on whether formalizing such signals would be beneficial. This ongoing dialogue within the developer community emphasizes the importance of evolving LN's infrastructure to support more reliable and efficient payment processing while considering the broader impacts on the network's dynamics. For more detailed examination of these discussions and various viewpoints, interested readers can access the initial proposal and subsequent debates [here](https://www.mail-archive.com/lightning-dev@lists.linuxfoundation.org/msg03094.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-02-11T18:03:23.763000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
