<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
  <updated>2025-02-06T02:23:08.804418+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ 2025-02-05 23:33:28.574000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-05 16:48:23.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth 2025-02-05 16:46:45.483000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Davidson  . 2025-02-05 00:35:23.038000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-04 15:03:32.537000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-04 14:47:45.351000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-04 14:45:08.444000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 21:19:50.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-03 17:01:05.827000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:24:44.565000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:13:28.337000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-02-03 14:03:57.645000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-02 17:00:25.514000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 23:00:58.162000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-02-01 19:18:18.695000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ  . 2025-02-01 17:06:17.550000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-31 13:25:10.101000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-30 23:11:20.253000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-30 13:34:13.143000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2025-01-29 15:25:42.441000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-29 11:22:02.630000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>roasbeef  . 2025-01-28 23:44:14.837000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>sanket  . 2025-01-28 22:28:00.644000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2025-01-28 13:10:04.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4189_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4186_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4185_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4179_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4174_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4173_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4172_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4157_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4158_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4153_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4151_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4150_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4149_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4144_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4143_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4137_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4120_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4115_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4114_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4111_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4108_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4104_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4103_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/4102_ZK-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - ZK-gossip for lightning channel announcements</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T02:23:08.804571+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zk-gossip-for-lightning-channel-announcements/1407" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation delves into the intricacies of managing Lightning Network (LN) channels, focusing on the privacy and efficiency of channel closures and the implications for network functionality. Nodes, especially those backed by a full Bitcoin node, monitor the blockchain to detect when channel outputs are spent, thereby triggering the removal of these channels from their operational set. This process poses a challenge for light clients, which rely on `channel_updates` or trusted sources for information due to their inability to directly observe the blockchain. To manage the network's size and efficiency, nodes prune inactive channels if no updates are received within a two-week period. A proposal introduces a mechanism akin to a heartbeat for channels, requiring a refreshed `channel_announcement` every few weeks, ensuring that only active channels are considered in routing decisions, thus enhancing the network's reliability.

Privacy concerns are raised regarding the potential exposure of `channel_id` upon channel closure, which could deter channel closures and affect user privacy by making transactions more traceable. The current strategy involves proving in zero-knowledge (ZK) that the advertised channel capacity does not exceed the actual on-chain output value. This introduces uncertainty about the specific taproot outputs linked to a channel, preserving privacy. Additionally, employing utreexo checkpoints for verifying channel states offers a solution to maintaining privacy while ensuring network integrity, allowing for private channel use before public announcement. These strategies underscore ongoing efforts to balance privacy, security, and functionality within the LN ecosystem.

An innovative approach to managing channel closures is also discussed, proposing a radical shift where nodes would drop all channels periodically, necessitating the rebroadcast of active channel data. This method aims to enhance privacy by either omitting the capacity field from disclosures or adjusting it based on certain criteria. However, this could complicate pathfinding for payments. Pathfinding algorithms rely on channel capacity and historical data to predict successful payment transmission, suggesting that changes to capacity information handling could impact the user experience and network efficiency.

The email further explores the taproot gossip protocol extension designed for privacy-conscious users, leveraging Utreexo and ZK-proofs to allow channels to avoid revealing their outpoint. This system introduces a `channel_announcement_2` message containing a Musig2 signature, dissociating the channel from its on-chain output to preserve anonymity while securing against DOS attacks. Key elements such as bitcoin keys, node IDs, channel capacity, and a Utreexo accumulator are employed to validate several aspects, including the verification of the UTXO within the set using a Utreexo proof. A novel `channel_announcement_zk` message format is proposed to incorporate ZK-proofs efficiently, enabling nodes to verify channel announcements without direct linkage to on-chain transactions. This addresses privacy concerns effectively. Given the method's inability to detect channel closings on-chain, channels are suggested to refresh their announcements periodically to confirm their active status. Documentation and code outline the proof creation process, demonstrating the feasibility of integrating additional constraints into UTXO verification. This discussion represents a significant step towards more private and secure LN operations, inviting feedback on the proposed extension to further the development of privacy-preserving approaches in Lightning Network gossip protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-05T23:33:28.574000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
