<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
  <updated>2025-02-20T02:20:54.188587+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2025-02-19 18:28:29.521000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-02-19 16:18:32.286000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>morehouse 2025-02-19 16:11:27.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2025-02-19 15:14:08.326000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-02-19 14:46:22.347000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding 2025-02-19 14:21:01.845000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>t-bast 2025-02-19 09:44:53.454000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-18 14:54:25.455000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-02-18 14:31:14.930000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tbast  . 2025-02-18 13:06:24.718000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4333_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4332_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4331_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4330_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4329_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4328_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4325_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4319_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4317_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4316_Zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Zero-fee commitments for mobile wallets</title>
    <updated>2025-02-20T02:20:54.188689+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/zero-fee-commitments-for-mobile-wallets/1453" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the complex landscape of Lightning Network transactions, addressing the mechanics of fee payments in Hash Time Locked Contracts (HTLCs) is crucial for both the efficiency and security of these transactions. A nuanced understanding emerges where traditionally, it might seem that channel openers bear the costs of transaction fees. However, a more balanced approach allocates this responsibility to the HTLC transaction owner, typically a mobile wallet user, ensuring that peers are not unfairly burdened with additional costs. This structure plays a pivotal role in maintaining the economic equilibrium within the network, safeguarding against potential exploitation by malicious actors who might attempt to manipulate transaction fees to their advantage.

A proposed solution to enhance transaction handling introduces a dual-signature model for HTLC transactions. This model mandates peers to sign two versions of an HTLC transaction: a default version with no included fee requiring supplementary on-chain inputs, and a second version with a high feerate enclosed within a custom TLV of `commitment_signed` that mirrors the current observed feerate. This innovative approach aims to mitigate risks associated with transaction fees while ensuring optimal operation under varying network conditions. The proposal emphasizes economic incentives, suggesting a system where the cost implications of different feerate options are strategically managed to encourage prudent use of resources, enhancing both transaction security and liquidity management in inactive or obsolete channels.

Addressing the specific needs of mobile wallets in the cryptocurrency ecosystem, the development towards integrating zero-fee commitments into lightning channels marks a significant advancement. This initiative is designed to cater to the unique operational and threat models inherent to mobile wallet usage, focusing on securing funds without necessitating on-chain utxos for force-closure of transactions. It outlines a mechanism whereby mobile wallets can efficiently manage the risks associated with revoked commitments, leveraging immediate spending of channel outputs to cover on-chain fees and enabling the publication of penalty transactions if necessary. The proposal delineates clear strategies for managing received and sent HTLCs, highlighting the distinct security considerations and operational flexibilities in each scenario. 

Furthermore, the proposal introduces an essential measure for enhancing mobile wallet resilience through additional signatures on HTLC transactions. This measure allows for unilateral close actions by mobile wallets in the face of uncooperative peers, particularly vital for managing HTLCs in adverse conditions. Although it acknowledges limitations, such as scenarios lacking pending HTLCs, the overall framework signifies a progressive step toward improving mobile wallet experiences within the Lightning Network. The community's feedback is instrumental in refining this approach, aiming for eventual formalization through a bLIP to solidify these enhancements within the network's protocol, as detailed in the ongoing discussions and proposals found at [current spec proposal](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/867) and [zero-fee commitments](https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/1228).</summary>
    <published>2025-02-19T18:28:29.521000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
