<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Satoshi Style Message Signing</title>
  <updated>2024-05-05T02:01:38.078404+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>satsie 2024-05-04 02:57:32.995000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Satoshi Style Message Signing</title>
    <updated>2024-05-05T02:01:38.078432+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/satoshi-style-message-signing/850" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The prevalent method for signing general messages involves using a private key associated with a legacy P2PKH address, a technique that has been widely adopted by both hardware and software projects including Ledger, Trezor, Coldcard, Sparrow, and several multisig companies. This approach is particularly valued for its ability to verify the integrity of hardware controlling keys, protecting against bit rot. The origin of this message signing technique can be traced back to Bitcoin Core code developed by Satoshi Nakamoto, specifically found within `src/util/message.cpp`. Despite the significance of this method, comprehensive technical documentation is scarce outside the actual implementation code. However, [this page](https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Message_signing) on the Bitcoin Wiki attempts to bridge the gap, albeit with some critical technical details not made explicit. For instance, it overlooks the specification of "Bitcoin Signed Message:\n" magic bytes and the double hashing process each message undergoes, which are crucial for understanding the complete mechanics of the process.

Further exploration into the subject reveals additional resources that attempt to elucidate aspects of the message signing process that the Bitcoin Wiki page may not clearly convey. For example, the specific rules for the signature header byte, a complex component of the signing process, are better explained in a [post](https://bitcoin.stackexchange.com/questions/83035/how-to-determine-first-byte-recovery-id-for-signatures-message-signing) on Bitcoin Stack Exchange than in the original documentation. Despite the existence of these resources, the "Satoshi format" of message signing remains inadequately documented, resulting in a reliance on piecing together information from various implementations and community contributions. This situation is exemplified by the development of tools such as the [Bitcoin Message Tool](https://github.com/shadowy-pycoder/bitcoin_message_tool) and [checkmsg.org](https://checkmsg.org/), which indicate a community-driven effort to support message signing across different address types despite the lack of a single, reliable source of documentation. 

While there have been significant advancements in addressing message signing for other address types, through initiatives like BIP-137, [BIP-notatether-messageverify](https://notatether.com/notabips/bip-notatether-messageverify/), and BIP-322, the comprehensive documentation and understanding of the original "Satoshi format" remain elusive. This gap in documentation suggests either a widespread difficulty in deciphering the existing material or a testament to the considerable effort previous individuals have invested in unraveling the complexities of Satoshi's message signing technique without leaving a consolidated guide for future reference.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-04T02:57:32.995000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
