<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Anonymous usage tokens from curve trees or autct</title>
  <updated>2024-05-15T02:00:29.392971+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-05-14 17:39:45.215000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Anonymous usage tokens from curve trees or autct</title>
    <updated>2024-05-15T02:00:29.393011+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/anonymous-usage-tokens-from-curve-trees-or-autct/862/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of calculating the costs associated with a timelocked unspent transaction output (UTXO) is explored through the lens of the time value of money, as detailed in an analysis found at [this link](https://gist.github.com/chris-belcher/87ebbcbb639686057a389acb9ab3e25b). This method provides an explicit framework for understanding the financial implications of engaging with timelocked UTXOs. Conversely, the cost considerations for simply owning a UTXO at the time of a recent snapshot present a different financial picture, being primarily associated with the creation cost of a UTXO. This latter expense is suggested to be less burdensome and perhaps even mitigated under certain circumstances.

Further exploration into this topic raises the question of whether users might have the capability to demonstrate ownership of a timelocked UTXO. The discussion implies a nuanced understanding of blockchain technology and its financial ramifications, suggesting an area ripe for further investigation and clarification. This inquiry points towards a broader conversation about the mechanics of blockchain transactions and the intricate balance between security features such as timelocks and the economic incentives or disincentives they create for users within the digital currency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T17:39:45.215000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
