<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 27.0</title>
  <updated>2024-05-19T02:02:16.475348+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-18T07:24:11.421000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Inquisition 27.0</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T02:02:16.475385+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-inquisition-27-0/883" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The release of Bitcoin Inquisition 27.0 marks a significant update in the Bitcoin ecosystem, incorporating enhancements and proposed consensus changes based on the foundational [Bitcoin Core 27.0](https://bitcoincore.org/en/releases/27.0/). This version introduces support for three notable Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs): BIP 119 OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY ([PR55](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/55)), BIP 118 SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT ([PR56](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/56)), and BIN-2024-1, also known as BIP 347 OP_CAT ([PR57](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/57)). These features have been active on the default signet, with BIP 119 and BIP 118 operational since September 6, 2022, at block 106704, and BIP 347 since April 30, 2024, at block 193536.

To ensure transactions utilizing these new features are processed, users must connect with other inquisition nodes, as transactions will not be relayed by nodes without support for these features. An effective method to establish this connection is by specifying `addnode=inquisition.bitcoin-signet.net` in the user settings. The subversion string, visible through the `bitcoin-cli -netinfo 3` command, advertises Bitcoin Inquisition nodes, facilitating easier identification and networking among users.

However, it's important to note that the latest release discontinues relay support for two previously supported functionalities: annexdatacarrier and pseudo ephemeral anchors, as detailed in [PR22](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/22) and [PR23](https://github.com/bitcoin-inquisition/bitcoin/pull/23), respectively. Users relying on these features should anticipate adjustments as the signet inquisition miner and inquisition relay node are expected to undergo updates soon, impacting the confirmation of transactions using these features. For further details on these changes and their implications, referencing the [23.0 announcement](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2022-December/021275.html) provides comprehensive insights into the evolving landscape of Bitcoin Inquisition's network capabilities and user requirements.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-18T07:24:11.421000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
