<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-19T02:01:18.367450+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-19T00:44:40.880000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T02:01:18.367505+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The significance of transparency in various operations, particularly in the context of mining pools, is highlighted through the discussion of share log transparency. A particular method to enhance this transparency is through sharing accounting and accountability protocols, as demonstrated in a GitHub discussion ([Share Accounting + Accountability Protocol Extension · stratum-mining/sv2-spec · Discussion 76 · GitHub](https://github.com/stratum-mining/sv2-spec/discussions/76discussioncomment-9472619)). This approach aids users in verifying their payouts and making informed decisions about whether to continue with their current mining pool or switch to another.

Additionally, the proposal introduces an element of cryptographic attestation, which serves as an added layer of verification beyond the transparent share log. This means that, on top of having access to a transparent share log, miners also receive an attestation from the pool side. This attestation allows miners to independently verify the claims made by the pool regarding payouts and other related activities. The introduction of cryptographic attestation aims to bolster trust and accountability in the system, providing miners with more tools to ensure they are compensated fairly for their contributions.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T00:44:40.880000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
