<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:19.758937+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-19T15:43:33.538000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:19.758969+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of implementing a system for reusing ecash, presenting a complex challenge that requires innovative solutions. The primary concern raised is the inherent nature of ecash which, by design, seems resistant to reuse. This is because ecash is typically conceived as a one-time-use token, making the concept of its reuse both novel and challenging.

One proposed solution involves a mechanism where upon redeeming an ecash hash (ehash) for a reward, the user would simultaneously receive another ehash for future redemption. However, this idea raises critical questions about the feasibility and implementation specifics, such as tracking the issuance frequency of an ehash related to its original share, and establishing a reliable method to link an ehash to a specific share. Furthermore, the proposal touches upon the complexity introduced if an ehash were to be divided into smaller parts, representing less difficult shares, adding another layer of technical challenges to the concept's realization.

This exchange highlights the need for further exploration and inventive thinking in the realm of digital currency, especially regarding the potential for ecash reuse. The conversation underscores the importance of developing a robust system that can accurately track and manage the lifecycle of an ehash, ensuring that the process remains secure, transparent, and efficient.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T15:43:33.538000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
