<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:08.644091+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-19T21:26:33.276000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:08.644131+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of digital currency transactions, the concept of utilizing an ehash multiple times introduces a nuanced approach to transaction mechanics. Specifically, the idea revolves around implementing a swap mechanism that results in two distinct outputs: one being the actual transaction reward which could manifest in various forms such as on-chain currency, lightning network currency, or ecash, and the second output being another ehash. This dual-output model raises intriguing possibilities for transaction verification and reward mechanisms within digital currency systems.

Further exploration into this concept reveals complexities surrounding the linkage between an ehash and a specific share. The process of associating an ehash with a share is facilitated by a mint, which possesses the capability to identify the connection between a given ehash and its corresponding share post-redemption. It's important to note that the individual redeeming the ehash need not be the original creator of the ehash, a feature that adds a layer of flexibility to the system. This flexibility is reminiscent of traditional ecash systems but is adapted here within the context of ehash transactions. The operational framework supporting these interactions is detailed within the documentation available at [keyset](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts/blob/6024402ff8bcbe511e3e689f6d85f5464ecc3982/02.md), which outlines the technical underpinnings necessary for executing these types of transactions.

The discourse surrounding the double utilization of ehashes, their linkage to shares, and the operational role of mints in this ecosystem, underscores the evolving landscape of digital currencies. These discussions are pivotal in enhancing the understanding of digital currency mechanics, potentially influencing future developments in this rapidly changing field.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T21:26:33.276000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
