<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Silent Payments: Light Client Protocol</title>
  <updated>2024-05-23T02:00:32.215656+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cygnet3</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-22T12:03:45.159000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Silent Payments: Light Client Protocol</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T02:00:32.215688+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-light-client-protocol/891/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email contains a suggestion regarding the format of the `utxos` endpoint in a specific specification. The sender proposes an improvement to how unspent transaction outputs (UTXOs) are organized in the returned data. Currently, UTXOs are listed individually without grouping by transaction ID (`txid`). The suggestion is to modify this approach by grouping all UTXOs under their respective `txid`. This change aims to facilitate the processing of UTXOs, particularly when identifying and working with the `ScriptPubKey` values for outputs beyond the first (`k&gt;0`) within a transaction.

The rationale behind this suggestion stems from the observation that the current method requires additional client-side processing to group UTXOs by `txid` before further analysis or processing can be performed. This is especially relevant for steps in the specification where the `ScriptPubKey` for outputs other than the first needs to be calculated or identified. Grouping UTXOs by their `txid` would streamline this process, reducing the need for each client to implement this grouping mechanism independently.

Despite recognizing that UTXOs are not frequently requested—only necessary when a filter returns a match—the sender argues that incorporating this adjustment into the endpoint's design could significantly enhance efficiency and ease of use for all clients interacting with this data. The implicit suggestion is that optimizing the data format at the source could lead to more streamlined and efficient client-side applications, benefiting the broader user base involved in processing or analyzing these transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-22T12:03:45.159000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
