<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Silent Payments: Light Client Protocol</title>
  <updated>2024-05-23T02:00:19.127117+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>setavenger 2024-05-22 12:27:25.752000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Silent Payments: Light Client Protocol</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T02:00:19.127149+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/silent-payments-light-client-protocol/891/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of discovering `ScriptPubKey`s for scenarios where `k&gt;0` demands a comprehensive approach to analyzing transaction outputs. The key to resolving this involves grouping all outputs of a transaction and scanning them collectively. This method ensures the identification of all outputs, regardless of the value of `k`. The utilization of blindbitd, which scans all taproot outputs of a block, highlights a solution for identifying these outputs without direct reference to their transaction IDs (txids). This approach is critical because tweaks associated with these outputs are not labeled with their corresponding txids, necessitating a scan over all block outputs to successfully locate all relevant outputs.

Further examination reveals that the [function used by blindbitd](https://github.com/setavenger/go-bip352/blob/27de6d8b3f8aaf0d555e044d7d6edbf0ddb518a3/receive.goL27) incorporates all taproot outputs of a block as input for its scanning function. This strategy aligns with the observation that the proposed changes in a [Bitcoin core pull request](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/28241) similarly do not incorporate storage of txids for these operations. In contrast, Oracle's implementation includes an index for storing txids, though it serves only the tweaks to the client, not the txids themselves. This distinction points to varied approaches in handling the identification and retrieval of output information within blockchain technologies, underlining the importance of scanning mechanisms in ensuring the completeness of output data collection.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-22T12:27:25.752000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
