<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Tr(): rawnode() and rawleaf() support</title>
  <updated>2024-05-29T02:03:55.526150+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Eunovo</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-28T17:41:55.616000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Tr(): rawnode() and rawleaf() support</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T02:03:55.526182+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/tr-rawnode-and-rawleaf-support/901/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion touches upon the utilization of N2KBs in transactions, highlighting a concern that revolves around the apprehension other parties might have regarding hidden spend paths. The inquiry is directed towards gaining insights from both @sipa and @JeremyRubin, suggesting an interest in understanding their perspectives on the matter. This indicates a broader conversation within the community about the security and transparency of using N2KBs in transactional processes.

The mention of hidden spend paths as a potential issue suggests a need for clarity and possibly improved mechanisms to ensure that N2KBs can be used in a manner that maintains trust among all parties involved in a transaction. It reflects an ongoing dialogue aimed at addressing and mitigating fears related to the integrity of transactions facilitated by this technology. Engaging experts like @sipa and @JeremyRubin implies a desire to deepen the understanding of N2KBs' operational framework and explore solutions that could alleviate concerns related to hidden spend paths.

This conversation underscores the importance of transparency and security in the development and application of new technologies in transactions. It also highlights the community's reliance on expert opinions to navigate potential challenges, emphasizing a collaborative approach to innovation and problem-solving within the space.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-28T17:41:55.616000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
