<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Tr(): rawnode() and rawleaf() support</title>
  <updated>2024-05-29T02:03:42.037224+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-28T21:20:57.620000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Tr(): rawnode() and rawleaf() support</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T02:03:42.037256+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/tr-rawnode-and-rawleaf-support/901/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The utilization of N2KBs (Nested 2-of-3 Key Bundles) in the realm of digital transactions offers a nuanced approach to managing funds, especially in scenarios requiring heightened security and flexibility. The concept highlights the potential for creating spend paths that are not immediately apparent to all parties involved in a transaction. This characteristic of N2KBs is pivotal for contexts such as inheritance or escrow services, where the primary concern isn't the visibility of alternate spending pathways but rather ensuring the recoverability of funds under dire circumstances, such as the loss of all keys by the beneficiary. 

In situations where assets are distributed across multiple wallets, each serving distinct purposes or operating under varying levels of security - for instance, a main wallet equipped to handle complex contracts versus a backup hardware or cold wallet with limited functionality - N2KBs demonstrate significant utility. By knowing only the internal public key (ipk) and a specific rawnode leaf, a backup wallet can still execute transactions. This mechanism ensures that funds remain accessible even if advanced contract features supported by the primary wallet are beyond the backup wallet's capabilities. 

Such an arrangement underscores the versatility of N2KBs in enhancing the security and resilience of digital asset management strategies, catering to both sophisticated contractual needs and foundational recovery requirements.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-28T21:20:57.620000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
