<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
  <updated>2024-05-31T02:00:07.991699+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2024-05-30 14:44:23.077000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Merging incomparable linearizations</title>
    <updated>2024-05-31T02:00:07.991737+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/merging-incomparable-linearizations/209/46" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The composition algorithm, as discussed in a recent insight, suggests a simplified approach to merging processes. This method deviates from the traditional process of identifying the input linearization with the optimal remaining prefix. Instead, it proposes focusing solely on the prefixes of the remaining original chunks from the input linearizations. This adjustment streamlines the initial step by narrowing down the scope to pre-existing chunk boundaries rather than evaluating an extensive range of potential prefixes.

Furthermore, the revised strategy recommends a more focused approach when attempting to intersect the chosen prefix with other linearizations. Rather than examining every possible prefix intersection within the remainder of another linearization, it is more efficient to limit considerations to those prefixes that align with either the chunk boundaries of the remaining segments or strictly with the original chunk boundaries. This refinement significantly reduces the complexity and potential computational overhead involved in the merging process by leveraging existing structural divisions within the data. For more detailed information, the insights are accessible through this [composition algorithm](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-definitions-theory/202/14) link.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-30T14:44:23.077000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
