<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
  <updated>2024-06-01T02:04:09.663826+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes.916000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-31T09:42:41.916000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>DNM, eCash and privacy</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T02:04:09.663859+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/dnm-ecash-and-privacy/916/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the evolving landscape of digital financial tools and their implications for both legitimate use and illicit activities. One such tool, [Joinstr](https://joinstr.xyz/), is spotlighted for its non-custodial nature, which presents a significant challenge to efforts aimed at curbing money laundering, terrorist financing, child trafficking, and drug markets. Unlike custodial mixers and coinjoin solutions that have been used for various purposes over the years, Joinstr operates without a central coordinator, making it inherently resistant to shutdown or control.

Further exploration into the realm of digital currencies brings eCash into focus. Unlike Joinstr, eCash functions as a custodial accounting layer, which means it could potentially be adopted by regulated banks or private individuals. However, its suitability for dark net markets (DNMs) is questionable due to the high risks associated with such platforms. The text elaborates on these risks, noting that they are consistent across users of custodial DNMs, thereby underscoring the inherent dangers and challenges faced by participants in these shadowy corners of the digital economy.

In sum, the narrative provides a comprehensive overview of how different digital financial mechanisms, specifically Joinstr and eCash, fit into the broader context of online transactions, highlighting their potential applications and the significant risks involved. It sheds light on the complex interplay between technological innovation, regulatory challenges, and the ongoing battle against illegal online activities.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-31T09:42:41.916000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
