<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>FE'd Up Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-06-01T02:05:34.965359+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2024-05-31T18:50:11.352000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>FE'd Up Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T02:05:34.965392+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fed-up-covenants/929/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email discusses an advanced cryptographic technique involving the creation of a decryption key that can decrypt a given ciphertext to the output of a specified function \(F\) when its plaintext inputs are used. The technique is particularly applied to generate an ECDSA signature of a transaction, which is uniquely modified by the hash of the transaction itself. This modification ensures that the signature can only be successfully generated for the specific transaction, enhancing security measures.

The process works by defining a function \(F\) that takes a private key and a transaction as inputs and outputs the ECDSA signature of the transaction, altered by the hash of the transaction. By encrypting the tweaked private key and the transaction, these encrypted elements serve as inputs to produce the final signature. This mechanism leverages public key cryptography, where generating ciphertexts is open to anyone, but decrypting them to reveal the signature necessitates access to the specialized decryption key.

Furthermore, the inquiry seeks to clarify the accuracy of a proposed formula \(\sigma = Decrypt(C_F, C_p, Encrypt(M, TX))\), which extends the definition of the decryption function to handle two ciphertext arguments, based on the foundational encryption and decryption concepts outlined in the initial sections of the paper. This approach aims to verify the correct application of cryptographic principles in creating a secure and functional signature generation method.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-31T18:50:11.352000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
