<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
  <updated>2025-01-05T02:24:36.627369+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-01-04 07:56:50.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-05-09 15:43:20.132000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-05-09 15:16:43.719000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Fi  . 2024-05-06 10:00:29.691000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2024-05-04 21:22:17.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>evoskuil  . 2024-04-29 13:45:50.660000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-04-29 12:26:28.811000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Jan_2025/3957_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2397_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2396_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2376_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2368_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2348_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2347_Deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Deterministic tx selection for censorship resistance</title>
    <updated>2025-01-05T02:24:36.627433+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/deterministic-tx-selection-for-censorship-resistance/842" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a detailed examination of the challenges and potential solutions associated with transaction selection in Bitcoin mining, several key points emerge that highlight the complexity of achieving decentralization and security within the blockchain ecosystem. The discussion first addresses the strategic shift towards giving individual miners greater autonomy over transaction selection, as proposed by SV2 and Braidpool. This approach aims to reduce the risk of state-level attacks by increasing the number of entities required for compromise. However, it also introduces a higher variance in revenue for miners, particularly those with a smaller share of the network's hashrate, thereby raising concerns about financial stability for these participants.

The concept of deterministic transaction selection is critiqued for potentially limiting miners' freedom to choose the most lucrative transactions. This method requires transactions to be pre-mined into shares, which could inadvertently increase centralization by privileging certain transactions over others. Braidpool’s "full proportional" payout scheme is discussed as a means to distribute transaction fees more equitably among pool participants, suggesting a complex interplay between economic incentives and the goal of decentralization.

Furthermore, the practice of mining transactions directly into shares without broadcasting them to the traditional mempool is recognized for its ability to earn out-of-band fees, though it raises issues regarding censorship and the integrity of transaction selection. The vulnerability of the system to 51% attacks is acknowledged, along with the need to limit the size of the sharechain-mempool to prevent abuse.

Legal and regulatory challenges are also highlighted, with the varied responsibilities of miners across jurisdictions offering a glimmer of hope for addressing some of the technical limitations of blockchain technology. The discussion underscores the difficulty of implementing solutions at the bitcoin consensus level that are resistant to government intervention, pointing out the potential for regulatory mandates to enforce specific mining pools or transaction selection criteria.

Central to the conversation is the concern over the exacerbation of centralization through enforced uniformity in transaction selection strategies across decentralized mining pools. This scenario is feared to undermine the foundational principles of blockchain technology by limiting transaction diversity and compromising the democratic decision-making process inherent in decentralized systems.

Lastly, the dialogue touches upon the inefficacy of pool hopping as a defense against state threats and the promising introduction of braids at scaling HK as a new direction worth investing in. It concludes with a critical view of the current transaction selection process, advocating for a deterministic and consensus-based approach to enhance decentralization and resist censorship. This proposition involves significant technical adjustments and reevaluation of pooling and validation practices, aiming to navigate the practical challenges of Bitcoin's operation while adhering to its core principles.</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T07:56:50.468000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
