<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-19T02:08:01.932100+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-18 15:50:41.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake 2024-06-18 13:10:57.761000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2741_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2740_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T02:08:01.932297+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on enhancing the Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT) framework to accommodate silent payments delves into several technical challenges and propositions aimed at ensuring transaction integrity, efficiency, and compatibility. A major point of discussion is the management of input orders and the emphasis on not using a fixed ordering system that could potentially introduce errors in silent payment outputs. This concern underscores the importance of a system where inputs can be dynamically modified without compromising the security and intended structure of the transactions. The strategy involves optimizing for scenarios where wallets consolidate multiple small unspent transaction outputs (UTXOs) into a single payment to a silent payment address, which significantly reduces the computational burden on hardware wallet signers.

Further, the dialogue explores the nuanced interaction between SIGHASH_ALL and ANYONECANPAY flags within Bitcoin transactions. The conversation highlights the potential vulnerabilities and complexities introduced when combining these flags, especially concerning transaction malleability and integrity. It emphasizes the need for careful consideration of how inputs are added and the implications for silent payment outputs, suggesting a backward-compatible method to enhance security through the introduction of specific flags that track the state of silent payments within a transaction. 

The proposal to streamline the cryptographic proof mechanism for silent payments is notable, suggesting that consolidating proofs for inputs associated with the same signer could reduce the verifier's workload and simplify the transaction verification process. This approach aims to balance efficiency and security by minimizing the data and computational requirements for transactions involving silent payments.

Significant attention is given to the potential addition of `PSBT_IN_SP_ECDH_SHARE` and related fields to the PSBTv2 specifications. This inclusion aims to support silent payment transactions efficiently by enabling the storage of ECDH shares and DLEQ proofs directly within the PSBT structure. Such enhancements would facilitate the secure computation of output scripts and ensure that transactions including silent payments are handled correctly by both aware and unaware parsers, thereby maintaining the integrity and privacy of the transactions.

The elimination of the OutputGenerator role and the shift towards an ECDH share technique for managing silent payments highlight an evolving approach to securing and streamlining PSBT transactions. These changes reflect a broader commitment to integrating advanced cryptographic techniques and improving the user experience in executing silent payments within the Bitcoin network.

Moreover, the discussion acknowledges the complexity of implementing confidential transactions within the blockchain network, focusing on reducing the overhead associated with generating and verifying cryptographic proofs. By proposing a more streamlined verification process for transaction inputs and outputs, the communication outlines a path toward more scalable and privacy-preserving transactions, emphasizing the importance of innovation and collaboration in addressing the challenges of cryptocurrency transactions.

Overall, the email threads articulate a comprehensive examination of the technical, security, and operational considerations involved in enhancing PSBTs for silent payments. Through a collaborative effort among contributors, there's a clear direction towards refining the PSBT framework to support more complex and privacy-focused transactions, marking a significant step forward in the evolution of blockchain technology and its applications.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-18T15:50:41.699000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
