<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-18T02:01:13.803457+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-18T02:01:13.803628+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers on the nuances of cryptocurrency mining, specifically addressing the mechanisms and ramifications of immediate liquidity for mining rewards. The importance of such liquidity is emphasized as it enables miners to swiftly access their rewards, thereby facilitating a more efficient migration between pools based on payout sufficiency. Stratum V2's proposal for custom work selection is highlighted, offering an automated fallback solution for miners when a pool fails to pay adequately. This approach underscores the distinction between the ease of rapid payouts and the complexity of automating pool migration based on actual payout discrepancies.

Further, the conversation delves into the limitations imposed by current payout schemes within mining pools. It critiques the inability of these systems to offer real-time payouts, with the most common methodologies allowing for payouts only once every few blocks or daily. This limitation hampers the goal of immediate reward liquidity due to inherent delays and the need for manual intervention by users, thus challenging the objective of streamlining miner payouts without complicating the process unnecessarily.

The email also explores innovative approaches to payment distribution within the mining ecosystem, invoking discussions around the use of ecash and the Lightning Network (LN) to facilitate faster and more flexible payouts. Notably, it presents an examination of the Cashu system's attempt at enhancing privacy and facilitating small, non-custodial payouts free from liquidity prerequisites. However, this discussion acknowledges the potential regulatory hurdles and the custodial risks associated with centralized pool management, reflecting on the broader challenges facing the integration of new technologies into existing frameworks.

A detailed analysis of the proposed integration of Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange mechanism into the Stratum v2 Protocol is provided, aiming to bolster privacy and auditability for pool rewards. This method introduces a sophisticated interaction between miners and pools through blinded messages and signed responses, ensuring transaction integrity while maintaining confidentiality. The narrative suggests a proactive exploration of technological advancements, like ASIC computational offloading and the compatibility of Fedimint as an ecash solution, to enhance efficiency and privacy in mining operations.

References and resources are meticulously included to support further investigation into the discussed topics, offering a comprehensive overview of the strategic considerations and potential innovations aimed at optimizing cryptocurrency mining practices. These include links to foundational documents and protocols such as the [Cashu ecash protocol](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts), [ecash Proof of Liabilities](https://gist.github.com/callebtc/ed5228d1d8cbaade0104db5d1cf63939), and [Ocean TIDES documentation](https://ocean.xyz/docs/tides), alongside a [vocal summary](https://fountain.fm/episode/zfEPkjPmQd8rD2cxq5tR) providing an auditory complement to the written material.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-17T17:32:19.936000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
