<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-21T01:57:51.548705+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T01:57:51.548842+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an exploration of the benefits cryptographic attestation offers in enhancing share log transparency within mining pool operations. The proposed protocol allows for comprehensive auditing by any pool user, ensuring that payouts made by the pool are both transparent and verifiable. This system is touted for its simplicity and low overhead, despite a noted time lag which is deemed non-critical due to inherent payout delays within pools.

Further, the concept of reusing ecash through a dual-output model introduces a nuanced mechanism into digital currency transactions. This system facilitates the generation of two outputs from a single transaction: one being the transaction reward in various possible forms (on-chain currency, lightning network currency, or ecash) and the other being another ehash. The process of linking an ehash with a specific share is executed through a mint, allowing for a flexible association between ehashes and shares post-redemption. This flexibility enhances the traditional ecash system, adapting it to accommodate the mechanics of ehash transactions as detailed in the provided documentation at [keyset](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts/blob/6024402ff8bcbe511e3e689f6d85f5464ecc3982/02.md).

In addressing the challenges of implementing a reusable ecash system, the critical nature of ecash as a typically one-time-use token is examined. Proposing a solution where redeeming an ecash hash yields another for future use raises significant feasibility and implementation questions, especially regarding the issuance frequency and linkage of an ehash to specific shares. The discussion also touches on the complexity added if ehashes were to be divided into smaller parts, indicative of less difficult shares, presenting additional technical hurdles.

The need for a detailed critique and analysis of cryptographic protocols emerges, emphasizing the importance of identifying potential vulnerabilities and weaknesses that could compromise the system. This approach reflects a commitment to refining and securing the protocol against theoretical and practical exploitation, underscoring the value of constructive criticism in enhancing system integrity.

The dialogue shifts focus to the practicality and implications of adopting certain strategies or technologies by mining pools, particularly noting the absence of tangible benefits from the discussed approach. This conclusion stems from a thorough evaluation of the strategy's alignment with the operational goals and efficiency enhancements commonly sought by mining pools.

Moreover, the conversation around immediate liquidity of mining rewards delves into the challenges and potential solutions within cryptocurrency mining payout systems, including Stratum V2's proposal for custom work selection. This feature aims to address fairness in compensation without manual intervention, highlighting the limitations current payout schemes impose on the frequency and verification of payouts.

The TIDES documentation offers insights into the weighting of shares, revealing a preference for direct methods over retrospective valuation by mint operators. This decision prioritizes simplicity and efficiency in the system's design, avoiding complexities associated with post-transaction value assignments.

Critique of NUT 16 within the Cashu framework centers on regulatory implications for non-KYC compliant mining pools and the practicality of micro-payouts. Concerns are raised about the complexity and risks introduced, especially for custodial mining pools adhering to KYC/AML regulations, suggesting a skepticism towards the proposal's merit and potential regulatory entanglements.

An in-depth examination of the allocation of target proof-of-work difficulties within mining pools underscores the necessity of accommodating diverse hashing power across devices. This ensures equitable participation and compensation, emphasizing a balanced approach to share valuation influenced by targeted difficulty levels.

Bolt12 is recognized for its contribution to enhancing auditability and facilitating micro payouts in financial transactions, particularly within Lightning Network channels. The discussion acknowledges the significance of privacy and the challenges of regulatory compliance in the cryptocurrency space, highlighting the immediate liquidity of mining rewards as a compelling benefit amidst these considerations.

Lastly, the proposal for integrating Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange mechanism into the Stratum v2 Protocol reflects a sophisticated effort to enhance privacy, auditability, and flexibility in cryptocurrency mining rewards distribution. This detailed framework, supported by references and resources, signifies a comprehensive approach to improving the mechanisms of digital finance and asset management within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-20T23:51:47.228000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
