<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
  <updated>2024-08-12T02:09:52.504825+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Christian Decker 2024-08-11 10:26:23.542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptorevue  . 2024-08-10 18:30:41.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-07-30 02:07:35.029000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-07-23 13:08:44.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cdecker  . 2024-07-12 11:16:37.983000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptorevue  . 2024-05-30 16:40:43.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-30 15:49:44.159000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptorevue  . 2024-05-27 21:20:32.118000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-18 16:38:35.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:29:28.256000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-16 17:49:21.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2938_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2936_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2904_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2892_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2878_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2577_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2576_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2547_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2453_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2432_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2430_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
    <updated>2024-08-12T02:09:52.504910+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stable-channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-lightning/875/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around the nature and functionality of hosted channels versus traditional Lightning Network (LN) channels brings to light the nuanced differences and operational frameworks within the LN ecosystem. Hosted channels, unlike their classical counterparts, cannot be settled on-chain, offering at best a proof of misbehavior without an automatic dispute mechanism via the blockchain. This distinction underscores the inherent differences in how these channels operate and are perceived within the network.

The introduction of Valet's support for both hosted and traditional LN channels, alongside innovations like "Drain fiat channel" and "Credit channels," presents a novel approach to liquidity management within the Lightning Network. These developments aim to enhance the flexibility and utility of the LN by allowing users to convert fiat-denominated channels into real LN channels, using real LN channels as collateral. Such mechanisms could significantly impact how liquidity is provided and managed, potentially making the LN more accessible and versatile for users requiring diverse financial services.

Stable Channels proposes utilizing bitcoin within a Lightning Channel without the need for tokens or external values, focusing on the stability of bitcoin rather than creating a new stable instrument. This project emphasizes self-custody and operates each channel as an independent Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO), aiming to mitigate systemic risks and offer users various options in the event of market downturns. The initiative seeks to address the challenges of achieving stability through pegged currencies or assets while avoiding the pitfalls that have historically increased volatility and risk.

The debate between the Fiat channels proposal and Tony's construction highlights critical aspects of custodianship, operational differences, and the integration of BTC and USD within the same LN node. These discussions reveal the complexity and diversity of solutions within the LN ecosystem, emphasizing the importance of precise language and understanding of each system's distinct features and trade-offs.

Fiat Channels introduces several innovative concepts aimed at enhancing cryptocurrency operations and liquidity within the Lightning Network. Through a series of publications, the proposal outlines the standardization of Satoshi transactions, addresses liquidity abstraction challenges, and explores the socio-economic impacts of adopting Satoshi as a standard unit of transaction. This comprehensive approach signifies a forward-looking perspective on the potential transformations within the blockchain ecosystem.

Addressing the challenge of communicating engineering trade-offs to users highlights the necessity of informed decision-making in a market filled with diverse options. The integration of the Chaumian eCash system, Cashu, demonstrates an innovative approach to stable dollar tokens despite concerns over the custodial nature of such systems. This development aims to improve scalability and user experience but also brings to light the inherent risks of custodial structures.

Stable Channels seeks to integrate bitcoin-backed dollar balances with the Lightning network, aiming to address bitcoin’s volatility and enhance its utility. By matching BTC shorts with BTC longs, the project enables the creation of synthetic dollar balances, proposing a decentralized solution to the stability offered by centralized stablecoins. Despite facing user experience and operational challenges, Stable Channels represents a significant step towards decentralized financial stability on the bitcoin network, opening up possibilities for trading use cases and liquidity enhancement on the Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-11T10:26:23.542000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
