<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-30T02:09:49.363292+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-29 21:00:11.488000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-22 14:51:45.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-21 14:07:17.974000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-21 13:41:15.741000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-21 13:15:06.505000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-20 20:29:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-20 09:21:52.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-18 15:50:41.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-18 13:10:57.761000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2828_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2779_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2778_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2777_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2776_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2773_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2771_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2741_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2740_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-30T02:09:49.363466+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with a consideration of technical feedback on the PSBT draft, suggesting a separation of the DLEQ (Discrete Logarithm Equality) proofs into their own Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). This proposition is underpinned by a draft that builds upon @RubenSomsen's gist, providing a foundation for further development in this area. The conversation delves into several key aspects of programming and cryptocurrency transactions, emphasizing the importance of handling group proofs, silent payment verification by signers, and the intricacies of implementing Anti-Counterfeiting Proofs (ACP) within the context of cryptocurrency transactions.

On the topic of silent payments, a nuanced approach to transaction verification is outlined, focusing on the conditions under which a signer should fail a transaction involving silent payment outputs. The dialogue underscores the necessity for signers to check for ACP on inputs they are responsible for signing, particularly when a sighash type other than `ALL` is present alongside silent payment outputs. The exploration into this subject reveals suggestions for simplifying the process through which signers verify transactions involving silent payments, proposing the addition of global shares and proofs for all inputs if applicable. This strategy aims to balance computational and memory demands on signers, acknowledging the varied capabilities of devices used in the signing process.

The conversation also highlights the security implications of using the `ACP` signature, pointing out the significant risk it poses to the funds of the parties involved in a transaction. It outlines the safer alternative of signing with `ALL`, protecting inputs regardless of how other parties have signed the transaction. This distinction emphasizes the criticality of choosing the appropriate signature type to ensure transaction security.

Further, the discourse examines the challenges associated with the `SINGLE | ACP` signing mechanism, illustrating potential security vulnerabilities when incorrect script generation or manipulation by external observers occurs. This analysis leads to broader considerations on trust and verification in the transaction process, particularly for silent payment-aware signers.

Additionally, the technicalities of managing shares and proofs within Payment Service Buses (PSBTs) are explored, suggesting an efficient way to handle transaction data by incorporating shares and proofs as global attributes. This method seeks to optimize transaction verification processes while maintaining or enhancing privacy measures and transactional integrity.

In addressing the optimization of cryptographic protocols, the discussion presents two approaches for handling inputs in cryptographic proofs, advocating for a unified proof for each scan key alongside its corresponding set of inputs. This proposal aims to streamline management and verification processes, highlighting the ongoing efforts to enhance security and efficiency in cryptographic operations.

Lastly, the updated draft for the BIP introduces the DLEQ proof, marking a substantial enhancement aimed at bolstering the security and efficiency of the proposed improvements. This update signifies a commitment to incorporating advanced cryptographic techniques, underscoring the collective endeavor to refine and advance the standards governing cryptocurrency transactions and programming constructs.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T21:00:11.488000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
