<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:42.397167+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T02:00:42.397295+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an examination of the innovative use of `ehash` within a mining framework, focusing on its dual-purpose functionality. This includes its role as both a reward and a mechanism for obtaining another `ehash`, raising questions about the linkage between `ehash` and shares, and the process for tracking `ehash` issuance. The conversation evolves into a broader inquiry about the cryptographic protocol's robustness, specifically seeking feedback on any technical weaknesses that could compromise its integrity. This reflects a deep engagement with applied cryptography and a desire to understand potential vulnerabilities at both theoretical and practical levels.

Further discourse explores the enhancement of transparency in mining operations through the introduction of a share accounting and accountability protocol, as discussed on GitHub. This method aims to increase miners' trust by allowing them to verify their payouts more effectively, introducing an additional layer of verification beyond transparent share logs. Despite the initial optimism, subsequent analysis reveals a consensus that the proposed strategy offers no tangible benefits to mining pools, indicating a comprehensive evaluation of its practical implications.

The conversation shifts to the immediacy of liquidity in mining rewards, highlighting the challenges associated with current payout schemes and the promise of automated systems like Stratum V2 for ensuring fair compensation. However, the reality of implementing such automation is complicated by the inherent limitations of PPLNS and PPS payout models. Despite these obstacles, the discussion acknowledges the potential for transparency enhancements to empower miners, suggesting that increased information sharing could mitigate some of the challenges faced by miners today.

Technical discussions delve into the valuation of shares within the TIDES documentation, emphasizing the complexity of converting `eShares` into satoshis and reflecting on alternative valuation methods that were ultimately deemed impractical. This leads into a critique of NUT 16 within the Cashu framework, expressing concerns over regulatory implications for non-KYC compliant pools and questioning the practicality of enforcing micro-payouts through ecash.

The discourse then examines the differentiation in target proof-of-work difficulties across various mining hardware, underscoring the necessity of balancing operational efficiency with fairness in share distribution. This segues into an assessment of Bolt12's role in enhancing auditability and liquidity in financial transactions, particularly within Lightning Network channels, while also recognizing the custodial risks associated with mining pools and the implications of KYC regulations.

A detailed proposal outlines a system for managing and reusing ecash, featuring a `share_log_window` for recording eligible transactions and a secure one-time redemption process for each blinded signature. This is juxtaposed with an exploration of atomic swap spending conditions under the NUT-11 proposal, highlighting the potential for direct peer-to-peer asset exchanges without intermediaries.

Lastly, the integration of the Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange mechanism into the Stratum v2 Protocol is proposed, aiming to improve privacy and auditability in pool rewards distribution. This includes a detailed description of the BDHKE process, from share submission to redemption, and considers the application of various spending conditions supported by Cashu. The proposal emphasizes the importance of privacy, flexibility, and efficiency in cryptocurrency mining rewards distribution, recommending further resources for a comprehensive understanding of the subject matter.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T21:26:33.276000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
