<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-24T02:03:06.923602+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-24T02:03:06.923756+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/23" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the domain of digital currency transactions, a nuanced approach to utilizing an ehash multiple times has been proposed, focusing on a swap mechanism leading to dual outputs: one being the transaction reward in various forms like on-chain currency, and the other being another ehash. This complex process involves a mint identifying the connection between an ehash and its corresponding share post-redemption, which adds a layer of flexibility to the system. This methodology parallels traditional ecash systems but within the context of ehash transactions, detailed in the technical documentation hosted on [keyset](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts/blob/6024402ff8bcbe511e3e689f6d85f5464ecc3982/02.md). The conversation extends into the realm of digital currency mechanics, emphasizing the importance of further exploration into this concept.

The discussion also delves into cryptographic attestation as a means to enhance transparency and security in mining pools. By authenticating individual shares through digital signatures, this method ensures data integrity from validation onwards, safeguarding against unauthorized modifications and enhancing trust within the system. Additionally, it allows participants to audit payouts, potentially highlighting discrepancies in pool practices with minimal overhead despite a time lag in auditing, deemed inconsequential compared to the inherent payout delay in mining pools.

A critical analysis and request for feedback on a cryptographic protocol were highlighted, signaling an interest in refining its design by identifying potential vulnerabilities. This proactive approach seeks specific critiques focusing on the protocol’s susceptibility to exploitation, aiming to fortify its soundness against theoretical and practical weaknesses. This engagement underscores a commitment to advancing applied cryptography through constructive criticism.

Furthermore, the discourse includes a discussion on enhancing share log transparency in mining operations. A GitHub discussion ([Share Accounting + Accountability Protocol Extension · stratum-mining/sv2-spec · Discussion 76 · GitHub](https://github.com/stratum-mining/sv2-spec/discussions/76discussioncomment-9472619)) highlights methods for miners to verify payouts and decide on continuing or switching mining pools. Cryptographic attestation is introduced as an additional verification layer, providing miners with tools to independently verify pool claims about payouts, thereby fostering trust and accountability.

The TIDES documentation sheds light on how shares are weighted, using a `share_log_window` and blinded signatures matched with target difficulty for valuation, indicating a departure from a straightforward conversion rate between eShares and satoshis. An alternative valuation method was considered but ultimately not adopted to avoid complexities associated with post-transaction value assignment.

On regulatory concerns, there's skepticism toward the Cashu framework's NUT 16 proposal for mining pools, particularly regarding its implications for non-KYC compliant pools and the practicality of implementing micro-payouts through KYC-compliant methods. [NUT 16](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts/pull/106) is critiqued for adding unnecessary complexity and risk, especially for custodial mining pools already adhering to regulations, suggesting the proposal might inadvertently lead to increased governmental oversight.

In mining pool operations, setting target proof-of-work difficulties accommodates various hardware capabilities, ensuring equitable participation without compromising operational stability or fairness. This process emphasizes a balanced mechanism for compensating participants, taking into account the diversity of mining hardware and maintaining the integrity of the mining process.

Bolt12 is discussed as a method that enhances liquidity and auditability in financial transactions, specifically within Lightning Network channels, by facilitating micro payouts without prior liquidity requirements. This approach aims to simplify user participation while respecting privacy through the endorsement of custodial wallets as ecash systems, complementing existing efforts towards self-custody solutions.

Lastly, the immediate liquidity of mining rewards presents both benefits and inherent risks within the cryptocurrency mining ecosystem, necessitating an understanding of regulatory landscapes and the significance of liquidity in mining operations. The conversation also touches on the limitations of current Bitcoin Mining ASIC technology and the quest for auditability and reduced payout thresholds, with [BOLT12](https://ocean.xyz/docs/lightning) mentioned as a solution facing challenges due to Lightning Network fees.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-23T21:57:57.171000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
