<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
  <updated>2024-05-19T02:02:02.340771+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>tony 2024-05-18 16:38:35.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:29:28.256000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-16 17:49:21.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2453_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2432_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2430_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T02:02:02.340820+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stable-channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-lightning/875/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The integration of the Chaumian eCash system, Cashu, into the cryptocurrency ecosystem marks a significant advancement in creating stable dollar tokens. Led by Developer Star Builder and others, this project capitalizes on a "Stable Channel" to ensure the token's value remains constant. Users interested in exploring this innovative approach can find more details through the user interface available on [Boardwalk Cash](https://boardwalkcash.com/wallet) and the eCash minting process detailed on the [Umint mint website](https://umint.cash). Despite its benefits, such as eliminating the need for users to run a node or stay online continuously, thus improving scalability and user experience, the custodial nature of eCash systems raises concerns. These systems are susceptible to regulatory scrutiny and potential malpractices due to their custodial structure, despite efforts to mitigate these risks by providing on-chain proof of liabilities and reserves.

Stable Channels is an open-source project designed to integrate bitcoin-backed dollar balances with the Lightning network, aiming to enhance bitcoin's stability and draw more interest and investment. By matching BTC shorts seeking fiat stability with BTC longs willing to provide it, the project creates synthetic dollar balances. This initiative seeks to address bitcoin’s volatility which stands as a barrier to its adoption when compared to centralized stablecoins that offer a predictable value store. However, it also avoids the systemic risks associated with centralized stablecoins, such as vulnerabilities to hacks and regulatory pressures, by proposing a model that enables continuous settlement between users to minimize counterparty risk. The operational framework of Stable Channels allows for self-custody and the possibility for participants to exit the system at any time, settling transactions based on a median price from multiple reliable price feeds.

Despite its potential to enhance the utility of the Lightning Network, the implementation of Stable Channels faces challenges similar to those encountered by bitcoin and Lightning users, including the complexity of running a node, the necessity of being always online, and potentially high fees. Future enhancements to the Lightning Network may help to alleviate some of these issues. Moreover, the project outlines various risk factors and mitigation strategies, highlighting the importance of cooperative behavior and possibly introducing reputation-based mechanisms to foster trust among users. The integration with the Chaumian eCash system Cashu showcases the project's adaptability, offering scalability and user experience benefits over traditional Lightning approaches while navigating the inherent custodial risks. The development of Fedimints could further address these custodial challenges, emphasizing the ongoing innovation in creating stable, decentralized financial instruments on the bitcoin network. Overall, Stable Channels represents a promising development toward achieving financial stability within the decentralized bitcoin ecosystem, potentially expanding its appeal and functionality through continuous settlements on the Lightning Network.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-18T16:38:35.184000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
