<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-19T02:01:40.563158+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T02:01:40.563277+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The dialogue presents an in-depth analysis and critique of various aspects of cryptocurrency mining, particularly focusing on payout systems, regulatory challenges, privacy concerns, and the technical implementation of cryptographic protocols. At its core, the discussion sheds light on the limitations and potential solutions for ensuring fair compensation to miners, emphasizing the role of transparency and technological innovation in addressing these issues. The proposed Stratum V2's feature for custom work selection is highlighted as a significant advancement, aimed at automating the switch of miners between pools based on payout adequacy. However, the practicality of such automation faces hurdles due to the inherent limitations of current payout schemes like PPLNS and PPS, which restrict the frequency and verification of payouts.

The discourse extends into the examination of share log transparency and the cryptographic attestation's role in enhancing it. A transparent share log, supplemented by additional attestation from the pool side, is considered a step towards empowering miners with verifiable evidence of payout fairness, notwithstanding skepticism about its practical benefits for mining pools. This skepticism also touches upon the Cashu framework's integration within the mining sector, especially regarding the implications for non-KYC compliant pools and the feasibility of implementing micro-payouts via KYC-compliant methods.

Furthermore, the conversation delves into the technicalities of share valuation and weighting in mining pools, underlining the complexity of equitably compensating participants across varying hardware capabilities. The nuanced approach to share valuation, particularly through the TIDES documentation, illustrates the intricacies involved in balancing fairness and operational stability within mining pools.

Bolt12's introduction as a mechanism for enhancing auditability and facilitating micro payouts without prior liquidity highlights a shift towards simplifying participation for users while prioritizing privacy through custodial wallets functioning as ecash systems. Yet, this approach brings to the fore concerns about custodianship and regulatory vulnerabilities, especially given the susceptibility of mining pools to governmental interventions.

The email further explores the technical and regulatory nuances of Bitcoin mining, ASIC limitations, the pursuit of decentralized pool architectures, and the potential role of pleb mining in decentralization efforts. It critically assesses the valuation of keysets in Cashu, Ocean's KYC policy, and the legal and operational complexities surrounding payment mechanisms and regulatory compliance.

Lastly, the proposal for integrating the Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange mechanism into the Stratum v2 Protocol encapsulates a comprehensive framework aimed at enhancing privacy, auditability, and flexibility in the distribution of cryptocurrency mining rewards. This proposition underscores the need for meticulous record-keeping and transparency, aligning with the ecash Proof of Liabilities protocol to ensure the integrity of transactions.

In conclusion, the multifaceted discussion encapsulated in the email threads offers a profound insight into the current challenges and innovative solutions within the realm of cryptocurrency mining, highlighting the delicate balance between technological advancements, regulatory compliance, and the overarching goal of ensuring fair and transparent compensation for miners.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T00:53:41.633000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
