<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-16T01:59:56.125616+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T01:59:56.125714+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email presents a detailed discussion on the implementation and potential benefits of using Cashu for mining payouts, specifically focusing on aspects such as auditability, small payouts, and privacy. The sender expresses skepticism about the benefits of using Cashu for achieving privacy due to its custodial nature and the potential regulatory vulnerabilities it introduces, including the need for Know Your Customer (KYC) and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) compliance.

A significant portion of the email delves into technical specifics regarding the proposal's execution. It outlines a mechanism whereby a `share_log_window` captures valid signatures that can be redeemed, suggesting a process for swapping `eHash` tokens within this window alongside other redemption methods. This process involves the replacement of old blinded signatures with new ones in the share log, addressing concerns about the practicality of multiple redemptions for each blinded signature by emphasizing the unique secrets (`x` and `C`) known to the pool/mint post-redemption.

Further elaboration is provided on the use of Cashu's Blind Diffie-Hellman key exchange (BDHKE) as a Stratum v2 Protocol Extension to facilitate private, auditable, and small-scale pool rewards through `eHash`. This system allows hash providers (HPs) to negotiate jobs with pools and request the active `block_keyset`, leading to the generation of a blinded message (`B_`) upon finding a valid share. This message requests a signature from the pool, which is then used along with the share data to populate a time-ordered `share_log`.

The document also touches on multiple recommended readings and references, including links to the Cashu ecash protocol, ecash Proof of Liabilities, Ocean TIDES, and the Stratum v2 Specification. These resources offer further insight into the technical background and broader context of the discussion.

Additionally, the email proposes the possibility of reusing `eHash` shares for redemption multiple times, facilitated by atomic swap spending conditions, highlighted as a notable advantage and an innovation desired by Ocean. This proposal is positioned as an exciting development within the context of enhancing the functionality and flexibility of blockchain-based transactions and mining operations.

Overall, the email articulates a complex proposal aimed at integrating Cashu within the mining payout process to achieve greater auditability, privacy, and efficiency in handling small payouts. It suggests a series of technical implementations and considerations, reflecting a deep engagement with the subject matter and a commitment to exploring innovative solutions in the cryptocurrency space.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-16T01:04:54.921000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
