<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CISA and Privacy</title>
  <updated>2025-10-20T02:47:58.289960+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-04-22 21:24:52.155000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>harding  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-04-24 19:27:03.356000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>murch  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-05-05 12:14:30.846000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-05-05 13:13:25.676000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-05-06 04:15:02.962000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>AdamISZ  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-06-06 16:16:11.913000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>bytes  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-06-06 20:02:55.481000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>1440000bytes</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-19 12:49:21.139000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2298_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2024/2321_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2369_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2371_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2374_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2658_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2660_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6111_CISA-and-Privacy.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CISA and Privacy</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T02:47:58.291739+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cisa-and-privacy/824/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-04-22 21:24:52.155000+00:00</published>
    <summary>Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA) represents a significant development in blockchain technology, specifically within the Bitcoin ecosystem. CISA is designed to amalgamate multiple signatures into one, thereby reducing transaction weight and associated fees. This technique offers a range of savings, from 7.6% for partial aggregation to 15.2% for full aggregation, as illustrated through an example with Alice conducting transactions without CISA versus using CISA to combine payments into a single transaction. Despite these benefits, the introduction of CISA raises concerns regarding privacy and complexity, potentially diminishing the perceived value of its financial advantages. Further exploration into this topic is facilitated by resources such as [BlockstreamResearch on GitHub](https://github.com/BlockstreamResearch/cross-input-aggregation) and a [CISA playground](https://github.com/fjahr/cisa-playground), offering insights into practical applications and implications.
The debate extends into the realm of payment batching in Bitcoin, highlighting how CISA could enhance this already efficient process. Batching alone presents substantial savings, reducing transaction sizes significantly. When combined with CISA, additional savings are realized, though these are relatively modest. Contrary to initial apprehensions, integrating CISA might not necessitate new address formats but could adapt existing ones like bech32m, simplifying the transition and potentially broadening its acceptance. Moreover, CISA's role in lowering costs for privacy-focused protocols like coinjoins and payjoins underscores its potential to positively impact transaction privacy at a broader scale.
However, the requirement for a new output script type distinct from the current P2TR framework due to CISA introduces complexities. Such a move would need a hardfork, posing operational challenges, yet the continued use of bech32m addresses might ease this transition. A constrained version of CISA suggests limited efficiency gains, prompting discussions about its real-world utility and the strategic importance of backward compatibility in blockchain enhancements.
Addressing the management of UTXOs unveils contrasting strategies affecting privacy and sustainability within the blockchain network. The trade-offs between maintaining a high number of UTXOs versus consolidating them under a &quot;max greed&quot; policy highlight the nuanced impacts of user behavior on privacy and efficiency. CISA indirectly influences these practices by promoting co-spending, which may offer some resolution to the privacy concerns associated with each strategy. Yet, it does not directly incentivize privacy-preserving behaviors, instead potentially facilitating easier transaction analysis and tracing.
Finally, the Coin Selection Algorithm's adaptation in light of CISA's encouragement of including more inputs per transaction reflects ongoing challenges. The integration of CISA necessitates reevaluating coin selection methodologies to maintain transaction security and privacy while optimizing efficiency. Despite theoretical advantages in privacy and cost reduction, practical barriers to implementing complex, privacy-enhancing transactions remain significant, indicating a need for further innovation and user-friendly solutions in this space.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>