<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Liquidity provider utxo management</title>
  <updated>2024-09-12T02:13:51.637348+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>remyers</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>murch  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>remyers  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Sept_2024/3162_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2403_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2400_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1988_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1984_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1955_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1951_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1953_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1952_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1950_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1928_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2024/1766_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1672_Liquidity-provider-utxo-management.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Liquidity provider utxo management</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T02:13:51.637443+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/liquidity-provider-utxo-management/600/13" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent developments in optimizing transaction fees through innovative coin selection strategies have garnered significant attention within the cryptocurrency community, particularly among Bitcoin developers and Lightning Service Providers (LSPs). A focal point of these discussions has been the draft pull request [PR 30080](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30080) on Bitcoin's GitHub repository. This PR introduces an advanced parameter, `add_excess_to_recipient_position`, aimed at enhancing efficiency in transactions by allocating excess input values to outputs under user control rather than expending these as fees. This strategy is particularly advantageous in high-fee environments where the creation of change outputs becomes costly, thereby conserving value by reducing unnecessary fee expenditures.

An extensive simulation conducted to assess the impact of this new parameter revealed promising results. The simulation, which analyzed over 24,809 funding transactions, indicated that the addition of excess to the funding output could significantly reduce extra transaction fees by about 14%, compared to a 26% increase in the baseline scenario without any changes to coin selection algorithms. This outcome highlights the potential for more economical transaction fee management through strategic coin selection adjustments. Furthermore, the use of the `max_excess` parameter, while not drastically affecting the extra fees result, showed an increase in changeless transactions, thus promoting more efficient UTXO management and fostering the creation of new funding opportunities within the mempool.

Another aspect of the discussion revolves around the Python script [`simulate-funding-v2.py`](https://github.com/remyers/coin-selection-simulation/blob/c82354cb7d13ed2ff64f2044e400be8e6d9e123f/scripts/simulate-funding-v2.py), developed as a faster alternative to traditional bitcoind-based simulations. This script aims to simplify the coin selection process by identifying the best single input for each funding attempt, bypassing the complexities of bitcoind's algorithms. The goal is to discover heuristics that minimize total fees across simulations, providing an avenue for further research into cost-effective transaction execution.

Moreover, the conversation extends to the practical considerations of coin selection mechanisms, highlighting the advantages of specific algorithms such as CoinGrinder and Branch and Bound (BnB) over others like Knapsack and SRD. These preferred algorithms are believed to offer more efficient outcomes in terms of reducing total transaction fees and optimizing liquidity management. The email suggests potential modifications to the `sendmany` RPC call to enable selective algorithm usage, aiming to refine the transaction process for better economic and operational efficiency.

The dialogue also touches upon the broader implications of these optimization strategies beyond their immediate application to Bitcoin and Lightning Network transactions. It considers how these methods could be beneficial in scenarios involving coin join operations and send-only exchange wallets, indicating a wider relevance and applicability of the proposed solutions.

In summary, the discussions encapsulate a concerted effort within the cryptocurrency development community to enhance transaction efficiency through innovative coin selection strategies. By focusing on reducing unnecessary fee expenditures and optimizing the use of UTXOs, these strategies aim to improve the overall economic viability of conducting transactions on the blockchain. The ongoing experiments and proposals, such as [PR 30080](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/30080), signify a proactive approach to addressing the challenges of transaction fee management, with potential benefits extending across various applications and users within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2024-09-11T15:14:28.042000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
