<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-05-22T03:11:44.275067+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T03:11:44.275231+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Cryptographic attestation emerges as a significant advancement in enhancing transparency and verifiability within mining pools, enabling a robust audit mechanism for miners to verify payouts. This technology allows mining pools to sign individual shares at the time of validation, ensuring that any post-validation modifications are easily identifiable as malicious behavior. The proposal underscores the minimal overhead introduced by this protocol and argues that the inherent delay in the auditing process is negligible compared to the existing payout delays within mining pools. Therefore, the benefits of ensuring transparent and verifiable share logs through cryptographic attestation are deemed to outweigh potential timing concerns.

The discourse extends into the realm of digital currency transactions, particularly focusing on the innovative use of ehash multiple times. A key aspect discussed is the swap mechanism that yields two outputs from a transaction: the actual reward and another ehash, facilitating a unique approach to transaction verification and reward mechanisms. The link between an ehash and its corresponding share, facilitated by a mint, introduces flexibility into the system, reminiscent of traditional ecash systems but adapted for digital currency transactions. This concept is further elaborated in the [keyset documentation](https://github.com/cashubtc/nuts/blob/6024402ff8bcbe511e3e689f6d85f5464ecc3982/02.md), highlighting the complexities and opportunities in reusing ehashes within digital currencies.

The complexities of implementing a system for reusing ecash are also explored, emphasizing the challenge posed by its one-time-use nature. Proposals for allowing the reuse of ehash upon redemption, while receiving another ehash for future use, underscore the need for innovative solutions in tracking and linking ehashes to specific shares. This conversation points to the necessity for a robust system capable of managing the lifecycle of ehashes securely and efficiently.

Furthermore, the email solicits technical feedback on a cryptographic protocol, seeking insights into potential vulnerabilities or weaknesses. This request indicates a deep commitment to refining the protocol by addressing identified flaws, showcasing a proactive approach to enhancing the system's integrity through constructive criticism.

Transparency in mining operations is further highlighted, with emphasis on sharing accounting and accountability protocols. The introduction of cryptographic attestation as an additional verification layer aims to bolster trust among miners by providing tools for independent verification of pool claims regarding payouts. This approach is supplemented by a discussion on GitHub, offering insights into practical and technological considerations for enhancing transparency and accountability in mining pools.

The conversation also reflects on the practicality and benefits of adopting specific strategies or technologies by mining pools. It concludes with a recognition of the absence of tangible advantages in implementing the discussed approach, underscoring the importance of thorough analysis in decision-making processes related to new technologies in cryptocurrency mining.

Additionally, the discourse sheds light on the immediate liquidity challenges and potential solutions within cryptocurrency mining payout systems. Stratum V2's custom work selection feature is highlighted as a significant advancement towards ensuring fair compensation for miners without manual intervention. However, limitations inherent in current payout schemes, such as PPLNS and PPS, complicate the automation of payout verification, pointing to transparency as a feasible step toward empowering miners.

The TIDES documentation provides clarity on share weighting, indicating a nuanced approach to valuation diverging from a direct satoshi conversion. This decision reflects a preference for simplicity in the system's design, avoiding complexities associated with retrospective value assignment of blind signatures.

Lastly, the email discusses the implications of NUT 16 within the Cashu framework, critiquing its potential complexity and regulatory implications for non-KYC compliant mining pools. Concerns are raised about the practicality of micro-payouts and the broader implications of adopting NUT 16, suggesting skepticism towards its benefits for custodial mining pools already complying with KYC/AML regulations.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T11:16:50.720000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
