<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-06-15T02:02:12.875458+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow101 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T02:02:12.875583+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877/17" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens with a technical exploration of the challenges and considerations in implementing silent payments within the Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBT) framework. It outlines the potential risks associated with relying on the ordering of inputs due to the modifiability feature, suggesting that any reliance on consistent input order could lead to issues if an unaware constructor adds an input incorrectly. This concern extends to the implementation of silent payment outputs, emphasizing that such outputs should only be added under specific conditions to prevent unintended modifications by constructors who might not be aware of silent payments.

A significant portion of the discussion is dedicated to enhancing the security and efficiency of PSBTs through cryptographic innovations. One notable proposal involves the inclusion of fields such as `PSBT_IN_SP_ECDH_SHARE` and `PSBT_IN_SP_DLEQ`, alongside a `PSBT_OUT_SP_V0_INFO` field. These additions aim to facilitate the secure and efficient computation of silent payments by allowing parsers that understand silent payments to generate the necessary output scripts without compromising backward compatibility or transaction integrity.

Further, the conversation delves into the optimization and management of cryptographic proofs within transactions. The original draft for the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) suggests significant changes, including the removal of the OutputGenerator role, focusing instead on using the Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) share technique for enhanced security. This shift towards a more secure method of calculating transactions underscores the ongoing efforts to balance efficiency with security, particularly in transactions involving multiple signers and recipients.

Central to the dialogue is the challenge of ensuring transaction integrity and security, especially in complex scenarios like coinjoins. The proposal posits that it's not necessary to generate separate proofs for every output, advocating instead for a system where proofs are attached to inputs. This approach aims to reduce the computational and data overhead associated with securing transactions. Additionally, it discusses the possibility of simplifying the signing process in cases where a single signer controls all relevant private keys, suggesting a more streamlined method for verifying transaction authenticity.

The email chain also touches on practical aspects of implementing silent payments in PSBTs, detailing a basic workflow developed for a donation wallet. This includes modifications to the spend private key through a `shared_secret_tweak` and the use of proprietary fields to manage silent payment addresses. While this setup is described as an initial, somewhat limited approach, it lays the groundwork for future enhancements aimed at integrating silent payments more seamlessly into blockchain transactions.

In summary, the conversation encapsulates a broad spectrum of technical discussions focused on improving the PSBT framework to support silent payments securely and efficiently. From addressing the intricacies of input and output management to exploring cryptographic proofs and proposing new fields for secure transactions, the dialogue reflects a deep engagement with the challenges of enhancing privacy, security, and operational efficiency in cryptocurrency transactions.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T23:48:23.139000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
