<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
  <updated>2024-08-06T02:06:03.757180+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>vazertuche 2024-08-05 21:35:18.395000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-29 21:00:11.488000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-22 14:51:45.345000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-21 14:07:17.974000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-21 13:41:15.741000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-21 13:15:06.505000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-20 20:29:14.700000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-20 09:21:52.200000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-18 15:50:41.699000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-18 13:10:57.761000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:48:23.139000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 23:45:29.411000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 19:24:15.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-14 18:38:31.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-14 18:10:10.742000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>achow  . 2024-06-13 23:11:18.592000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-11 03:41:52.012000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-02 08:44:37.010000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-06-02 01:44:13.210000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-06-01 18:04:52.150000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-29 13:51:12.405000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-28 12:16:55.572000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 22:13:47.258000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-27 00:34:44.509000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>andrewtoth  . 2024-05-20 17:56:49.967000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-20 12:01:29.956000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Sosthene  . 2024-05-19 17:32:48.113000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josibake  . 2024-05-17 11:51:04.620000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Aug_2024/2918_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2828_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2779_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2778_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2777_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2776_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2773_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2771_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2741_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2740_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2719_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2720_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2718_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2717_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2716_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2712_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2681_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2596_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2595_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2594_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2562_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2553_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2548_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2539_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2478_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2462_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2458_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2441_BIP352-PSBT-support.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352: PSBT support</title>
    <updated>2024-08-06T02:06:03.757360+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-psbt-support/877" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation opens with a discussion on the integration of the Anti-exfil protocol into the secp256k1 library, highlighting its relevance due to demands for Discrete Logarithm Equality (DLEQ) proofs in future updates and the necessity posed by vulnerabilities such as those exposed by the darkskippy.com attack. This suggestion is motivated by the need for broader hardware wallet support and the aim to enhance security measures within core cryptographic libraries, presenting an opportunity to address multiple concerns simultaneously.

A shift in strategy for handling DLEQ proofs within Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) is observed, leading to the separation of these proofs into their own BIP to maintain clarity and focus in the PSBT draft. This move, inspired by RubenSomsen's work, aims to organize Bitcoin's technical frameworks more thoughtfully, ensuring specialized topics receive the dedicated attention they require for refinement and discussion within the community.

Technical challenges surrounding group proofs and silent payment verification are discussed, emphasizing the complexities of ensuring transaction integrity and the specific conditions under which transactions should be invalidated to maintain security. These intricacies underscore the importance of precise proof handling and input management to prevent potential vulnerabilities during the transaction verification process.

Moreover, the dialogue explores methodologies for optimizing the verification process for silent payment transactions, proposing several strategies for signers to efficiently verify transactions while considering the computational and memory capabilities of their devices. This includes suggestions for global versus per-input proof applications, aiming to balance processing power and memory usage effectively.

The text also delves into the nuances of transaction signing practices, particularly focusing on the security implications of using different signature types, such as `ACP` and `ALL`. It emphasizes the critical nature of choosing secure signing methods to protect funds and outlines scenarios demonstrating how various approaches can either safeguard or potentially compromise transaction integrity.

Further, the conversation addresses the technicalities of implementing silent payments within the PSBT framework, examining the roles of constructors, updaters, and signers in ensuring transaction integrity. It proposes adjustments to streamline the efficiency of verifying silent payments, suggesting modifications to the PSBT's structure to accommodate new fields aimed at enhancing privacy and compatibility.

Lastly, the text concludes with a comprehensive overview of ongoing proposals and discussions aimed at refining the implementation of confidential transactions and cryptographic protocols within blockchain networks. This includes exploring efficient ways to manage and verify cryptographic proofs, enhancing the security and privacy of transactions through innovative approaches to key management and signature verification, and considering the implications of new additions to the BIP draft that focus on integrating advanced cryptographic techniques.

Overall, the discourse encapsulates a forward-thinking exploration of cryptographic enhancements within the context of Bitcoin transactions, emphasizing community collaboration, technical innovation, and a thorough consideration of security and privacy implications as the ecosystem evolves.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T21:35:18.395000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
