<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - FE'd Up Covenants</title>
  <updated>2024-06-01T02:06:19.351131+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AdamISZ</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2590_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2589_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2588_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2587_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2586_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2584_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2583_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2580_FE-d-Up-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - FE'd Up Covenants</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T02:06:19.351237+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fed-up-covenants/929" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussed correspondence delves into the technical nuances and potential innovations within blockchain technology, specifically focusing on the development and implications of what's termed as "FE'd Up Covenants." These covenants represent a novel approach to managing and executing contracts or agreements directly within the blockchain framework without necessitating ongoing trust between parties or recurrent signatures from federations, which is a common requirement in traditional signing mechanisms. This method contrasts with regular federations that require active participation for validation, highlighting a shift towards a more autonomous and secure process where the initial setup by compilers suffices for the lifetime of the covenant, barring advancements in quantum computing that could disrupt current cryptographic practices.

The conversation further explores the mechanics behind these covenants, detailing the process of creating specific transaction signatures using functional encryption ($C_F$) and a particular process or key ($C_p$). It outlines a system wherein owners can generate public keys for covenant outputs through a combination of existing keys and transaction hashes, subsequently allowing anyone to produce a signature for a specified transaction. This capability underscores a significant advancement in script-based security and flexibility, providing a foundation for more intricate and self-enforcing contractual agreements within the blockchain ecosystem.

Moreover, an error was identified and clarified regarding the encryption and decryption functions, enhancing the understanding of the underlying cryptographic operations. The clarification pertains to the accurate usage of encryption keys and the decryption process, presenting a corrected viewpoint on how signatures are generated and verified within this framework. The discussion points out a typo related to variable naming, which is essential for maintaining the integrity and accuracy of the cryptographic processes described.

Additionally, the correspondence references a high-level paper that proposes the introduction of covenants to Bitcoin through a combination of Functional Encryption and Zero Knowledge Proofs without requiring a soft fork. This document is presented as a pivotal piece of literature for further discussion and exploration within the community, available at [https://rubin.io/bitcoin/2024/05/29/fed-up-covenants/](https://rubin.io/bitcoin/2024/05/29/fed-up-covenants/). The mentioned paper likely expands on the concepts discussed in the emails, offering a comprehensive analysis and theoretical background necessary for understanding and implementing such advanced cryptographic solutions in the context of Bitcoin and potentially other blockchain platforms.</summary>
    <published>2024-05-31T19:04:37.497000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
