<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
  <updated>2024-06-04T02:05:43.255959+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo 2024-06-03 17:16:36.575000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-06-02 21:08:52.095000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-31 20:13:43.809000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-24 13:07:52.580000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-23 21:57:57.171000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-23 07:29:56.103000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-21 11:16:50.720000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-20 23:51:47.228000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 21:26:33.276000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-19 15:43:33.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:53:41.633000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:44:40.880000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-19 00:41:14.044000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>MattCorallo  . 2024-05-17 17:32:19.936000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-17 10:29:21.212000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-17 02:30:14.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 02:14:39.285000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-17 01:45:46.482000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:18:12.704000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>plebhash  . 2024-05-16 21:38:15.178000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>calle  . 2024-05-16 10:20:39.195000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 10:07:06.183000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-16 01:25:28.001000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 01:04:54.921000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 22:54:49.056000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>davidcaseria  . 2024-05-15 22:25:05.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>EthnTuttle  . 2024-05-15 16:58:18.975000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2615_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2024/2604_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2591_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2530_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2527_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2514_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2484_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2479_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2460_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2457_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2456_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2455_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2454_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2447_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2437_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2435_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2434_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2433_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2424_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2431_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2427_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2426_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2423_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2422_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2421_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2420_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2418_Ecash-TIDES-using-Cashu-and-Stratum-v2.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Ecash TIDES using Cashu and Stratum v2</title>
    <updated>2024-06-04T02:05:43.256134+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ecash-tides-using-cashu-and-stratum-v2/870/27" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse evaluates the potential benefits of employing e-cash for making pool shares a tradable asset, alongside critiquing the complexity involved in linking shares directly to e-cash for payouts. It suggests that utilizing e-cash could streamline payout processes and enhance privacy without the need for complex modifications. The concept of cryptographic attestation is introduced as a means to ensure the integrity and authenticity of shares, proposing its integration into existing protocols like Sv2 to enhance security without adding unnecessary complexity. This method aims to maintain data integrity and instill trust within the system by authenticating individual shares through digital signatures.

The discussion further delves into the mechanics of electronic cash (ecash) transactions and the necessity for rapid redemption by recipients to mitigate double-spending risks. It highlights the share window concept from the TIDES documentation, which involves monitoring a constantly updating list of electronic hashes (ehashes) to maintain transaction integrity. The role of mints in tracking ownership and redemption of ehashes is elaborated upon, emphasizing the crucial function of accurately identifying current holders for effective management and redemption processes.

Privacy in payout processes is underscored as a primary focus, with suggestions to simplify mechanisms for enhancing transaction security and privacy. The proposal critiques delve into peripheral issues that detract from the core objective of improving privacy and suggest directing more attention towards relevant matters. Cryptographic attestation is explored as a verification method that not only secures share distribution but also facilitates transparent auditing by allowing pool participants to audit payouts independently.

The narrative examines the intricacies of reusing ehashes within a digital currency framework, proposing innovative solutions to address challenges associated with ecash reuse. It discusses the need for a robust system to manage ehash lifecycles securely and efficiently. Additionally, the conversation seeks technical feedback on a cryptographic protocol to identify vulnerabilities, emphasizing the importance of refining the protocol to mitigate identified weaknesses.

Transparency in mining pools is highlighted through discussions about share log transparency and the implementation of accountability protocols. These measures aim to provide miners with tools to verify payouts and make informed decisions regarding their mining pool affiliations. The dialogue acknowledges the challenges in automating fair and timely payouts due to limitations in current payout schemes and suggests enhancing transparency as a feasible step towards empowering miners.

On the topic of NUT 16 within the Cashu framework, concerns are raised about regulatory implications for non-KYC compliant mining pools and the practicality of using eCash for micro-payouts. The proposal's complexity and potential risks for custodial mining pools are scrutinized, questioning its overall benefit to the mining ecosystem. The discussion extends to the allocation of target difficulties in mining pools to accommodate diverse hardware capabilities, ensuring equitable compensation and operational stability.

Bolt12's introduction for improving liquidity and auditability within Lightning Network channels is discussed, focusing on facilitating micro payouts. This approach aims at simplifying participation and enhancing privacy through custodial wallets, complementing efforts towards decentralization. Lastly, the email touches upon the technical aspects of Bitcoin mining ASICs, the pursuit of minimizing payout thresholds, and the importance of cryptographic proof in maintaining the transparency and trustworthiness of mining pools, despite the challenges posed by centralized structures.</summary>
    <published>2024-06-03T17:16:36.575000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
