<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
  <updated>2024-07-31T01:47:58.493737+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>tony 2024-07-30 02:07:35.029000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>mcelrath  . 2024-07-23 13:08:44.042000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cdecker  . 2024-07-12 11:16:37.983000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptorevue  . 2024-05-30 16:40:43.188000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-30 15:49:44.159000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>cryptorevue  . 2024-05-27 21:20:32.118000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-18 16:38:35.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bytes  . 2024-05-16 22:29:28.256000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>tony  . 2024-05-16 17:49:21.750000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2904_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2892_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2024/2878_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2577_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2576_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2547_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2453_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2432_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2024/2430_Stable-Channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Stable Channels - peer-to-peer dollar balances on Lightning</title>
    <updated>2024-07-31T01:47:58.493812+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/stable-channels-peer-to-peer-dollar-balances-on-lightning/875/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Stable Channels presents a unique approach to stability within the Bitcoin ecosystem, diverging from typical stablecoins or fiat-pegged currencies. It operates on the Lightning Network, using bitcoin as its base without introducing any external tokens or assets. This mechanism allows for the creation of channels that are not susceptible to the same risks as centralized stablecoins, such as bank runs, because it lacks a central point of failure and users maintain self-custody of their funds. The system is designed to withstand market fluctuations, allowing users to retain more bitcoin during downturns, which could be seen as an indirect way of buying the dip.

The debate around Fiat channels and Tony's construction within the Bitcoin Lightning Network highlights the differences in custody and operational mechanisms. Fiat channels require custodial control, whereas Tony's construction allows for direct currency mixing and swap services within the same LN node, offering a non-custodial solution. This distinction emphasizes the need for clear communication regarding the capabilities and limitations of different solutions within the Lightning Network to ensure users make informed decisions based on their requirements for custody and flexibility.

Hosted channels, operating under a custodial model, contrast with the non-custodial nature of Stable Channels. The reliance on oracles for pricing in fiat channels introduces potential risks, such as forced closures due to discrepancies among oracles. This complexity underscores the challenges in achieving stable value exchanges in digital currencies, pointing towards a balance between technical solutions and financial stability mechanisms.

The introduction of Fiat Channels brings attention to cryptocurrency operations and liquidity enhancements within the Lightning Network. By focusing on standardizing Satoshi transactions, improving liquidity management, and envisioning the widespread use of Satoshi as a standard transaction unit, these initiatives aim to streamline transactions, address scalability, and promote financial inclusion within the cryptocurrency ecosystem.

Communicating the trade-offs between different systems, such as self-custodial Lightning setups and custodial solutions like ecash, is crucial for user understanding and market competition. The integration of Cashu within Stable Channels illustrates an attempt to create a stable dollar token, demonstrating both the advantages of scalability and user experience over traditional Lightning approaches and the inherent custodial risks.

Stable Channels seeks to mitigate bitcoin’s price volatility by matching short positions seeking fiat stability with long positions providing it, thereby creating a synthetic balance of dollar values within the Lightning Network. This initiative aims to enhance the utility of the Lightning Network by addressing operational challenges and exploring risk factors, attack vectors, and mitigation techniques. The project’s integration with derivative trading and the Chaumian eCash system Cashu highlights its potential in offering decentralized financial instruments and addressing the volatility that limits bitcoin's wider adoption.</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T02:07:35.029000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
