<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Lightning Fees - inbound vs outbound</title>
  <updated>2024-01-04T13:54:25.700867+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.472000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2023-01-12T07:16:51.472000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Lightning Fees - inbound vs outbound</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T13:54:25.700867+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/lightning-fees-inbound-vs-outbound/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In a scenario where Alice and Bob are negotiating fees for payment transactions through a channel, the dynamics of fee optimization play out interestingly under different assumptions about their knowledge of channel demand. When both parties possess complete knowledge of the channel demand, represented as a function $Q(f)$ that predicts the payment volume based on a given total fee $f$, they can calculate the optimal fees to maximize revenue. The total fee is expressed as the sum of outbound and inbound fees, with Alice receiving fee $a$ and Bob receiving fee $b$. If each party knows the demand perfectly, they will independently arrive at an even split of fees ($a = b$) by setting the derivative of their respective earnings in relation to their own fee to zero.

However, this even split does not necessarily result in the maximization of the total fees collected. Both parties are inclined to raise their fees above the optimal level because they benefit from increasing their individual fee while sharing the loss due to reduced demand with their partner. This behavior might lead to a situation where the combined fee $a + b$ is higher than the optimal fee $f^{opt}$, which would reduce the total income to less than what could be achieved with a balanced approach.

If the assumption of perfect knowledge is removed, Alice and Bob may optimize against different demand predictions, $Q_A(f)$ and $Q_B(f)$ respectively. Their individual calculations would generally lead to different values for $a$ and $b$. In the given example, the resolution results in $a=5-b/{2}$ and $b = 7.5-a/2$ or $a=5/3$ and $b=20/3$. Interestingly, in such a case, the channel activity alone does not allow either party to falsify the other's prediction of demand. If Alice's prediction is accurate, Bob stands to profit more by lowering his fee to encourage more traffic; if Bob's prediction is correct, Alice benefits from increasing her fee despite an overall reduction in channel traffic.

This discussion illustrates the complexity of fee negotiations in payment channels and highlights how varying degrees of knowledge and economic incentives can influence the decision-making process. It underscores the importance of understanding demand functions and the impact of strategic fee setting on overall revenue in payment networks.</summary>
    <published>2023-01-12T07:16:51.472000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
