<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Delving Simplicity Part Ⅳ:Two Side Effects</title>
  <updated>2025-11-04T02:44:02.462545+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>roconnor-blockstream.409000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-03T18:58:48.409000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Delving Simplicity Part Ⅳ:Two Side Effects</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T02:44:02.462580+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/delving-simplicity-part-two-side-effects/2091" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the ongoing exploration of Simplicity, a programming language tailored for blockchain applications like Bitcoin and Liquid, the series delves into enhancing computational expressions with side effects. Side effects, in this context, vary widely from state updates to logging, and their integration is pivotal for extending the functional scope of Simplicity beyond its core combinators, which are sufficient for any finite pure computation. For Bitcoin and Liquid, the focus narrows down to two specific side effects: the Failure effect, acting as an exception mechanism where the exception type is unit (`𝟙`), and the Reader effect, facilitating access to transaction-related data.

Jets, a concept introduced to incorporate new primitives with side effects, play a crucial role in this expansion. Examples include `bip0340-verify`, a jet designed for Schnorr signature validation that leverages the Failure effect by aborting computations upon validation failure, and `sig-all-hash`, which employs the Reader effect to produce transaction hash values analogous to Bitcoin Script's `SIGHASH_ALL`. These jets exemplify how side effects can be seamlessly integrated into Simplicity's framework, enabling more complex transactional operations while adhering to the language's purity principles.

The discussion further classifies side effects based on their compatibility with program transformations—commutative, idempotent, and unitary effects. Commutative effects allow the swapping of expression outputs without altering the overall effect, making them favorable for certain optimizations. Idempotent effects permit the duplication of expressions without changing their outcome, and unitary effects enable the discarding of expressions without impact, provided the effect remains unchanged. Simplicity prioritizes effects that are both commutative and idempotent, allowing for a broader range of program optimizations.

The rationale behind incorporating side effects into Simplicity stems from practical considerations. For instance, the Failure effect supports batch verification of Schnorr signatures, enhancing efficiency by pooling multiple signature checks into a single operation. Additionally, the Reader effect leverages precomputed transaction data to maintain constant-time performance for transaction hash calculations, addressing scalability challenges observed in early Bitcoin Script implementations. Looking ahead, features like cross-input signature aggregation are anticipated, suggesting further extensions of Simplicity’s capabilities through additional side effects such as the Writer effect.

This installment not only illuminates the technical advancements within Simplicity but also underscores the strategic incorporation of side effects to bolster both the functionality and efficiency of blockchain applications. By carefully selecting and implementing these effects, Simplicity aims to provide a robust foundation for developing secure, scalable, and sophisticated smart contract systems on platforms like Bitcoin and Liquid. The exploration of adding inputs such as digital signatures to Simplicity programs is slated for future discussions, promising further enhancements to this innovative programming language.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-03T18:58:48.409000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
