<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-06T02:45:59.468534+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-11-05 22:39:58.538000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T02:45:59.468575+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussion on the implementation and functionality of covenants within blockchain technology, particularly focusing on the use of zero-knowledge proofs (ZKPs) such as STARKs, an intricate mechanism is outlined. This mechanism involves the binding of spending conditions to the script authors. Specifically, it necessitates a Schnorr signature over a message that incorporates a commitment to the proof in the locking script at the time the Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) is created. This requirement introduces a nuanced approach to creating covenants in blockchain transactions.

The inquiry raises a critical analysis of how these mechanisms enforce transaction shape restrictions through the use of ZKPs. It suggests that, for a covenant to be effectively implemented, there may need to be an element of introspection or the capability for the STARK verifier to accept a signature as an additional piece of input. This points towards a sophisticated interaction between the cryptographic verification processes and the transaction parameters defined by the script authors.

This discussion hints at the broader implications for blockchain security and the development of smart contracts. By leveraging advanced cryptographic techniques such as Schnorr signatures and STARKs within the framework of script authoring, developers can craft more secure and versatile covenants. These covenants are pivotal for enhancing the control over transaction flows and ensuring adherence to predefined rules, thereby fostering a more robust blockchain ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T22:39:58.538000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
