<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-07T02:43:55.535497+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-07T01:06:06.018000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T02:43:55.535539+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of a decentralized bitcoin mining network, termed as a "p2share" network, introduces an innovative framework for the distribution of mining rewards. This network operates under its own set of consensus rules, similar to how traditional bitcoin functions, with the distinctive feature being the manner in which rewards are allocated to miners. In this system, miners are rewarded with "shares" for creating valid blocks. These shares are transferable among participants, allowing for a dynamic and fluid ecosystem where ownership can change hands based on the network's predefined rules.

A notable aspect of the p2share network is its method of distributing the bitcoin reward from a successfully mined block. Unlike conventional methods that either distribute rewards proportionally among all participating miners or rely on centralized services for allocation, this network adopts a unique approach by awarding the entire bitcoin reward to a single shareholder. This selection is made randomly among all shareholders, thus introducing a novel mechanism for reward distribution. The process ensures that the coinbase output remains compact, thereby minimizing transaction bloat and maximizing the potential revenue from fee-paying transactions on the bitcoin network.

This model presents several advantages, including maintaining fairness over time as every share is expected to be rewarded in proportion to its prevalence in the total supply, ensuring efficiency by keeping the bitcoin coinbase output small, and upholding a trustless and decentralized environment as the selection process is deterministic and governed by the network's consensus rules. Moreover, it aligns incentives among miners to accumulate shares, enhancing their chances of receiving the bitcoin reward, whether actively mining or holding shares as a speculative asset.

Several questions arise regarding the viability and implications of the p2share network. These include considerations about incentive compatibility for miners, the distinction between a sharechain network and a sidechain, and the potential impact on Bitcoin's mainnet. The network's relationship with Bitcoin's security is also noteworthy, as it contributes to, rather than detracts from, the overall security of Bitcoin by functioning essentially as a mining pool from Bitcoin's perspective.

In conclusion, the p2share network offers a fresh perspective on mining incentives and network participation, encouraging a more decentralized and innovative ecosystem within the realm of Bitcoin mining. By reimagining the distribution of rewards and leveraging the principles of fairness, efficiency, and trustlessness, this model holds the potential to influence future developments in blockchain technology and cryptocurrency mining practices.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T01:06:06.018000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
