<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-08T02:26:52.123772+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-07T09:30:26.903000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-08T02:26:52.123805+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the adaptability and functionality of millisatoshis within the Lightning Network, emphasizing their potential to represent internal divisions of amounts among participants without deviating from the underlying Bitcoin blockchain. This underscores a critical viewpoint that as long as transactions remain presigned and compatible with Bitcoin, new implementations leveraging millisatoshis can emerge without necessitating the creation of an alternate cryptocurrency. The emphasis is on maintaining the integrity and continuity of Bitcoin's ecosystem, suggesting that innovative uses of Bitcoin are feasible and desirable as long as they adhere to its foundational principles.

Moreover, the conversation touches on the security aspects of such implementations, drawing parallels between the proposed network's resilience against attacks and the established mechanisms within the Lightning Network, like penalty transactions. This comparison serves to highlight the possibility of creating a secure environment that deters fraudulent activities while enabling new functionalities within the Bitcoin framework.

Additionally, the dialogue explores the implications of block time durations on network functionality, positing that the traditional 10-minute block interval of Bitcoin might not only be adequate but preferable for certain applications, such as DNS records. It suggests that flexibility in block times, potentially even extending them, could cater to specific needs without compromising the system's overall efficiency. For scenarios requiring shorter block intervals, solutions like P2Pool demonstrate that layering additional systems atop Bitcoin can address these demands, thereby reinforcing the argument that Bitcoin's infrastructure offers a versatile foundation for innovation.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T09:30:26.903000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
