<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-10T02:50:31.499170+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-11-09 06:07:07.470000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T02:50:31.499210+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The process of determining a value `q` through a specific calculation that involves the sha256 function, block headers from the sharechain, and a modulus operation based on the number of shares outstanding at a given block, introduces a mechanism where rewards on the Bitcoin blockchain are linked to the shares owned in the share network. This setup presents a significant risk for what is known as a grinding attack. In such an attack, an individual with a substantial portion of shares and more than half of the hashrate on the share network can manipulate future mining efforts to ensure rewards are consistently directed towards them. This manipulation is achieved by influencing the outcome of the hash function used to select who gets the mining reward.

This potential for grinding attacks underscores a fundamental flaw within proof-of-stake systems: the assumption that it's not possible to predict or influence the selection of who wins the staking reward. However, as outlined, the ability to grind the selection process effectively transforms the system into a proof-of-work mechanism but with additional complexities. Such complexities not only fail to solve inherent problems but might introduce new vulnerabilities. For instance, a scenario where a single operator initially controls a majority of shares and hashrate could deter other miners from joining the network. Without sufficient incentive for others to participate, the network cannot achieve the decentralization needed to distribute shares widely and mitigate the risk of centralized control.

Moreover, the discussion highlights how increasing complexity in mining mechanisms can inadvertently open doors to exploitations, much like the ASICBOOST method disrupted the mining industry and delayed SegWit activation. The implication here is clear: while attempting to innovate within the mining space, there's a real risk of simply creating convoluted systems that offer no real improvement over traditional methods. Instead, they may only serve to centralize control further or introduce unintended weaknesses, drawing parallels to the critique of solo-mining but with unnecessary additional steps.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-09T06:07:07.470000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
