<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-10T02:50:44.245881+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>cmp_ancp</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-09T14:44:47.356000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T02:50:44.245914+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of integrating a "pool sidechain" with blockchain technology presents an innovative approach to decentralized mining and resource coordination. The notion revolves around allowing miners to commit to a sidechain while they are mining Bitcoin (BTC) blocks. This could be achieved by incorporating commitments into the nonce or the coinbase, potentially involving a Merkle tree that contains multiple values. Such a system would enable miners to contribute proof of their computational efforts, even in instances where they do not successfully mine a block. By submitting what are known as weak blocks to the sidechain, miners can demonstrate that they are actively expending power in the mining process.

An intriguing aspect of this idea is the potential for the sidechain to support faster block times, which could be structured in a variety of ways, including a lattice configuration. This flexibility suggests that miners would not need to synchronize with the entire sidechain, as the necessary commitments could be accessible on the BTC blockchain itself. This method of integrating commitments could significantly streamline the interaction between the main blockchain and the sidechain.

However, the proposal also acknowledges the importance of efficiency and sustainability. It's crucial that such a system does not impose excessive bandwidth demands or computational strain on participants. The underlying principle is that adopting this pool sidechain methodology should not disadvantage miners by increasing their operational costs or reducing their mining efficiency. The ultimate goal is to enhance the mining ecosystem without compromising its accessibility or profitability for individual miners. This concept invites further exploration and development from those within the community who have the expertise to refine and realize its potential.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-09T14:44:47.356000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
