<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:09.551965+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr 2025-11-09 21:11:28.980000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:09.551996+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the innovative concept of sharechain networks and their potential integration with Bitcoin to enhance economic and philosophical outcomes. The concept draws inspiration from P2Pool's approach but introduces transferable shares and a fixed schedule for fair share issuance, aiming to prolong the lifespan of sharechain networks. These networks are envisioned as symbiotic with Bitcoin, serving as platforms for testing new features, uses, and services that may not be suitable for the main Bitcoin network. The speculative value of these shares remains uncertain, echoing early skepticism about Bitcoin's value.

The proposal suggests that directing even a small fraction of Bitcoin's overall hashrate through such networks could generate meaningful information signals within the Bitcoin ecosystem. This leads to a broader discussion on the desirability of converting non-Bitcoin investments into Bitcoin-compatible proof of work, arguing for the benefits of incorporating investments like equity in Wall Street companies into the Bitcoin ecosystem. The underlying rationale is to promote a transition towards a more Bitcoin-centric investment model, away from traditional fiat systems and their associated mindset.

The p2share model is highlighted as a mechanism allowing Bitcoin holders to invest in future mining earnings of specific sharechain networks. This model is considered risky yet trustless, offering a unique way to support the Bitcoin ecosystem while potentially bypassing traditional financial systems. The discussion acknowledges the challenges of bootstrapping such networks, acknowledging that initial hurdles might include low network difficulty and competition for shares.

An analysis suggests that if participants value Bitcoin's future and see p2share as a means to support it, they might direct their mining power towards sharechains aligning with their preferences. This behavior would not only secure the Bitcoin network but also decentralize it further, sending a clear signal of the community's desired future directions. The comparison is made to the practice of accumulating Bitcoin itself, suggesting that participation in sharechain mining could be seen as an extension of behaviors already encouraged within the Bitcoin community. However, the conversation remains open-ended, questioning whether the p2share concept will ultimately prove viable.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-09T21:11:28.980000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
