<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:18.853174+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-09T23:15:13.002000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:18.853216+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse raises critical viewpoints on the evolution and adaptability of Bitcoin, emphasizing the necessity for Bitcoin to demonstrate its ability to evolve before considering the implementation of new features or testing grounds. It highlights a fundamental principle from Bitcoin's whitepaper, the idea that the "longest chain of proof-of-work wins," which inherently suggests a singular Bitcoin despite the emergence of various altcoins. This principle underscores the unique position Bitcoin holds in the cryptocurrency space, attributing its dominance to being the first of its kind, where early participants could experiment freely with what were then valueless tokens.

Furthermore, the discussion introduces a hypothetical scenario where Bitcoin miners could adhere to additional self-imposed rules within a specific sub-network, without applying these rules to the broader Bitcoin network. This concept, referred to as a "softerfork," suggests a form of network modification that is less invasive than a traditional softfork. In this softerfork, while the overarching network remains unchanged, a sub-network could implement new rules, potentially allowing for innovations like committing to an extra non-Bitcoin block that transacts a separate currency with distinct semantics. This proposal presents an innovative way to explore new functionalities within the Bitcoin ecosystem, without necessitating a complete consensus or altering the foundational protocols of the entire network.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-09T23:15:13.002000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
