<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-11T02:46:52.874988+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr.824000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-10T21:26:38.824000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T02:46:52.875021+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the innovative p2share model and its implications for Bitcoin's blockchain, emphasizing the concept of a "softerfork" as a notable advancement in cryptocurrency technology. The p2share model, by design, integrates work done on a sharechain with the main Bitcoin chain, suggesting that efforts to secure a sharechain directly contribute to the security of the main Bitcoin blockchain. This model posits an intriguing method of selecting random shareholders to validate transactions, which could potentially align with the principle of incentive compatibility without the prerequisite for participants to be existing bitcoin miners. It opens up the possibility for enthusiasts with minimal hashing power to initiate a softerfork, exploring new avenues beyond traditional mining practices.

The dialogue also addresses concerns regarding why individuals or entities would prefer mining on a sharechain over direct solo mining on the mainchain and the potential risks of larger miners attacking the sharechain. Despite these challenges, the inherent proof-of-work mechanism of sharechains ensures that any attack entails a significant, irreversible cost, thus deterring frivolous attempts to undermine the network. Interestingly, even if larger miners were to attempt disrupting the sharechain, their actions would inadvertently bolster the security of the main Bitcoin blockchain, highlighting a unique self-preserving feature of this model.

Moreover, the conversation touches upon the economic incentives for miners, especially larger ones, to engage with sharechains. Market dynamics and the prospect of arbitrage opportunities between sharechain shares and mainchain Bitcoin might attract miners to participate in sharechain activities, thus diversifying their mining operations. The speculative nature of these engagements suggests a natural cap on the price per share in satoshis, ensuring that sharechains complement rather than compete with Bitcoin. This approach could potentially decentralize mining efforts, reducing the dominance of large mining pools.

Finally, the exchange introduces technical inquiries about the p2poolv2 project, aiming to rejuvenate certain aspects of the original P2Pool concepts while maintaining a non-custodial framework akin to p2share. Questions raised include the custodial nature of the project, the motivations behind market makers or large miners purchasing smaller shares, and the longevity or expiration of shares within the system. These queries underscore a continued interest in evolving the decentralized mining landscape, fostering a collaborative environment for development and innovation in the cryptocurrency domain.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-10T21:26:38.824000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
