<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T02:44:37.703003+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jungly 2025-11-11 07:59:21.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T02:44:37.703042+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discussion introduces a novel approach in the realm of cryptocurrency mining, specifically concerning the p2poolv2 concept which is under development. This new model is designed to ensure that mining remains non-custodial, diverging from traditional methods that may involve custodial elements such as FROST federations. The core idea revolves around rewarding the top 20 miners within any Pay-Per-Last-N-Shares (PPLNS) window directly through bitcoin coinbase transactions. Meanwhile, smaller miners obtain shares on a sharechain, which they can then sell to larger miners or market makers via atomic swaps. This system necessitates support for Script-based transactions on the sharechain to accommodate such exchanges and potential future applications using technologies like Ark/Spark.

The motivation for large miners or market makers to purchase shares from smaller miners stems from two primary incentives. Firstly, they have the opportunity to acquire these shares at a discount, where the rate is determined by market dynamics. Secondly, maintaining their position among the top 20 miners to secure direct payouts from the coinbase presents another advantage. However, this arrangement carries inherent risks, particularly if p2pool fails to find a block within a specific PPLNS window, which would render the purchased shares worthless for that period.

An important aspect of this design is the temporal limitation imposed on shares. Shares are only valid for the duration of a PPLNS window, expiring afterwards. This temporal boundary clarifies the risk for market makers, who must consider the pool's hashrate and the likelihood of finding a block within each window when deciding on the discount rate for purchasing shares. The proposition includes potentially extending the length of the PPLNS window, currently contemplated to be as long as a week as opposed to the original p2pool's three-day window, to mitigate some of the risks involved. This change, however, is still under consideration and subject to further analysis before implementation.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-11T07:59:21.471000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
