<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T02:44:53.660063+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr 2025-11-11 19:37:16.933000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T02:44:53.660096+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The communication delves into the complexities of designing a cryptocurrency mining protocol, with a particular focus on how to manage and incentivize shareholder participation effectively. It outlines a proposal for recalibrating the discount factor `d`, which is integral to determining the value of shares within the system. This factor is divided into two components: `d_time` and `d_params`, where `d_time` accounts for the time-value-of-money considerations—emphasizing that immediate availability of assets is more valuable—and `d_params` represents protocol-specific constraints such as PPLNS window size and share expiry.

A significant portion of the discussion is dedicated to exploring how these parameters influence the market's functionality and the equitable distribution of rewards among shareholders, large and small. The correspondence suggests an ideal scenario where the market would price at `d = 1.0`, implying that all shares, irrespective of their size, are valued equally. This would encourage large miners and market makers to purchase shares from smaller shareholders at full price, thus maintaining a balanced and inclusive market environment.

However, the challenge lies in setting the `d_params` such that this ideal state can be approached without compromising the protocol's non-custodial nature and without necessitating changes to the mainchain bitcoin. The email proposes a theoretical design improvement wherein only a proportionate percentage of the mainchain bitcoin reward is allocated to the top shareholders, based on their share of the total outstanding shares, with the remainder distributed among the lesser shareholders through an off-chain mechanism. Yet, it acknowledges the difficulty of implementing such a model due to the constraints of mainchain covenants and the desire to remain non-custodial.

Further complicating the design is the method of dealing with share redemption and the distribution of rewards. The original concept presented was akin to a profit distribution model rather than a share buyback scheme, primarily due to unresolved issues like overflow—where a selected shareholder doesn't have enough shares for redemption—and the need to emulate market depth within the sharechain. A suggestion is made to explore a hybrid model, whereby shares are bought back or destroyed upon reward allocation, potentially encouraging shareholders to distribute their holdings across multiple outputs to minimize losses if selected. This idea aims to address the inefficiencies and imbalances in the current design, though it also recognizes potential downsides such as putting downward pressure on share prices and bloating the sharechain UTXO set.

Overall, the dialogue underscores the intricate balance required to devise a fair, efficient, and scalable mining protocol. It highlights the ongoing quest for an optimal design that maximizes marketability while remaining true to the principles of decentralization and non-custodianship.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-11T19:37:16.933000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
