<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Private Key Handover</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T02:45:56.823895+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj 2025-11-12 00:15:13.806000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Private Key Handover</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T02:45:56.823928+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/private-key-handover/2098/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Shared-spending Inter-Protocol Framework offers a sophisticated solution for managing Bitcoin transactions, particularly enhancing the capability of wallet software to handle complex transaction protocols. This framework introduces a methodology whereby it can automatically batch outputs into a single transaction without necessitating manual intervention from users to initiate batch processes. By embracing Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms, it affords flexibility in transaction management, ensuring that transactions can be adjusted or replaced based on network conditions or user requirements.

Key to this framework are two primary functions: `fund_output` and `spend_input`, each designed to facilitate specific types of transaction requests. The `fund_output` function is pivotal for creating transactions that aim to fund an address before a specified timeout. It leverages callbacks to interact with various protocols, determining the optimal set of Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) to utilize, calculating fees, and confirming transaction readiness before finalization. This system allows for dynamic interaction with protocols such as the Lightning Network's BOLT protocol, enabling seamless initiation and completion of channel funding transactions.

Conversely, the `spend_input` function caters to scenarios where a particular input must be spent by a certain deadline. This is particularly relevant in protocols requiring specific signing arrangements, such as those involving revocation keys in the Lightning Network. The framework's design to automatically handle fee surges and batch transactions underscores its utility in managing Bitcoin transactions efficiently. 

Moreover, the framework's architecture ensures robustness across system restarts. It achieves this through persistent storage of pending requests and predefined protocol registrations, allowing it to recover state and continue operations seamlessly after a restart. This approach not only enhances reliability but also simplifies integration with various protocols by using stable identifiers, thereby making the framework a versatile tool for Bitcoin transaction management.

In essence, the Shared-spending Inter-Protocol Framework represents a significant advancement in the realm of cryptocurrency wallets. By automating complex processes such as transaction batching and RBF, while ensuring compatibility with a wide range of protocols and maintaining resilience against disruptions, it sets a new standard for wallet functionality and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:15:13.806000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
