<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Private Key Handover</title>
  <updated>2025-11-13T02:50:54.771456+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ZmnSCPxj</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-12T00:15:13.806000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Private Key Handover</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T02:50:54.771488+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/private-key-handover/2098/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Shared-spending Inter-Protocol Framework introduces a sophisticated approach to Bitcoin wallet management, enabling the integration of additional protocols for enhanced flexibility in transaction handling. This framework allows for the automatic batching of transactions and supports Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms, streamlining the process for end-users who wish to fund outputs or spend inputs without delving into the complexities of batch transaction creation. By automating these processes, the framework significantly simplifies the user experience, providing an efficient and user-friendly interface for managing Bitcoin transactions.

At the core of this framework are two primary functions: `fund_output` and `spend_input`. The `fund_output` function is designed to initiate transactions for sending specific amounts before a designated timeout. It utilizes a series of callbacks to ensure that the transaction is created, signed, and confirmed efficiently. These callbacks include requesting an address to fund, confirming readiness for transaction creation, and acknowledging the completion of funding. This mechanism exemplifies the framework's ability to facilitate protocol interactions such as those outlined in the LN BOLT `openv1` protocol, thereby enhancing its utility for various applications.

The `spend_input` function, on the other hand, focuses on spending a specified input before a set timeout. This function also utilizes callbacks, notably for signing the transaction with a PSBT, highlighting the framework's capacity to accommodate different transaction requirements, including those necessitated by protocols like the LN BOLT `revocation` protocol. This versatility is further demonstrated through the framework's support for simple "send to an address" use cases, which benefit from automatic batching and RBF capabilities, improving transaction efficiency and flexibility in response to changing fee conditions.

A significant feature of the Shared-spending Inter-Protocol Framework is its resilience and reliability across restarts. By requiring pre-registration of protocols with stable identifiers and storing pending requests on persistent storage, the framework ensures continuity and integrity of operations through system restarts. This robustness is critical for maintaining transaction continuity and preventing data loss, making the framework a reliable tool for Bitcoin wallet management.

In summary, the Shared-spending Inter-Protocol Framework offers a comprehensive solution for enhancing Bitcoin transaction management through automatic batching, Replace-By-Fee strategies, and robust support for protocol integration. Its design prioritizes ease of use, flexibility, and reliability, catering to both end-users and developers seeking to implement advanced transaction protocols within their Bitcoin wallets.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:15:13.806000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
