<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-11-13T02:48:52.157773+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>junderw</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-12T15:56:16.956000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T02:48:52.157805+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion primarily revolves around the proposal for modifying Bitcoin transaction descriptor formats to enhance wallet recovery processes. The modification suggests excluding the use of descriptors and specific public and private key notations (sppub/spprv) while incorporating a transaction's birthday and a maximum label value as additional data points. This approach aims to simplify the recovery process by providing scanners with hints, thereby potentially negating the need to include overly detailed UTXO and ECDH information, which was deemed excessive for a descriptor.

The proposal also emphasizes the importance of standardizing the output format across different wallets to prevent confusion among users. It criticizes the current variability in output formats, such as some wallets using a complex mix of keys and others opting for simpler, user-friendly identifiers. The argument is made that a more standardized approach, possibly involving a single encoded string for scan and spend keys along with comma-separated birthday and maximum label values, would benefit users. This encoding method would inherently discourage users from tampering with the internal components of the data, reducing the risk of errors.

Furthermore, there's a consideration towards making the birthday and maximum label values easily alterable by end-users. This flexibility could lead to quicker initial scans by adjusting the birthday value, albeit with a trade-off against the completeness of the transaction history recovered. This part of the proposal seems to be in a contemplative phase, indicating openness to further discussion and refinement.

In summary, the conversation targets the enhancement of wallet recovery descriptors by proposing the inclusion of birthday and maximum label hints, advocating for standardized output formats to avoid user confusion, and contemplating the user's ability to adjust certain values for potentially more efficient recovery processes.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T15:56:16.956000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
