<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-11-14T02:46:42.450299+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>pyth.435000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-13T03:59:38.435000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T02:46:42.450326+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation touches on the importance of incorporating birthday and max label hints to aid in scanners, noting that these pieces of information are not commonly included in descriptors but might enhance performance by facilitating faster rescanning. The discussion acknowledges that while these elements are not strictly necessary within a Single Point (SP) context, they serve a significant role in optimizing scanning processes. The idea is floated that assuming a high default value for max_label—such as 100, 1,000, or 10,000—could enable efficient scanning without significantly impacting performance.

There's a proposal to explore ways to integrate both scan and spend functionalities into a unified unit while maintaining birthday and max label as integer values. This approach aims to streamline the process without sacrificing the potential benefits these hints could offer. The suggestion includes treating keys as separate entities, defined as `Key Expression` within a descriptor context, following the guidelines laid out in [BIP-0380](%EF%BF%BC). This method suggests a structured approach to enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of cryptocurrency scanners by carefully considering the inclusion of specific information types that have traditionally been overlooked.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-13T03:59:38.435000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
