<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-15T02:40:30.413870+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Nuh 2025-11-15 01:04:33.320000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-15T02:40:30.413907+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The inquiry raises significant concerns regarding the feasibility and reliability of Zero-Knowledge Virtual Machines (ZKVMs), highlighting a general apprehension about their capability to undergo formal proofs. This skepticism towards ZKVMs is attributed to their reliance on upgradable smart contracts, especially on platforms like Ethereum, to address and rectify provable bugs. The question implicitly critiques this approach by pointing out its potential incompatibility with Bitcoin’s architecture, which is less amenable to such upgrade mechanisms.

Further exploration in the query delves into comparing the assurances provided by Cairo and STARK proofs, as utilized by Starknet, against the backdrop of the limitations observed in ZKVMs. The underlying concern revolves around the necessity of having an upgrade mechanism as a fallback to tackle bugs, specifically those that are not preemptively identifiable through formal proofs, such as under constraints or other bug forms. This comparison seeks to understand whether the methodologies employed by Cairo and STARK proofs can offer a more robust framework that circumvents the need for such reactive measures, thereby providing a more stable and reliable foundation for development.

The discussion implicitly touches upon broader themes related to the evolution and security of blockchain technologies, emphasizing the importance of constructing systems that can ensure high levels of trustworthiness and integrity without relying heavily on post-deployment fixes. This conversation is crucial in the context of developing decentralized applications and platforms, where security and reliability are paramount.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-15T01:04:33.320000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
