<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-17T02:47:36.291451+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Abdel 2025-11-16 12:47:17.280000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T02:47:36.291485+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intriguing comparison between Cairo and RISC-V architectures concerning zkVMs, an area that has garnered significant attention within cryptographic and blockchain circles. The provided [link](https://hackmd.io/@AbdelStark/cairo-vs-riscv-zkvms) leads to a comprehensive analysis that sheds light on the rationale behind preferring Cairo for implementing zk-STARKs over the RISC-V architecture. This preference is rooted in specific technical advantages and compatibility with zero-knowledge proofs, particularly relevant in the context of blockchain technologies and privacy-preserving protocols.

Additionally, the conversation extends into the zcash community forum, where similar inquiries regarding the adoption of Cairo STARKs for ZtarkNet and Stark Verify TZE are addressed. A pertinent [discussion](https://forum.zcashcommunity.com/t/why-cairo-starks-for-ztarknet-and-stark-verify-tze/) in this forum further elaborates on the choice of Cairo over other potential alternatives. The selection is based on Cairo's inherent characteristics that make it more suited for applications requiring high levels of security and efficiency in executing zero-knowledge proofs, especially within the domain of decentralized finance and cryptocurrency.

This exploration into the comparative benefits of Cairo versus RISC-V architectures in the application of zkVMs highlights the ongoing advancements in cryptographic technology. It underscores the importance of selecting the appropriate computational framework that aligns with the operational requirements and security standards of emerging financial technologies.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-16T12:47:17.280000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
