<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MergeSync: Parallel UTXO-set construction in assumevalid trust model</title>
  <updated>2025-11-18T02:45:36.733113+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>murch 2025-11-17 19:14:27.009000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MergeSync: Parallel UTXO-set construction in assumevalid trust model</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T02:45:36.733140+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mergesync-parallel-utxo-set-construction-in-assumevalid-trust-model/2097/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the discussion about improving data handling in blockchain technology, a significant critique is raised against a proposed idea aimed at optimizing input/output operations. The critique highlights concerns regarding the approach's efficiency, especially when compared to existing methodologies such as Bitcoin Core's current strategy and SwiftSync's innovative use of accumulators for compressing checks of spent Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs). The person raises doubts about the expected benefits of the new proposal, questioning its ability to reduce I/O operations given that it necessitates writing out all UTXO data along with all inputs' outpoints. This method contrasts with SwiftSync's technique, which not only minimizes the amount of data to be processed through the use of hints but also allows for the potential of parallel processing, thereby enhancing efficiency.

The skepticism stems from the comparison with SwiftSync, which represents a more advanced solution by enabling a compression of the verification process into a single accumulator. Such an approach is seen as advantageous because it can be executed in parallel, suggesting a significant improvement in processing speed and efficiency. The communication seeks clarification on what novel contribution the proposed idea offers over these established methods, implicitly questioning the justification for adopting a potentially less efficient procedure. This request for further explanation underscores the importance of clearly demonstrating a method's superiority or innovative edge before it is considered a viable alternative to current practices in blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T19:14:27.009000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
