<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
  <updated>2025-11-18T02:46:44.908736+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>gmaxwell 2025-11-17 22:07:46.639000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T02:46:44.908768+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/propagation-delay-and-mining-centralization-modeling-stale-rates/2110/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the misconception surrounding average revenue models in the context of mining operations, pointing out that a significant portion of the $91 million often cited could be allocated to power costs, thereby inflating the net profit figures for miners more than initially perceived. This situation underscores the complexity of accurately assessing the financial outcomes for miners, suggesting that the reality is far more nuanced than simple revenue calculations suggest.

Further examination reveals concerns about the visibility and management of stale blocks within the network, especially post-implementation of compact blocks. The suggestion of introducing a new "STALEHEADER" message protocol aims to improve the network's efficiency by allowing for the relay of headers connected near the best chain tip without necessarily implying the ability to serve the entire block. This proposed mechanism would facilitate better statistics on network performance by tracing stale headers that connect closely to the block chain's tip or those accepted as stale, enhancing visibility into large invalid forks while maintaining security against DOS attacks, provided it activates only after achieving minimum chain work. This approach underscores the ongoing efforts to refine blockchain protocols to address specific operational challenges while safeguarding network integrity.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T22:07:46.639000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
