<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T02:46:50.925919+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Nuh</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-18T11:09:47.745000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T02:46:50.925958+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the digital age, communication platforms are varied and numerous, each with its unique features and user base. Among these platforms, Email remains a steadfast tool for formal and professional correspondence, Matrix emerges as a decentralized and secure alternative for real-time communication, and Signal stands out for its end-to-end encryption, prioritizing privacy in instant messaging. These platforms cater to different needs, from the traditional and widely accepted email for professional exchanges to the more specialized Matrix and Signal, which focus on security and privacy, respectively.

The availability of diverse communication tools like Email, Matrix, and Signal underscores the importance of choosing the right platform based on the nature of the information being shared and the required level of security. While Email is universal and indispensable for official and business-related communication, Matrix offers a robust option for those seeking an open-source and decentralized network for real-time conversations. On the other hand, Signal provides an excellent choice for users who prioritize privacy above all else in their communications, thanks to its strong encryption protocols.

For further details on how to access accounts on these platforms, one can refer to the provided link ([nuh.dev](https://nuh.dev/)). This link serves as a gateway to understanding how to effectively use and navigate these different platforms, offering insights into the unique advantages of each and guiding on setting up accounts or enhancing existing ones.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T11:09:47.745000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
