<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T02:45:13.809299+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-11-18 15:48:35.039000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T02:45:13.809338+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/taxonomy-of-transaction-fees-in-smart-contracts/512/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In exploring the intricacies of Bitcoin's scripting capabilities, a notable advancement is highlighted through the introduction of OP_CCV, or OP_CheckContractVerify, a proposal by a developer known as @salvatoshi. This development is poised to significantly enhance the flexibility and functionality of Bitcoin scripts, addressing a longstanding limitation related to the execution conditions for transactions within the Bitcoin network.

The traditional script mechanism in Bitcoin offers limited expressiveness, particularly when attempting to create conditions that extend beyond the immediate transaction. For instance, a simple output script aiming to incentivize miners through conditional payouts based on block discovery cannot guarantee the inclusion of a transaction by a miner, simply because the miner has no assurance of finding a specific block, such as the 100th following the one that includes the said transaction. This scenario underscores the necessity for a more expressive scripting language that can accommodate complex conditions and ensure their persistence across multiple stages of transaction processing.

OP_CCV emerges as a solution to this predicament by enabling a novel approach to script design. It allows for the creation of outputs that are initially set as anyone-can-spend, meaning they do not have restrictive spending conditions. However, it innovatively incorporates the ability to "carry forward" specific conditions to subsequent spenders, effectively introducing a "second stage" of conditions that must be met. This dual-stage capability facilitates a broader range of transaction types and interactions within the Bitcoin ecosystem, opening up new possibilities for smart contracts and conditional payments that were previously unattainable.

For those interested in delving deeper into the technical aspects and potential applications of OP_CheckContractVerify, further information is available through an insightful piece found at [delvingbitcoin.org](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkcontractverify-and-its-amount-semantic/1527). This resource provides a comprehensive overview of the functionality and implications of OP_CCV, contributing to a richer understanding of its role in advancing the expressiveness and versatility of Bitcoin scripting.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T15:48:35.039000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
