<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Raw₿it — the visual raw transaction builder &amp; script debugger</title>
  <updated>2025-11-21T02:46:00.200685+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rawBit 2025-11-20 11:41:25.531000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Raw₿it — the visual raw transaction builder &amp; script debugger</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T02:46:00.200717+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/raw-it-the-visual-raw-transaction-builder-script-debugger/2119" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of a visual, node-based editor named raw₿it revolutionizes the way individuals can learn and build Bitcoin transactions from scratch. This innovative tool allows users to construct raw Bitcoin transactions visually by dragging and dropping predefined nodes on a canvas. It offers an in-depth learning experience by displaying the exact Python code behind every calculation node, enabling users to step through script execution and observe the stack's mutation with each opcode. Users have the flexibility to modify amounts, locktimes, scripts, and instantly view updates to preimages, signatures, witnesses, TXID/WTXID. The platform is designed to enhance user productivity and learning with features like a multi-tab workspace, full undo/redo capabilities, dark mode, local save/load options, and shareable flows, alongside a switch between testnet, mainnet, and regtest environments.

Additionally, raw₿it enriches the learning experience with 10 hands-on lessons covering various Bitcoin transaction types such as P2PKH, multisig, timelocks, SegWit, and payment channels, with all transactions being broadcasted to testnet for verification purposes. This educational initiative promises more lessons to be added in the future, aiming to broaden users' understanding and skills in cryptocurrency transactions.

Emphasizing privacy and accessibility, raw₿it is entirely open-source and available for free online. The hosted version ensures that calculations run on a minimal backend that is rate-limited and does not store any data, offering peace of mind regarding privacy. For those seeking complete privacy, a local installation option is provided that operates 100% offline, ensuring no data exposure. Despite its extensive capabilities, raw₿it is primarily designed as an educational tool and is not intended for managing real funds, underlining its purpose in fostering learning and experimentation within the cryptocurrency space.

For those interested in exploring this educational tool, it is accessible at [raw₿it.io](https://rawbit.io), with the source code available on [GitHub](https://github.com/rawBit-io/rawbit). A short demonstration of what the tool offers and how it operates can be viewed at [this YouTube link](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wGZ5H535jwQ), providing a quick overview of its functionalities and benefits to learners and enthusiasts in the Bitcoin community.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-20T11:41:25.531000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
