<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>MergeSync: Parallel UTXO-set construction in assumevalid trust model</title>
  <updated>2025-11-22T02:31:41.646607+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>RubenSomsen 2025-11-21 15:47:35.625000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>MergeSync: Parallel UTXO-set construction in assumevalid trust model</title>
    <updated>2025-11-22T02:31:41.646638+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mergesync-parallel-utxo-set-construction-in-assumevalid-trust-model/2097/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of SwiftSync, as outlined in a [shared document](https://gist.github.com/RubenSomsen/a61a37d14182ccd78760e477c78133cd), presents an alternative approach to managing the Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) set without the need for a hints file, which typically consumes about 80MB when compressed. This model requires tracking all transaction outputs directly, which inherently increases the memory footprint since it involves not only tracking the outpoints but also other necessary details to accurately determine the UTXO set. Such an increase in memory usage is akin to what is expected in running a full node, signifying a major drawback due to the enhanced resource requirements for sorting or lookups.

Another point of concern with this approach is its limitation regarding signature validation. The system's design does not allow for the disablement of the assumevalid feature, thereby preventing full signature validation. This could be seen as a significant downside for users who prioritize validation processes within their systems.

Despite these drawbacks, the technique introduces an interesting perspective on data management, particularly highlighting how sorting mechanisms might serve as a viable replacement for traditional database lookups in certain scenarios. This observation suggests a potential for efficiency gains in how additions and removals are handled, implying that the method could offer benefits in order-independent operations. The trade-offs involved in adopting such a strategy, however, remain complex and require careful consideration to fully assess their impact.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-21T15:47:35.625000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
