<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-26T02:48:31.008888+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-25T05:08:28.126000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T02:48:31.008920+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/19" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies of managing a sharechain, specifically addressing the allocation of shares to winners within the Bitcoin onchain framework. The suggestion of burning a portion of the winner's shares was mentioned, highlighting a solution to a previously discussed problem. This approach is debated in terms of its necessity and technical feasibility, with an acknowledgment that winners might repeatedly earn block rewards over time. The market's ability to adjust to this occurrence was noted, suggesting confidence in the system's self-regulatory mechanisms.

Further exploration into the operational parameters of a sharecoin block raises questions about issuance frequency, difficulty adjustments, and transaction capacities. The design flexibility of p2share is underscored, indicating that these aspects can be tailored to meet specific objectives or operational goals. A prior post introduces the concept of a "Hard Money Coffee" sharechain as an example of how sharechains can vary in function and design, illustrating the potential for customized implementation.

The conversation then shifts towards the compatibility of sharechains with existing Bitcoin technology, namely the possibility of instant atomic swaps facilitated by lightning-like channels within sharechains. This interoperability suggests a seamless exchange between Bitcoin and sharechain assets, enhancing the fluidity and efficiency of transactions across networks.

Lastly, the topic of inclusivity and operational costs for miners is addressed, advocating for a structure that supports small miners by keeping the costs of running a fully validating sharechain node low. This approach mirrors Bitcoin’s principles, promoting a decentralized and accessible network. The idea of having either a single sharecoin pool or multiple competing pools is presented, leaving room for diversity in features and innovation, as exemplified by the "Hard Money Coffee" sharechain scenario.

For further details on the initial discussion and insights into the proposed sharechain model, refer to the [prior post](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/12).</summary>
    <published>2025-11-25T05:08:28.126000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
