<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-26T02:48:56.338172+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>VzxPLnHqr</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-25T19:14:25.408000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T02:48:56.338204+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/21" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the evolving landscape of blockchain and cryptocurrency, a new concept known as sharechain has been introduced, drawing parallels with Bitcoin while incorporating unique mechanisms. Sharechains operate on a network similar to Bitcoin's, utilizing a unit of account referred to as "shares" within their transactions. These shares are distinct because they possess an equity-like property through a mechanism called p2share, which selects a random shareholder, diverging from Bitcoin's model. This system allows sharechains to function without traditional legal structures, akin to Bitcoin, yet introduces a novel approach to share distribution and reward allocation.

The discussion around sharechains also delves into technical specifics, such as the utilization of an Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) model versus an account-based tracking method. While the choice between these mechanisms remains open, the consensus leans towards the simplicity and efficacy of the UTXO model. This model underpins the method of randomly selecting specific shares for rewards, addressing potential concerns such as the ease of share manipulation by miners through distribution across multiple outputs.

A key aspect of sharechains is the simplification of reward distribution. Instead of burning a set amount of shares equivalent to a Bitcoin block reward, the proposal suggests randomly selecting a single share and awarding the entire Bitcoin reward to its holder. This method mirrors traditional share buybacks but eliminates the need for complex calculations or price signals within the sharechain. It’s argued that this approach maintains fairness and simplicity, ensuring that all shareholders are considered equally over time, regardless of the inflationary aspects or the increasing difficulty and supply of shares.

The concept further explores the implications of share issuance and inflation. In a linear model where each share represents a constant amount of work, the continuous issuance of shares is counterbalanced by a difficulty adjustment algorithm. This ensures that despite an ever-growing supply of shares, the system remains fair, giving both early and later shareholders equitable chances in reward distribution based on the work they contribute. 

Moreover, sharechains offer the potential for innovative coordination mechanisms and features without impacting the main Bitcoin blockchain. The flexibility of sharechains to experiment with various models and features positions them uniquely within the cryptocurrency ecosystem. Markets play a crucial role in determining the success of different sharechains, as those with reckless issuance models or features may struggle to attract interest. Conversely, sharechains that offer solid, differentiated feature sets and maintain fair issuance practices hold better prospects for success, emphasizing the importance of market dynamics in shaping the future of sharechain applications.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-25T19:14:25.408000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
