<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-11-29T02:47:31.895141+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>rustyrussell</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-11-29T00:01:44.200000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-11-29T02:47:31.895174+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the challenges and strategies involved in managing the computational costs associated with decoding processes, particularly in contexts like handling network communications where there's a risk of being flooded with unnecessary or malicious data. One practical solution mentioned is the concept of preemptively limiting the amount of data processed by trimming inputs to a manageable size. This approach helps in mitigating potential griefing attempts—where an attacker might try to overload a system with excessive data—by setting an upper limit on the data processed, thus protecting valuable computational resources.

Moreover, the conversation points towards the need for precise specifications, such as those that might be outlined in a BOLT (Basics of Lightning Technology) specification, to better manage these risks. It suggests that having detailed benchmarks could provide clearer guidelines on how to efficiently handle data, from the creation of data sets to their maintenance over time. Such benchmarks would ideally cover various aspects, including the initial build time of data sets containing all necessary gossip and their subsequent update times following each block, offering a more systematic approach to handling data in a secure and efficient manner.</summary>
    <published>2025-11-29T00:01:44.200000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
