<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:35.399751+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>garlonicon  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 09:30:26.903000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 20:18:38.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 06:07:07.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>cmp_ancp</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 14:44:47.356000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 15:51:03.139000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 21:11:28.980000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 23:15:13.002000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6196_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6197_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6199_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6203_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6204_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6205_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6207_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6208_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T02:51:35.400834+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The innovative &quot;p2share&quot; network proposes a decentralized bitcoin mining framework that redefines the distribution of mining rewards, setting itself apart from traditional models. Within this network, miners are allocated &quot;shares&quot; for validating blocks, which can be transferred among participants according to the network's consensus rules. This model diverges from the norm by awarding the entire bitcoin reward from a successfully mined block to a single shareholder through a random selection process. This approach not only maintains fairness, ensuring that rewards are proportionate to share ownership over time but also enhances efficiency by keeping the coinbase output minimal. This contributes positively to the overall Bitcoin network by minimizing transaction bloat and maximizing fee revenue potential. Furthermore, the p2share network fosters a trustless and decentralized environment, with a deterministic selection process that aligns miner incentives towards share accumulation, either for active mining or speculative holding.
Discussions around millisatoshis within the Lightning Network highlight their adaptability, offering a way to facilitate transactions that remain true to Bitcoin's foundational principles without necessitating an alternate cryptocurrency. This dialogue emphasizes the importance of maintaining the integrity of Bitcoin's ecosystem, suggesting that innovations like millisatoshis can provide additional functionalities while ensuring security measures akin to those in the Lightning Network. The exploration of varying block time durations further suggests that the existing structure could be optimized for specific applications without compromising the network's efficiency, reinforcing Bitcoin's capacity for innovation on its foundational infrastructure.
The integration of privacy features into the p2share network, drawing inspiration from MimbleWimble semantics, represents an advanced stride towards enhancing user privacy without departing from the Bitcoin framework. This endeavor faces challenges, particularly in adapting the selection mechanism for shareholder's public keys within a privacy-centric sharechain. The proposed solutions aim to preserve privacy while maintaining the network's decentralized ethos, indicating a complex yet promising path towards combining privacy with cryptocurrency mining.
Furthermore, concerns about the viability and implications of the p2share network are raised, touching upon issues such as incentive compatibility for miners and the distinction between sharechain networks and sidechains. The potential impact on Bitcoin's mainnet and the network's contribution to Bitcoin's security are considered significant, underscoring the need for a balanced and well-thought-out approach to integrating new features into the Bitcoin ecosystem.
Lastly, the concept of a &quot;pool sidechain&quot; is explored as an elegant solution to coordinate mining efforts in a decentralized manner. This idea revisits and refines the P2Pool model by proposing a system where miners commit to a sidechain, potentially improving the distribution of mining rewards and reducing reliance on centralized pool coordinators. This approach underscores the ongoing search for mechanisms that preserve Bitcoin's decentralization while accommodating innovation and addressing the practical challenges faced by miners in a competitive landscape.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>