<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-11-23T02:59:46.947698+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-20 16:18:51.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-22 22:48:46.117000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-23 00:35:19.795000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6299_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6312_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6314_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-11-23T02:59:46.948773+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The Lightning Network (LN) has been the focus of various improvements and observations since its inception, particularly concerning the efficiency of message propagation within its peer-to-peer (P2P) network. One significant project aimed at understanding these dynamics involved monitoring the LN's gossip network, collecting gossip messages from a diverse array of nodes. This effort has highlighted several key insights, including a notable decrease in convergence delay for message spread across the network, and the predominance of channel_update messages among the collected data. The project has also indicated a potential underestimation of node bandwidth usage due to additional loads from receiving identical messages across multiple peers. Plans are underway to expand this research by setting up a permanent infrastructure to receive gossip from various geographic locations and P2P graph segments, with the community encouraged to contribute towards identifying valuable metrics and specific nodes for tracking.
Discussion around improving the LN's efficiency has delved into the transition from a message flooding protocol to more efficient designs, inspired by the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). A key aspect of this transition is the adaptation of Minisketch for LN gossip, aiming to reduce latency and propagation delays while minimizing reconciliation time through unique salts and transaction identifiers (TXIDs). The proposed gossip 1.5 format introduces optional fields in messages, allowing for tailored information exchange based on mutually supported features, thereby potentially eliminating the need for message flooding entirely. However, challenges such as disparate node filtering policies and the practicality of frequent set reconciliations present hurdles that necessitate standardized practices and engagement with LN implementers.
The comparative inefficiency of Minisketch's superlinear decoding costs has raised concerns about its scalability and efficiency. An alternative approach involving frequent reconciliations and the potential use of Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables (IBLT) over Minisketch was discussed, highlighting the need for careful technology selection based on specific requirements. Recent studies and benchmarks, including those found at [nislab/gensync](https://github.com/nislab/gensync) and [arxiv.org](https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.17530), have explored various synchronization strategies, offering insights into their applicability and trade-offs for different settings. The exploration suggests that integrating frequent IBLT-based synchronizations with less frequent Minisketch usage could offer a balanced approach to managing bandwidth overhead and CPU utilization, especially in environments where conserving resources is crucial.
Further discussions have critiqued academic representations of IBLT schemes, cautioning against misleading data due to significant overheads. The practical application of minisketch in a quasi rateless manner was suggested, emphasizing dynamic data transmission until recovery is possible, thereby maintaining computational efficiency. This method minimizes extra element overhead, showcasing a potentially more efficient utilization in practical applications.
Lastly, practical experiences and considerations were shared regarding the use of Minisketch within the LN, detailing a multi-sketch strategy for handling different message types and suggesting techniques for optimizing bandwidth and set maintenance. The importance of real-world traffic pattern analysis and direct message flooding strategies to mitigate discrepancies in peer timing was underscored, highlighting the ongoing efforts to enhance LN's data reconciliation methods and overall network efficiency.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>