<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-11-02T02:48:38.445123+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>nymius  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>junderw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 03:50:00.461000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>junderw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 05:26:14.844000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6139_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6149_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6181_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6182_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-11-02T02:48:38.446069+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The integration of Schnorr Protocol (SP) compatibility into Bitcoin payment solutions like BTCPayServer presents a fascinating technical challenge, focusing on the necessity to effectively encode specific key combinations. This coding is essential for facilitating transactions that adhere to the protocol's requirements, emphasizing the need for a new string format to encapsulate these key configurations for SP operations. The proposed combinations include scan public plus spend master public key, scan private plus spend master public key for delegated scanning, and scan private plus spend private key for spending operations and address generation. This initiative underlines the developer community's commitment to refining cryptocurrency protocols for broader usability, highlighting efforts to tackle the complexities of integrating advanced cryptographic mechanisms into user-friendly applications.
Further discussion at the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024 conference shed light on encoding enhancements for silent payment descriptors. The dialogue proposed a novel approach to creating a more self-contained spending mechanism for transactions. By combining `tweak` with `b_spend` and incorporating elements such as `label`, `b_scan`, and a shared secret, this methodology aims to bypass current limitations by ensuring all necessary spending information is included within individual outputs. Additionally, the consideration to encode a range or limit onto the string enhances flexibility and functionality, addressing the issue where existing key setups fall short without the tweak material from the originating transaction. These proposed enhancements signify a move towards simplifying transactions while bolstering security and privacy in cryptocurrency exchanges.
On the topic of practical application and user experience, there's a suggestion to incorporate labels and per-transaction information in a way that allows wallets to initiate scans based on imported data, potentially encoding a &quot;birthday&quot; block number to streamline verification processes. The inclusion of labels, especially a default change label, could improve wallet restoration experiences. A GitHub pull request has been created to kickstart modifications to the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), aiming to incorporate these new encoding strategies. This demonstrates an active engagement with the process of making cryptocurrencies more accessible and efficient for users, reflecting ongoing attempts to enhance the operational framework of Bitcoin and similar platforms.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>