<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-11-28T02:48:32.626358+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-20 16:18:51.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-22 22:48:46.117000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-23 00:35:19.795000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-26 00:46:27.546000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-27 21:01:18.494000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6299_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6312_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6314_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6347_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6353_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-11-28T02:48:32.627639+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/11" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The project's focus has been on monitoring the Lightning gossip network, collecting gossip messages from a diverse set of nodes since its initiation at PlebFi Miami. The repository, containing the utilized code, raw data acquired before the lightning++ update, and presentation slides, is available [here](https://www.example.com). This initiative has led to several key observations about message propagation dynamics within the network. There's been a noticeable reduction in convergence delay, the time it takes for a message to spread across the network, decreasing from around 500 seconds to 200 seconds for 75% propagation since last year. This improvement is likely due to Lightning Network (LN) implementations opting for more peer-to-peer connections by default. Moreover, a significant portion of all received messages were transmitted to the observing node by less than one-quarter of its peers, indicating potential inefficiencies or selective filtering policies within LN implementations. Regarding message types, channel_update messages made up 60% of the total volume, with 20% of channels having over 144 messages, which is crucial for considering proposed rate limits for Taproot gossip or gossip version 1.5. For node_announcement messages, making up 30% of all messages, 2.5% of nodes were announced over 144 times, pointing to issues with certain implementations or automated tools. The total size of unique messages collected surpassed expectations at 103.2 MB, suggesting potential underestimations of node bandwidth usage from receiving identical messages across multiple peers. The project aims to expand by establishing permanent infrastructure for receiving gossip from various geographic locations and P2P graph segments, including functionalities for broadcasting messages to study their spread further. The community's engagement is encouraged, especially for suggestions on interesting metrics, tracking specific nodes’ gossip propagation, or other contributions. There's also ongoing exploration into making the raw data available for independent analysis, with a particular interest in unsupervised anomaly detection.
The transition from a message flooding protocol to a more efficient design for the Lightning Network (LN) peer-to-peer (P2P) network has been a point of discussion, drawing inspiration from the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). This change could reduce latency and propagation delay in LN gossip, which tolerates slightly outdated fee information due to the nature of gossip messages being publicly signed. A focal point is adapting Minisketch for LN gossip, emphasizing a mapping mechanism resistant to collisions while keeping data elements short to minimize reconciliation time. The Erlay paper suggests generating unique salts for each peer connection combined with transaction identifiers (TXIDs) to create distinct Minisketch set elements through a fast hash function like SipHash. This method scales hashing operations with the number of peer connections, reducing computational requirements by advocating for shorter set elements. The proposed gossip 1.5 format introduces optional fields in messages, allowing nodes to tailor information based on mutually supported features, aiming to eliminate message flooding in favor of set reconciliation methods. However, challenges such as disparate node filtering policies might lead to inefficiencies and failed reconciliations, highlighting the need for standardized practices.
There's a comparative inefficiency in using message flooding in LN implementations, as shown in Erlay's design. Combining limited flooding with set reconciliation could reduce total propagation delay. Despite Minisketch's potential to efficiently fill in small omissions, its superlinear decoding costs could significantly increase CPU usage with large sketches. An alternative involves frequent reconciliations to mitigate this, though it increases communication overheads due to overshooting the required amount for effective reconstruction. Erlay’s flooding technique is acknowledged for its ability to alleviate most of the load from the sketch, optimizing the process by addressing only minor gaps effectively. The idea of potentially choosing IBLT (Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables) over Minisketch for solely relying on reconciliation is considered, stemming from IBLT’s different cost-benefit dynamics. This nuanced perspective underscores the importance of selecting technologies based on specific requirements and constraints of the LN's operational environment.
Minisketch faces challenges with superlinear decoding costs with large sketches, significantly consuming CPU resources. To mitigate this, more frequent reconciliations are considered; however, they introduce communication overheads. Erlay's approach of combining flooding with sketches is highlighted as beneficial because it offloads the majority of the workload to the flooding process, allowing sketches to address smaller omissions efficiently. The discussion transitions to alternative reconciliation methods, specifically highlighting the potential of using IBLT over Minisketch in certain scenarios due to IBLT's higher overheads being potentially less significant when processing all traffic through it, despite worse performance compared to Minisketch. A recent paper proposing an IBLT-based set reconciliation protocol appears promising. Additionally, a study comparing various synchronization strategies provides insights into trade-offs and applicability to different settings. Cuckoo filters, while explored, were deemed not entirely suitable due to their operational characteristics. The exploration led to the discovery of the Rateless IBLT (RIBLT</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>