<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
  <updated>2025-11-13T02:49:12.935845+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>nymius  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-27 20:20:28.705000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 03:50:00.461000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>junderw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-01 05:26:14.844000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>pyth</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:41:23.310000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>junderw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 10:57:57.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>sipa</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 14:49:16.312000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>junderw</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-12 15:56:16.956000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6139_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6149_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6181_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6182_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6220_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6223_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6224_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6228_BIP352-private-key-formats.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - BIP352 private key formats</title>
    <updated>2025-11-13T02:49:12.936908+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip352-private-key-formats/2080/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-25 00:43:40.738000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion surrounding the enhancement of Bitcoin payment solutions through the integration of Schnorr Protocol (SP) compatibility highlights a technical challenge in encoding key combinations for seamless transactions. The focus lies on creating a string format that can encode various key configurations essential for SP operations, such as combining scan public plus spend master public keys, scan private plus spend master public keys for delegated scanning, and scan private plus spend private keys for spending operations and generating new SP addresses. This approach aims to make the process more intuitive and efficient for users and developers, emphasizing the need to adapt cryptocurrency protocols for broader application and usability.
Insights from the Bitcoin Core Dev Tech 2024 conference shed light on proposals to enhance silent payment descriptors. One key suggestion is to develop a format that includes self-contained spending material for individual outputs by combining `tweak` with `b_spend`, derived from a mixture of `label`, `b_scan`, and a shared secret. Additionally, there's contemplation of encoding a range or limit directly onto the string for applicable labels to improve system flexibility and functionality. These enhancements aim to simplify transactions while bolstering security and privacy, addressing limitations in the current setup where keys alone are insufficient without tweak material from the originating transaction.
The conversation further delves into refining the Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) by suggesting how labels and per-transaction information are handled during wallet imports. Incorporating a block number as the &quot;birthday&quot; for both labels and per-tx data could streamline the restoration process by indicating to the wallet that it need not verify transactions prior to this block. Proposing the encoding of labels as an array at the end of transaction data facilitates efficient organization and retrieval, aiming to refine the wallet import process by making it more user-friendly and functional.
A new BIP PR marks a significant step in advancing Bitcoin's protocol, opening avenues for community feedback and contribution. This initiative underscores an active engagement with the community to address challenges and introduce enhancements, reflecting a commitment to the evolution of Bitcoin. Available for review on [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/2026), this platform invites transparent examination and discussion, fostering an inclusive environment for proposal evaluation.
The debate also touches upon the usage of output descriptor languages in encapsulating private versus public information within SP descriptors. Despite the inability of SP descriptors to directly encode outputs, the adaptation of syntax to include private key material alongside public variants is considered, following precedents in other settings. This approach could potentially simplify the inclusion of private keys in descriptors, enhancing their utility in cryptocurrency transactions.
Finally, suggestions for incorporating birthdays and maximum label values as hints to aid scanners are discussed, alongside the consideration of encoding scan and spend keys into a single unit. These ideas reflect ongoing thoughts on optimizing the efficiency and safety of Bitcoin transactions, demonstrating a deliberative process aimed at improving user experience and network functionality.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>