<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
  <updated>2025-11-18T02:46:59.398355+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 14:18:31.321000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>gmaxwell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 22:07:46.639000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6256_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6265_Propagation-Delay-and-Mining-Centralization-Modeling-Stale-Rates.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Propagation Delay and Mining Centralization: Modeling Stale Rates</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T02:46:59.398846+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/propagation-delay-and-mining-centralization-modeling-stale-rates/2110/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-17 14:18:31.321000+00:00</published>
    <summary>A detailed analysis was previously conducted on the strategy known as &quot;Selfish Mining,&quot; revealing how miners with substantial but not majority control over the network's hashrate can increase their revenues by selectively publishing blocks. This strategy underscores the significant advantage that longer block propagation times offer to larger miners. Following this, further examination focused on how propagation time impacts miner revenue in relation to their share of the network's hashrate, employing a simplified model where all miners immediately mine and publish upon finding a block, and switch as soon as a valid chain with more proof of work (PoW) is received. In this model, if propagation time were instantaneous, a miner's revenue would directly correlate with their hashrate share. However, delays mean there's always a risk of a block becoming stale due to another miner's block being propagated first.
Two key scenarios were identified where a miner's block could become stale: one, if another miner finds a block shortly before them, leading others to mine on top of this new block; and two, if a block is found by another miner shortly after, especially if this miner controls a significant portion of the hashrate, increasing the chances of them finding consecutive blocks. The likelihood of these events, and thus of a block becoming stale, diminishes as a miner's control of the hashrate increases. However, the exact impact varies based on the uniformity of block propagation time and the distribution of hashrate among miners.
Simulations were conducted under different conditions to illustrate how propagation time affects mining centralization and the stale rate of blocks - the rate at which blocks are found but not included in the longest blockchain. These simulations showed that even minor differences in stale rates can lead to significant revenue variations for mining operations, highlighting the material gains from choosing mining pools with lower propagation times.
The analysis also touched upon the broader implications for the Bitcoin network, particularly concerning the potential benefits of protocol changes aimed at improving the visibility of stale blocks through new message types. Such changes could provide clearer insights into the network's behavior without significantly altering its operational dynamics.
In conclusion, while average revenue models suggest a certain impact of propagation time on revenues, the reality is more nuanced. Major portions of mining revenue are consumed by power costs, meaning that any increase in revenue due to lower stale rates proportionally boosts net profits by a larger margin. Understanding these dynamics is crucial for evaluating potential network improvements or protocol adjustments aimed at optimizing performance and fairness across the network.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>