<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Generalizing RBF under Cluster Mempool</title>
  <updated>2025-11-20T02:49:01.434501+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>josh  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 00:51:03.774000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>sdaftuar</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 15:29:46.556000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>josh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 20:43:23.070000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6280_Generalizing-RBF-under-Cluster-Mempool.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6289_Generalizing-RBF-under-Cluster-Mempool.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6291_Generalizing-RBF-under-Cluster-Mempool.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Generalizing RBF under Cluster Mempool</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T02:49:01.435226+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/generalizing-rbf-under-cluster-mempool/2115/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-19 00:51:03.774000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The cluster mempool proposal is designed to optimize the total fees within the mempool by ensuring a structured ordering of transaction clusters. This initiative aims to enhance the overall fee structure by maintaining &quot;incentive compatibility,&quot; which requires new transactions to contribute positively to the existing mempool's fee configuration. The introduction of the Replace-by-Fee (RBF) mechanism, specifically through Peter Todd's RBFr proposal, is discussed in detail. This proposal offers solutions to address concerns related to free relay and denial-of-service attacks by proposing a method to evaluate transaction replacements beneficially, focusing on additional profits for miners and considering future states of the mempool.
A formal model outlines the criteria under which a transaction replacement would be deemed profitable, emphasizing the need to compare the virtual size and fee differences between original and replacement transactions. Additionally, the model considers the potential profit from subsequent transaction clusters that could fill the space left by the replaced transaction. The success of such a replacement hinges on whether these subsequent transactions can surpass a certain minimum profit threshold. Challenges in identifying suitable transaction clusters due to computational complexity are acknowledged, with proposed solutions including offloading this computational task to users or utilizing transaction identifiers during the relay process.
Moreover, the discussion acknowledges the risk of irrational mining behavior and the importance of establishing a high enough minimum profit threshold to deter exploitation. The broader implications of these proposals aim to improve the incentive compatibility of the RBF mechanism within the cluster mempool context. By adjusting parameters and definitions to account for the effects of previous replacements, these proposals strive to balance maximizing mempool fees with safeguarding network operations against potential abuses. This approach underscores the necessity for community feedback and collaboration in refining blockchain protocols.
Further insights are provided through a [link](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/mempool-incentive-compatibility/553) shared in the conversation, which delves deeper into the nuances of mempool incentive compatibility. The discussion raises questions about the feasibility of proving RBF-like profitability given the variable nature of mining pool sizes and market structures. It suggests that an optimal mining strategy might depend on the ability to maximize fees over multiple blocks, rather than focusing solely on the fees from a single block containing a specific transaction. This perspective opens up considerations for extending strategies beyond immediate transaction blocks and acknowledges the theoretical challenges and solutions presented by the cluster mempool concept.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>