<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-11-21T02:45:46.750635+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-20 16:18:51.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6299_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T02:45:46.751512+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/6" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The project has been actively monitoring the Lightning gossip network, gathering data to analyze message propagation dynamics. Since its initiation at PlebFi Miami, significant insights have been garnered, notably a decrease in convergence delay from 500 seconds to 200 seconds for 75% of message propagation, attributed to Lightning Network (LN) implementations increasing peer connections. The majority of messages were received from a minority of peers, indicating potential connectivity or filtering inefficiencies. Channel update messages, comprising 60% of total volume, highlighted that 20% of channels exceeded 144 messages, raising concerns over proposed rate limits for Taproot gossip. Node announcement messages accounted for 30% of all messages, with 2.5% of nodes being announced more than 144 times, pointing to possible implementation issues. The day's unique message total was 103.2 MB, surpassing expected node bandwidth usage assumptions and underlining the need for further infrastructure expansion for comprehensive geographic and P2P graph coverage. Community engagement is encouraged for suggestions on metrics, tracking specific nodes, or other contributions, alongside exploring data availability for independent analysis.
The transition towards a more efficient LN P2P network design, inspired by the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP), suggests reducing latency and propagation delay through methods other than message flooding. This includes adopting Minisketch for LN gossip, focusing on collision-resistant mapping mechanisms and introducing optional fields in messages for tailored information exchange based on mutual feature support. These changes aim to simplify implementation and reduce bandwidth by eliminating message flooding, though challenges such as inconsistent node filtering policies might lead to inefficiencies. Future development depends on feedback from LN implementers regarding per-peer state management, set reconciliation feasibility, and addressing current design issues.
Minisketch faces scalability challenges due to superlinear decoding costs, suggesting a shift towards more frequent reconciliations or alternative technologies like Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables (IBLT) for better efficiency. Erlay's method combines limited flooding with sketches to optimize workload distribution, potentially integrating IBLT for handling all traffic. Recent research explores various synchronization strategies, including Cuckoo filters, CPI, and IBLT, with Rateless IBLT (RIBLT) showing promise for efficient set size encoding. Such innovations could balance bandwidth overhead and CPU utilization, especially for small average message sizes typical in network gossip protocols.
When evaluating academic findings on IBLT and similar schemes, caution is advised due to potential misleading data concerning overheads and efficiency. Some studies may overlook significant overheads, affecting the perceived viability of these methods. A novel approach suggests using minisketch in a quasi rateless manner, dynamically transmitting data until recovery is achievable, preserving computational efficiency while avoiding excessive overhead. This strategy represents a potentially more practical application of reconciliation schemes in real-world settings.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>