<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-11-15T02:40:07.805414+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 21:06:42.717000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:23:23.781000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>oohrah  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:49:06.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 07:59:32.322000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jamesob  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 13:35:01.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:09:47.569000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:51:51.294000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>glozow  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:16.511000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:24.165000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 15:00:12.757000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:06:12.440000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1406_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1408_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1421_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1422_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1425_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1428_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1426_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1443_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1444_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1445_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1446_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6244_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-11-15T02:40:07.806968+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/taxonomy-of-transaction-fees-in-smart-contracts/512/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the intricate mechanisms of Bitcoin transaction fees, specifically focusing on the distinction between endogenous and exogenous fee structures and introducing a nuanced category known as explicit fee outputs. In Bitcoin transactions, fees can be allocated from within the transaction itself, termed endogenous fees, which are straightforward and maximize block space efficiency. This contrasts with exogenous fees that source additional inputs or outputs outside the transaction to cover costs, often increasing complexity but allowing for singular transaction completion. The text also highlights a strategic method called Child-Pays-for-Parent (CPFP), facilitating transactions where users lack control over initial fees, by integrating the fee in a parent transaction, thus bypassing direct conflict resolution.
Furthermore, the conversation transitions to a critical examination of explicit fee outputs, an alternative fee approach where fees are distinctly represented as separate transaction outputs. While this might offer a solution to optimizing miner compensation, it introduces concerns regarding the block space and the potential bypass of coinbase maturity restrictions. Coinbase maturity is essential for Bitcoin's security framework, ensuring stability and trust in the system by delaying the spendability of newly mined coins. The dialogue suggests that explicit fee outputs, unless meticulously designed, could undermine this mechanism, hinting at broader implications for blockchain integrity, especially in scenarios of increased chain reorganizations.
In consideration of future landscapes where transaction subsidies diminish, the narrative speculates on the necessity for users, particularly receivers, to adopt explicit fee outputs mimicking coinbase maturity features to secure transactions. This adaptation could involve creative scripting to emulate traditional security measures, potentially through Conditional Payment methods like CPFP. Such measures would ensure that despite the evolving dynamics of blockchain transaction validations, the core principles of security and reliability remain uncompromised, fostering a stable and trustworthy digital currency environment.
This exploration underscores the importance of balancing innovation with foundational security principles in the development of Bitcoin's transaction processing methods. It reflects a deep understanding of the technical intricacies involved and the need for forward-thinking solutions that prioritize both efficiency and security in the blockchain ecosystem.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>