<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-12-17T02:53:09.827656+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-20 16:18:51.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-22 22:48:46.117000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-23 00:35:19.795000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-26 00:46:27.546000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-27 21:01:18.494000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-29 00:01:44.200000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-01 20:19:43.253000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 04:36:13.212000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>rustyrussell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-04 04:38:51.748000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="14">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-15 18:58:58.332000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="15">
      <author>jpjuni0r</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 15:18:32.572000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="16">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 16:26:15.798000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_18" depth="0" position="17">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 16:52:48.693000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_19" depth="0" position="18">
      <author>endothermicdev</author>
      <timestamp>2025-12-16 18:33:26.624000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6299_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6312_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6314_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6347_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6353_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6356_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6358_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6374_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6375_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6435_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6438_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6440_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6441_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Dec_2025/6442_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-12-17T02:53:09.830269+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/20" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The project's objective has been to monitor the Lightning Network's gossip network, collecting gossip messages from a diverse set of nodes since its inception at PlebFi Miami. The repository containing the code used, the raw data collected before the lightning++ update, and presentation slides are available [here](https://www.example.com). This initiative led to several important findings about how messages propagate within the network. One of the key observations was a decrease in the time it takes for a message to spread across the network, known as convergence delay, which improved from approximately 500 seconds to 200 seconds for 75% propagation compared to measurements taken in 2022. This enhancement is attributed to Lightning Network implementations opting for more peer connections by default. Furthermore, it was noted that a significant portion of all received messages were transmitted by less than a quarter of the peers, indicating potential inefficiencies in network connectivity or selective filtering policies within LN implementations.
Regarding message types, channel_update messages, accounting for 60% of total message volume, showed that 20% of channels had over 144 messages. This statistic is important for contemplating rate limits for Taproot gossip or gossip version 1.5. Also, for node_announcement messages, which made up 30% of all messages, 2.5% of nodes were announced over 144 times, suggesting issues with certain implementations or automation tools. The total size of all unique messages collected during the observed period was 103.2 MB, exceeding expectations and underlining potential underestimations of node bandwidth usage due to receiving identical messages across multiple peers. Plans include expanding the project's scope by establishing permanent infrastructure for receiving gossip from various geographic locations and different segments of the P2P graph. This expansion will facilitate further study on message spread. Continuous community engagement is encouraged, particularly regarding suggestions for interesting metrics to calculate, requests for tracking gossip from specific nodes, or other contributions.
The discussion also delves into transitioning the Lightning Network (LN) peer-to-peer (P2P) network from a message flooding protocol to a more efficient design inspired by the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). This transition would benefit the LN by reducing latency and propagation delay, crucial for managing gossip due to the network's tolerance for slightly outdated fee information. A major focus of this transition is employing Minisketch for LN gossip, highlighting the need for a collision-resistant mapping mechanism that keeps data elements short to minimize reconciliation time. The Erlay paper's suggestion involves creating unique salts for each peer connection combined with transaction identifiers (TXIDs) to form distinct Minisketch set elements using fast hash functions like SipHash. This approach aims to reduce computational requirements by scaling hashing operations with the number of peer connections and advocating for shorter set elements.
Furthermore, the proposed gossip 1.5 format introduces optional fields in messages, allowing nodes to customize the information sent based on mutually supported features. This evolution seeks to eliminate the need for message flooding in favor of set reconciliation methods for gossip propagation, simplifying implementation and reducing bandwidth consumption. However, challenges such as differing node filtering policies could lead to inefficiencies and failed reconciliations, indicating a need for standardized practices. Engaging with LN implementers on these changes' feasibility is crucial, focusing on managing per-peer state, the practicality of frequent set reconciliations, and addressing current design issues.
In summary, this detailed exploration emphasizes the comparative inefficiency of existing message flooding techniques in LN implementations, proposing a shift towards a combination of limited flooding and set reconciliation to enhance efficiency and scalability. The potential use of Minisketch and alternative reconciliation methods like Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables (IBLT) underscores the necessity for careful selection of technologies based on specific network requirements. This conversation highlights the ongoing efforts to optimize data reconciliation methods for distributed networks like the Lightning Network, aiming to balance computational efficiency, overhead management, and adaptability to meet particular application needs.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>