<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T02:45:21.589076+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>garlonicon  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 09:30:26.903000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 20:18:38.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 06:07:07.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>cmp_ancp  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 14:44:47.356000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 15:51:03.139000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 21:11:28.980000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 23:15:13.002000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>jungly  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-10 05:29:55.984000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-10 21:26:38.824000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>jungly</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-11 07:59:21.471000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-11 19:37:16.933000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6196_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6197_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6199_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6203_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6204_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6205_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6207_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6208_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6209_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6213_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6215_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6216_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T02:45:21.590954+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/12" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The concept of a decentralized bitcoin mining network known as &quot;p2share&quot; offers a novel framework for the allocation of mining rewards. This network operates with its own consensus rules, rewarding miners with shares for creating valid blocks. These shares are transferable among participants, allowing for a dynamic ecosystem where ownership shifts based on the network's rules. A unique feature of this system is the method of distributing the bitcoin reward from successfully mined blocks, which awards the entire bitcoin reward to a single shareholder through a random selection process. This approach ensures compactness in the coinbase output, optimizing transaction efficiency and maximizing revenue from fee-paying transactions on the Bitcoin network. 
The p2share model presents several advantages by maintaining fairness, efficiency, and a trustless environment. It encourages miners to accumulate shares to increase their chances of receiving the bitcoin reward, fostering a more decentralized and innovative ecosystem within Bitcoin mining. However, the viability and implications of the p2share network, including questions about incentive compatibility for miners and the potential impact on Bitcoin's mainnet, are areas of discussion.
Further discourse explores the adaptability of millisatoshis within the Lightning Network, emphasizing their potential in representing internal divisions without affecting the Bitcoin blockchain. This highlights the capacity for innovation within Bitcoin's existing framework, suggesting that as long as transactions remain compatible, new functionalities can be introduced. The security parallels drawn between these implementations and established mechanisms within the Lightning Network underscore the possibility of creating secure environments that enable new features without deviating from Bitcoin's core principles.
Additionally, the integration of privacy features into the p2share mining pool structure, utilizing MimbleWimble (MW) semantics, proposes an interesting approach to enhancing user privacy. This design suggests atomic swaps between the main Bitcoin chain and the sharechain to facilitate privacy without leaving the Bitcoin network. However, challenges arise in selecting a shareholder’s public key within a MW-like privacy-enhanced sharechain, revealing complexities in applying Bitcoin's UTXO model to a sharechain with enhanced privacy features.
The potential for grinding attacks within the proof-of-stake systems of the p2share model highlights fundamental flaws and risks associated with complex mining mechanisms. Such systems, while innovative, might not solve inherent problems but could introduce vulnerabilities or centralize control further. This discussion underlines the importance of careful consideration in developing new mining methodologies to avoid unintended consequences.
The introduction of a &quot;pool sidechain&quot; proposes an innovative method for decentralized mining and resource coordination, allowing miners to commit to a sidechain while mining Bitcoin blocks. This concept aims to enhance the mining ecosystem without increasing operational costs or reducing mining efficiency for individual miners. It suggests a pathway for integrating commitments into the blockchain, potentially leading to faster block times and streamlined interactions between the main blockchain and sidechains.
P2Pool's revival with a separate &quot;sharechain&quot; seeks to address scalability issues by randomly selecting a shareholder for rewards, diverging from traditional even distribution methods. Challenges in maintaining equitable reward distribution among miners highlight the complexities of devising a scalable and fair mining pool mechanism. Proposed solutions, such as a Lightning-like mechanism for aggregating small payments, face technical limitations within the Bitcoin framework, indicating the need for continued innovation and adaptation to overcome these obstacles.
Finally, discussions surrounding the evolution of Bitcoin emphasize the necessity for adaptability and the exploration of new functionalities within the network. The concept of a &quot;softerfork,&quot; allowing for modifications within a sub-network without altering the overall Bitcoin protocol, presents an inventive approach to implementing new features. The ongoing development of P2Poolv2, aiming to improve upon the original design with optimizations for functionality and scalability, represents a significant step toward advancing decentralized mining practices. This project, along with discussions on the economic incentives and technical aspects of sharechain networks, points to a vibrant future for innovation within the cryptocurrency mining landscape.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>