<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
  <updated>2025-11-20T02:48:31.933983+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>jonhbit  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 21:48:21.505000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>gmaxwell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 21:51:45.899000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>jonhbit</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 22:36:32.299000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>gmaxwell</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-19 23:43:49.164000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6246_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6247_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6264_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6293_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6294_Gossip-Observer-New-project-to-monitor-the-Lightning-P2P-network.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Gossip Observer: New project to monitor the Lightning P2P network</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T02:48:31.934986+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/gossip-observer-new-project-to-monitor-the-lightning-p2p-network/2105/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-14 20:48:38.161000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The project aimed at monitoring the Lightning gossip network has provided several insights into the dynamics of message propagation. Since its start at PlebFi Miami, efforts have involved collecting gossip messages from various nodes, with findings and resources available [here](https://www.example.com). Observations indicate a decrease in convergence delay, suggesting improvements in network efficiency, partly due to Lightning Network (LN) implementations increasing peer connections. A considerable portion of messages were received from a limited number of peers, indicating potential connectivity or filtering inefficiencies. The analysis of message types revealed significant data on channel updates and node announcements, underscoring challenges and considerations for proposed rate limits and the impact on network bandwidth usage. Plans are underway to enhance the project's infrastructure to capture more diverse gossip data, encouraging community engagement for further analysis and implementation suggestions.
Discussions around transitioning the LN P2P network towards a more efficient design have been inspired by the Erlay paper and Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP). The proposed move away from a message flooding protocol could reduce latency and propagation delay, crucial for LN gossip. Emphasis is placed on adapting Minisketch for LN gossip, utilizing unique salts and transaction identifiers for collision-resistant mapping. This approach aims to simplify gossip propagation through set reconciliation methods, potentially reducing bandwidth consumption. However, challenges such as disparate node filtering policies need addressing. Feedback from LN implementers will be vital in refining these proposals.
Critique of the current message flooding technique used in LN implementations highlights potential benefits of combining limited flooding with set reconciliation, following Erlay's design. Nonetheless, concerns regarding Minisketch's superlinear decoding costs and its impact on CPU usage have been raised. Alternatives such as IBLT (Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables) and frequent reconciliations are considered to mitigate these issues. Recent research suggests that IBLT-based protocols may offer a promising solution, particularly in scenarios requiring efficient small set exchanges. This exploration underscores the importance of selecting appropriate technologies based on LN's operational needs, balancing effectiveness against overheads in data propagation.
The efficacy of IBLT and related schemes for set reconciliation in the LN context has been further explored, revealing advantages in terms of bandwidth overhead and encoding costs. Notably, the Rateless IBLT (RIBLT) protocol demonstrates potential for efficient sync without needing to estimate set differences, offering an appealing mix of low bandwidth overhead and linear encoding cost growth. However, careful consideration of element sizes and the trade-off between bandwidth overhead and CPU savings is necessary. Moreover, the practicality of integrating these technologies into LN implementations warrants further investigation, highlighting the ongoing need for research and development in this area.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>