<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-06T02:46:33.862796+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 16:09:26.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-16 16:45:25.792000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ftw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 14:38:17.246000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-29 13:49:36.191000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-31 15:44:02.036000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>moonsettler</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-05 22:39:58.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rijndael</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-06 00:44:27.038000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6071_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6080_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6097_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6100_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6156_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6178_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6194_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6195_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T02:46:33.863852+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent proposal to integrate `OP_STARK_VERIFY` into Tapscript marks a significant advancement in incorporating zero-knowledge proof capabilities directly into Bitcoin, proposing a direct on-chain mechanism for verifying STARK proofs. This initiative is motivated by the potential applications of such technology in enhancing Bitcoin's scalability through Validity rollups, securing it against future quantum threats with post-quantum signatures, and improving transaction privacy. The focus on vanilla STARKs, particularly the Stone prover, is due to their transparent assumptions, scalability in verification complexity, and efficiency in proof size relative to computation size, presenting a robust solution for scaling Bitcoin's Layer 1.
However, the proposal acknowledges substantial challenges, including the selection of a specific STARK protocol without compromising Bitcoin's neutral stance, managing the larger proof sizes of STARKs compared to alternatives like SNARKs, and the risks of embedding a particular proof system into Bitcoin's consensus mechanism. It explores various alternative methods for ZK proof verification within Bitcoin, weighing their efficiency, flexibility, and the degree of protocol enshrinement against the complexities they introduce.
In terms of resource usage within proof systems, the discussion centers around the balance between proof sizes and verification times, highlighting the implications for decentralized activities such as block building and relay. Techniques like compression are noted for their ability to significantly reduce proof sizes, though concerns remain about the impact of large proofs on mining unpredictability and block verification budgets. This brings about a broader conversation on the goals for &quot;average&quot; block size and time, emphasizing the need for clear targets to guide consistent application across different scenarios.
The exploration of STARK implementation strategies reveals a nuanced consideration of trade-offs among proving speed, proof size, and verification efficiency. A multistage optimization pipeline is described, which balances these factors to achieve verifier-friendly proofs. This includes adapting hash functions and parameters to support efficient verification at the cost of proving speed and increased computational requirements. The analysis extends to the on-chain costs associated with different proof compression techniques and their feasibility within the Bitcoin script context, pointing out the implications for blockchain transactions and system resilience against attacks like DoS.
An alternative approach to integrating ZK verification into Bitcoin involves a metaprotocol layered over the base protocol, utilizing existing witness space for STARK proofs and off-chain state management through open-source indexers. This method offers several advantages, including reduced risk of adding complex cryptographic primitives to the base layer, market-driven adoption, and the flexibility to adapt to superior technologies without necessitating contentious forks. However, skepticism remains regarding the security and efficacy of metaprotocols compared to established solutions like Starknet, which has demonstrated the practical viability and security of STARK proofs in handling significant transaction volumes and value.
Finally, the discussion touches upon the technicalities of proof settlement using the OP_CAT verifier and the strategic division of the verification process into multiple transactions to enhance network efficiency, security, and data packing in blocks. Additionally, concerns are raised about the lack of binding between the proof and specific transactions, suggesting the potential for proof reuse across different transactions, which could undermine the security of permissionless exits from multiparty systems. Suggestions include incorporating transaction-specific elements into the proof parameters or employing Schnorr signatures to ensure proofs are explicitly tied to the transactions they authorize, addressing the critical need for transaction-bound verifications to maintain system integrity and prevent unauthorized use of proofs.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>