<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T02:47:06.832499+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-14 16:09:26.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-16 16:45:25.792000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ftw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-17 14:38:17.246000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-29 13:49:36.191000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-10-31 15:44:02.036000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>moonsettler  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-05 22:39:58.538000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>rijndael  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-06 00:44:27.038000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>ftw  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-08 00:01:32.351000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>Nuh  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-15 01:04:33.320000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>Abdel  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-16 12:47:17.280000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>Nuh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 05:38:28.037000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>Abdel</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 10:20:12.238000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>Abdel</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 10:27:00.251000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="14">
      <author>Abdel</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 10:39:56.616000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="15">
      <author>Nuh</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 11:09:47.745000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6071_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6080_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6097_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6100_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6156_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Oct_2025/6178_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6194_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6195_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6200_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6248_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6252_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6267_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6268_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6269_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6271_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6272_Proposal-OP-STARK-VERIFY-Native-STARK-Proof-Verification-in-Bitcoin-Script.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Proposal: OP_STARK_VERIFY - Native STARK Proof Verification in Bitcoin Script</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T02:47:06.834600+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/proposal-op-stark-verify-native-stark-proof-verification-in-bitcoin-script/2056/16" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-10-14 10:55:51.298000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The recent proposal to integrate `OP_STARK_VERIFY` into Tapscript, aiming to enhance Bitcoin's capability with direct on-chain verification of STARK (Scalable Transparent ARgument of Knowledge) proofs, marks a significant stride towards incorporating zero-knowledge proof verifications within the Bitcoin ecosystem. This initiative addresses the need for scalable and efficient verification processes that bypass the complexities tied to off-chain computations and the limitations of on-chain challenge mechanisms currently in place. By focusing on vanilla STARKs, particularly those demonstrated by the Stone prover, the proposal leverages their transparent, post-quantum-secure assumptions, and poly-logarithmic verification complexity, offering an avenue for scaling Bitcoin L1 through Validity rollups, enabling post-quantum signature aggregation, and facilitating privacy-preserving transactions.
However, this proposition is not without its challenges and alternatives. The discussion acknowledges credible neutrality issues in selecting a specific STARK protocol, the larger proof sizes compared to other systems like SNARKs, and the technical and consensus risks of incorporating a specific proof system into Bitcoin's consensus layer. It explores alternative approaches such as `OP_CAT`-based verifiers and arithmetic opcodes for constructing a verifier within Script, each presenting its own set of complexities, efficiencies, and levels of protocol enshrinement.
Further examination delves into the practical considerations surrounding resource usage within proof systems, highlighting the trade-offs between proof sizes, verification times, and the implications these factors have on blockchain efficiency and decentralization. The discourse expands on compression techniques and multistage pipelines aimed at optimizing proof sizes and verification speeds, illustrating the nuanced balance required to maintain operational efficiency while minimizing on-chain costs.
A metaprotocol layered over Bitcoin is also discussed as an alternative method to introduce ZK verification functionality, circumventing the need for direct modifications to the Bitcoin base protocol. This approach suggests leveraging existing witness space for embedding STARK proofs, advocating for risk reduction, market-driven adoption, and the flexibility to adapt to superior proof systems without contentious soft forks.
Contrasting perspectives highlight Starknet’s proven track record in production as evidence of the technical feasibility and security of systems built on STARK proofs, challenging the skepticism towards the reliability of Zero-Knowledge Virtual Machines (ZKVMs) and the necessity for upgrade mechanisms to address provable bugs. Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the intricacies of implementing covenants and the critical importance of securely associating cryptographic proofs with specific transactions to prevent misuse.
Critics of integrating STARK technology into Bitcoin’s consensus layer raise concerns about contravening Bitcoin's principles of simplicity, security, and stability. They warn of the potential economic implications and long-term risks associated with enshrining a specific iteration of STARKs into Bitcoin’s protocol, advocating for a cautious approach that preserves Bitcoin's core attributes and flexibility to adapt to technological advancements.
The dialogues underscore the ongoing debate around the implementation of advanced cryptographic technologies within Bitcoin, emphasizing the need for careful consideration of the trade-offs involved, the evolution and security of blockchain technologies, and the broader implications for decentralized applications and platforms.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>