<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-11-18T02:45:13.685423+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 21:06:42.717000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:23:23.781000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>oohrah  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:49:06.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 07:59:32.322000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jamesob  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 13:35:01.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:09:47.569000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:51:51.294000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>glozow  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:16.511000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:24.165000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 15:00:12.757000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:06:12.440000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 18:53:09.743000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 19:39:15.036000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1406_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1408_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1421_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1422_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1425_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1428_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1426_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1443_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1444_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1445_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1446_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6244_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6260_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6262_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T02:45:13.687122+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/taxonomy-of-transaction-fees-in-smart-contracts/512/14" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion begins with an analysis of the mechanisms behind transaction fees within Bitcoin, emphasizing the importance of understanding these mechanisms for the development of mempool design and Bitcoin scaling solutions. The conversation highlights two types of fee structures: endogenous and exogenous. Endogenous fees are described as those that come from within the transaction itself, which is a straightforward approach used in typical wallet sends and certain Lightning Network configurations. This method is praised for its efficiency and compactness. On the other hand, exogenous fees involve using funds external to the smart contract but within the same Bitcoin transaction, seen in scenarios like `SIGHASH_SINGLE | ANYONECANPAY`. This setup, while potentially increasing complexity, allows for a single transaction to cover the necessary fees.
Further exploration delves into the Child-Pays-for-Parent (CPFP) strategies and their suitability in situations where users have limited control over the parent transaction. The text outlines how the Lightning Network and various smart contracts leverage CPFP, distinguishing between endogenous and exogenous fees within this context. A notable mention is of Package RBF (Replace-By-Fee), which facilitates a child transaction paying for a parent's conflict, highlighting the challenges posed by Bitcoin's current mempool implementations to this approach.
The narrative shifts towards discussing the impact of rising transaction fees on developers, who now prioritize code compactness, sometimes at the expense of security. This situation prompts a reconsideration of covenant constructions to minimize on-chain footprint amidst economic constraints. It touches upon the potential risks to decentralization, especially concerning practices favoring larger miners and the dynamics of transaction prioritization by Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) under variable fee conditions.
The conversation then addresses concerns around securing low fees through on-chain transactions versus the implications for security and decentralization. It critically views the economic dynamics that may disadvantage smaller miners and explores strategic adaptations among LSPs, including out-of-band payments to miners for transaction prioritization and the operational considerations for LSPs running their mining operations versus using acceleration services. Highlighted is the centralization risk tied to both scenarios, emphasizing the influence of frequent, substantial transactions on Bitcoin's decentralization ethos.
In a more technical inquiry, the dialogue turns to the concept of explicit fee outputs as a potential future necessity, particularly in post-subsidy conditions or high re-organization scenarios. This part of the discussion scrutinizes the security implications of bypassing coinbase maturity restrictions and speculates on the use of explicit &quot;anyone_can_spend&quot; fee outputs to maintain network integrity. Through a hypothetical example involving CPFP, the text underscores the balance between transaction confirmation speeds and the risks associated with giving receivers a false sense of security, pondering the long-term impacts on miner incentives and network stability in an environment where explicit output fees dominate.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>