<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-11T02:47:12.194679+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>garlonicon  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 09:30:26.903000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 20:18:38.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 06:07:07.470000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>cmp_ancp  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 14:44:47.356000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 15:51:03.139000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 21:11:28.980000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>ZmnSCPxj  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-09 23:15:13.002000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>jungly</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-10 05:29:55.984000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-10 21:26:38.824000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6196_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6197_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6199_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6203_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6204_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6205_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6207_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6208_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6209_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6213_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-11T02:47:12.196099+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/10" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The p2share network presents a novel approach to Bitcoin mining, emphasizing a decentralized method for distributing mining rewards. In this framework, miners receive &quot;shares&quot; for their contributions, which are transferable and can be exchanged among participants according to the network's rules. A standout characteristic of this system is its reward distribution mechanism, where the entire Bitcoin reward from a mined block is given to a single shareholder chosen randomly. This method aims to keep the coinbase output compact, enhancing the network's efficiency by minimizing transaction bloat and maximizing revenue from fee-paying transactions. The design promises fairness, with each share expected to be rewarded in proportion to its prevalence in the total supply, and maintains a trustless environment through deterministic, consensus-driven processes. Importantly, it encourages miners to accumulate shares, aligning incentives across the network.
The discussion also explores the potential of millisatoshis within the Lightning Network, suggesting that these smaller units could enable new functionalities without necessitating an alternate cryptocurrency. This idea underscores the importance of keeping Bitcoin's ecosystem intact while exploring innovative implementations. Security mechanisms akin to those in the Lightning Network, such as penalty transactions, are considered crucial for deterring fraudulent activities within these new frameworks. Furthermore, the dialogue hints at the adaptability of Bitcoin's block time durations, suggesting that certain applications might benefit from flexibility in this aspect.
Privacy features within the Bitcoin mining pool structure, particularly through a proposed p2share design incorporating MimbleWimble semantics, aim to enhance user privacy without leaving the Bitcoin network. This integration faces challenges, notably in selecting a shareholder's public key in a manner that retains MimbleWimble's privacy benefits. Solutions may involve adapting consensus rules to ensure transactions do not reveal specific participant amounts, thereby preserving privacy.
Concerns about the feasibility of the p2share network include the risk of grinding attacks, where individuals could manipulate the selection process for mining rewards. This highlights potential vulnerabilities in proof-of-stake systems and the complexities introduced by trying to innovate in the mining space, which might inadvertently centralize control or introduce new weaknesses.
The concept of a &quot;pool sidechain&quot; suggests an innovative way for miners to demonstrate their computational efforts through the submission of weak blocks, potentially allowing for faster block times and reducing operational costs for miners. This concept maintains a focus on efficiency and sustainability, aiming to enhance the mining ecosystem without compromising profitability.
The revival of the P2Pool design, with adjustments for scalability and reward distribution, addresses issues in traditional mining pools. Proposals include mechanisms for aggregating small payments without centralized coordination, though technical and economic barriers might complicate implementation. The influence of large custodians poses significant challenges to decentralization and innovation within the mining process.
Sharechain networks propose a symbiotic relationship with Bitcoin, testing new features and services. They offer a speculative investment model that supports the Bitcoin ecosystem while potentially bypassing traditional financial systems. However, bootstrapping such networks faces hurdles like low difficulty and competition for shares.
Finally, the discourse raises philosophical points on Bitcoin's evolution, suggesting that innovations within the Bitcoin network should preserve its foundational principles. The notion of a &quot;softerfork&quot; introduces the possibility of modifying the network in less invasive ways, allowing for experimentation without altering the core protocols. The p2poolv2 project aims to replicate and refine the original P2Pool design, addressing scalability and reward distribution, with ongoing developments available on [GitHub](https://github.com/p2poolv2/p2poolv2).</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>