<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T02:45:55.100771+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>rustyrussell  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-01 21:06:42.717000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:23:23.781000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_4" depth="0" position="3">
      <author>oohrah  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 04:49:06.308000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_5" depth="0" position="4">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 07:59:32.322000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_6" depth="0" position="5">
      <author>jamesob  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 13:35:01.683000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_7" depth="0" position="6">
      <author>ajtowns  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:09:47.569000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_8" depth="0" position="7">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:51:51.294000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_9" depth="0" position="8">
      <author>glozow  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:16.511000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_10" depth="0" position="9">
      <author>sipa  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 14:57:24.165000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_11" depth="0" position="10">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2024-02-02 15:00:12.757000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_12" depth="0" position="11">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-14 20:06:12.440000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_13" depth="0" position="12">
      <author>instagibbs  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 18:53:09.743000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_14" depth="0" position="13">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-17 19:39:15.036000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_15" depth="0" position="14">
      <author>AntoineP</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 15:48:35.039000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_16" depth="0" position="15">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 19:58:37.663000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_17" depth="0" position="16">
      <author>instagibbs</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 20:27:24.160000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_18" depth="0" position="17">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-18 20:50:25.577000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1406_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1408_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1421_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1422_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1425_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1428_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1426_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1443_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1444_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1445_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1446_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6244_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6260_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6262_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6275_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6278_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6279_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6281_Taxonomy-of-Transaction-Fees-in-Smart-Contracts.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Taxonomy of Transaction Fees in Smart Contracts</title>
    <updated>2025-11-19T02:45:55.102587+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/taxonomy-of-transaction-fees-in-smart-contracts/512/18" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2024-02-01 16:52:08.683000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The discussion delves into the complexities of fee mechanisms within Bitcoin transactions, particularly focusing on the distinctions between endogenous and exogenous fees in relation to smart contracts and wallet transactions. Endogenous fees, originating from within the transaction itself, are exemplified by straightforward transactions such as typical wallet sends and certain Lightning Network channels, valued for their compactness in blockchain space utilization. Conversely, exogenous fees, sourced from outside the smart contract yet within a single transaction, are highlighted in scenarios like `SIGHASH_SINGLE | ANYONECANPAY` signatures, which are essential for applications such as HTLC presigned transactions in the Lightning Network and statechains. The examination extends to strategies like Child-Pays-for-Parent (CPFP) and Package Replace-By-Fee (RBF), which offer solutions for managing transaction fees when users cannot alter parent transactions directly, facilitating efficient fee handling in complex scenarios such as Lightning Network's anchor channels.
The conversation further explores the implications of rising transaction fees on blockchain technology and the prioritization of cost efficiency over security by some users. This shift towards minimizing transaction fees, potentially compromising security, signals a trend where developers may favor centralized databases or blockchains with greater centralization to reduce costs. Such practices raise concerns about the impact on decentralization and the competitive viability of smaller miners, highlighting the delicate balance between transaction cost efficiency, security, and the fundamental principles of decentralization in blockchain networks.
Moreover, the discussion touches on strategies employed by Lightning Service Providers (LSPs) and miners to manage high or variable transaction fees, such as utilizing specific UTXOs with ALL|ANYONECANPAY signatures and engaging in out-of-band payments to prioritize transactions. These tactics underscore the challenges and potential compromises faced by entities operating within the Bitcoin network, emphasizing the need for innovative solutions to preserve network integrity and decentralization while addressing economic realities.
Central to this discourse is the exploration of explicit fee outputs as a mechanism to address transaction fee management, especially under conditions where blockchain blocks are consistently full. The concept of explicit &quot;anyone_can_spend&quot; fee outputs, potentially circumventing coinbase maturity restrictions, presents both opportunities and risks for network security and integrity. This approach, particularly through the use of Child Pays for Parent (CPFP) transactions, offers a method for receivers to ensure quicker transaction confirmations. However, it also raises concerns about network stability and the incentives for miners to engage in potentially destabilizing reorganizations, highlighting the intricate interplay between transaction fee management strategies and the overarching goals of blockchain technology.
In conclusion, the discourse underscores the critical importance of carefully considering transaction fee mechanisms and their broader implications on blockchain technology's development and sustainability. It calls for a nuanced understanding of the economic, security, and decentralization factors at play, advocating for innovative solutions that balance these considerations to advance the field.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>