<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
  <updated>2025-11-08T02:27:15.742542+00:00</updated>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <thread>
    <message id="msg_1" depth="0" position="0">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr  .</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_2" depth="0" position="1">
      <author>garlonicon</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 09:30:26.903000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
    <message id="msg_3" depth="0" position="2">
      <author>VzxPLnHqr</author>
      <timestamp>2025-11-07 20:18:38.916000+00:00</timestamp>
    </message>
  </thread>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6196_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6197_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Nov_2025/6199_P2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - P2share: how to turn any network (or testnet!) into a bitcoin miner</title>
    <updated>2025-11-08T02:27:15.743144+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/p2share-how-to-turn-any-network-or-testnet-into-a-bitcoin-miner/2093/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <published>2025-11-07 01:06:06.018000+00:00</published>
    <summary>The concept of a decentralized bitcoin mining network, known as a &quot;p2share&quot; network, emerges as an innovative approach to mining and reward distribution within the realm of cryptocurrency. This network operates with its own set of consensus rules, mirroring those of traditional bitcoin networks, but distinguishes itself through a unique reward allocation system. In this setup, miners receive &quot;shares&quot; for validating blocks, which are transferable and can change ownership based on pre-defined network rules. A significant deviation from conventional reward distribution methods is observed here; rather than distributing bitcoin rewards proportionately among all miners or using centralized services for allocation, the p2share network awards the entire bitcoin reward to a single shareholder through a random selection process. This methodology not only ensures fairness and efficiency by keeping the coinbase output compact but also encourages a trustless, decentralized environment. The design is aimed at aligning miner incentives towards share accumulation, thereby enhancing their chances of receiving bitcoin rewards, whether through active mining or holding shares as speculative assets.
Further discussions around the p2share network explore its viability, touching upon incentive compatibility for miners, differentiation from sharechain and sidechain concepts, and its potential impact on Bitcoin's mainnet security. Despite these considerations, the network is seen as contributing to Bitcoin's overall security architecture, akin to a mining pool, but from a decentralized perspective. This model advocates for a more innovative and participatory ecosystem within bitcoin mining, emphasizing fairness, efficiency, and trustlessness.
In addition to the foundational aspects of the p2share network, there are suggestions regarding the implementation of privacy features reminiscent of MimbleWimble (MW), aiming to incorporate a privacy layer within the p2share framework. This would enable atomic swaps between mainchain BTC and the sharechain, ensuring privacy without exiting the Bitcoin ecosystem. However, challenges arise in maintaining MW-like privacy while achieving pseudorandom uniform selection of a shareholder’s public key, given the inherent privacy features of MW that obscure transaction details. Potential solutions could involve adjusting consensus rules to mandate equal transaction output amounts, thereby mimicking sharejoins from a blockchain analysis perspective and potentially meeting privacy criteria within the sharechain network. This discussion illustrates the ongoing exploration and adaptation required to balance privacy, security, and functionality in developing decentralized financial technologies.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>