<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
  <updated>2025-03-06T02:24:03.577404+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>marathon-gary.602000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-05T17:21:57.602000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T02:24:03.577436+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-119-op-checktemplateverify-no-activation/1494" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Given the provided context, a detailed summary cannot be generated as the actual content of the discussion or the emails regarding Bitcoin Core PR 31989 is not provided. To create a comprehensive summary, specific details from the email thread, such as key points of debate, technical insights, or consensus reached regarding PR 31989, would be necessary. Without access to the actual content of the emails, it's not possible to adhere to the instructions for summarizing the information in a structured, paragraph format. 

For a fruitful summary, including the main arguments, technical challenges, proposed solutions, and any implications of implementing PR 31989 discussed in the email thread would be essential. This would typically involve outlining the purpose of PR 31989, its impact on Bitcoin Core, any contentious issues, and how it proposes to improve or alter functionalities within Bitcoin Core. Additionally, insights into how the community or contributors are reacting to this PR, including support, criticisms, or suggestions for amendments, would also provide valuable content for a summarized blog post. 

In absence of the actual email content, these guidelines outline the approach one would take to distill the essence of the discussion into a coherent, informative piece, focusing on reorganizing the provided information into a narrative that offers a clear overview of the topic at hand while adhering to the rules specified.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-05T17:21:57.602000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
