<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
  <updated>2025-03-06T02:23:51.562116+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-05T22:59:10.884000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>BIP-119 (OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY) (no activation)</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T02:23:51.562149+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bip-119-op-checktemplateverify-no-activation/1494/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the mailing list revolves around the combination of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) with another primitive as suggested by Bitcoin Core's Pull Request 31989. It emphasizes the importance of focusing solely on the technical merits of BIP-119 without being influenced by previous issues related to OP_EVAL. The design of BIP-119 has been intentionally conservative to prevent the recurrence of such problems.

BIP-119, or CheckTemplateVerify, proposes a method that could enhance Bitcoin's protocol by adding new functionalities while aiming to maintain the network's security and efficiency. The conversation suggests that any evaluation of this proposal should strictly consider its technical contributions and potential impact on the ecosystem. This approach ensures that discussions remain objective and focused on the innovation's value rather than historical challenges associated with similar proposals in the past.

Incorporating another primitive with CTV, as indicated in the Pull Request 31989, introduces a nuanced layer to the debate, suggesting a development direction that might offer benefits beyond those initially envisioned by BIP-119 alone. This aspect underlines the significance of thorough technical scrutiny and the need for a detailed examination of how these combined enhancements could influence Bitcoin's operational capabilities and overall resilience against various threats or inefficiencies.

The insistence on discussing BIP-119 based on its "technical merits alone" signifies a deliberate effort to prioritize substance over sentiment, ensuring that the proposal is assessed on the basis of its potential to contribute positively to the Bitcoin network. This approach is crucial for fostering an environment where innovations can be critically evaluated, devoid of bias or undue influence from past experiences.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-05T22:59:10.884000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
