<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-11T02:26:21.787514+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose.610000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-11T01:45:46.610000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T02:26:21.787555+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around covenants in the Bitcoin ecosystem has seen a notable shift towards positive sentiment among developers, an observation highlighted by the shared insights and proposed roadmaps on platforms like Twitter. This includes the author's own roadmap, which, despite being a quick contribution to the conversation, is rooted in two years of contemplation and has garnered significant support and minimal objection from the community. The roadmap and the feedback it received underscore a growing interest and optimism in the potential of covenants to enhance Bitcoin's functionality and expressiveness without compromising its core properties.

The role of Bitcoin protocol developers is twofold: maintaining the decentralized and permissionless nature of the network while expanding its utility for application development. This task comes with inherent challenges, such as the risks associated with consensus code changes that could lead to bugs, chain splits, or incentive misalignments. With the goal of maximizing protocol expressiveness while safeguarding network security, the [Great Script Restoration](https://rusty.ozlabs.org/2024/01/19/the-great-opcode-restoration.html) project by Rusty Russel stands out. It aims to restore much of Bitcoin’s original script capabilities, including transaction introspection through covenants, via a careful approach that ensures validation requirements are met efficiently.

Despite the utility covenants offer for developing second-layer protocols, hesitancy remains within the broader community regarding their integration into Bitcoin. This hesitance stems from both the technical complexities of designing a practical framework for generalized covenants and the implications such features may have on the network's incentive structures. However, there exists a cautious optimism towards incremental steps in covenant technology, exemplified by the proposal and spec outlining of the [OP_TXHASH opcode](https://covenants.info/proposals/txhash/) as a foundational element for future developments. This opcode, inspired by Russel O’Connor’s ideas, represents a precursor to more sophisticated covenant mechanisms and aligns with the previously introduced [OP_CTV](https://covenants.info/proposals/ctv/) and [OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK (CSFS)](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/050d422b2ac24d8221edab0ff0053e0f585409f7/bip-0348.md), showcasing a pathway towards enhancing Bitcoin's expressiveness and utility for complex protocols.

The combination of CTV and CSFS opcodes not only augments existing protocols but also paves the way for novel applications within Bitcoin's ecosystem. These include improvements to pre-signed transaction protocols, enhancements to the Lightning Network through the potential implementation of LN Symmetry, and the facilitation of multi-party channels and PTLCs. Additionally, this opcode pairing holds promise for the Ark protocol, DLC simplification, and the BitVM project, indicating a broad spectrum of innovation made possible by these developments. Moreover, the support for these proposals within the developer community and the constructive feedback from proponents of alternative covenant solutions suggest a collaborative effort towards refining these technologies for eventual integration into the Bitcoin protocol.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T01:45:46.610000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
