<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-12T02:24:22.481643+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-03-11 22:08:19.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T02:24:22.481679+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion around changing Bitcoin's consensus rules, particularly through a proposed soft fork involving CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) and CSFS, brings to light various perspectives on technological advancements and their implications for the network. The primary argument for CTV centers on its ability to simplify protocols that rely on pre-signed transactions by eliminating the need for interactivity during the pre-signing process and the associated requirement to store signatures. This reduction of interactivity is viewed as a significant benefit, with potential applications in enhancing Lightning Network (LN) protocols and other second-layer solutions.

Developers within the Lightning community have expressed interest in implementing LN Symmetry with the availability of CTV+CSFS, highlighting the demand for features that can be immediately beneficial over those that are speculative or intended for future development. However, there's skepticism about the immediate priority of such developments, given the current focus on delivering user-demanded features that are already feasible without new soft forks.

CTV is also touted as a game-changer for newer protocols like Ark, a second-layer solution aiming to improve upon current implementations within Bitcoin's existing framework. The protocol could see significant user experience improvements with CTV, offering a strong case for its adoption. However, the concrete benefits for end users, especially in relation to Bitcoin's broader ecosystem, remain a question. For instance, the application of CTV in Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) and its role in simplifying these contracts is noted, yet the actual interest and adoption among Bitcoin users appear limited.

Furthermore, concerns are raised about categorizing certain constructions as "vaults," pointing out the nuances and potential risks involved in their implementation. While CTV might offer advantages in reducing interaction in some vault constructions, the overall traction and impact of such applications on Bitcoin security and utility are still up for debate.

In conclusion, the argument for integrating CTV and CSFS into Bitcoin via a soft fork finds some support in the potential to reduce transaction interactivity. Nevertheless, the justification based solely on this aspect seems insufficient to warrant a consensus rule change at this time. The debate underscores the need for a careful and considered approach to evolving Bitcoin's technology, ensuring that any changes align with the network's long-term interests and the immediate needs of its users.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T22:08:19.968000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
