<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:51.536827+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-11T16:22:24.494000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:51.536856+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the implementation of CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) in various projects and its potential adoption by Bitcoin users. Despite some skepticism, there is evidence of interest and utility in using discreet log contracts (DLCs) among Bitcoin enthusiasts. Contrary to the belief that Bitcoin users are not interested in DLCs, platforms such as Atomic Finance and Lava have successfully utilized them, indicating a demand for such contracts beyond the failure of individual projects.

The concept of vaults has been introduced as a security measure for Bitcoin transactions, allowing users to delay external spends through an "unvault" period. This mechanism is designed to protect users from unauthorized transactions by adding a time constraint before funds can be moved again. Despite criticisms, vaults offer a significant security enhancement, demonstrating their utility and adoption within the cryptocurrency space. The use of pre-signed transactions further complicates the process, requiring precise management of funds to avoid unintended loss or fees.

CTV's role in facilitating reduced interactivity in protocols has been highlighted as a motivation for considering it in a soft fork, specifically aiming to replace presigned transactions with CTV commitments. Although some may view this application as insufficient justification for a soft fork, the previous year's interest in activating APO and creating a vault demo underscores the ongoing exploration and potential of CTV in enhancing Bitcoin's functionality. The support from co-authors of APO for incorporating CTV+CSFS into a soft fork reinforces the argument for its development and implementation in improving security and efficiency within Bitcoin protocols.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T16:22:24.494000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
