<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:39.989408+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-03-11 16:26:19.217000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:39.989439+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/7" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The ongoing discourse among programmers about the design and implications of fully generalized covenants for networks reflects a cautious approach towards developing a practical protocol. There is an acknowledgment of the complexities and uncertainties that lie ahead, with a preference for creating something fundamentally new that allows for clear reasoning, despite recognizing that such an endeavor is ambitious and its success uncertain. In the interim, focusing on shorter-term improvements and adopting mature proposals seems prudent.

The conversation touches upon specific technical aspects, such as the comparison between CTV+CSFS functions and [SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT](https://covenants.info/proposals/apo/) (APO). It highlights the limitations and challenges of using CTV+CSFS as a direct replacement for APO, including its reliance on CPFP over single transaction exogenous fees for cost-effectiveness and reliability from a relay perspective. These nuances underscore the complexity of making protocol enhancements and the careful consideration required in balancing innovation with practicality and user demand.

The discussion also delves into the potential for updating to PTLCs and the advantages of re-bindable signatures in simplifying the integration of stacked protocols. However, there is caution against allowing the adoption of a soft fork to be contingent upon a single group's immediate use, emphasizing instead the importance of utility and improvement to existing constructions as the key criteria for implementation.

BitVM's development and potential adoption is another point of interest, with inquiries about its usage among Bitcoin users and its development by [multiple companies](https://bitvm.org/about-bitvm-alliance). The appeal of trust-minimized bridges and the desire for concrete performance metrics illustrate the ongoing search for solutions that enhance security and efficiency within the ecosystem.

In conclusion, the exchange reflects a nuanced understanding of the challenges and opportunities in advancing blockchain technology. It acknowledges the incremental nature of current improvements like CTV+CSFS while stressing the need for modular, forward-compatible developments that can withstand future innovations and shifts in the landscape without imposing significant maintenance burdens.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T16:26:19.217000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
