<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:25.760558+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-11 16:42:06.052000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:25.760590+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/8" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion emphasizes the evolution of Bitcoin from a protocol known intimately by its users to one where the distinction between users and developers has become more pronounced. The original point stresses that modern Bitcoin users interact with the cryptocurrency through applications developed on top of the Bitcoin protocol, rather than directly engaging with the protocol itself. This shift reflects the maturation of Bitcoin, moving from an era where users were also developers to a broader user base that relies on developers to create user-friendly applications.

The conversation also touches upon the topic of Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) and their reception within the Bitcoin community. It points out the contrasting perspectives provided by different participants, highlighting a failed venture that attempted to build on DLCs and another that recently secured significant funding. This disparity underscores the nuanced reality of adoption and interest levels in such technologies among Bitcoin users versus developers. BitVM is introduced as an example of a project that, despite its challenges and being in its infancy, has garnered attention and investment from developers looking to extend Bitcoin's capabilities. This interest in BitVM illustrates a demand for more expressive features within the Bitcoin protocol, even if these are pursued through less than ideal means due to current limitations.

Furthermore, the debate around protocol upgrades, such as CTV, is explored. The reluctance to embrace new implementations due to the absence of existing ones is criticized, especially considering historical precedents like taproot, which saw no implementations at the time of deployment. This argument suggests a disconnect between the conceptual and practical aspects of protocol development, pointing out the significant investment of time and resources required for implementation compared to theoretical discussions. The discourse encourages a recognition of the developer ecosystem's efforts and challenges in innovating within the constraints of the Bitcoin protocol, advocating for a more supportive stance towards exploring and implementing new features.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T16:42:06.052000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
