<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:15.054567+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>reardencode.897000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-11T17:19:12.897000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T02:25:15.054598+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/9" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse centers around the complexities and differing viewpoints within the Bitcoin development community regarding when and how to implement consensus changes. A significant tension exists between two ideologies: one advocating for changes only under extreme necessity, and another favoring upgrades whenever clear improvements are available. The proposed "Team Slow and Steady" approach attempts to find a middle ground, promoting a cautious but progressive path towards enhancing Bitcoin's functionality through specific upgrades like CTV+CSFS. This strategy, however, is not without its critics. Some argue that any upgrade must present a strong and undeniable reason for its inclusion, a criterion that is challenging to meet given the delicate balance required to maintain Bitcoin's incentive structure.

Further analysis reveals a nuanced debate over the technical specifics of potential Bitcoin upgrades, particularly around the concepts of IKEY and PC (Pair Commit). The discussion highlights a concern that without the implementation of IKEY, certain transactions could become unnecessarily larger, thereby increasing costs without justifiable benefits. This point underscores the broader argument for carefully considered enhancements that do not compromise Bitcoin's operational efficiency or its foundational incentives.

One innovative solution presented in the dialogue is Jeremy Rubin's key laddering concept, which enables Merkle-tree-like commitments through sigops, thus fostering multi-commitments without directly adding them to Bitcoin. This approach suggests an alternative method of achieving similar outcomes as would be gained through more direct modifications to the Bitcoin protocol, like the CSFS BIP. However, it's argued that relying solely on sigops could lead to higher validation costs, albeit not exceeding current worst-case scenarios, but unnecessary nonetheless. The conversation concludes with a reflection on the development of the CSFS BIP and the decision to propose PC as a separate opcode to address these concerns, highlighting the ongoing efforts to refine and improve Bitcoin's underlying technology in a responsible and sustainable manner.

For further exploration of these topics, references include a [pinned post](https://x.com/reardencode/status/1871343039123452340) providing additional context, the internal documentation for the [IKEY proposal](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/050d422b2ac24d8221edab0ff0053e0f585409f7/bip-0349.md), and the pull request for [PAIRCOMMIT](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1699). These resources offer deeper insight into the technical discussions and proposals at the heart of Bitcoin's evolutionary debate.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T17:19:12.897000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
