<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-13T02:27:09.539544+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-12T03:32:38.781000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T02:27:09.539576+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/15" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Ark, a project designed with an innovative approach, incorporates elements introspection opcodes and pre-signed transactions at its core. This design choice marks a significant stride in the development of blockchain technologies. However, despite its promising framework, Ark has not ventured into integrating CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) into its system. This absence of practical application raises concerns, especially given the potential that CTV holds for enhancing Bitcoin's functionality. The initial announcement suggested that Ark could be implemented using either BIP 118 (SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT or APO) or BIP 119 (CTV), yet the lack of engagement with CTV is perplexing. 

This oversight is particularly glaring when considering the willingness within the community to experiment with complex solutions like "purrfect" vaults, which demonstrates an openness to exploring new ideas within the Bitcoin ecosystem. The reluctance or inability to explore CTV's implementation, therefore, stands out as a significant oversight. For more information on Ark's approach and the discussions surrounding the use of CTV, one can refer to the detailed documentation and conversation trails available at [this link](https://codeberg.org/ark-bitcoin/bark/src/branch/ctv). This resource provides an in-depth look into the technical aspects of Ark's construction and the ongoing discourse on the potential benefits and challenges of integrating CTV into its architecture.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T03:32:38.781000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
