<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-13T02:26:21.074655+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob.837000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-12T19:51:09.837000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T02:26:21.074685+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/23" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the utility and application of CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) in creating advanced vault structures, a topic that has been a subject of debate within the programming and cryptocurrency communities. The argument posited against the usefulness of "vaults" designed solely for CTV is challenged by highlighting their significance in custodial operations. It is noted that large custodians already employ CTV to replace pre-signed transactions, emphasizing its essential role in developing more sophisticated vault solutions. This point is further supported by industry demand for efficient vault mechanisms as evidenced by Rob Hamilton's insights, which also align with firsthand experiences attesting to the continuous interest in such applications.

Moreover, the conversation touches upon the technical comparison between CTV and TXHASH's CTV mode, underscoring the complexity and potential difficulty in validating the latter. This comparison suggests a preference towards the simplicity and reliability of CTV for implementing certain functionalities, such as output scriptPubKey calculations that facilitate either delayed spending or immediate transfer to cold storage. The provided implementation example demonstrates CTV's capability to support both time-delayed transactions and instant sweeps, contradicting any claims of its limitations in this regard.

The discourse extends into the evaluation of CTV's role in "congestion control," challenging the skepticism surrounding its viability. Through discussions with industry participants like LukeJr from Ocean Mining, it's established that miners would find practical uses for CTV in managing payout compression during high fee periods, despite potential hardware constraints. This illustrates the broader applicability and value of CTV beyond the initial context of vault creation, showcasing its utility in optimizing transaction efficiency on the blockchain. Finally, the mention of CTV's "bare legacy" mode underscores its minimalistic approach to securing a series of payments, highlighting its importance in the broader ecosystem of bitcoin transaction management.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T19:51:09.837000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
