<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-03-13T02:28:23.114888+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin 2025-03-13 00:40:24.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T02:28:23.114917+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/question-about-op-ctv-and-non-recursive-covenants/1517/3" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The exploration of Contract Through Voice (CTV) showcases its flexibility and capability to handle multiple inputs, which can significantly enhance the functionality and applications of smart contracts in the blockchain domain. Specifically, the ability to write option contracts using CTV opens up avenues for registering on-chain auctions for ordinals, demonstrating a practical use case. For those interested in delving deeper into the specifics of such implementations, the Sapio programming language offers a repository with relevant code examples. This repository is accessible at [GitHub](https://github.com/sapio-lang/sapio/tree/master/sapio-contrib/src/contracts/derivatives), providing a resource for developers looking to explore or implement similar functionalities.

Additionally, the discussion touches upon the concept of relative references within the context of blockchain and smart contracts, aligning closely with John Law's proposal regarding inherited IDs. This idea presents an innovative approach to addressing and referencing entities within a blockchain network, potentially simplifying interactions and enhancing the efficiency of smart contract operations. The conversation around these concepts indicates a broader interest and ongoing exploration in the field, suggesting that further investigation and development could lead to more sophisticated blockchain and smart contract solutions. Engaging with these discussions and proposals could offer valuable insights and opportunities for innovation in the rapidly evolving landscape of blockchain technology.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:40:24.184000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
