<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-03-13T02:28:12.506123+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.028000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-13T00:46:49.028000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T02:28:12.506155+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/question-about-op-ctv-and-non-recursive-covenants/1517/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the integration of stocks and securities into the Bitcoin network through a protocol that emphasizes the advantages of such a decentralized approach over traditional centralized management. The argument suggests that central management by companies issuing stocks or controlling securitized assets could lead to more efficient operations. However, the potential for anonymous trading, the use of stablecoins or wrapped BTC for transactions, and the aggregation of securities on a unified platform are highlighted as significant benefits of leveraging a decentralized model like Bitcoin. This approach could facilitate automated market makers and simplify cross-security trades, suggesting a comprehensive ecosystem for trading stocks and securities.

A specific challenge within this context is addressed concerning the runes protocol and the creation of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) for buying offers. The issue stems from the current limitation that requires separate PSBTs for each UTXO (Unspent Transaction Output) when making multiple buy offers. This constraint complicates the process for users who wish to make offers on multiple UTXOs simultaneously, as it prevents a streamlined and efficient operation for acquiring runes through trustless PSBT offers.

The conversation delves deeper into technical solutions for overcoming these limitations, discussing the feasibility of using elements-style introspection to allow a script to assert control over transaction outputs in a way that accommodates the purchase of runes without necessitating different signatures for each transaction. However, the complexity increases when considering how to distinguish between acceptable UTXOs for a transaction without resorting to separate PSBTs for each one. The discussion touches on the limitations imposed by OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (OP_CTV), which is designed to prevent recursive covenants by committing only to transaction outputs and not inputs, thereby highlighting the inherent challenges in creating a flexible yet secure method for making aggregated buy offers within the Bitcoin protocol.

Furthermore, an exploration of the technical implications of OP_CTV reveals the computational impracticality of committing to both inputs and outputs due to the recursive nature of hash calculations that would be required. This part of the discussion underscores the complexities involved in implementing a system that could accommodate the desired flexibility for transactions while maintaining the security and integrity of the blockchain, concluding with a note on the theoretical and practical challenges faced when attempting to enhance the functionality of Bitcoin's transactional capabilities in this manner.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:46:49.028000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
