<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-14T02:26:10.046620+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-03-13 05:18:58.979000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T02:26:10.046645+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/29" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Greg's post delves into the intricate process of utilizing a general [zero-knowledge proof](https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=277389.0) mechanism to facilitate specific covenant constructions. These constructions uniquely restrict a coin along with all potential expenditures of that coin, ensuring they are perpetually bound in a predefined manner. A significant aspect of this method includes the creation of a burn address. This particular address is not just a mere repository but is designed to enable the repeated burning of coins. Such a feature introduces an innovative approach to how coins, once burnt, can be subjected to the burning process multiple times, underscoring a novel utilization of zero-knowledge proofs in cryptocurrency transactions.

This methodology underscores a pivotal advancement in the realm of digital currency, highlighting an enhanced level of security and flexibility in the management and utilization of cryptocurrencies. By enabling coins to be burnt repeatedly through a dedicated burn address, the approach opens up new avenues for how transactions can be structured and the manner in which coins are circulated or removed from circulation within the digital economy. The application of zero-knowledge proofs in this context not only augments the privacy and security features inherent in such cryptographic techniques but also leverages their potential to enforce stricter control mechanisms over digital assets.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T05:18:58.979000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
