<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-03-14T02:24:09.574354+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding.033000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-13T14:33:28.033000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T02:24:09.574387+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470/22" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email opens with an acknowledgment of the insights gained from conversations with two notable project contributors, emphasizing a reflective approach to understanding their perspectives on the project. The sender clarifies any potential misunderstandings, expressing regret if previous comments were perceived as disparaging towards the current development team. Highlighting a longstanding involvement with Bitcoin documentation spanning 11 years, the sender shares experiences of working with multiple generations of Bitcoin Core developers. This historical perspective underlines a recognition of the current team's capabilities, equating them with the competence observed in predecessors.

Further into the message, the challenges faced by software development over time are addressed. It is noted that as a project matures, the tasks involved in its advancement become increasingly complex. Early stages might offer quick and significant improvements ("easy wins"), but over time, these opportunities dwindle. Developers then face a landscape marked by more intricate problems and diminishing returns on their efforts. Additionally, maintaining an established project often involves combating 'bitrot'—the gradual deterioration or obsolescence of software not actively maintained—and managing technical debt, which can hinder new development.

The sender lauds the current development team's ability to navigate these hurdles, achieving substantial progress with each major release despite the escalating difficulties inherent in long-term software enhancement. This progress is presented as evidence of the team's exceptional skill and commitment. By concluding with an expression of admiration for the team's accomplishments and offering an apology for any unintended offense, the email reinforces the sender's respect for the development team's diligence and achievements.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T14:33:28.033000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
