<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-14T02:25:35.287547+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-13T17:30:22.924000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T02:25:35.287574+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/32" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers around the potential application of CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) within the Liquid network, a topic that has garnered some skepticism. The significance of this dialogue is highlighted by the involvement of Andrew Poelstra, a notable figure in the field, who has expressed a positive stance on the matter. Poelstra's viewpoint lends considerable weight to the argument that CTV can indeed be effectively integrated with Liquid. This assertion is not isolated but is supported by another independent endorsement, suggesting a consensus among experts about the utility of CTV in enhancing Liquid's capabilities.

The conversation underscores the importance of bringing such technical discussions into public forums, where they can be openly debated and validated. This approach not only promotes transparency but also aids in establishing a well-rounded understanding of the technological advancements at play. The mention of Poelstra's tight schedule and his active choice to engage in this dialogue through a third party emphasizes the value he places on addressing these speculative claims head-on. 

Ultimately, the exchange serves to potentially quell doubts regarding the integration of CTV with Liquid by presenting informed opinions from credible sources. These insights contribute to a broader narrative on the evolution and optimization of blockchain technologies, fostering an environment where innovative solutions are critically examined and discussed.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T17:30:22.924000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
