<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:23:33.572235+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns.264000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-14T03:19:50.264000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:23:33.572270+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/37" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email highlights a significant concern regarding the focus of discussions on the technical amendment to CTV (CheckTemplateVerify). The sender expresses frustration over what they perceive as an unnecessary emphasis on the Motivation section of the BIP (Bitcoin Improvement Proposal), suggesting that such focus detracts from more substantive, technical deliberations. They argue that this fixation on motivational wording is hindering constructive dialogue about potential alternatives or enhancements to CTV, including the exploration of combinations with other opcodes, variations on introspection methods, and entirely different opcodes.

Moreover, the email implies that the ongoing debates around the Motivation section have led to a stagnation in discussions about possible improvements or modifications to the existing proposal. This situation is portrayed as counterproductive, with the sender indicating a disillusionment with the process, viewing it as a repetitive cycle that fails to advance the conversation in a meaningful direction. The mention of Jeremy's role in perpetuating this confusion suggests a specific point of contention within the community, further illustrating the challenges faced in reaching consensus on the technical amendment under discussion.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T03:19:50.264000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
