<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:51.582998+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob.909000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-14T18:22:17.909000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:51.583032+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/41" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion centers on the significance of bare CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) in contrast to its implementation complexities and the implications of an additional fork deployment. The argument posits that integrating bare CTV, despite being viewed as trivial or non-essential by some, introduces minimal complexity from a technical standpoint. Specifically, the process of treating CTV as `OP_NOP4` is highlighted as a point of contention. This designation for CTV might be seen as a sticking point due to the perceived simplicity in implementation, suggesting that opposition may stem from considerations beyond mere technical difficulty. 

Moreover, the conversation sheds light on the broader implications of opting for an additional fork deployment to accommodate changes associated with CTV. Such a deployment is characterized as significantly more complex, not just in terms of coding but also in regards to the procedural aspects involved. This comparison underlines the inherent trade-offs between choosing a seemingly straightforward implementation path for CTV versus the intricate challenges posed by pursuing an extensive fork deployment strategy. 

Overall, the discourse encourages a reevaluation of priorities and challenges associated with the integration of CTV within the broader context of development and deployment strategies, urging a consideration of the balance between implementation simplicity and the potential complications of more substantial procedural changes.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T18:22:17.909000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
