<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:42.290297+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob 2025-03-14 18:28:01.399000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:42.290329+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/42" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Recent discussions around the use-case worthiness of covenants in blockchain technology have seen notable advancements, moving beyond mere theoretical debates. In a significant shift from previous standpoints, the practical applicability of such covenants, particularly CheckTemplateVerify (CTV), has gained considerable support from influential figures within the blockchain community. This change is highlighted by several key developments that underscore the growing interest and perceived value of CTV.

Firstly, two engineers from Blockstream, a leading blockchain technology company, have publicly stated their belief in the value that CTV could bring to Liquid, a sidechain-based settlement network designed to facilitate faster, more confidential Bitcoin transactions. This endorsement from technical experts within a prominent blockchain firm emphasizes CTV's potential to enhance the functionality and efficiency of existing blockchain solutions.

Moreover, the CEO of one of Bitcoin's most widely used hardware wallets has expressed his intention to implement vaults, a feature made feasible by CTV technology. His commitment, showcased through a public statement available [here](https://x.com/nvk/status/1899918763728003420), signals a tangible step towards adopting CTV in consumer-facing products, potentially increasing security and user control over digital assets.

Similarly, the CEO of the sole custodial insurance product for Bitcoin has revealed his desire to utilize vaults, further illustrating the demand for CTV's capabilities in enhancing security measures for digital asset custody. His interest can be explored in more detail [here](https://x.com/Rob1Ham/status/1897781338796966103).

Lastly, the development and successful testing of an Ark prototype based on CTV mark a noteworthy accomplishment in reducing the need for interactivity in certain blockchain processes. This reduction not only streamlines operations but also paves the way for more efficient and user-friendly blockchain technologies.

These developments collectively indicate a shift away from skepticism towards a more optimistic view of CTV's role in advancing blockchain technology. Far from "doing circles," the blockchain community is making significant strides in identifying and embracing practical applications of covenants, with influential industry leaders spearheading this change.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T18:28:01.399000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
