<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:28.440538+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-14T19:00:11.718000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:28.440571+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/43" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the complexity introduced by bare/legacy CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) and the justification for the NOP/verify pattern largely due to its bare usage. An alternative suggestion is made, aiming at enhancing efficiency specifically for the use cases involving signing hashes that are located on the stack. This proposal, although preliminary and admittingly speculative, seeks to address and replace the current functionality with a more efficient solution, highlighting an interest in optimizing specific operational aspects.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the challenges and complexities associated with deploying an additional fork, emphasizing the implications for both code and process enhancements. The dialogue suggests a willingness to consider the bare case as significant if consensus deems it valuable, proposing a bundling approach to mitigate concerns. A query is raised about the specific issues or reservations concerning the designation of CTV as `OP_NOP4`, underlining a preference for solutions that simplify or eliminate the need to account for legacy scripting mechanisms. This inquiry reflects a broader desire to streamline and improve the efficiency of the system, prioritizing advancements that reduce cognitive load and increase operational effectiveness.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T19:00:11.718000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
