<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:09.863065+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jamesob.353000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-14T21:37:02.353000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:09.863098+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/45" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the essential mechanisms and technologies in cryptocurrency security, specifically focusing on vaults and their foundational technology. A key point made is that for vaults to function effectively, there must be a clear mechanism for locking coins to a specific destination during what is referred to as the trigger stage. The technology identified as most fundamental to achieving this is CTV (CheckTemplateVerify), which is presented not just as one method but as the basis for any technology capable of securely locking coins in this manner. This underlines the argument that advocating for the utility of vaults inherently supports the value of CTV or its more advanced derivatives that include CTV functionality.

Further exploration into the conversation brings up differing perspectives on the adoption of another technology, taproot, within the cryptocurrency infrastructure. Bob McElrath's [statement](https://x.com/BobMcElrath/status/1900445574626693258) highlights a divide among custodians regarding the use of taproot. Some custodians express reluctance to adopt taproot, citing it does not align with their needs or the direction of their projects. These sentiments, however, are contrasted by a group of more forward-looking custodians who see significant potential benefits in taproot for their operations. This dichotomy showcases the varied responses to technological advancements in the cryptocurrency sector, emphasizing that resistance from a minority does not negate the overall potential impact and desirability of innovation like taproot among other industry participants.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T21:37:02.353000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
