<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:01.317503+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP.706000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-14T21:44:33.706000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-15T02:22:01.317536+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/46" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights the significance of ensuring that coins are securely locked to a designated destination during the trigger stage of vault creation, emphasizing this as a core argument for the value of vaults. This perspective specifically points towards the necessity of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) for its realization. However, there's a counterpoint presented that challenges the approach of advocating for changes to Bitcoin based on potential future enhancements or modifications. The argument posits that when proposing alterations to Bitcoin, proponents should focus on making a case for the immediate change in question rather than relying on speculative future developments that might complement the initial change. 

Further elaboration on this viewpoint suggests that any future modifications (referred to as "Y" in the context) should primarily be considered to ensure that the current proposed change (referred to as "X") will not become obsolete quickly. This approach was defended effectively in the original proposition, convincing stakeholders of the value of implementing the suggested soft fork without the need to wait for additional future changes. This discourse underscores a practical approach to evolving Bitcoin, emphasizing careful consideration of immediate changes and their long-term relevance before embarking on the complex process of a soft fork.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T21:44:33.706000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
