<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-16T02:37:36.029273+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob1Ham.964000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-15T17:32:28.964000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T02:37:36.029303+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/49" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The CEO of Bitcoin's sole custodial insurance product has expressed a desire for vaults, as highlighted in a recent statement available via a [tweet](https://x.com/Rob1Ham/status/1897781338796966103). This declaration brings to light the absence of discussion around `OP_CTV` in certain discourse, underlining its importance in the context of designing secure vaulting structures. The CEO's insights are drawn from extensive reading of `OP_VAULT`, specifically outlined in the [Bitcoin Improvement Proposal 345 (BIP 345)](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/00c13baff0dc4a3a250d9725129b0d2c8d0be6a9/bip-0345.mediawiki), which references `OP_CTV` multiple times. This highlights the necessity of incorporating mechanisms like `OP_CTV` to commit to future transactions, an essential feature for the functionality of these vaults.

Furthermore, despite being a recent entrant, AnchorWatch is acknowledged positively, although it was launched less than three months ago. The CEO's engagement in the community, albeit rare, underscores the significance they place on the technical discussions surrounding Bitcoin's security and infrastructure enhancements, particularly through innovations like CTV and CSFS. This involvement reflects a broader interest in advancing Bitcoin's custodial solutions through technological development and dialogue within the community.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-15T17:32:28.964000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
