<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-03-18T02:29:55.279853+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-17T17:23:04.588000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-03-18T02:29:55.279886+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initiates by outlining the fundamental aspects and benefits of using CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) in the Ark protocol, particularly emphasizing its application for creating virtual UTXOs (vUTXOs). In the Ark system, users possess off-chain UTXOs, referred to as vUTXOs, which are essential for facilitating various transactions within the network. The original design employs a tree of transactions, each linked by CTV covenants, enabling a seamless transition from one transaction to the next, akin to congestion control mechanisms.

A detailed explanation is provided on the structure of these vUTXOs, highlighting two critical policies that govern their creation and transfer. The first policy involves a chain of transactions with a specific condition combining CTV or a combination of the Ark server's key and a time-based expiration. This design allows for the non-interactive issuance of new vUTXOs, given the known parameters of the Ark's server key and the relative timelock. The second policy addresses the transfer of ownership, requiring both the owner's key and either the server's key or a passage of a predefined time period. This mechanism ensures secure transitions between owners while maintaining flexibility in the system's operation.

The blog post then transitions into discussing the development of clArk, an iteration of the protocol without covenants, which however introduces a limitation requiring the presence of the eventual owner for the issuance of co-signed vUTXOs. This necessity stems from the inherent risk of unsanctioned constructions without the owner's consent. To mitigate this, the team at Second has designated specific rounds for users with expiring vUTXOs, allowing them to essentially "send" vUTXOs to themselves, thus bypassing the need for the owner's presence during issuance.

One significant advantage of utilizing CTV in this context is the ability to send vUTXOs to others without necessitating their participation in Ark rounds, enhancing the usability and efficiency of the system. Additionally, the server's capability to automatically re-issue expired vUTXOs and facilitate the receipt of Lightning payments without direct user involvement in rounds presents a notable improvement in the system's functionality. These advancements not only streamline the process for users but also open up new possibilities for exchanges or DCA providers to distribute payouts to their users non-interactively.

In conclusion, the integration of CTV within the Ark protocol offers substantial benefits across various facets of its operation, from simplifying transactions to broadening the scope of possible interactions within the network. The ongoing efforts by Second to refine and test the clArk implementation, especially in mobile settings, underscore the potential for further enhancements to user experience and system viability. Links to additional resources and discussions provide readers with avenues to explore the topic in greater depth, including the [original thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), the [Ark case for CTV](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733), and the [Ark protocol introduction](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/vtxos/index.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-03-17T17:23:04.588000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
