<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Bitcoin node P2P traffic analysis</title>
  <updated>2025-03-19T02:25:43.567257+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik 2025-03-18 11:08:29.248000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Bitcoin node P2P traffic analysis</title>
    <updated>2025-03-19T02:25:43.567297+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-node-p2p-traffic-analysis/1490/4" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the operation of three pruned Bitcoin Core nodes, with an emphasis on their configuration and accessibility. These nodes are designed with limited storage capacity, meaning they do not retain all historical blocks. Despite this limitation, two of these nodes are accessible externally via IPv4, ensuring they remain part of the larger network. All three nodes are kept up-to-date with the latest chainstate, allowing them to verify and relay transactions efficiently. Additionally, one of these nodes extends its support to a pruned Elements Core node that is operational on the liquidv1 platform, which can be found at [anyone.eu.org](https://anyone.eu.org).

The conversation also touches upon a critique regarding blocksonly nodes. These nodes, which only process blocks without relaying unconfirmed transactions, are seen as diverging from Satoshi Nakamoto's original vision for the Bitcoin network as outlined in the Network chapter of his whitepaper. The critique suggests that while both pruned and blocksonly nodes have become a reality within the network's ecosystem, they represent a departure from foundational principles. However, it is acknowledged that the presence and operation of such nodes are now an irreversible aspect of the network's infrastructure.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-18T11:08:29.248000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
