<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-19T02:26:14.603351+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>harding</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-18T15:59:31.117000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-19T02:26:14.603384+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/55" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The development of the original idea, which predates the publication of the taproot and tapscript Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs), signifies an important moment in the evolution of Bitcoin's protocol enhancements. Despite its conceptual inception before these BIPs, drafts for taproot and tapscript were made available approximately two weeks prior to the introduction of OP_COSHV, a precursor to CheckTemplateVerify (CTV). This timeline suggests that while the foundational concept for CTV existed before the broader discussion and formalization of taproot and tapscript, the formal introduction and consideration of OP_COSHV in the development community occurred thereafter.

The significance of this sequence of events lies not just in the chronology but also in the implications for Bitcoin's protocol development. The introduction of taproot and tapscript BIPs marked a pivotal advancement towards enhancing Bitcoin's efficiency, privacy, and flexibility. Following closely on their heels, OP_COSHV's emergence as CTV's predecessor highlights a period of rapid innovation and proposal within the Bitcoin developer community. This era is characterized by a focused effort to address longstanding challenges and unlock new capabilities within the network, demonstrating a commitment to continuous improvement and adaptation.

The documentation and discussion surrounding these developments, accessible through provided [links](https://gnusha.org/pi/bitcoindev/CAPg+sBg6Gg8b7hPogC==fehY3ZTHHpQReqym2fb4XXWFpMM-pQ@mail.gmail.com/) and [communications](https://mailing-list.bitcoindevs.xyz/bitcoindev/CAD5xwhgHyR5qdd09ikvA_vgepj4o+Aqb0JA_T6FuqX56ZNe1RQ@mail.gmail.com/), offer invaluable insights into the thought processes, debates, and technical considerations that underpin these proposals. They serve not only as a historical record of this dynamic period but also as a resource for ongoing and future developments. Through such documentation, the developer community ensures transparency, fosters collaboration, and promotes a deeper understanding of the complexities involved in evolving a decentralized digital currency like Bitcoin.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-18T15:59:31.117000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
