<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-21T02:30:01.228642+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2025-03-21 00:13:23.968000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T02:30:01.228674+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/57" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation revolves around the development of Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs) concerning Taproot and its associated scripts, highlighting the timing and foundational aspects of these proposals. Initially, it is noted that the idea for OP_COSHV, a predecessor to CTV (CheckTemplateVerify), was conceived before the publication of the taproot and tapscript BIPs. However, drafts of these BIPs were made available approximately two weeks prior to the introduction of OP_COSHV. These developments are crucial as they illustrate the interconnectedness of Bitcoin's evolving scripting capabilities and the introduction of new opcodes like `OP_SUCCESSx` in tapscript, which were instrumental in the progression from COSHV to CTV.

Further examination reveals technical details and potential applications of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) within Bitcoin's scripting language. A specific code snippet demonstrates how CTV operates under certain conditions, with particular attention to error handling and the discouragement of upgradable CTV hashes without the necessary verification flags. This nuanced approach to script execution underlines the flexibility and security considerations inherent in Bitcoin's design, allowing for future upgrades while maintaining backward compatibility.

Discussions extend to the practicality and economic implications of using bare CTV, emphasizing its utility in preventing accidental fund loss through misaddressed transactions. However, concerns are raised about the immutability of transaction chains created with CTV, suggesting a need for enhanced address formats that convey sufficient information for verifying the chain's semantics. This concept is pivotal for ensuring that recipients can confidently validate intermediary transactions within a congestion control tree, thereby safeguarding against unintended fund freezing.

Finally, the potential for CTV to facilitate adversarial transaction withholding is explored. By enabling equality checks on transaction templates, CTV could serve as a primitive for creating smart contracts that conditionally withhold transactions, as discussed in a referenced [blog post](https://blog.bitmex.com/txwithhold-smart-contracts/). However, this application raises questions about the collaborative nature of such mechanisms, pointing out that the templated transactions would require valid witnesses for the probed UTXOs, thus necessitating some level of consent from the UTXO owners. This observation suggests a nuanced understanding of CTV's capabilities and limitations, particularly in the context of non-collaborative UTXO oracles.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-21T00:13:23.968000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
