<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
  <updated>2025-03-22T02:23:27.414635+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-03-21 19:09:48.508000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Great Consensus Cleanup Revival</title>
    <updated>2025-03-22T02:23:27.414668+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710/81" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the realm of Bitcoin, a significant observation has been made regarding transaction sizes within its blockchain. Over the span of 16 years since Bitcoin's inception, there hasn't been a single instance of a 64-byte transaction occurring on the network. This fact underscores a unique aspect of Bitcoin's transaction history and structure, providing insights into the patterns and technical limitations inherent within the system.

The findings are detailed in a comprehensive list which documents instances of 64-byte transactions within the Bitcoin blockchain, accessible through a GitHub repository. The documentation can be found at [this link](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/pull/1760/filesdiff-62b4650c88cc2ccee485ed278b8e7c55dd985a22d7d7c056fbf9b3b92cb14c9b). Although the exact hash of the block where these results were produced is not documented, it is referenced around a specific block hash. This detail indicates the meticulous effort undertaken to scan the blockchain and identify these transactions, despite the absence of an exact hash making the search more challenging.

The significance of this discovery cannot be understated, as it adds to the understanding of how Bitcoin transactions have evolved over time and highlights the rarity or non-existence of certain transaction sizes. While the research indicates that it's unlikely any 64-byte transactions have occurred since the noted block, it also leaves room for the possibility, however slim, that such transactions could exist or occur in the future. This opens avenues for further investigation and monitoring of Bitcoin's blockchain for anomalies, trends, and patterns that defy the norm or highlight unexpected behaviors within the cryptocurrency's ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-21T19:09:48.508000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
