<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Bitcoin Core 29.0 release candidate is available</title>
  <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:21.006329+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>glozow</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-24T16:47:48.819000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Bitcoin Core 29.0 release candidate is available</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:21.006364+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/bitcoin-core-29-0-release-candidate-is-available/1536" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The latest development in the Bitcoin Core ecosystem is the availability of binaries for version v29.0rc2, which can be accessed from [Bitcoin Core's official website](https://bitcoincore.org/bin/bitcoin-core-29.0/test.rc2). This iteration marks a significant milestone as a release candidate for a major version upgrade, emphasizing its importance and potential impact on the network. For those interested in reviewing or contributing to the source code, it has been made available under the signed tag on [GitHub](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/tree/v29.0rc2).

To assist users and developers in understanding the changes and enhancements introduced in this release, preliminary release notes have been published [here](https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/29.0-Release-Notes-draft). Additionally, a comprehensive testing guide is provided to facilitate effective testing of the new features and to identify any potential issues. This guide can be found on the project's GitHub wiki page at [29.0 Release Candidate Testing Guide](https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/29.0-Release-Candidate-Testing-Guide).

Community feedback plays a crucial role in the refinement of release candidates. As such, contributors and users are encouraged to report any issues or comments they might have regarding this version on its dedicated GitHub issue page, located at [GitHub Issues](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/32052). The progression from a release candidate to an official release hinges on the identification and resolution of critical problems during this testing phase. Assuming no critical problems emerge, this release candidate will be officially tagged as version 29.0, marking another step forward in the evolution of the Bitcoin Core software.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T16:47:48.819000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
