<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>0</id>
  <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:34.596729+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-24 23:47:15.140000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:34.596764+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem/1537" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The concept of quantum computing presents a unique challenge to Bitcoin, not in its current capacity but as a potential future risk. This stems from the perception that quantum technology could theoretically undermine the cryptographic foundations of Bitcoin, leading to hesitancy among investors and affecting Bitcoin's valuation. Despite this concern, it's critical to understand that Bitcoin's security model, particularly the use of hashed public keys, offers a degree of protection against quantum attacks. The distinction between Bitcoin and blockchain technology is often blurred, with many failing to recognize that Bitcoin's essence is more social than technical. 

Given the speculative nature of quantum threats, there's an ongoing debate on whether the Bitcoin community should proactively address these concerns. A drastic measure, such as initiating a quantum-resistant fork of Bitcoin, is considered unnecessary by some. Instead, offering assurances about the safety of assets in the face of quantum advancements may be more prudent. This could involve promoting a voluntary movement where Bitcoin users sign quantum-resistant public keys and provide proof of ownership without any enforced mechanism. Utilizing platforms like [OpenTimestamps](https://opentimestamps.org) and employing [BIP322](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/02ad0e01c2a9189124e05a52afe97ef90a3b7f1f/bip-0322.mediawiki) proofs of ownership could facilitate a seamless transition to quantum-resistant measures if necessary. 

This approach doesn't seek to solve the quantum dilemma through technical means but aims to bolster confidence among Bitcoin stakeholders, from individual holders in remote areas to global financial institutions. It suggests a path forward that preserves the existing ledger without resorting to drastic measures. The proposal highlights the importance of proactive community engagement in safeguarding Bitcoin's future against potential quantum computational breakthroughs. Whether this strategy has been previously considered or would garner sufficient support within the Bitcoin community remains an open question.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T23:47:15.140000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
