<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-26T02:31:40.823129+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-03-25 06:58:42.766000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-26T02:31:40.823155+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem/1537/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the exploration of enhancing the efficiency and privacy of blockchain transactions, a significant focus has been placed on the method of embedding proofs within transactions. Traditionally, proofs have been inserted inside the `OP_RETURN` field of a transaction. This practice, while functional, presents limitations in terms of transaction size and the detectability of commitments.

A proposed shift in methodology suggests directly committing to the ECDSA signature by adjusting the R-value. This approach offers two primary advantages. Firstly, it results in a reduction of the overall transaction size, as it eliminates the need for additional data space traditionally reserved for `OP_RETURN`. Secondly, it significantly improves the concealment of commitments, making it more challenging to ascertain whether any commitment has been attached to the transaction or not.

The implementation of this technique could potentially revolutionize the way data is stored and verified on the blockchain, offering a more streamlined and secure method for embedding proofs within transactions. By directly modifying the ECDSA signature, developers can maintain the integrity of the data while ensuring a higher degree of privacy and efficiency.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-25T06:58:42.766000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
