<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-28T02:28:22.954708+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh</name>
  </author>
  <timestamp>2025-03-27T02:49:13.270000+00:00</timestamp>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T02:28:22.954738+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem/1537/5" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion highlights an innovative approach to enhancing Bitcoin's security against quantum threats by suggesting a method for users to commit to quantum-resistant public keys. This method involves tweaking signatures in the inputs rather than embedding data in the UTXO (Unspent Transaction Output) itself. It is pointed out that while a P2TR (Pay-to-Taproot) UTXO allows for a commitment to be made directly in the output script, the proposed strategy focuses on securing outputs created within the same transaction or those existing elsewhere through input signature adjustments.

The idea centers around the flexibility of commitment placement, emphasizing that the critical factor is the use of the earliest provable commitment as a UTXO's proof of ownership. This concept garners full agreement from the participants, highlighting its potential viability.

Furthermore, the conversation touches upon the social implications of such technological advancements. The establishment of a standard method for committing to a quantum-resistant backup public key could significantly mitigate perceived quantum risks associated with Bitcoin. This perception shift is crucial as it could lead to increased user and investor comfort, thereby possibly enhancing Bitcoin's real-term purchasing power. The dialogue underscores the importance of not only addressing technical challenges but also considering the social and perceptual aspects related to cryptocurrency security and trustworthiness.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-27T02:49:13.270000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
