<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>1</id>
  <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
  <updated>2025-04-01T02:48:58.474624+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sjors 2025-03-31 16:19:09.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>Timewarp attack 600 second grace period</title>
    <updated>2025-04-01T02:48:58.474657+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/timewarp-attack-600-second-grace-period/1326/37" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of how difficulty adjustment in a hypothetical blockchain system is influenced by a specific parameter, denoted as $G$. This parameter represents a time stretch that affects each period within the system. Initially, at period 0, the array is filled with zeros until the last position, which holds a value $P$. As we move into subsequent periods, the starting value demonstrates a decrease by $P-G$ and culminates at an increased value, demonstrating a linear progression with each period ($1P$, $2P$, $3P$, etc.), adjusted by the subtraction of $G$. The essence of this pattern is to depict how the difficulty level decreases over time, with a specified decrement rate per retarget period, which, for a given example where $G$ equals 2 hours, results in a decrease of 0.6% per retargeting period. Over a span of a year, this accumulative effect leads to a total decrease in difficulty of approximately 15%.

Furthermore, an important mechanism within this model is the ability to reset any accumulated decrease in difficulty. This reset can occur if an honest miner successfully finds the last block of any retarget period. Such a design implies a dynamic balance mechanism, allowing for adjustments in difficulty that can both increment and decrement, depending on the network's mining activities and the specific conditions met at the end of each retarget period. This intricate balance aims to maintain a stable and fair mining process, adjusting for fluctuations in network participation and ensuring the continuity and security of the blockchain.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-31T16:19:09.870000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
