<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_inout_amount</title>
  <updated>2025-05-08T02:44:53.616208+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-05-07 17:16:31.067000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2025-05-02 17:37:51.549000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2025-03-13 21:08:20.247000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2024-02-27 14:02:08.104000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2024-02-12 15:05:39.857000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4956_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4923_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4521_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1718_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1520_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_inout_amount</title>
    <updated>2025-05-08T02:44:53.616266+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The case study on OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and the subsequent discussion revolve around the innovative use of Script opcodes to implement amount locks in Bitcoin transactions, ensuring that transaction values meet specific criteria without deferred checks. At the core of this exploration are two significant proposals: enhancing Script with 64-bit arithmetic capabilities and introducing `OP_IN_AMOUNT` and `OP_OUT_AMOUNT` opcodes for direct enforcement of transactional restrictions. These enhancements aim to improve upon existing mechanisms by allowing for more sophisticated control over transaction outputs and inputs directly within the Script, moving away from reliance on external validation processes post-transaction input verification.

In examining the functionality of `OP_VAULT` and `OP_VAULT_RECOVER`, the study delves into the procedural intricacies of verifying transaction amounts through embedded logic within these opcodes, alongside the proposed `OP_INOUT_AMOUNT`. This method signifies a notable shift towards integrating amount lock validations within the transaction verification stage itself, facilitated by the design of the witness stack which enables direct checks of transaction amounts, thereby omitting the need for `revault_amount`.

Further analysis highlights the proposition of `OP_INOUT_AMOUNT`, inspired by Elements' `OP_INSPECTINPUTVALUE` and `OP_INSPECTOUTPUTVALUE`, but with enhanced flexibility to accommodate transactions with variable input and output sizes. This opcode simplifies correlating transaction inputs and outputs through bitmaps, representing a leap forward in scripting capabilities, especially in scenarios like CoinJoin transactions. However, this advancement brings forth several design considerations, including complexities in handling subsets of inputs and outputs, concerns over transaction malleability affecting script validation, and the adaptability of the opcode to various transaction designs.

The email also touches on the broader implications of these developments for Bitcoin scripting, suggesting an interest in expanding the system’s flexibility to efficiently manage complex transactions. The potential for specifying indexes to merge or split UTXOs hints at a desire for a system capable of intricate transactional operations without introducing undue complexity. 

The draft proposal for `OP_INOUT_AMOUNT`, aimed at refining Bitcoin's Script interpreter, is documented [here](https://github.com/Christewart/bips/blob/92c108136a0400b3a2fd66ea6c291ec317ee4a01/bip-op-inout-amount.mediawiki), with its implementation detailed in a [GitHub repository](https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/tree/op-inout-amount). This proposal, together with a 64bit opcode integration effort ([PR](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/29221)), represents a step towards leveraging script functionalities for more dynamic transaction verification processes. The ongoing dialogue on platforms like [Delving Bitcoin](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/64bit%20arithmetic%20soft%20fork/397/25) underscores the community's investment in exploring these enhancements, particularly considering the operational nuances of `SIGHASH` flags and the structural placement of new functionalities within Bitcoin's framework. These discussions are pivotal for the future support of advanced scripting capabilities, such as `[OP_TLUV](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-September/019419.html)`.</summary>
    <published>2025-05-07T17:16:31.067000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
