<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-03-23T02:38:46.069063+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-22 19:12:19.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-22 19:02:45.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>neha  . 2025-03-21 16:49:31.233000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-03-17 17:26:03.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-17 17:23:04.588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4590_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4589_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4583_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4560_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4559_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-03-23T02:38:46.069116+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Arkoor model introduces a nuanced approach to handling virtual transaction outputs (VTXOs), emphasizing user choice in managing liquidity costs associated with VTXO refreshes. This model allows users to opt for full trustless ownership by refreshing their VTXOs early, albeit at a higher liquidity fee, or to rely on the Arkoor trust assumption for a reduced fee by postponing the refresh closer to the VTXO's expiration. This flexibility is particularly relevant for users involved in significant transactions with unknown parties, who may prefer the security of early refreshes, contrasted with those conducting smaller, routine transactions who might lean towards saving on fees. The model, however, acknowledges the substantial risk of denial-of-service (DoS) attacks, as the requirement for participant interactivity in rounds can be exploited. Mitigation strategies include banning non-cooperative users and penalizing the VTXOs of participants who abandon rounds, though this penalty system inherently differs for senders versus receivers due to their relationship with existing VTXOs.

Arkoor's "statechain model" posits a temporary reduction in trust, contingent on the server not colluding with a previous VTXO owner, which can be circumvented by users through VTXO refreshes during rounds—returning them to a state of trustlessness. The implication of a time-bound trust assumption highlights the balance between user experience and security, suggesting that while some security risks are accepted for usability improvements, they remain a critical consideration in system design. This model points to ongoing discussions around securing communications and transactions within such protocols without overly compromising on convenience.

The exploration of out-of-round (OOR) transactions within the [Arkoor protocol](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/oor/index.html) and the potential integration of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) signifies an attempt to refine and secure transaction methods. Currently reliant on OOR transactions for user-to-user exchanges, this method introduces additional security assumptions, deemed a stopgap solution pending the adoption of CTV. The incorporation of CTV could reintroduce in-round transactions, potentially simplifying the process and enhancing security by reducing dependency on these assumptions. This shift underscores a broader aim to evolve transaction mechanisms within the protocol towards more secure, efficient means without unduly increasing complexity or compromising safety.

Furthermore, the integration of CTV into the Ark protocol is elucidated, showcasing its utility in creating and transferring virtual UTXOs (vUTXOs) through a structured transaction tree facilitated by CTV covenants. The delineation of policies governing the creation and transfer of vUTXOs reflects a strategic blend of security and operational flexibility, enabling non-interactive issuance and secure ownership transitions. The development of clArk, an iteration devoid of covenants, reveals limitations such as the necessity for the presence of an eventual owner during co-signed vUTXO issuance—a constraint mitigated through designated rounds for expiring vUTXOs. This adaptation, alongside the server's ability to reissue expired vUTXOs and support Lightning payments without direct user engagement, exemplifies the protocol's evolution to enhance user experience and expand functional possibilities. The ongoing refinement of clArk, especially for mobile use, alongside links to further discussions and resources, illustrates a comprehensive effort to bolster the protocol's efficacy and user friendliness. These resources include discussions on consensus regarding CTV's application, the Ark case for CTV, and an introduction to the Ark protocol, available for deeper exploration through provided links: the [original thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), the [Ark case for CTV](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733), and the [Ark protocol introduction](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/vtxos/index.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-03-22T19:12:19.635000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
