<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Post-Signature Cross-Input Scripting Using the Taproot Annex</title>
  <updated>2025-04-04T02:29:00.311640+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh.326000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  ..199000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  ..796000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4697_Post-Signature-Cross-Input-Scripting-Using-the-Taproot-Annex.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4677_Post-Signature-Cross-Input-Scripting-Using-the-Taproot-Annex.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4524_Post-Signature-Cross-Input-Scripting-Using-the-Taproot-Annex.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Post-Signature Cross-Input Scripting Using the Taproot Annex</title>
    <updated>2025-04-04T02:29:00.311684+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/post-signature-cross-input-scripting-using-the-taproot-annex/1520" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion initiates with an examination of a novel approach in cryptocurrency scripting, where a transaction signer not only fulfills existing conditions but also sets forth new conditions for subsequent signers. This mechanism, drawing parallels with various delegation technologies such as OP_CSFS, graftroot/g'root, and BitVM-style Script-based Lamport signatures, suggests embedding additional script operations within the annex rather than the conventional witness stack. The perspective argues that this method may not yield substantial benefits, highlighting the need for a deeper exploration into its practical advantages.

Delving further into the realm of cryptocurrency protocols, the conversation shifts to the proposition of integrating advanced introspection opcodes, specifically tailored for the delegation phase of script execution. This nuanced approach distinguishes itself by limiting certain introspective capabilities to the delegation stage, rather than the initial script creation, sparking debate over its practical utility and implementation specifics. The absence of clear, demonstrable scenarios complicates the understanding of how these introspective enhancements could be advantageous, signaling a call for more concrete examples and elucidation.

At the heart of the proposals is the intention to augment Bitcoin's scripting environment through cross-input scripting functionality. This ambition aims to introduce a richer set of transaction capabilities, encompassing commitments like timelocks, additional signatures, or Conditional Transaction Velocity (CTV) templates post-signature. By leveraging the taproot annex for optional script commitments evaluated after signing, the proposals outline a vision for subscripts that include delegated signatures, timelocks, and transaction templates for potential covenants. These subscripts, encoded using a protocol tag and TLV format, would undergo evaluation only upon successful execution of the regular script, ensuring compatibility with existing Bitcoin scripts while proposing a soft fork for new programmable features.

The initiative seeks community feedback on several key aspects, including the perceived value of the proposed functionalities, the community’s willingness to amend consensus rules to accommodate taproot annex meanings, potential security concerns, and suggestions for improvement. This solicitation of input underscores the proposal's nascent stage and the proponent's openness to refining the concept through collective insights, emphasizing the critical role of community engagement in the ongoing evolution of Bitcoin's scripting landscape.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T22:22:17.326000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
