<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-27T02:32:38.121113+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon 2025-03-26 06:46:51.640000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-25 17:24:08.332000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  . 2025-03-25 06:58:42.766000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-24 23:47:15.140000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4630_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4605_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4599_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4597_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-27T02:32:38.121163+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem/1537" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around the security and efficiency of blockchain technologies, particularly in relation to Bitcoin, addresses several innovative approaches aimed at enhancing cryptographic practices amidst potential quantum computing threats. One such approach involves the modification of Schnorr public keys by integrating the hash of a quantum-resistant public key into them. This strategy is geared towards achieving a dual objective: reducing the on-chain footprint and simplifying off-chain backup requirements. By amalgamating quantum-resistant algorithms with existing infrastructure, the proposal offers a smooth transition towards bolstering cryptographic standards against future threats, including those presented by advancements in quantum computing. This method underscores the necessity for forward-thinking in cryptographic security and outlines a pragmatic pathway for preserving the integrity and robustness of digital assets.

Further innovation is suggested in the method of embedding proofs within blockchain transactions to enhance efficiency and privacy. The traditional practice of using the `OP_RETURN` field for inserting proofs, while functional, has its limitations in transaction size and the detectability of commitments. An alternative proposition involves directly committing to the ECDSA signature by adjusting the R-value, which could significantly reduce transaction size and improve the concealment of commitments. This technique promises to revolutionize data storage and verification on the blockchain, offering a more streamlined and secure method for embedding proofs, thus maintaining data integrity alongside heightened privacy and efficiency.

The conversation also touches upon the theoretical challenge posed by quantum computing to Bitcoin's cryptographic foundations, which has stirred apprehension among investors and impacted Bitcoin's valuation. However, Bitcoin's security model, especially its use of hashed public keys, provides a certain level of protection against quantum attacks. The distinction between Bitcoin and blockchain technology highlights that Bitcoin's essence is more social than technical. In response to speculative quantum threats, the document suggests a non-drastic approach that emphasizes community engagement and voluntary measures over technical solutions. Initiatives like signing quantum-resistant public keys and utilizing platforms such as [OpenTimestamps](https://opentimestamps.org) along with [BIP322](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/02ad0e01c2a9189124e05a52afe97ef90a3b7f1f/bip-0322.mediawiki) proofs of ownership are recommended to assure the safety of assets. This approach aims to reinforce confidence among Bitcoin stakeholders without resorting to significant alterations to the existing ledger, highlighting the importance of proactive community involvement in securing Bitcoin's future against quantum computational advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-26T06:46:51.640000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
