<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Op_inout_amount</title>
  <updated>2025-03-14T02:23:46.403550+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-03-13 21:08:20.247000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>halseth  . 2024-02-27 14:02:08.104000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_  . 2024-02-12 15:05:39.857000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4521_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1718_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2024/1520_Op-inout-amount.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Op_inout_amount</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T02:23:46.403597+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-inout-amount/549" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The email delves into the technical details and aspirations behind enhancing Bitcoin's Script capabilities through the introduction of a new opcode, `OP_INOUT_AMOUNT`. This proposed feature aims to augment the flexibility of Bitcoin transactions by enabling the specification of input and output indexes for merging or splitting Unspent Transaction Outputs (UTXOs) more effectively. The concept suggests a shift from the current model, which is limited to pushing the value of the current input index and its corresponding output index onto the stack, to a more versatile approach that could handle complex transactions without significantly complicating the underlying technology.

At the core of this proposal is an intention to address and possibly extend the functionality provided by existing opcodes within Elements, such as `OP_INSPECTINPUTVALUE` and `OP_INSPECTOUTPUTVALUE`, by allowing variable-sized sets of inputs and outputs in Bitcoin transactions. The modification proposed involves taking two stack parameters interpreted as bitmaps to sum the values at specified output and input indices, thereby pushing these results onto the stack. This mechanism is illustrated with a simple transaction example, highlighting its potential utility in scenarios like Coinjoin transactions where uniform output amounts might be desired among participants. 

Furthermore, the communication underscores several design considerations and challenges associated with implementing `OP_INOUT_AMOUNT`. These include the need for ensuring all transaction values are known to accurately calculate fees, the potential complexity introduced by allowing for the specification of subsets of inputs/outputs, and questions around the ordering of stack inputs and concerns about malleability. Each of these points reflects deeper questions about how best to balance flexibility, security, and usability in evolving Bitcoin's scripting language.

The narrative also points to ongoing discussions and feedback loops within the community, evidenced by references to a draft Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) found [here](https://github.com/Christewart/bips/blob/92c108136a0400b3a2fd66ea6c291ec317ee4a01/bip-op-inout-amount.mediawiki), along with its implementation details available in a [GitHub repository](https://github.com/Christewart/bitcoin/tree/op-inout-amount). Additionally, the sender cites engagement with broader community forums and technical discussions as vital components of the development process, suggesting a commitment to collaborative innovation in pursuit of enhancing Bitcoin's scripting capabilities. The ambition to support future developments like `[OP_TLUV](https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-September/019419.html)` further illustrates the forward-looking nature of this endeavor.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T21:08:20.247000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
