<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
  <updated>2025-03-02T02:25:54.291514+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-03-02 00:48:13.376000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP 2025-03-01 20:51:16.570000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-02-28 16:50:32.255000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2025-02-28 16:06:05.748000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>adrienlacombe  . 2025-02-28 05:44:49.927000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-02-26 08:41:17.325000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-02-25 19:19:21.102000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler  . 2025-02-25 15:48:22.686000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-02-25 14:40:45.694000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>bruno  . 2025-02-25 13:20:23.639000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>jsarenik  . 2025-02-23 08:37:34.438000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2025-02-22 00:14:24.712000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-21 20:00:22.524000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>AntoineP  . 2025-02-21 18:10:50.840000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-02-21 16:47:25.808000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4401_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4400_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4399_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4398_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4397_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4380_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4379_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4376_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4375_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4374_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4368_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4363_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4360_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4359_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/Feb_2025/4358_Antoine-Poinsot-on-Bitcoin-Core-s-Priorities.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Antoine Poinsot on Bitcoin Core's Priorities</title>
    <updated>2025-03-02T02:25:54.291623+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/antoine-poinsot-on-bitcoin-cores-priorities/1470" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse on Bitcoin Core's development raises several pivotal points concerning the project's direction, user engagement, and technical challenges. It begins with a discussion on the decision to disable automated unit testing on Windows after years of flaky continuous integration (CI) and considerable time investment by maintainers. This move sparked debate within the community, especially in light of existing efforts to address such issues, evident from contributions like those seen in the pull request to improve the situation. The conversation extends into the realm of Bitcoin Core's evolution, emphasizing the importance of making core developments accessible to end users. A perspective shared suggests that features not readily usable by end users may need further refinement or reconsideration regarding their inclusion in the software.

Further elaboration is provided on the significance of Bitcoin Core for various user groups, highlighting that while all Bitcoin users are impacted by the software's quality, not all interact with it directly. The distinction between direct and indirect users brings about a nuanced understanding of user priorities and the critical role of the Core node in maintaining network security. It articulates the substantial stakes involved in Core node development compared to other components like the wallet and GUI, arguing for a focus on enhancing the node's accessibility to end users as a priority.

Additionally, the dialogue touches upon the challenges and considerations brought forth by the introduction of `libbitcoinkernel`. This initiative aims at encapsulating Bitcoin Core's validation engine, facilitating alternative full node implementations without risking network integrity. The implications of such advancements underscore the delicate balance between fostering innovation and ensuring the robustness of the Bitcoin network. Concerns are raised about the potential dilution of development focus and resources, stressing the necessity of cautious exploration of extensive re-implementation projects.

The exchange also delves into the nuances of defining software users, particularly in the context of Bitcoin's consensus rules enforcement. It draws an analogy with internet service providers (ISPs), exploring the implications of trade-off decisions made by software that primarily benefits its direct users over the broader beneficiary base. This discussion illuminates the critical need for a large number of Bitcoiners to run economic full nodes, empowering them to independently verify transactions and uphold network integrity.

On a more technical note, the conversation explores the proposition of refocusing Bitcoin software development on its node components, suggesting a split into multiprocess binaries to streamline development. This idea aligns with the broader goal of separating core functionalities from user-related data to enhance privacy and security. The narrative further investigates the complexities of managing shared code and configuration in this proposed setup, calling for collaborative problem-solving to address these technical challenges effectively.

Lastly, AntoineP's blog posts serve as a comprehensive critique and proposal for the future direction of Bitcoin Core. They highlight concerns about the decentralized project's fragmented efforts, advocate for prioritizing development that solidifies the software as a stable foundation for the Bitcoin network, and propose a structural evolution towards a multiprocess project initiative. These insights aim to stimulate reflection and action towards more focused, efficient, and effective development efforts within the Bitcoin Core project, ensuring its continued relevance and utility for the entire Bitcoin ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-02T00:48:13.376000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
