<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-03T02:55:33.637352+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk 2025-07-02 13:03:14.145000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-07-01 22:03:02.578000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-30 17:09:09.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-06-30 00:57:12.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-06-02 14:22:43.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-22 21:20:03.071000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-12 17:47:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:20:40.305000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:17:55.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-04-15 15:55:25.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5392_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/July_2025/5387_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5379_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5371_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5192_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5092_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4993_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4878_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4877_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4790_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-03T02:55:33.637455+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The economics of routing payments within cryptocurrency networks, particularly through routers in the context of transactions, entails a complex array of costs and risks beyond the superficial layer of router fees often perceived as clear profit. These fees are pivotal in covering expenses such as on-chain fees necessary for payment resolution, risks of losses from system failures, computational expenses, and communication network maintenance costs. The model challenges the misconception of complete capital utilization, highlighting an overestimated capacity for capital doubling, which realistically aligns more with a 19% compounded annual rate of return, reflecting a more grounded financial projection and risk assessment. Additionally, the intricate distribution of costs across the network necessitates a calculation of Hold fees that compensates for the immobilization of capital during transaction processing, requiring downstream nodes to stake amounts covering anticipated capital costs incurred by all upstream nodes.

In exploring the specifics of hold fee charges and ensuring fund availability to cover these fees, the process delineated involves initial commitment of funds by both downstream and upstream nodes into a burn output, securing the necessary amount for eventual hold fee coverage. This method calculates hold fees based on maximum possible delays, integrating the cost of capital held up across all nodes involved in a transaction. Such a comprehensive approach ensures the full accounting of time-value money costs, offering flexibility in fee calculation to accommodate various transaction scenarios, thereby enhancing protocol adaptability for different payment types including stable coins.

A novel Fee-Based Spam Reduction Protocol proposes a differentiated fee structure comprising Upfront Fees, Hold Fees, and Success Fees across a ten-hop payment scenario, aiming to efficiently mitigate spam and malicious activities within the network. This protocol introduces a nuanced fee calculation, targeting comprehensive coverage of operational costs and risks, contrasting with existing protocols that do not account for the myriad of associated risks and costs, especially in delayed or failed payments scenarios. The innovative approach ensures fair compensation to nodes for capital costs due to delays instigated at any point in the transaction chain, showcasing significant advantages in efficiency, fairness, and resilience against undesirable network behaviors.

Further advancements include the refinement of latency issues introduced by bug fixes in payment channel networks, proposing solutions to maintain low latency while implementing time-dependent Hold Fees. This approach addresses latency penalties, facilitating faster payment propagation without compromising security or efficiency. Moreover, a detailed examination of the two-stage update process for Commitment transactions suggests a mechanism for incorporating increased burn funds and HTLC outputs in a manner that mitigates previously identified bugs, ensuring a safe and efficient protocol operation.

Addressing vulnerabilities within the Lightning Network's framework regarding the handling of HTLCs highlights the importance of developing strategies to prevent potential exploitation through unwarranted hold fees. This exploration acknowledges the need for reliable mechanisms to assure message delivery and acknowledgment, preventing manipulation tactics that could lead to financial losses for unsuspecting nodes. The discussion extends to the risks associated with JIT channels and the potential for exploitation, underlining the critical need for enhanced protective measures within the network's operational protocols.

Building upon foundational strategies proposed by Jager and Teinturier, subsequent enhancements aim to fortify the Lightning Network against spam and inefficiency through the introduction of Upfront Fees and Time-Dependent Reverse Hold Fees, integrating mechanisms like burn outputs to secure fee allocation and encourage cooperative behavior amongst nodes. This refined strategy delineates a structured framework for fee collection, emphasizing the importance of collaboration and deterrence of malicious activities to foster a more secure, efficient, and cooperative network ecosystem.</summary>
    <published>2025-07-02T13:03:14.145000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
