<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
  <updated>2025-03-18T02:29:17.347031+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-03-17 18:49:16.589000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-03-17 18:25:33.005000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Chris_Stewart_5 2025-03-17 16:59:40.135000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-03-17 13:42:37.277000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>salvatoshi 2025-03-17 12:29:05.169000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4562_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4561_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4555_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4553_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4551_OP-CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY-and-its-amount-semantic.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY and its amount semantic</title>
    <updated>2025-03-18T02:29:17.347101+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/op-checkcontractverify-and-its-amount-semantic/1527" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the concept of `OP_CHECKCONTRACTVERIFY` (OP_CCV), a proposed opcode that introduces state-carrying UTXOs, enabling transactions to carry data, rules, and amounts, thereby allowing for more complex and dynamic smart contract functionalities within the Bitcoin network. The concept of OP_CCV facilitates transactions where inputs and outputs can be dynamically linked through embedded data and rules, utilizing tweaks similar to those found in Taproot for committing to additional arbitrary data. This approach is highlighted as being fully compatible with Taproot, providing efficiency and flexibility without imposing extra burdens on nodes or requiring explicit storage of state.

The core functionality of OP_CCV lies in its handling of transaction amounts, offering mechanisms to specify how coins are distributed across outputs. Three distinct behaviors are outlined: default, deduct, and ignore, which cater to various scenarios ranging from assigning all unassigned input amounts to a particular output, deducting a specified portion for an output, or merely performing script checks without enforcing amount constraints. These features are designed to ensure that the allocation of transaction amounts is accounted for explicitly, avoiding implicit assumptions about money flow and facilitating a wide range of transaction types including 1-to-1, many-to-1, and partial amount transactions.

Examples provided illustrate the versatility of OP_CCV in crafting transactions that update smart contract states, aggregate inputs towards a single output, and manage partial withdrawals or allocations among multiple parties. These examples underscore the potential of OP_CCV to enable sophisticated contracts like vaults or shared-UTXO schemes, albeit acknowledging the need for additional verification mechanisms like `CHECKSIG` for certain operations.

Critically, the proposal suggests integrating amount logic directly within the OP_CCV's scope, arguing against separating script and amount introspections to maintain ergonomic and efficient contract designs. This integrated approach aims to simplify the implementation of complex transaction patterns without resorting to cumbersome or less secure alternatives. Furthermore, the possibility of extending OP_CCV's functionality with direct equality checks on output amounts or more generic introspection opcodes is explored, indicating areas for further development and enhancement of the opcode's utility.

In conclusion, OP_CCV represents a significant advancement in Bitcoin scripting capabilities, promising to enrich the ecosystem with more dynamic and flexible smart contracts. The proposed opcode combines state management with precise control over transaction flows, offering a robust framework for developing advanced financial instruments and applications on the Bitcoin network.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-17T18:49:16.589000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
