<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-11T02:27:16.137949+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-11 01:45:46.610000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>moonsettler 2025-03-10 23:35:27.440000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>1440000bytes 2025-03-10 22:58:38.433000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4461_CTV-CSFS-Can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4463_CTV-CSFS-Can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4462_CTV-CSFS-Can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - CTV+CSFS: Can we reach consensus on a first step towards covenants?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T02:27:16.137999+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/2" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion on the integration of covenants into the bitcoin protocol reflects a nuanced exploration of enhancing the blockchain's functionality while preserving its core principles. The recent positive shift in sentiment among bitcoin developers towards covenants has been noteworthy. This change is partly attributed to proposed roadmaps for their incremental introduction, which aim to balance innovation with the network's foundational values of decentralization and permissionlessness. One such roadmap, which received significant community support, suggests a phased approach to covenant implementation, beginning with simpler, more established opcodes before moving towards more generalized solutions.

Bitcoin protocol developers face the critical responsibility of safeguarding the network's integrity while extending its capabilities. This challenge includes evaluating potential consensus changes cautiously to prevent adverse outcomes like bugs, chain splits, or altered incentive structures. To address these concerns, the overarching strategy involves making the bitcoin protocol as expressive as possible for application developers without compromising security or core network properties. The [Great Script Restoration project](https://rusty.ozlabs.org/2024/01/19/the-great-opcode-restoration.html) by Rusty Russel exemplifies this approach by proposing to restore much of Bitcoin's Script functionality, thereby expanding the protocol's expressiveness in a safe manner. This initiative, coupled with the introduction of a VarOps budget for script execution, lays the groundwork for efficient and practical covenant-based transaction introspection.

The cautious yet forward-looking stance on covenants considers the technical and network implications of fully generalized solutions. The OP_TXHASH opcode, inspired by Russel O’Connor’s ideas and detailed at [covenants.info](https://covenants.info/proposals/txhash/), illustrates an intermediate step towards broader covenant functionalities. It also highlights the potential for combining established opcodes like CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) and CSFS (CHECKSIGFROMSTACK) to enhance bitcoin's utility for second-layer protocols without necessitating immediate, comprehensive upgrades.

CTV and CSFS collectively enable new protocol possibilities, simplifying and extending the scope of existing frameworks. For instance, they offer a foundational structure for transaction templates, reduce the need for signature storage, and facilitate more user-friendly implementations of Lightning Network channels. Moreover, their compatibility with future covenant advancements ensures that these opcodes will remain relevant as the network evolves. These developments underscore a strategic approach to covenant integration, emphasizing incremental progress, broad utility, and careful consideration of the network's fundamental characteristics.

Finally, the proposed roadmap for covenants, including a combination of CTV, CSFS, and other opcodes, represents a thoughtful attempt to enhance bitcoin's functionality responsibly. By prioritizing safety, utility, and consensus, developers aim to introduce capabilities that enrich the ecosystem without undermining its core values. This approach not only reflects the complexity of implementing covenants but also the collaborative and cautious ethos that guides bitcoin protocol development.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T01:45:46.610000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
