<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-03-26T02:31:24.061830+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-25 14:23:10.708000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-03-24 14:32:20.830000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-22 19:12:19.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-22 19:02:45.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>neha  . 2025-03-21 16:49:31.233000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-03-17 17:26:03.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-17 17:23:04.588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4601_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4594_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4590_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4589_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4583_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4560_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4559_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-03-26T02:31:24.061895+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the intriguing domain of cryptocurrency transactions, a particular model enables users to enhance the security and trust in their transactions by allowing them to refresh their Unspent Transaction Output (VTXO) during a transaction round. This refreshing process resets the trust level associated with the VTXO, thus leveraging blockchain technology's inherent features to simplify and secure asset transfers. Users engage in "send to self" transactions, which mitigates the complexities and potential security vulnerabilities tied to transferring assets to others, streamlining the process on the client's end.

The Arkoor model introduces a nuanced method for managing liquidity costs linked to refreshing VTXOs, which depends on the time remaining until their expiration. This model provides a choice between obtaining full trustless ownership of the VTXO, thereby incurring a higher liquidity fee, or accepting an extended trust assumption to save on fees. The decision largely depends on the amount held in the VTXO and the source of these funds, with larger amounts from unknown parties likely prompting early refreshes. However, this system's reliance on user interactivity during rounds poses a vulnerability to denial-of-service (DoS) attacks, as an attacker could disrupt the process by failing to cooperate. To address this, the model employs strategies like banning non-cooperative users and penalizing the VTXOs of participants who abandon the round, although challenges remain in penalizing receivers due to their lack of an existing VTXO to reduce in value.

The statechain model within the arkoor system ensures that a VTXO cannot be double-spent as long as there is no collusion with previous owners, thereby reducing trust requirements and facilitating a trustless state restoration for VTXOs directly resulting from a round. This mechanism encourages users to hold onto their arkoor VTXOs longer by imposing a liquidity fee proportional to the time until the VTXO's expiry, aimed at enhancing overall liquidity management in the system.

User experience (UX) and trust trade-offs are evident in the requirement for recipients to be online during message sending, where reliance on the server and sender not colluding introduces a time-limited security assumption but mitigates the need for interactivity. This highlights the significant impact of UX considerations on the design of secure communication systems, balancing ease of use against potential security risks.

Concerning advancements in transaction methods, the discussion touches upon out-of-round (OOR) transactions facilitated by Arkoor and the potential integration of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) to streamline these processes. The current reliance on OOR transactions introduces additional security assumptions, seen as a temporary measure until a more secure settlement method can be implemented. The introduction of CTV aims to enable secure vUTXO transfers within transaction rounds, potentially reducing the current method's security assumptions.

Finally, the application of CTV in the Ark protocol for creating virtual UTXOs (vUTXOs) offers substantial benefits, enabling seamless transaction transitions and flexible ownership transfers without owner presence during issuance. This is further enhanced by the development of clArk, an iteration without covenants but with mechanisms to mitigate unsanctioned constructions and streamline user participation in rounds. The integration of CTV thus presents notable improvements in usability, efficiency, and security within the network, evidenced by ongoing efforts to refine and test the clArk implementation. Further exploration of this topic can be found through resources such as the [original thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), the [Ark case for CTV](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733), and the [Ark protocol introduction](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/vtxos/index.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-03-25T14:23:10.708000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
