<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-03-18T02:30:14.836785+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-03-17 17:26:03.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose 2025-03-17 17:23:04.588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4560_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4559_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-03-18T02:30:14.836822+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discussion revolves around the intricacies and benefits of using CTV (CheckTemplateVerify) in the Ark protocol, particularly highlighting its impact on virtual utxos (vtxos), which are off-chain utxos held by users within the system. The original design leverages CTV for constructing vtxos through a series of transactions that form a tree structure, where each transaction is linked to the next via a CTV covenant. This setup facilitates various functions like congestion control, with the overall aim being to enhance user experience and system efficiency.

A notable aspect of using CTV is its non-interactive nature, allowing for the autonomous issuance of vtxos that expire at a specified time. This feature is critical for "onboarding" new participants into the Ark, as it enables them to enter the ecosystem without requiring interactive processes. However, a newer model termed `clArk` (covenant-less Ark) has been developed, which replaces the CTV policy with a MuSig2 pre-signature involving the server's key and those of all users below a certain node. Although this reduces reliance on CTV, it introduces limitations such as additional signing and storage demands, and crucially, requires the eventual owner's presence for issuing vtxos safely.

Despite these challenges, the ability to issue vtxos to others without their participation in Ark rounds presents several advantages. It simplifies the process of sending vtxos, bypassing the need for receiver involvement in the transaction rounds. Moreover, it empowers servers to automatically re-issue expired vtxos and facilitate the reception of Lightning payments without necessitating virtual channels. These capabilities significantly improve user convenience and the overall functionality of the Ark ecosystem.

Furthermore, the utilization of CTV allows for the non-interactive issuance of multiple vtxos from a single on-chain output, offering a powerful tool for entities like exchanges or DCA providers to regularly disburse amounts to their users. This aspect underscores the potential of CTV to streamline payouts and enhance the viability of participating in Ark rounds, especially in mobile settings.

The team at Second is actively working to validate these claims by testing the implementation of co-signed Ark on mobile clients, aiming to substantiate the benefits outlined and further refine the system's effectiveness.

For more detailed information, references are made to specific resources, including an introduction to out-of-round (Arkoor) transactions at [ark-protocol.org](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/oor/index.html), and further elaboration on the Ark case for CTV can be found at a dedicated [link](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733). This discussion initially emerged in another thread, which can be accessed [here](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), to avoid derailing the primary conversation.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-17T17:26:03.792000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
