<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
  <updated>2025-07-01T03:57:13.867479+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk 2025-06-30 17:09:09.803000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw 2025-06-30 00:57:12.392000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk 2025-06-02 14:22:43.705000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-22 21:20:03.071000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-05-12 17:47:12.512000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:20:40.305000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-25 21:17:55.471000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ClaraShk  . 2025-04-15 15:55:25.988000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-04-05 19:42:07.993000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-25 06:09:28.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-21 21:08:20.002000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>harding  . 2025-03-18 15:11:31.870000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JohnLaw  . 2025-03-14 23:58:49.861000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5379_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5371_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/June_2025/5192_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/5092_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/May_2025/4993_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4878_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4877_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4790_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4708_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4598_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4586_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4568_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4541_Fee-Based-Spam-Prevention-For-Lightning.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Fee-Based Spam Prevention For Lightning</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T03:57:13.867577+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/fee-based-spam-prevention-for-lightning/1524" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse concerning the Lightning Network (LN) spans several critical enhancements and theoretical discussions aimed at addressing the network's efficiency, fairness, and resistance to spam and malicious activities. A foundational aspect of this dialogue is the implementation of a fee-based protocol designed to mitigate spam by introducing Upfront Fees, Hold Fees, and Success Fees. These fees are structured to cover the costs and risks associated with processing payments through the network, such as the temporary allocation of channel funds, the opportunity cost of locking funds in a pending state, and incentivizing successful transaction completions.

A pivotal element of the protocol is the calculation and charging of Hold Fees, which compensate nodes for the capital held during the delay of a payment's resolution. The process involves staking the maximum possible hold fee charge in a burn output, ensuring that funds are available to cover the fee once the payment is resolved. This mechanism addresses the opportunity cost for nodes by providing compensation based on the duration a payment is held, thereby aligning with the principle of covering the cost of capital across all upstream nodes involved in a transaction.

Furthermore, the correspondence delves into the practicalities and theoretical underpinnings of handling Hash Time-Locked Contracts (HTLCs), highlighting a two-step update process for commitment transactions to accommodate increased burn funds and HTLC outputs. This nuanced approach aims to rectify latency issues and simplify protocol operations, thereby enhancing the network's efficiency and user experience. It also touches on the psychological dynamics of transactional relationships within the network, suggesting automated protocols to prevent exploitation and ensure fair compensation.

Additionally, discussions around the Fee-Based Spam Reduction Protocol propose an innovative structure for fee distribution, leveraging burn outputs to foster cooperation among nodes and deter fee misappropriation. The protocol outlines methods for calculating Upfront and Hold Fees, introducing concepts such as staking and matching funds to preemptively cover potential delays, thus maintaining network integrity and trust.

In terms of technological advancements, the proposal includes improvements aimed at reducing latency introduced by bug fixes, specifically focusing on streamlining the transaction process while ensuring secure and efficient payment forwarding. This involves a strategic adjustment to the handling of commitment transactions and HTLC outputs, emphasizing the importance of minimizing performance impact and optimizing network operations.

Moreover, the evolution of these discussions reflects a concerted effort to refine the Lightning Network's operational framework, focusing on mitigating jamming attacks, optimizing payment routing, and enhancing overall network resilience. By addressing both theoretical and practical challenges, the ongoing dialogue underscores a commitment to continuous improvement and innovation within the LN ecosystem, aiming to provide a robust, efficient, and equitable platform for digital transactions.</summary>
    <published>2025-06-30T17:09:09.803000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
