<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Cluster mempool partitioning attacks</title>
  <updated>2025-04-01T02:51:00.842912+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>sipa 2025-04-01 01:34:34.599000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-03-31 19:47:44.102000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stefanwouldgo 2025-03-31 14:57:05.826000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/April_2025/4655_Cluster-mempool-partitioning-attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4654_Cluster-mempool-partitioning-attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4649_Cluster-mempool-partitioning-attacks.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Cluster mempool partitioning attacks</title>
    <updated>2025-04-01T02:51:00.842974+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/cluster-mempool-partitioning-attacks/1548" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In the evolving landscape of Bitcoin transaction processing, particularly with the advent of cluster mempools and Replace-By-Fee (RBF) mechanisms, several nuanced challenges have emerged. These include complexities surrounding transaction relay, linearization of transaction clusters post-processing, and how these factors interplay during blockchain reorganizations. The discussion highlights that after a block is processed, it necessitates the relinearization of all clusters affected by transactions either included in the block or conflicting with it. This process becomes particularly intricate in the event of a blockchain reorganization, where transactions from disconnected blocks are reintegrated into the mempool, potentially breaching cluster count or size limitations.

The discourse further delves into the intricacies of RBF transactions within this new framework, emphasizing the non-confluent nature of transaction relay. Factors such as DoS protection, conflict resolution, and the inherent differences in policy rules contribute to this complexity. Notably, the challenge of ensuring an optimal choice or order of transactions amidst dependencies and conflicts is underscored, revealing the practical difficulties in achieving global or object optimums in transaction linearization. This situation is compounded by the varying interpretations and implementations of RBF rules across different nodes, which could hinder the seamless relay and confirmation of transactions.

A significant portion of the conversation revolves around the proposal for requiring linearizations when replacing existing transactions using RBF, a measure aimed at mitigating time constraints during relay. However, this proposal is met with skepticism, particularly due to the potential bandwidth wastage and the impracticality of expecting wallets or nodes to possess comprehensive knowledge of mempool contents for effective linearization. The dialogue references a specific attack scenario where an attacker submits multiple versions of a transaction group, each version conflicting with the others but having incomparable fee diagrams. This tactic, designed to exploit the partial order of diagrams over scalar fees, could effectively partition network mempools, hindering the relay of honest transactions.

The conversation incorporates links to further discussions on the topic, including a detailed write-up on post-cluster mempool RBF ([How to linearize your cluster](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/how-to-linearize-your-cluster/303)) and a reference to a proposed set of RBF rules in a cluster mempool context ([Bitcoin's mempool replacements proposal](https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/20e42a4a7423d7bc62326cdb6405bc6d5900953e/doc/policy/mempool-replacements.md)). These resources provide valuable insights into the ongoing efforts to refine and enhance transaction processing mechanisms in response to the evolving challenges posed by blockchain technology advancements.</summary>
    <published>2025-04-01T01:34:34.599000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
