<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-03-13T02:29:04.536815+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns 2025-03-13 00:46:49.028000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin 2025-03-13 00:40:24.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard 2025-03-13 00:27:38.831000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-12 23:02:27.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4502_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4501_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4500_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4497_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T02:29:04.536863+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/question-about-op-ctv-and-non-recursive-covenants/1517" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The utilization of Bitcoin for issuing stocks and securities through a protocol appears to be an intriguing concept, especially in the context of decentralized versus centralized management systems. The idea posits that while stocks and securities are traditionally managed centrally by the issuing companies themselves for efficiency and control, implementing these processes on Bitcoin could introduce benefits such as anonymous trading, the use of automated market makers through wrapped BTC or stablecoins, and the facilitation of cross-security trades on a unified platform. However, there's an acknowledgment that custom solutions might eventually outcompete such implementations on Bitcoin due to their more tailored approach to handling these financial instruments.

A specific challenge within this discourse is highlighted in the creation of buy offers for multiple unspent transaction outputs (UTXOs) using a single Partially Signed Bitcoin Transaction (PSBT). This process is currently hampered by the necessity to create separate PSBTs for each UTXO one wishes to acquire, which stands as a significant limitation within the runes protocol—an initiative aimed at facilitating trustless transactions. The difficulty lies in crafting a PSBT that can encompass offers for multiple UTXOs without needing to resort to individual transactions for each, compounded by the intricacies of ensuring transaction integrity and specificity towards the intended UTXOs.

The OP_CheckTemplateVerify (OP_CTV) proposal is examined as a potential solution to this problem, albeit with limitations. OP_CTV allows users to commit to the outputs of a transaction but not its inputs, thereby preventing the creation of recursive covenants—a concept deemed undesirable due to its complexity and potential for misuse. Despite initial hopes, OP_CTV does not seem to offer a direct solution for creating multi-UTXO buy offers due to its inability to commit to specific inputs. However, the exploration into OP_CTV and related technologies like elements-style introspection suggests ongoing efforts to find workarounds for these limitations, including the possibility of committing to the "location" of an input rather than its direct inclusion in a transaction, although this introduces other complexities such as script validation challenges and reorg risks.

This debate and exploration touch upon broader discussions in the Bitcoin development community regarding the balance between enabling advanced transactional features and maintaining the security and simplicity of the network. References to resources such as [Sapio](https://github.com/sapio-lang/sapio/tree/master/sapio-contrib/src/contracts/derivatives) for writing option contracts and inherited ID proposals indicate a vibrant dialogue around enhancing Bitcoin's functionality for complex financial transactions without compromising its foundational principles. Furthermore, the mention of historical discussions on covenant ideas underscores the depth of thought and consideration being applied to these developments.

In summary, the discussion encapsulates a nuanced exploration of integrating sophisticated financial instruments like stocks and securities into the Bitcoin ecosystem, grappling with technical challenges, and evaluating potential solutions within the constraints of Bitcoin's design philosophy. While the path forward involves technical hurdles and philosophical debates, the exploration itself highlights the ongoing evolution of Bitcoin's capabilities and its potential role in broader financial contexts.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:46:49.028000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
