<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
  <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:07.701249+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs 2025-03-24 14:32:20.830000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-22 19:12:19.635000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-22 19:02:45.865000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>neha  . 2025-03-21 16:49:31.233000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>instagibbs  . 2025-03-17 17:26:03.792000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>stevenroose  . 2025-03-17 17:23:04.588000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4594_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4590_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4589_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4583_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4560_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4559_The-Ark-case-for-CTV.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - The Ark case for CTV</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T02:30:07.701314+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/the-ark-case-for-ctv/1528" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The Arkoor model introduces a nuanced system for handling the liquidity costs associated with refreshing VTXOs (Unspent Transaction Outputs), balancing between trustless ownership and cost efficiency. This model permits users to refresh their VTXO, transitioning from a state of reduced trust back to full trustlessness, albeit at a higher liquidity fee. This fee is proportional to the remaining time until the VTXO's expiration, incentivizing users with large amounts or those receiving VTXOs from unknown sources to refresh early, thus avoiding potential risks. On the other hand, individuals dealing with smaller transactions might opt for delaying the refresh to save on fees. The model, however, faces challenges related to its interactivity requirement, which is critical for operation but also exposes it to denial-of-service (DoS) attacks. To mitigate these vulnerabilities, strategies such as banning non-cooperative users and penalizing participants who abandon the round are implemented. Yet, enforcing penalties on receivers remains complex due to their lack of an existing VTXO to penalize, highlighting the operational challenges in systems demanding high user cooperation.

The statechain model employed by Arkoor ensures that a VTXO cannot be double-spent, provided the server does not collude with any previous owner. This model reduces the trust requirement by allowing users to refresh their VTXO within a round, thereby exiting the reduced trust assumption. The option to refresh VTXOs immediately after acquisition is provided, though it comes with a liquidity fee that encourages users to delay refreshing to reduce frequency and potentially improve the system’s liquidity management. The necessity for recipients to be online during a transaction introduces a trade-off between user experience and security. Leveraging server and sender integrity, albeit introducing a temporary security assumption, alleviates the need for recipient interactivity, underscoring the importance of balancing convenience and security in communication systems.

Further discussion touches upon the limitations and future improvements in transaction methods within the Arkoor protocol, particularly the integration of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) to enhance out-of-round (OOR) transactions. The current reliance on OOR transactions introduces additional security assumptions, seen as a stopgap until a more secure method involving real swaps to a new Ark can be implemented. Incorporating CTV could allow for intra-round VTXO transfers, potentially diminishing the need for these additional security layers. This transition aims to bolster the security and trust model of transactions, emphasizing the quest for more efficient and reliable transaction methods without compromising safety. 

The use of CTV in the Ark protocol, specifically for creating virtual UTXOs (vUTXOs), is highlighted as a significant advancement. CTV facilitates seamless transaction chains through non-interactive issuance and transfer of vUTXOs, governed by two main policies ensuring security and flexibility. The development of clArk, an iteration without covenants, addresses the limitation requiring the presence of the eventual owner for co-signing, by allowing users to refresh their vUTXOs. The capability of sending vUTXOs to others without their participation in rounds, alongside automatic reissuance of expired vUTXOs and facilitating Lightning payments, marks a notable improvement in system usability and functionality. These enhancements suggest a broader applicability, including for exchanges or DCA providers to distribute payouts non-interactively. The ongoing refinement of the clArk implementation indicates potential for further improvements, as detailed in discussions and resources available at [the original thread](https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/ctv-csfs-can-we-reach-consensus-on-a-first-step-towards-covenants/1509/50?u=stevenroose), [the Ark case for CTV](https://x.com/stevenroose3/status/1865144252751028733), and [the introduction to the Ark protocol](https://ark-protocol.org/intro/vtxos/index.html).</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T14:32:20.830000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
