<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-03-19T02:27:05.440175+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-18 15:12:03.779000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2025-03-17 22:39:49.013000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-13 14:48:52.122000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-13 14:29:22.659000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2025-03-13 02:37:26.459000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-13 02:21:42.542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-13 02:12:51.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-03-13 00:46:49.028000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2025-03-13 00:40:24.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2025-03-13 00:27:38.831000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-12 23:02:27.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4569_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4564_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4513_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4508_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4507_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4506_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4505_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4502_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4501_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4500_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4497_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-03-19T02:27:05.440264+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/question-about-op-ctv-and-non-recursive-covenants/1517" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse opens with a critique of the potential for adversarial contracts within blockchain transactions, emphasizing concerns over the stability of miner networks and the integrity of blockchain properties such as linearity and finality. This conversation evolves into a consideration of advanced solutions like signature-time cross-input scripting to enhance Bitcoin's transactional flexibility without compromising its foundational principles. The suggestion of a subscript-only opcode for full introspection highlights a balance between innovation and the preservation of blockchain's core functionalities.

Further, the dialogue explores the concept of using Bitcoin for issuing stocks and securities, presenting a novel approach for companies to raise capital directly from Bitcoin holders. This method proposes bypassing traditional financial intermediaries, offering a streamlined process for capital raising, share buybacks, and dividend issuance through direct secondary markets between Bitcoin and company stock. However, technical challenges related to creating scalable and efficient buy offers for digital assets on Bitcoin are acknowledged, particularly in the context of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) and the limitations imposed by current Bitcoin transaction standards.

The discussion delves into the utility of CheckTemplateVerify (CTV) in creating binding offers and commitments within Bitcoin transactions, aiming to address scalability issues by reducing the number of required signatures. Despite the innovative prospects of CTV and PSBTs for enhancing Bitcoin's transactional capabilities, practical limitations exist, notably the inability to commit to specific spent outpoints—a critical requirement for the proposed transactional schemes to work effectively.

The conversation transitions to a broader examination of blockchain technology's evolution, focusing on the development of covenants that could potentially improve the security and functionality of digital transactions. These discussions contemplate the ethical and technical implications of imposing transactional constraints, considering alternatives that might mitigate risks without overly restricting the movement or utility of digital assets.

In addressing the integration of stocks and securities into the Bitcoin network, the discussion acknowledges the benefits of decentralized management over traditional centralized approaches, highlighting the potential for automated market makers and simplified cross-security trades. Technical solutions to overcome existing limitations in making aggregated buy offers within the Bitcoin protocol are explored, with a particular emphasis on the complexities of implementing a flexible yet secure system for transactions.

Finally, the dialogue circles back to the initial proposal of Contract Through Voice (CTV) and the exploration of relative references and inherited IDs within blockchain transactions. The potential for CTV to facilitate complex contract structures, such as on-chain auctions for ordinals, is underscored, alongside the ongoing explorations in the field aimed at advancing blockchain technology and smart contract applications. This comprehensive discussion encapsulates the dynamic nature of blockchain innovation, reflecting a commitment to exploring new avenues for enhancing the transactional capabilities of cryptocurrencies.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-18T15:12:03.779000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
