<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
  <updated>2025-03-14T02:28:48.273688+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-13 14:48:52.122000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-13 14:29:22.659000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin 2025-03-13 02:37:26.459000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-13 02:21:42.542000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh 2025-03-13 02:12:51.646000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ajtowns  . 2025-03-13 00:46:49.028000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>JeremyRubin  . 2025-03-13 00:40:24.184000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>ariard  . 2025-03-13 00:27:38.831000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  . 2025-03-12 23:02:27.468000+00:00</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4513_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4508_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4507_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4506_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4505_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4502_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4501_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4500_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4497_Question-about-OP-CTV-and-Non-Recursive-Covenants.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Question about OP_CTV and Non-Recursive Covenants</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T02:28:48.273765+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/question-about-op-ctv-and-non-recursive-covenants/1517" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation begins with a focus on the potential of integrating stocks and securities into the Bitcoin network, proposing a decentralized model as an alternative to traditional centralized management. This approach is heralded for its promise in enabling anonymous trading, utilizing stablecoins or wrapped BTC for transactions, and consolidating securities on a unified platform. The benefits described include facilitating automated market makers and simplifying the process of cross-security trades, outlining a vision for a comprehensive ecosystem for the trading of stocks and securities within the Bitcoin framework.

A specific technical challenge is addressed regarding the runes protocol and the creation of Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) for buy offers. The current limitation necessitates separate PSBTs for each Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO), complicating the process for users aiming to make offers on multiple UTXOs concurrently. This section dives into the feasibility of using elements-style introspection for a script to assert control over transaction outputs, thus potentially simplifying the purchase of runes without requiring distinct signatures for each transaction. However, distinguishing between acceptable UTXOs for transactions remains complex under the current system.

Further discussion explores the constraints of OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (OP_CTV), specifically its design to prevent recursive covenants by committing only to transaction outputs, not inputs. This highlights the challenges in creating a flexible yet secure method for making aggregated buy offers within the Bitcoin protocol. The conversation also delves into the computational impracticality of committing both to inputs and outputs, emphasizing the complexities of enhancing Bitcoin's transactional capabilities.

The exploration of Contract Through Voice (CTV) is noted for its flexibility and capability in handling multiple inputs, which could significantly improve smart contracts' functionality and applications within the blockchain domain. The ability to write option contracts using CTV introduces practical use cases, such as registering on-chain auctions for ordinals. Additionally, the discussion mentions the concept of relative references, aligning with John Law's proposal on inherited IDs, suggesting innovative approaches to referencing entities within a blockchain network.

In 2013, Gregory Maxwell introduced the concept of a covenant in blockchain, focusing on establishing rules that govern chains of transactions. This idea aimed at enhancing security and functionality by embedding conditions for transactions to proceed. The ensuing discussion explored technical intricacies, potential applications, and concerns about transaction malleability and overall integrity improvements in blockchains. Such covenants could introduce a new layer of programmability, expanding the utility of blockchain and smart contracts.

The OP_CTV proposal garners interest for its implications on Bitcoin's functionality, especially concerning covenants. It allows users to commit to transaction outputs without committing to inputs, preventing recursive covenants. This limitation complicates executing complex transactions like making multiple buy offers within a single PSBT. The discourse considers whether it would be feasible or beneficial to allow commitments to the location of an input rather than the input itself, despite potential complications such as increased script validation complexity and issues from blockchain reorganizations. This theoretical functionality could meet the needs for making multi-UTXO offers without enabling recursive covenants, reflecting ongoing interest in enhancing Bitcoin's utility, particularly for companies integrating Bitcoin into their treasury strategies.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T14:48:52.122000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
