<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>2</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
  <updated>2025-03-28T02:28:41.758498+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>garlonicon  .</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>josh  .</name>
  </author>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4637_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4636_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4630_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4605_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4599_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="delvingbitcoin/March_2025/4597_Is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem-.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Is there a social approach to the quantum problem?</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T02:28:41.758559+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/is-there-a-social-approach-to-the-quantum-problem/1537" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The discourse around the security and future-proofing of Bitcoin and blockchain technology against potential quantum computing threats has led to a variety of suggestions and technical explorations. One such exploration focuses on the method by which commitments, particularly those aimed at enhancing security or adding additional data, are integrated into transactions. It is posited that tweaking inputs rather than outputs presents a more user-friendly approach, avoiding confusion that may arise from changes in address formats and the challenges associated with managing commitments in output descriptors. This approach advocates for a standardized method of committing data to ensure consistency and reliability across the network, especially as it evolves through soft forks and other updates.

A notable proposal within this context is the adjustment of Schnorr public keys to include the hash of a quantum-resistant public key. This technique aims to minimize the blockchain's on-chain footprint while simplifying the off-chain backup processes necessary for secure and efficient transaction verification. By integrating quantum-resistant elements into existing cryptographic practices, such as Schnorr signatures, the community can prepare for future advancements in quantum computing without sacrificing the current system's integrity.

Another innovative suggestion involves altering the ECDSA signature’s R-value to embed proofs directly within transactions, bypassing traditional methods that utilize the `OP_RETURN` field. This proposed method could significantly decrease transaction sizes and enhance the concealment of commitments, making it more difficult to detect the presence of any additional data. This shift towards embedding proofs within the ECDSA signature represents a move towards optimizing blockchain transactions for greater privacy and efficiency.

The broader conversation also touches upon the social and speculative aspects of Bitcoin's security concerning quantum computing. While there is an acknowledgment of the theoretical risk posed by quantum advancements, the immediate concern seems to be more about perception than technical vulnerability. Bitcoin's architecture, particularly its use of hashed public keys, inherently provides some level of quantum resistance. However, the speculation about quantum threats could impact investor confidence and, consequently, Bitcoin's valuation. In response, strategies like promoting the voluntary adoption of quantum-resistant measures and leveraging platforms such as [OpenTimestamps](https://opentimestamps.org) alongside [BIP322](https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/02ad0e01c2a9189124e05a52afe97ef90a3b7f1f/bip-0322.mediawiki) for proof of ownership are suggested. These approaches aim to reinforce trust among Bitcoin users and investors by ensuring a degree of readiness for possible future quantum computational abilities without necessitating immediate drastic changes to Bitcoin's structure or operations. This perspective underscores the importance of community engagement and proactive planning in maintaining Bitcoin's robustness against evolving technological landscapes.</summary>
    <published>2025-03-27T05:19:09.309000+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
