<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007097</id>
  <title>OpenSSL 1.0.0p / 1.0.1k incompatible, causes blockchain rejection.</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:24:47.256802+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007097</id>
    <title>OpenSSL 1.0.0p / 1.0.1k incompatible, causes blockchain rejection.</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:24:47.256802+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2015-January/007097.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The recent release of OpenSSL 1.0.0p/1.0.1k is incompatible with the Bitcoin system and could lead to consensus forks. However, Bitcoin Core released binaries from Bitcoin.org are not affected, nor are any built with the gitian deterministic build system. If you are running third-party or self-compiled Bitcoin Core or an alternative implementation using OpenSSL, you must not update OpenSSL or must run a Bitcoin software containing a workaround. The incompatibility is due to OpenSSL's update changing the behavior of ECDSA validation to reject any signature that is not encoded in a rigid manner. This change can constitute a security vulnerability for the Bitcoin system as all participants must generally agree on the exact validity or invalidity of the input data. An uncontrolled fix can lead to potential hard-forks due to signature encoding handling, which is why a targeted soft-fork to enforce strict DER compliance soon has been proposed by the author as an incremental improvement. Adding a blockchain rule for strict DER will reduce the risk of consensus inconsistencies from alternative implementations of signature parsing or verification, simplify BIP62, and better isolate the cryptographic validation code from the consensus algorithm. A failure to do so can leave us in this situation or worse again in the future. The relevant incompatible transactions have already been non-standard on the network since 0.8.0's release in February 2013, although there was seemingly a single miner still mining incompatible transactions. That miner has been contacted and has fixed their software, so a soft-fork with no chain forking should be possible.</summary>
    <published>2015-01-10T04:26:23+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
