<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007095</id>
  <title>Bi-directional micropayment channels with CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:24:14.006926+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007095</id>
    <title>Bi-directional micropayment channels with CHECKLOCKTIMEVERIFY</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:24:14.006926+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2015-January/007095.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In an email conversation dated January 9, 2015, Mike Hearn discusses the idea that Bitcoin must work even if lots of miners are malicious and willing to break arbitrary things in order to get more money. He argues that Bitcoin is not safe even if only 1% of the hash power is naughty, as an attacker will have a 1% success rate. In addition, he believes that absolute soundness is best, followed by cryptographic soundness, economic soundness, and then honesty soundness. However, users of Bitcoin must navigate this risk stack. Hearn also points out that one man's integrity is another man's malice and thus a risk analysis has to import the clarity of judgment, morality, coerceability, personal values, etc. of everyone in the trust chain. Therefore, users of Bitcoin ought to behave in ways that cannot be harmed by a failure to follow the rules so that they do not invite failures to follow the rules and thereby create an institution of it. A straight forward "relay and store any locked spend" policy has unbounded space and communications complexity, and it is not clear if any real degree of "you can take your risks, it'll probably work, but maybe not" can be supported without a very large resource cost to the network and without creating incentives to DOS attack the network.</summary>
    <published>2015-01-09T14:50:09+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
