<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007081</id>
  <title>Combined summary - Re-enabling simple tx replacement</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:25:33.314122+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007081_Re-enabling-simple-tx-replacement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007080_Re-enabling-simple-tx-replacement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007078_Re-enabling-simple-tx-replacement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007085_Re-enabling-simple-tx-replacement.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007081</id>
    <title>Combined summary - Re-enabling simple tx replacement</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:25:33.314122+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2015-January/007081.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>The conversation is about atomic cross-chain trading between the Bitcoin and Dogecoin blockchains. Ross Nicoll has developed a mostly functional prototype, but there is an issue where if the refund transaction is relayed before the actual spend transaction, it blocks the legitimate spend transaction from being accepted into the memory pool. Gregory Maxwell suggests that this is not the case unless there is a serious bug that he is not aware of since the unlocked transaction is not relayable and will not be mempooled until right before it locks. Ross Nicoll has drafted a patch to solve the problem but has not yet raised a PR because historically, it has led to a lot of discussion in Github which is better suited to the mailing list. He continues to test the patch and comments are welcomed. However, according to Gregory Maxwell, the behavior on testnet is faulty because the non-mempooling is enforced by IsStandardTx, which is bypassed in testnet. They should enforce it elsewhere, but this is not the case on the real network. Additionally, Peter's patch for testnet is expected to fix the issue. Ross Nicoll thanks Gregory Maxwell for his suggestion and for presenting the solution as code, which is a useful way to communicate. Finally, there is a concern that Ross Nicoll's patch has no protection against denial of service since a single user can rapidly update their transaction and exhaust the relay bandwidth of the entire network.</summary>
    <published>2015-01-04T17:44:59+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
