<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007191</id>
  <title>Combined summary - SIGHASH_WITHINPUTVALUE</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T22:26:16.707628+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Gregory Maxwell</name>
  </author>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007191_SIGHASH-WITHINPUTVALUE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007203_SIGHASH-WITHINPUTVALUE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="Jan_2015/007200_SIGHASH-WITHINPUTVALUE.xml" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>mailing-list-bitcoin-2015-January-007191</id>
    <title>Combined summary - SIGHASH_WITHINPUTVALUE</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T22:26:16.707628+00:00</updated>
    <link href="https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2015-January/007191.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>In January 2015, a discussion among Bitcoin developers took place regarding the implementation of a new signature type. Alan Reiner suggested that there was no soft-fork way to achieve the benefits of this new signature type since most of the soft-fork variations required coins being spent to have been originated in a special way. On the other hand, slush proposed a straight-forward soft-fork approach that was safe and only required newly created addresses to get coins that used the new signature type instead of expecting every other user of the system to replace their software with an incompatible new version. Slush also mentioned that the step of building a table is what takes up to 40 minutes of time for TREZOR to validate some complex transactions, but this can be optimized by avoiding dynamic memory allocation and using a table to avoid retransmitting reused transactions. Additionally, the process of streaming all previous transactions into the device for every signed input slows down the signing of transactions with hundreds of inputs on a device with limited memory capabilities like TREZOR.</summary>
    <published>2015-01-23T16:05:10+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
